<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Empowered Participation: Exploring How Citizens Use Technology in Local Governance</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sheena</forename><surname>Erete</surname></persName>
							<email>serete@depaul.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">College of Computing and Digital Media</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">DePaul University Chicago</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>60604</postCode>
									<region>IL</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Burrell</surname></persName>
							<email>jennifer@madxllc.com</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">MadX, LLC Alexandria</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>22302</postCode>
									<region>VA</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Empowered Participation: Exploring How Citizens Use Technology in Local Governance</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3025453.3025996</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T04:56+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>H.5.m. Information Interfaces and Presentation (e.g. HCI): Miscellaneous low income</term>
					<term>civic engagement</term>
					<term>participatory governance</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The partnership between local residents and city officials to inform policy and decision-making about government resources, or participatory governance, has been extensively studied. In addition to numerous ethnographic studies about how citizens engage in-person, there has been increased focus in HCI to understand the impact of technology on citizen participation in local governance. Building upon those studies, this paper provides unique insight from a 3-year longitudinal study on the use of online tools that were organically adapted by citizens to engage in local governance in three diverse Chicago neighborhoods. Though the responsiveness of government officials varied across communities, our results suggest that citizens use technology to heighten the visibility of their concerns, to support mechanisms of government accountability, and to provide various options for resident participation in local governance. We argue that while communities may be effective in their use of ICTs, technology may not increase their political power.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>For decades, scholars have studied participatory governance, the partnership between local residents and city officials to inform policy <ref type="bibr">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">30]</ref>. Though traditional studies have focused on citizen engagement in-person, in the past decade HCI scholars have focused more on understanding digital democracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">17]</ref>. Many of these approaches do not address institutional inequalities embedded in social, economic, and political infrastructures (e.g., poverty, unemployment, lack of educational opportunities, inadequate housing) that impact community issues such as crime -the topic of this paper.</p><p>Many of the inequalities that impact crime are perpetuated by local policies, which have been mostly shaped by groups with political power <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[31]</ref>. We define political power as the ability of a collective group of citizens to influence local policies. The economic status of a group impacts their political power, and the poor have not traditionally had as much political power to change policies that have direct effects on their health, safety, and educational opportunities <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">50]</ref>. For example, in Chicago (like most major cities), violent crime is disproportionately prevalent in low-income neighborhoods <ref type="bibr">[40]</ref>. Yet, much of public policy around violence prevention has been created without the full participation of poor communities that disproportionately experience violent crime. For instance, the mayor's office and the police decide the details of programs, initiatives, and agendas (e.g., policing budgets and the frequency and structure of community-police meetings) to address crime in Chicago, not citizens <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[42,</ref><ref type="bibr">40]</ref>.</p><p>Though there is much debate about the effect of statesponsored community crime prevention programs <ref type="bibr">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">15]</ref>, some scholars suggest that poor communities can gain political power by participating in such programs <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref>. Given the pervasiveness of information and communication technologies (ICTs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[44,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">45]</ref>, there is a unique opportunity to explore the role ICTs play in citizen engagement in local participatory governance. Specifically, we examine the research question: How do ICTs affect political engagement and interactions with city officials around crime prevention in diverse neighborhoods? By ICTs, we refer to any tools that support interactions amongst many citizens that are relatively easy to access and join (e.g., web forums, email lists, social media websites).</p><p>In this paper, we describe how citizens use ICTs to influence local policy, particularly among law enforcement and local government officials. Our results suggest that residents influenced local policies ranging from increasing police presence on a particular street corner to petitioning for the demolition of abandoned buildings by leveraging ICTs to increase the visibility of community concerns, to support holding officials accountable, and to provide additional methods of participation. However, we also observed that though residents in affluent and lower-income neighborhoods used technology similarly, city officials responded more promptly to residents in affluent neighborhoods. This paper makes several contributions to the field of HCI. First, our findings provide insights into the usage of ICTs to Civic Technology CHI 2017, May 6-11, 2017, Denver, CO, USA Police officer assigned to a particular area for at least a year.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Commander</head><p>Appointed official who overseas a police district. Online Moderator A self-appointed citizen that manages online communication between community members, aldermen, CAPS officers, and other officials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CAPS Sergeant</head><p>One officer per district charged with liaising with the community and is ranked higher than beat officers but much lower than commanders.</p><p>support local governance for crime prevention, extending prior HCI research focused on the use of technology to support local engagement <ref type="bibr">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">12,</ref><ref type="bibr">18,</ref><ref type="bibr">21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">26,</ref><ref type="bibr">34]</ref>. Specifically, this work provides accounts of community ICT usage and its impact on relationships with government as evidenced by local in-person meetings with law enforcement and government officials. Second, our results add to the conversation that technology alone cannot equitably empower citizens to solve deep-seated social problems such as crime without addressing the underlying inequities across communities <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[48]</ref>. Our results indicate that while communities in this study are successful in their use of ICTs to address local issues, technology did not increase their political power. Lastly, our study builds on prior work in HCI that provides insights into designing for traditionally marginalized groups <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">53,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">54]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RELATED WORK Participatory Governance and ICTs</head><p>Local government has a major impact on improving neighborhood issues such as crime, walkability, and investment. The lack of addressing these issues impacts residents' mortality <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[10]</ref>, economic mobility <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[52]</ref>, health <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">29]</ref>, and risk of victimization <ref type="bibr">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">35]</ref>. This phenomenon is particularly concerning to lower income areas that often lack political capital and collective efficacy, and thereby more susceptibility to continual neighborhood decline <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">41]</ref>. As a result, there has been a push for residents to engage in participatory governance, the practice of involving community members in the local political process. The goal of participatory governance is to create a functional democracy in which community members influence the actions of local government officials <ref type="bibr">[14,</ref><ref type="bibr">16]</ref>.</p><p>HCI researchers have explored the use of technology to support participatory governance. A theme in recent work is designing tools that incorporate social media and support hyper-local and real-time civic engagement. For example, Yuheng Hu and colleagues designed and evaluated a web service called Whoo.ly that filters content on Twitter that is relevant to a particular neighborhood, which was an effective method to help people find information related to their neighborhood <ref type="bibr">[18]</ref>. Bohøj and colleagues designed a mobile phone technology that facilitated citizen engagement in municipal planning using location-activated alerts and augmented reality to communicate a proposed building plan to citizens while they are in-situ. The system incorporated a messaging platform for users to respond and converse about the plan and take further action if they had objections or suggestions for the proposal <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref>. Researchers at Aalto University used a participatory design approach to redesign urban planning software that enables conversation and collaboration between planners and citizens regarding proposed traffic plans <ref type="bibr">[33]</ref>. These projects use design to encourage the public's engagement in local governance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Empowered Participation in Chicago</head><p>Community engagement in participatory governance has been extensively studied in <ref type="bibr">Chicago [6,</ref><ref type="bibr">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">37]</ref>. In his book, "Empowered Participation: Reinventing Urban Democracy," Archon Fung describes how Chicago residents participated in monthly meetings with police and educators <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref>. He argues that residents were able to influence change by engaging in decision-making processes with city officials and law enforcement agencies. Fung's work provides an example of what participatory governance looked like in practice during the late 1990s and is a relatively optimistic outlook of the power that residents have in influencing their circumstances. Fung suggests that "accountable autonomy," a hybrid of independence and transparent responsibility for government agencies, best impacts residents' ability to participate in local governance about issues such as crime. Essentially, Fung found that participating in government-run crime prevention strategies empowered residents because the Chicago Alternative Policing Strategy (CAPS) meetings were accessible to everyone; and, the structure afforded citizen-led deliberation on issues and decentralized decision-making abilities. Fifteen years after Fung's study, we describe the impact that three communities' online engagement had on local CAPS meetings and the actions taken by city officials. Our results suggest that ICTs further empowered residents, particularly those in affluent communities, by increasing the visibility of the community's concerns, improving how residents hold city officials accountable, and diversifying residents' methods of participation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>METHODS</head><p>During our three-year study, we took a triangulated approach to address our research question using observations, interviews, and qualitative content analysis. In year one, we built relationships with residents and local stakeholders, obtained permissions from locals to observe community meetings, and built tools to gather online data. In year two and three, we continued our observations of community meetings in five geographically-bound areas in Chicago, Illinois, USA. These meetings were sponsored by the City of Chicago's Chicago Alternative Policing Strategies (CAPS) and held once a month with residents and the police. Additionally, in year three we interviewed 45 residents from five communities. By the end of our study, we conducted qualitative content analyses on over 7,000 online messages sent among local residents in three of the five areas through grassroots community-created web forums or email lists. In this paper, we focus on the three communities that used ICTs. Below we describe the three communities and how we collected and analyzed our data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Communities</head><p>We focus on three communities. We define "community" as a police beat, which is a relatively small geographically-bound area (typically 30 to 40 square blocks) containing approximately 20,000 residents (sometimes fewer in less densely populated areas of the city). We selected police beats as the geographic boundaries because residents often used the terms "beat" and "community" interchangeably in their online and offline language about crime and when appropriating ICTs for community use, residents typically described the tools as being for those who live in certain police beats. Beats may have been heavily used by residents, because it may be easier to have conversations about crime if the targeted boundaries are mapped onto police beats. We do not refer to neighborhoods because a Chicago "neighborhood" refers 77 larger geographic regions with a median population of 31,000. One Chicago neighborhood could be made up of as many as nine beats. We use the term "community" to refer specifically to the areas studied and "neighborhood" to refer to a more general definition open to interpretation by a broader audience outside of Chicago.</p><p>The three communities were selected based on crime rates and racial compositions. We considered crime rate because citizens' behaviors, reactions, and attitudes towards civic participation may be affected by the amount of crime and social disorder they experience on a daily basis <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[43]</ref>. We considered racial composition because crime rates and racial composition are confounded with socioeconomic status (SES) levels <ref type="bibr">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr">40]</ref> and to compare our work to previous studies, which consider race <ref type="bibr">[40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">49]</ref>.</p><p>Two communities (Communities 1 &amp; 2) were classified as middle income based on the median household income, while the other (Community 3) was classified as low income, with poverty and unemployment rates greater than 21% and 15%, respectively. Community 3, the lower income community, also reported higher crime as compared to the middle-income communities. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> provides demographic details of each community.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Collection Observations</head><p>We collected over 300 pages of ethnographic fieldnotes from attending 48 meetings and community events. We observed monthly community-police meetings in each of the three communities for a little more than two years. Meetings were held at local churches, libraries, schools, and community centers.</p><p>There was an average of 22 citizens and four police officers in attendance, including at least one community facilitator (i.e., a resident who volunteered to be the liaison between the community and police). We also attended community events such as community walks, block parties, and block club meetings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Semi-structured Interviews</head><p>We interviewed 27 residents from the three neighborhoods. We recruited nine interviewees at the community-police meetings and 12 from invitations sent on the community-based ICTs.</p><p>Another six were recruited from public places such as local libraries or by word-of-mouth, which allowed us to gather insight from those who live in the community but do not attend the community-police meetings or use the community-based ICTs.</p><p>Interviewees' ages ranged from 23 to 74 (median age 58). Fifteen of the 27 (56%) interviewees were women. Twenty (74%) of the interviewees were homeowners. Education level of interviewees varied as follows: four (15%) did not complete high school, two (7%) had high school diplomas or equivalent, one (4%) had some college or vocational training, eight (30%) had a bachelors degree, and six (22%) had a degree beyond a bachelors. Race of interviewees varied as follows: twelve (44%) identified as black, fourteen (52%) white, and one (4%) Latino. Interviewees' demographics, as detailed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, represent those who actively participate in local governance.</p><p>Interviews lasted an average of 50 minutes and were transcribed. We asked residents about their attendance at in-person community meetings and/or participation in online discussions with their neighbors about crime; their online and in-person participation and the factors that influence their decision to select either medium; and their satisfaction with communitypolice meetings and trust level of the police.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Online Qualitative Content</head><p>Lastly, we analyzed online conversations from communitybased ICTs created by residents, not by the police or other government agencies. We identified such ICTs by asking residents to describe if and how they engage in online discussions about local issues <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[13]</ref>.</p><p>Community 1. Community 1's main method of online communication was a Yahoo! Group that was created in April 2004. Roughly 250 users signed up using their real names, email addresses, and home addresses.  primarily used a private email list instead of the message board, where a moderator sent messages directly to members.</p><p>Community 3. Since May 2011, residents in Community 3 used a private email list with over 300 recipients, where a moderator distributed information related to crime.</p><p>Attendees were granted access to the private email lists after signing up at the in-person community-police meetings. After posting a notice to residents about the study and there were no objections, we developed a web crawler to retrieve information such as forum post, date, subject, and author from the community-based ICTs (e.g., web forums). Using this method, we collected 5,425 messages from Community 1's Yahoo! Group, 1,054 messages from Community 2's public message board and private email list, and 665 from Community 3's private email list. The message dates ranged from April 2004 to June 2013. Below is an example of an online forum post written by a resident:</p><p>"Saw drug dealing on Saturday afternoon @ 2:30 while having late lunch on my front porch. I can identify the car and will look for it now that I know....here's the info: A reddish-marroon Buick (at least 10 yrs old) did a strange move at the stop sign as it was heading south[...] I could not take the license number, but can identify the car again -very shiny!!"</p><p>Though the community-based ICTs in this study were web forums and email lists, we also searched for discussions using search engines and social media websites (e.g., Facebook or Twitter). While we found dated announcements about local meetings, we did not find up-to-date information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis</head><p>We analyzed the data described above using inductive qualitative analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[47]</ref>, where the first author and two undergraduate research assistants initially read through roughly 20% of the interviews, observations, and online data line-by-line, creating a total of 179 codes. We then recoded the data multiple times, resulting in a final codebook of 145 codes (e.g., community cohesion, action, meeting content, organizing, alderman). The lead author then coded all the data, and after achieving an interrater reliability of 81% using intra-class correlation coefficient using a two-way mixed model and absolute agreement, the two undergraduates each coded 50% of the data. The team met weekly for six months until the application of codes were exhausted. The team then grouped the codes into 13 higher level categories (e.g., trust, visibility, accountability, participation, criticism). In this paper, we discuss three major themes related to our research question, while other publications address other themes that emerged. We present quotes verbatim as illustrations of the repetitive phenomena, with little alteration except to protect the identity of participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FINDINGS</head><p>Our findings suggest that residents use ICTs for visibility, accountability, and participation when engaging in local governance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Heightening Visibility</head><p>Technology increased the visibility of the community's concerns with city officials. Specifically, residents created email lists and discussion boards to connect with other residents about local issues and persuade the police and the alderman to take action. As time went on, more and more people joined the electronic mailing lists to receive community-generated information. As the number of people on the lists increased, citizens stated that they received better responses from city officials and law enforcement agencies during the in-person meetings. Interviewees attributed the improved response to the fact that city officials recognized that many people were concerned about issues discussed online, even if only one person was stating the concern at the in-person meeting. There were three main ways that residents used technology to increase visibility of their concerns: through open communication strategies where many could reply and engage in online discussions, through a community leader who lead the majority of engagement with the alderman, and through strong relationships with government officials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Visibility Through Many</head><p>In Community 1, residents used their online email forum to discuss and share their concerns and the response (or lack thereof) from the alderman and police. During our observations, the alderman attended over 75% of the CAPS meetings and the commander attended 90% of the CAPS meeting.</p><p>Data from our meeting observations, online forum, and interviews suggest that the alderman or a representative from the alderman's office checked the community discussion board to be aware of residents' concerns. There were at least eight instances where the alderman responded to individuals who posted messages addressed to her office about neighborhood disorder. She also addressed the concerns citizens voiced on the discussion board in her weekly newsletter, which was sent out to citizens via email. One citizen, for example, sent a message to the entire online group addressed to the alderman about fliers being posted in the neighborhood that were a nuisance. The alderman responded directly to the resident, not the entire group. The resident later cc'ed the community email listserv with the alderman's response and his subsequent response (below):</p><p>"[Citizen's Name], I received your package over the weekend and calls were made on Monday. The businesses were told to stop distributing the literature. This ultimately is a police matter, so if this persists I suggest you contact them. [Signed the Alderman's first name]"</p><p>Below is the resident's response to the Alderman, copying the neighborhood group:</p><p>"Thanks for the follow up. In the future I would appreciate your office making an effort to contact me (an email would suffice) when action is taken. [...] I took the time to provide the evidence and pay to send the package, all they had to do was make the Overall, the data suggest Community 1 successfully used ICTs to leverage their political power. This was demonstrated as government officials attended community meetings and were responsive to electronic messages from Community 1 residents. Community 1's success may be attributed to the number of citizens engaged online to report community issues. Evidence demonstrates that the alderman consistently maintained a connection with the community by responding online and attending community meetings. Further, she influenced the commander's meeting attendance after citizens complained about a lack of results.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Visibility Through Community Leader</head><p>During this study, we observed residents in Community 2 use an open discussion board initially and change to a private email list. Despite the changes in the technologies, Community 2 mainly communicated their concerns through a community leader that was informally elected by the neighborhood. This community leader who served as the online moderator was also the beat facilitator.</p><p>During our observation, the alderman never attended a CAPS meeting; however, he sent representatives from his office to over 65% of the CAPS meetings. The district commander for both Communities 1 and 2 attended less than a third of Community 2's CAPS meetings (compared to 90% in Community 1). (The commander changed twice during our fieldwork.</p><p>Here, we refer to the longest standing commander during the two years of fieldwork.)</p><p>Our data demonstrate that the alderman and CAPS sergeant were made aware of residents' concerns via emails sent from Community 2's online moderator. Also, according to online data and an interview with the moderator, the alderman and CAPS sergeant were responsive to the emails. After the mod-erator received a response, he would then broadcast the results of the information to the rest of the community. Though the online moderator described having a contentious relationship with the alderman's office, the email list was a major factor in the alderman's quick response. The online moderator said: It seemed that the alderman and CAPS sergeant promptly responded to the moderator because of his role in sending out information to hundreds of people on the email list. For example, the aldermanic administrator of abandoned buildings stood up at the CAPS meeting and said that she would now be attending the meetings to represent the alderman's office based on emails from the community email list about unresolved abandoned and deleterious buildings. In this instance, the alderman's office sent a representative to directly address recent concerns that had been shared online about buildings that were a nuisance to the neighborhood.</p><p>Data from our observations demonstrate that police also responded to Community 2's online grievances at the CAPS meetings. Though they never officially posted to the discussion boards, over ten times during our observations, the police stated that they received all the messages shared on the discussion board including pictures of graffiti. The CAPS sergeant, for example, instructed citizens in Community 2 at a CAPS meeting to upload images of graffiti to the community website, because they go directly to his phone. As described in our fieldnotes:</p><p>"The CAPS sergeant says 'Take a photo and email it to us. We want to know if it's from a gang. There's graffiti before shootings.' He says that people should upload it to [the community website]. The CAPS sergeant says 'When it's sent there, it goes directly to my phone.'"</p><p>When another resident pointed out a problem street corner, the CAPS sergeant said, "Send me an email and I'll figure out what issue it is." Both of these statements reveal how the sergeant used email on his phone to keep up-to-date about neighborhood issues. Community 2's CAPS sergeant said that she received all emails from the community email list and forwards the "serious" emails to the commander. She stated that she never responds publicly because of liability issues with the police department.</p><p>Although there were major differences in the role that the alderman and the commander played in Community 2 as compared to Community 1, the data suggest Community 2 successfully leveraged their political power as well. Evidence demonstrates that the alderman and CAPS sergeant were aware of and responsive to the residents' issues. However, it was not to the level of Community 1 where the alderman and commander both attended in-person meetings with the community and proactively addressed local issues. In Community 2, we saw the CAPS sergeant, who has less power than the commander to address issues, respond. We argue that Community 2's success can be attributed to the moderator using technology to increase the visibility of community's concerns. A notable concern about this approach is that there is a heavy reliance on the one person to represent the entire neighborhood.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Visibility through Relationships</head><p>In Community 3, residents used a private email list to communicate, where an email moderator, who was a long-standing, well-respected community member received private emails from citizens about what was happening in the neighborhood.</p><p>The moderator then anonymized the information before sending it to the alderman and CAPS sergeant.</p><p>During our observation, the alderman never attended a CAPS meeting and sent representatives to less than 35% of the meetings. The commander attended one meeting after the third commander change in less than one year. Beat officers attended less than a third of meetings.</p><p>Our analysis revealed that although the alderman received the emails, little action was taken to address community concerns as a result of information that was shared via the private email list. Only two times during our three years in Community 3 did the alderman's office clearly respond to the community's concerns shared online. In one instance, an aldermanic representative began attending the CAPS meetings after a representative from the state's attorney office attended another official city meeting where she stated that their office received messages from the community's email list and that representatives from their office now planned to participate future CAPS meetings in the neighborhood. The email moderator stated that after the incident with the state's attorney representative, the alderman began to respond more promptly to requests, concerns, and needs. All interviewees in Community 3 strongly criticized the alderman's office, with one interviewee saying:</p><p>got a problem...they want you to call the Alderman's office. Well, we didn't have much success calling the Alderman's Office." agreed saying, feel that her role should be to get a little bit more involved with the their head man over there, the commander."</p><p>lot of things that we talked to the aldermen about, they say 'Oh, we're to fix it. We're going to take care.' But we don't get any response. We only see them when...they really want to be reelected. And that's another thing, they should really stick to what they say."</p><p>A woman described what she believed was the major reason crime and disorder in the neighborhood, saying:</p><p>"I think also the Alderman has a lot to do with it. Having a good means a lot."</p><p>The email moderator agreed with citizens' characterization of the alderman's office as neglectful, but said the alderman's office was unresponsive to community concerns until they felt that the community-based email list may be too large to ignore. Specifically, the moderator stated that by keeping it anonymous, the alderman's office was unaware of the email list's reach except when evidence suggests that influential and powerful officials are on the list when they begin getting involved in community issues (e.g., the state's attorney's office). When asked who, besides that alderman and the sergeant, are the email list, he says, During our interviews, residents described having a positive, trusting relationship with the CAPS sergeant and saw him as effective at addressing local concerns, though they always shared their concerns with him through the moderator. It is important to note that the sergeant had been in the position longer than any of the police commanders during our observations and had built a strong rapport with the community. The email moderator of the Community 3 email list said that he emailed the CAPS sergeant often but never emailed the commander. He said he interacted with the commander only if he went to district police station.</p><p>Community 3 used ICTs similarly to Community 2, but the data suggests they were not as successful in translating their online concerns to action by government officials. The alderman did not attend CAPS meeting and commander rarely attended. Also, emails were not responded to promptly by the alderman but were by the sergeant, who had little power. We argue that in the rare instances when alderman or commander took action, it was the result of leveraging relationships with powerful officials outside of the community on the anonymous email list and having a positive relationship with the CAPS</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Supports Accountability</head><p>With community concerns being increasingly visible, it is essential that local residents have the ability to hold government officials accountable for addressing those concerns as well as keeping their promises. In Chicago, CAPS meetings have long been an opportunity for citizens to not only share their concerns, issues, and problems with the police, but also challenge the police's efforts in addressing the problems <ref type="bibr">[40]</ref>.</p><p>Local residents in Communities 1, 2, and 3 used technology to deliberate about the important issues (and sometimes solutions) and share those issues during the in-person meetings with the police, subsequently influencing the in-person meeting agendas. They then used the technology to document the agreed upon solutions to follow-up on whether local officials completed specific tasks. The use of community-based ICTs seemed to increase pressure on police and city officials to take action because their responses (whether action or inaction) easily accessible to citizens and decision makers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Accountability By Sharing Agendas and Meeting Minutes</head><p>Residents in both Communities 1 and 3 created agendas and meeting minutes, respectively, for the CAPS meetings. The police also created agendas for the meetings. The moderators distributed the agendas and minutes both online and at the CAPS meetings. These documents were used to discuss prior concerns from previous meetings and to record action items that the police said they would accomplish. These digital documents were brought to susequent meetings to remind citizens of the agreed upon solution, which then allowed them to hold public officials accountable by asking if they have completed a task.</p><p>One example of citizens using technology to support efforts in holding government officials accountable is Community 3's alderman stated during a ward meeting, which is alderman-run, that she would not approve any new permits for pawnshops on a crime-ridden, commercial street in the neighborhood. Most residents in the community agreed, stating they wanted higher quality retail stores in the area and that they were opposed to any additional pawnshops to the area because there were already four in a two block radius on the commercial street. When the alderman discreetly approved a fifth pawnshop, residents referred back to digital documents they created that recorded when the alderman stated that no more pawnshops would be allowed. Citizens conveyed their discontent at the alderman's office and the CAPS meetings. They also shared their on the community email list, where they organized greater in-person attendance at CAPS meeting. Residents who could not attend shared ideas with the about how to leverage city ordinances that prohibit the unwanted store as well as community organizations and lawyers that may help residents fight the decision.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Accountability Through Sharing Police Responses</head><p>Community 2 did not create official community or Instead, Community 2's residents sent emails inothers of the alderman or police's response to specific issues that were reported online. For example, resident posted that they contacted the alderman's office about a troubled saying:</p><p>have requested that the alderman call in the building owners, who have been unresponsive to our e-mails. Will post when a meeting is "</p><p>After the CAPS meeting, attendees posted an update:</p><p>"Here's an update on [building address]. An officer went inside the building there is someone who lives on the 2nd floor only now, and woman with 4 kids currently moving out. It's in foreclosure the bank owns the building (mortagage [sic] fraud). [..] The Alderman, name]'s office is doing their part as are the police at this juncture. The building will remain accessible evidently until it's bought, something catastrophic happens or the bank secures it."</p><p>In addition to sharing what the in-person responses are to community concerns, residents in Community 2 also shared responses about incidents, whether it was originally private or not. For example, one resident posts an email from the police commander to the alderman: use ICTs in all three communities to document decisions made in community meetings and to keep those who did not attend informed. Using this community-created docuproves useful for monitoring progress and pushing community agenda forward. Although the outcomes of the meetings do not always result in action from local officials, ICTs can be used to hold government officials accountable to verbal commitments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Diversifying Methods of Participation</head><p>are numerous barriers to attending the CAPS meetings. Eight (80%) of the ten interviewees who did not attend the CAPS meetings stated that other obligations hindered their attendance. Whether it was a second job, sickness, lack of transportation, or a single parent who needed to be home in the evenings, there were various reasons given for not attending the CAPS meetings. In the past, Chicago citizens may have felt that they needed to be physically present at the CAPS meetings for their concerns to be heard by law enforcement <ref type="bibr">[40]</ref>. However, technology can address such barriers to participation. More than half of interviewees that used the community-based ICTs said that they used it as either an alternative or supplemental method of participating in community prevention.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Online Engagement to Supplement In-Person Meetings</head><p>In all three communities, citizens still felt that their online presence was a type of participation in community crime prevention. In Community 1, people used the technology to facilitate community discussion about problems and solutions. Six out of seven (85%) interviewees believed that their online participation influenced the police's reaction to solving issues.</p><p>One woman in Community 1, for example, explained why she did not attend the CAPS meetings but shared that she was aware of what happened at the meetings, saying, have health issues. So that's a big part of it. That was really the thing so usually I am pretty tired by that time in the evening.</p><p>[But] I usually hear it online, like somebody would be talking about it.</p><p>Similarly, a male from Community 1 said, "I was really heavily participating in CAPS, but since they changed</p><p>[meeting] day, I've had to pull away from it. But I still kind of, monitor the site. I post things on our neighborhood site that I think are if crimes happened or something has happened."</p><p>of these residents believed that their online participation allow them to be involved in crime prevention despite their of in-person participation at the CAPS meetings.</p><p>Residents in Communities 2 and 3 received emails from moderators (one-to-many communication) about what happened in the in-person meetings and were able to respond back to only the moderator. During the interviews, citizens reported instances that they emailed the moderator about issues that were later discussed at the in-person meetings. Also, many felt they were active participants in the community crime prevention efforts because they informed their neighbors who were not on the email list about community-created agenda and minutes read online (though they did not attend the CAPS meeting).</p><p>This was particularly prevalent in Community 3, where all interviewees discussed the significance of "word-of-mouth" communication among residents.</p><p>Online Engagement Supports Offline Participation some citizens are unable to attend the CAPS meetings, observed that residents in Community 1 &amp; 2 used ICTs to organize face-to-face meetings with residents that differed from the CAPS meetings. These meetings, for example, were more about "positive loitering," which community members organize informal walks and spend time outside talking to each other to discourage crime and disorder in the community by having "eyes on the street." It should be noted that, we did not observe instances where the email list was used to help organize informal community-driven meeting in Community 3. A post on Community 2's online discussion board describes the most recent community walk, which the alderman attended.</p><p>post said:</p><p>"Update on last night's (July 20) group walk...Attendance was down for this walk [but] we were joined by Alderman [name]. [..] Nevertheless, did manage to distribute some flyers and also get the message across a few 'questionable' sort that neighbors here are getting organized. walks do have an impact, but we need more walkers! Our area has been relatively quiet since the spring outbreak of violence. While our walks are not solely responsible for that, they have contributed to problems. The more people we can get to these walks the more send the message that we will not tolerate abusive behavior in our neighborhood."</p><p>The community-based ICTsS seem to make organizing these types of activities easier. Law enforcement officials were not required to be present. Yet, at six out of the eight communitypositive presence walks that we attended in Communities 1 and 2, at least two beat officers were present. While there were mixed feelings about law enforcement showing up to such unofficial community events, it demonstrates how online organizing can help stimulate police attention. This finding suggests that the vast number of people that ICTs can reach may nudge police and other city officials to be aware of what the community is doing.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DISCUSSION</head><p>This paper describes the role that ICTs play in supporting citizen participation in local governance in three Chicago communities. We framed our approach using Fung's definition empowered participation, which suggests citizens have the to engage local governance in ways that allow for citideliberation and decentralized decision-making. Theoretically, empowered participation leads to government officials being held accountable and accessible to the public. Based on our analysis, we found both similarities and differences across the communities studied. All three communities used ICTs to the visibility of local issues. Community 1 accomplished this by leveraging the power of many to engage and with the alderman and police. Community 2, on the other hand, relied on a trusted community member to liaison with city officials. Though using a similar approach as Community 2, Community 3 also needed to leverage relationships, specifically strong ties with the police sergeant and those in powerful positions outside of the community to motivate local change. Each community used ICTs to hold local officials by sharing community-driven meeting agendas and minutes (Community 1 &amp; 3) and decisions made by local officials about specific issues (Community 2). Lastly, citizens used ICTs as another method of in local governance, specifically by engaging online when they are unable to attend in-person meetings (Communities 1, 2, &amp; 3) and by using ICTs to organize community-based, in-person meetings (Communities 1 &amp; 2). We frame our discussion of these findings around our two major points: technology alone cannot equitably empower citizens and, the experiences of the marginalized can inform ICT design for local governance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Technology Alone Cannot Equitably Empower Citizens</head><p>"Empowered Participation, Reinventing Urban Democracy," argues that participatory democracy can effect social change. Based on our data, we support the notion that participatory-democratic organizing creates channels through which residents can voice their concerns about local issues. Furthermore, ICTs support the concept of empowerment as described by Fung <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref> by serving as a tool through which citizens share information, discuss potential solutions, and supplement their ways of participating directly in local governance. ICTs also provide an alternate or complementary means by which a relationship between city officials and the community can be initiated and developed. Using these tools, community members can, over time, generate and utilize a "durable network" [4, p. 248] to strategically confront local issues like crime. Despite these promising empowerment strategies, our research also suggests that less affluent neighborhoods still have the same problems affecting change as observed by Fung and other scholars for decades <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref>. Though technology provides an opportunity to make citizens' concerns visible, to hold officials accountable, and are an avenue for alternative methods of engagement; we argue that the use of ICTs alone cannot change ongoing challenges in marginalized communities lacking the social relationships inherent in more wealthy communities.</p><p>Fung suggests that of the inequality in service provision, opportunities, and outcomes across different neighborhoods stems from the background of social and economic disparity that characterizes all urban environments in the United States" p. 23]. Our work supports this notion. Our analysis suggests there are larger structural issues at play. One of the most noticeable and critical differences across communities is race <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[19]</ref>, which tends to be confounded with wealth due to hundreds of years of ongoing educational, employment, and otherwise economic disenfranchisement <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">52]</ref>. Subsequently, there continues to be a devaluing of predominantly Black and poorer communities politically, economically, and socially which is evidenced by the lack of public revitalization efforts, local resources, private investments, and the overly simplistic and stigmatized reporting when referring to these <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">51]</ref>.</p><p>In fact, since the 1960s studies of Chicago communities, social networks, and subsequent support or the lack thereof in minority and poor communities has been a well-known challenge <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[52,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">42,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">36]</ref>. The communities we studied all used ICTs to effectively communicate with local government officials, but varied in terms of racial and socioeconomic status. While each community in the study had a strong online presence, political figures responded differently to concerns across these communities. Seemingly most attentive to Community 1 -a majority white and middle-high income local political attended meetings and were responsive in addressing residents' concerns. eventually addressed, more was required for government officials to tackle local concerns in the two lower income, racially mixed and minority communities (Communities 2 &amp; 3, respectively). In fact, we saw varying levels of engagement from government officials communities, with the poorest community (Community 3) receiving the least amount of support. Therefore, through a venue designed to empower communities, poor and minority community residents' lack of power was demonstrated instead, potentially undermining their political power as compared to other communities. This begs the question if technology alone can remedy the problem of suppressed political power in minority and poor communities. Residents in the low-income community we observed responded to the call to engage in local governance using ICTs and at CAPS meetings because they believe their participation will make difference. While theoretically, these strategies increase communication and improve the likelihood of attention, the effectiveness of this approach in producing improvements in one community and not in others is a source of inequality. Subsequently, as evidenced by our research, there is still a need for these communities to engage in local governance at greater levels than more affluent communities in attempts to achieve the same goals while having a lower probability of success than more affluent communities.</p><p>Fung contended that, "Voices of minority, less educated, diffident, or culturally subordinate participants are often drowned out by those who are wealthy, confident, accustomed to management, or otherwise privileged" <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b5">5]</ref>. We agree and assert that powerful social ties with those in power who can and will advocate on behalf of residents in minority and less affluent communities are a necessity to change and citizen empowerment. The absence these social connections (or relationships), can lead to these residents' loss of confidence in local governance and a widening civic empowerment gap <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24]</ref>. Therefore, scholars seek to uncover how the increased levels of and varied participation that ICTs encourage in communities, particularly minority and communities, can be used to generate a durable network of relationships and support that and deploys political power in ways we have not seen before. The poses an opportunity for future work for HCI</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Designing for the Experiences of the Marginalized</head><p>The communities in this paper highlight complex, underlying issues such as the impact of race, class, and power on public policy and local governance <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">52]</ref>. Wilson's seminal work criticizes approaches to public policy that do not consider the reciprocal impact of policy decisions and economic mobilization of lower income citizens, particularly those who live in areas with concentrated poverty <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[52]</ref>. Similarly, when devel-oping community-based ICTs to support local governance, we must consider traditionally marginalized, lower income citizens and their realities of action (or inaction) by local city officials. By examining the differences in use, we can begin to draw insights into how to design tools that attempt to shift notions of power by moving beyond simply supporting information sharing and communication and aim to improve equity in local governance and action for disenfranchised communities. Based on our findings, we propose three approaches to designing such ICTs. We suggest designing ICTs that 1) suprelationship-building between the community and those in power beyond local decision makers to put outside pressure on local officials; 2) highlight local decisions made during in-person meetings to expose inaction and improve accountability; and, 3) support community organizing to successfully citizen participation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ICTS that Support Relationship Building</head><p>As evidenced in our study, explicit relationships with powerful government officials played a critical role in catalyzing change and action amongst local officials in the minority, lower income neighborhood (Community 3). While the effectiveness of this method is not completely clear, it is evident that creating relationships with more powerful people was successful in getting the alderman's attention (e.g., the state's attorney office lead the alderman to address a local situation). Therefore, ICTs that support relationships alone may not be the best solution; while, ICTs that help citizens understand the local hierarchy and build relationships with people that have the ability to put pressure on local officials would be more effective. For example, the commander answers to the Deputy Chief who answers to the Police Chief who answers to the Police Superintendent. ICTs also have the ability to help citizens consider non-traditional approaches to power; for example, the alderman who is on city council has the (unofficial) power to influence who becomes the commander in their area, which may be one reason why Community 1's alderman was very successful in engaging the commander. However, state representatives and senators have the ability to impact the decisions of the alderman. Helping residents identify and build relationships with potential advocates in the unofficial city, regional, and state power structure may be unconventional, but necessary to persuade local officials to address the community's</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ICTs that Expose Local Action and Inaction</head><p>We observed immediate responses from the alderman in Communities 1 &amp; 2 as a result of community concerns shared online. However, such reactions were not as prevalent in Community 3, despite the fact that there were similarities in the use of technology. Given that residents in lower income neighborhoods may have to do more than those in more affluent areas to see results, we imagine ICTs supporting their efforts to hold public officials accountable by publicizing local officials behavior beyond the email list. In Community 3, for example, the alderman who approved the creation of a fifth pawn shop, may have assumed that residents in Community 3 would not expose her actions. However, the uproar by the community led to the story being covered by several major newspapers and media outlets. As a result, she was not reelected, which is very rare for an incumbent alderman in Chicago with the mayor's support. Key states, "The blunt truth is that politicians and officials are under no compulsion to pay much heed to classes and groups citizens that do not vote" p.99]. A tool allowing residents to not only record decisions that were made in the meeting, but to also share them in a more public mat can increase the amount of pressure that local politicians feel from their constituents. All three neighborhoods shared information; however, future work can explore the impact of exposing local decisions to a broader audience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ICTs that Support Local In-person Organizing</head><p>Community walks, positive-presence events, and communitybased meetings demonstrate solidarity amongst community members and help spur local change <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8]</ref>. Although Commu-3 residents were engaged in trying to improve local issues, we did not observe such organizing online or in-person by citizens in Community 3. Despite this, we do not attribute their of organizing to a lack of interest in government or crime prevention as some previous studies suggest about citizens in low-income, minority communities <ref type="bibr">[40]</ref>. Low in-person attendance can be the result of overwhelming and competing responsibilities (e.g., second jobs or child care) that lower income citizens have to negotiate. For example, we witnessed Community 3 residents petition against the development of the fifth pawnshop in a two block radius; and, there was a large amount of public support for this effort as evidenced by the numerous people who signed the petition. However, despite this, the community's complaint was dismissed, and the pawnshop was approved because not enough opponents attended a meeting at city hall. This meeting was held at 10am on a weekday when residents were most likely working.</p><p>We imagine designing ICTs for local governance that inform citizens of the optimal times when their in-person attendance will have the greatest opportunity to enact change. Such technologies, for example, could alert residents when it is essential to be physically present at a meeting versus signing a petition to show support. It is unlikely that citizens in Community 3 understood the gravity of the city hall vote. They were passionate about this issue; and, we believe with the right information and tools, they would have organized to have better representation from the community at the meeting. Technology could provide an understanding of the sometimes murky political process and boost efforts to organize in-person by helping residents decipher when it is essential to participate in-person.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>LIMITATIONS AND FUTURE WORK</head><p>There are several limitations to this study, and thus opportunities to engage future research that can potentially lead to understanding of the role of technology in deliberative our qualitative approach to understanding our research questions does not lend itself to broad While we believe there may be similar dynamics in other cities, our results must be taken in the context of Chicago.</p><p>we attempted to include more Chicago communithe other communities we initially investigated did not engage with a prevalent community-based technology, and our research question did not lend itself to an investigation of communities that do not use ICTs. However, future research can explore how ICTs can support community organizations (e.g., churches, community centers) that have traditionally been activists in communities but do little online grassroots organizing. Recent studies regarding attitudes and perceptions about community technology found that minorities, those who are lower income, those who have less trust of the police, and in high-crime neighborhoods tend to use technology less to engage with government officials about local issues <ref type="bibr">[20]</ref>. Citizens from these communities instead relied heavily on inperson meetings. It would be interesting to see a comparison of grassroots results across different communities that include communities that do not engage with ICTs. Additionally, future work could examine the extent to which neighborhood characteristics influence the type of technologies citizens use and the structure of information sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[13]</ref>.</p><p>Lastly, it is important to consider the difference between measuring the action of government officials versus the promise of action. Whereas other scholars have used voting patterns of city officials as a measure of political power <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[41]</ref>, we measured the responses by government officials as confirmed by citizens.</p><p>it is difficult to know if those actions actually took place. The realization of action versus the promise of action is a limitation of this study that presents an opportunity for future research. Furthermore, our approach of viewing action as political power may differ from residents feelings. Though we saw less action from government officials in Community 3, demonstrating inequity in political power, we did not investigate if residents themselves are aware of this inequity or feel less empowered. Future work can measure citizens feelings as a result of their technology use. Addressing these types of questions will provide us with a richer understanding of the social and political factors that designers must consider to effectively design technology that supports civic engagement various communities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONCLUSION</head><p>The relationship between citizens and city officials is incredibly complex and requires a deep understanding of the social and political environments. Though many times we design technology to affect the behavior of a user, researchers should the greater ecological implications. In Chicago, for example, residents initially appropriated ICTs to share information and support discussions amongst residents. Heightened visibility of community concerns, police accountability, varied participation were subsequent effects. Scholars research technology's affect on social issues (e.g., crime, sustainability, health) should potentially extend beyond examining technology's influence on individual behavior. Instead, we may consider how technology affects the ability of communities, particularly those that are disproportionately plagued challenging social problems, to influence their political, social, and economic circumstances.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Community 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>From January 2008 -March 2011, Community 2 used an open discussion board, where anyone could send a message to all the members. Posts on the discussion board were publicly accessible but to post, real names and home addresses were required. As of March 2011, over 350 residents</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>"</head><label></label><figDesc>I intimidated [alderman's name]! I mean I would have never in a million years [intimidated him] out of all the stuff going on [without the email list]."</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>"</head><label></label><figDesc>Regarding last weekend's disturbances [the police] will be beefing up attention for the summer, see correspondence from [the] Police Chief [..] to [the alderman]: I have review the letter you submitted to our concerning the elevated activity the [..] area. [..] I have spoken with Deputy Chief [name] and extra attention will be give to this area as the warmer weather approaches. I have also instructed Mr.to capture video related to the below listed incidents for review. concerns are important to me and please feel free to contact me at [phone number]."</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Lexicon of terms</figDesc><table><row><cell>Term</cell><cell>Definition</cell></row><row><cell>Alderman</cell><cell>Elected official of a local ward</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>who sits on the City Council.</cell></row><row><cell>Beat officer</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Demographic information of the communities based on data from Census and the American Community Survey</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell cols="6">Population Income Level % White % Black % Latino Index Crime Rate</cell></row><row><cell>Community 1</cell><cell>24,200</cell><cell>Middle</cell><cell>54%</cell><cell>12%</cell><cell>17%</cell><cell>1528</cell></row><row><cell>Community 2</cell><cell>10,300</cell><cell>Middle-Low</cell><cell>28%</cell><cell>29%</cell><cell>34%</cell><cell>2889</cell></row><row><cell>Community 3</cell><cell>17,260</cell><cell>Low</cell><cell>2%</cell><cell>78%</cell><cell>19%</cell><cell>3048</cell></row><row><cell cols="7">The Index Crime Rate is the number of serious crimes (e.g., 1st and 2nd degree murder, rape, robbery) per 100,000 residents from</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">August 2012 -August 2013.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3 .</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Number of meetings observed and demographic information about the interviewees by community.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell># of Meetings Observed</cell><cell># of Interviewees</cell><cell cols="2">Avg. Age % Female</cell><cell></cell><cell>Race</cell><cell></cell><cell>% Homeowners</cell><cell>% &gt; High School Diploma</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">% White % Black % Latino</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Community 1</cell><cell>16</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>60</cell><cell>43%</cell><cell>100%</cell><cell>0%</cell><cell>0%</cell><cell>86%</cell><cell>100%</cell></row><row><cell>Community 2</cell><cell>17</cell><cell>9</cell><cell>41</cell><cell>56%</cell><cell>67%</cell><cell>22%</cell><cell>0%</cell><cell>33%</cell><cell>100%</cell></row><row><cell>Community 3</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>61</cell><cell>64%</cell><cell>9%</cell><cell>82%</cell><cell>9%</cell><cell>27%</cell><cell>36%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>calls and tell me what happened. Pretty simple to me. I will call the police going forward."</figDesc><table><row><cell>Further, our observations over two years revealed at least six</cell></row><row><cell>instances where the alderman came to CAPS meetings to</cell></row><row><cell>describe what she is doing to address issues she read about</cell></row><row><cell>on the online discussion board. Police officers in Community</cell></row><row><cell>1 were also diligent in engaging with community members</cell></row><row><cell>based on their use of ICTs. Our fieldnotes capture an example,</cell></row><row><cell>where during a CAPS meeting, a resident stands and states</cell></row><row><cell>that he,</cell></row></table><note>"sent a message but didn't hear additional information. Officer [name] says 'Sorry I printed out an email. Sorry I didn't get back to you on that. I have it here.' She holds up a paper with the information that the person was requesting."</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>"What kind of powerful people are in the community? They're in State Attorney's Office. they're in the Attorney General's Office. people don't know it anymore. They don't know [whose on the email distribution list] because my list has expanded from what it was. now it's blind copy...So you don't know but the reason [local city officials] know it because I can show up to any meeting, anytime, and they wonder who invites me. [Laughter] I done walked in meetings and they're like, 'What is he doing here?' [Laughter]"</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>We would like to thank our participants who so graciously welcomed us into their community, Jessa Dickinson, and Dan Lewis. This work was supported by the NSF GRFP.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Civic Technology</head><p>CHI 2017, May 6-11, 2017, Denver, CO, USA</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Twitter Democracy: Policy Versus Identity Politics Three Emerging African Democracies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><surname>Best</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Meng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2737856.2738017</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2737856.2738017" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Seventh International Conference on Information and Technologies and</title>
				<meeting>the Seventh International Conference on Information and Technologies and<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA, Article</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ICTD ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Health in the cities: When the neighborhood matters more than income</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vincenzo</forename><surname>Bilger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Carrieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.jhealeco.2012.09.010</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jhealeco.2012.09.010" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Health Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013. 2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Public Deliberation in Municipal Planning: Supporting Action and Reflection with Mobile Technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Morten</forename><surname>Bohoj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Nikolaj</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susanne</forename><surname>Borchorst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Korn</forename><surname>Bodker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pär-Ola</forename><surname>Zander</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 5th International Conference on Communities and Technologies (C&amp;#38</title>
				<meeting>the 5th International Conference on Communities and Technologies (C&amp;#38</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2103354.2103367</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2103354.2103367" />
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA, DOI</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Forms of Capital. In Handbook of Theory and Research for the Sociology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Bourdieu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>of Richardson J</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
			<publisher>Macmillan</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An analytical perspective on participatory inequality and income inequality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Henry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Brady</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="667" to="702" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>inequality</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Public Deliberation, Discursive Participation and Citizen Engagement: A Review of the Empirical Literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fay</forename><forename type="middle">Lomax</forename><surname>Delli Carpini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Cook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jacobs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annual Review of Political Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="315" to="344" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Promise of the Sharing Economy Among Disadvantaged Communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tawanna</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Dillahunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amelia</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Malone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2702123.2702189</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2702123.2702189" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;15)</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;15)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2285" to="2294" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community Empowerment Strategies: Limits and Potential of Community Organizing in Urban Neighborhoods</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Dreier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cityscape</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="121" to="159" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996. 1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Partnership working in rural regeneration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Goodwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Pemberton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Woods</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Governance and Empowerment</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000. 2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neighborhood Effects on Health: Exploring the Links and Assessing the Evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ingrid</forename><surname>Gould Ellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tod</forename><surname>Mijanovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Keri-Nicole</forename><surname>Dillman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/0735-2166.00096</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/0735-2166.00096" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Urban Affairs</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="408" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001. 2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Protecting the home: exploring the roles of technology and citizen activism from a burglar&apos;s perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sheena</forename><surname>Lewis Erete</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;13)</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;13)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2507" to="2516" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Engaging Around Neighborhood Issues: How Online Communication Offline Behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sheena L Erete</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social ACM</title>
				<meeting>the 18th ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social ACM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1590" to="1601" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Differences in Technology Use to Support Community Crime Prevention</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sheena</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Erete</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of CSCW</title>
				<meeting>of CSCW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="156" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Participatory governance as empowerment the cultural politics of discursive space</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American review of public administration</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Empowered participation: reinventing urban democracy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Archon</forename><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deepening democracy: Institutional innovations in empowered participatory governance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Archon</forename><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erik</forename><forename type="middle">Olin</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Politics and Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001. 2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Harding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bran</forename><surname>Knowles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nigel</forename><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Rouncefield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">HCI, Civic Engagement &amp;#38; Trust. Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;15)</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2702123.2702255</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2702123.2702255" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Whoo. ly: facilitating information seeking for hyperlocal communities using social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yuheng</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Shelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrés</forename><surname>Farnham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Monroy-Hernández</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of CHI. ACM</title>
				<meeting>of CHI. ACM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3481" to="3490" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Divergent Pathways of Gentrification: Racial Inequality and the Social Order of Renewal in Chicago Neighborhoods</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jackelyn</forename><surname>Hwang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sampson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing</title>
				<meeting>of the ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Snitches, Trolls, and Social Norms: Unpacking Perceptions of Social Media Use for Crime Prevention</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Neighborhood To Share or Not to Share</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cristina</forename><surname>Kadar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yiea-Funk</forename><surname>Te</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raquel</forename><forename type="middle">Rosés</forename><surname>Brüngger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Irena</forename><forename type="middle">Pletikosa</forename><surname>Cvijikj</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of CHI EA</title>
				<meeting>of CHI EA<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2148" to="2155" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Valdimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Key</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Georgia Historical Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="350" />
			<date type="published" when="1950">1950. 1950</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designs on Dignity: Perceptions of Technology Among Homeless</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W. Keith</forename><surname>Le Dantec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of CHI (CHI &apos;08</title>
				<meeting>of CHI (CHI &apos;08</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="627" to="636" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Civic Empowerment Gap: Defining the Problem and Locating Solutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Meira</forename><surname>Levinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Sherrod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Judith</forename><surname>Torney-Purta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Constance</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">In Handbook of Research on Civic Engagement in Youth</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Flanagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="331" to="361" />
			<pubPlace>Hoboken, NJ</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Examining Technology That Supports Community Policing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sheena</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2207676.2208595</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2207676.2208595" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;12)</title>
				<meeting>of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;12)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1371" to="1380" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tensions in Scaling-up Community Social Media: A Multi-neighborhood Study of Nextdoor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Masden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Grevet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Grinter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Gilbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Keith</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2556288.2557319</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2556288.2557319" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;14)</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;14)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA, DOI</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">American Apartheid: Segregation and the Making of the</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Massey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nancy</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Denton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neighborhood inequality, collective efficacy, and the spatial dynamics of urban violence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Morenoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sampson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Raudenbush</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Criminology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="517" to="558" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001. 2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Morenoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>House</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ben</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Hansen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">George</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kaplan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Haslyn</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding social disparities in prevalence, awareness, treatment, and control: The role of neighborhood context</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hunte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.socscimed.2007.05.038</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2007.05.038" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Science &amp; Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1853" to="1866" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Placing Health in Context</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Measuring empowerment: cross-disciplinary perspectives</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deepa</forename><surname>Narayan-Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<publisher>The World Bank</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Blackwell Dictionary of Twentieth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Outhwaite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Bottomore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
			<publisher>Century Social Blackwell Publishers</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Oxford</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Health Promotion As Activism: Building Community Capacity to Effect Social Change</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vasudhara</forename><surname>Kantroo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hee</forename><forename type="middle">Rin</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miguel</forename><surname>Osornio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mansi</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Grinter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems &apos;12)</title>
				<meeting>of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems &apos;12)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="99" to="108" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2207676.2207692</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2207676.2207692" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joanna</forename><surname>Saad-Sulonen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Botero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kari</forename><surname>Kuutti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">A Long-term Strategy for Designing (in) the Wild: Lessons from the Urban Mediator and Traffic Planning in In Proceedings of the Designing Interactive Systems Conference (DIS &apos;12)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="166" to="175" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2317956.2317982</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2317956.2317982" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Networks for Police and Residents in India: Exploring Online Communication for Crime Prevention</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ponnurangam</forename><surname>Sachdeva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kumaraguru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2757401.2757420</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2757401.2757420" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA, DOI</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>of the Conference on Digital Government Research (dg.o &apos;15</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Great American city: Chicago and the Enduring Neighborhood Effect</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sampson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<publisher>University of Chicago Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community Structure and Crime: Testing Social-Disorganization Theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">Byron</forename><surname>Sampson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Groves</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The American Journal of Sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="774" to="802" />
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989. 1989</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Civil Society Reconsidered: The Durable Nature and Community Structure of Collective Civic Action</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sampson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Doug</forename><surname>Mcadam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heather</forename><surname>Macindoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Simón</forename><surname>Weffer-Elizondo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Amer. J. Sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="673" to="714" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Sampson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Morenoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Inequality: Spatial Dynamics, Social Processes, and the Persistence of Poverty in Chicago Neighborhoods. Poverty Traps, Samuel Bowles</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Steven N</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karla</forename><surname>Durlauf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="176" to="203" />
			<pubPlace>Princeton</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Toward a theory of race, crime, and urban inequality. Race, crime, and justice: A reader</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">Julius</forename><surname>Sampson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995. 1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Police and Community in A Tale of Three Cities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wesley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Skogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective Action, Structural Disadvantage, and Crime. Tides and Currents in Police Theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wesley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Skogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Police Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="152" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Policing, Chicago style</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wesley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Skogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hartnett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Reactions to Crime Project</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Wesley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Skogan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fredric</forename><surname>Podolefsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Margaret</forename><surname>Dubow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Albert</forename><surname>Gordon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maxfield</forename><surname>Hunter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Greta</forename><surname>Salem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1982">1982</date>
			<pubPlace>Washington DC</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>U.S. Department of Justice-National Institute of Justice</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Americans and their Gadgets</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pew Internet and American Life</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010a</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mobile Access</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010b. 2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report. Pew Internet And American Life Project</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Economic inequality and democratic political engagement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frederick</forename><surname>Solt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Political Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="48" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Basics of qualitative research: Grounded theory procedures and techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Corbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
			<publisher>Publications, Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Geek heresy: Rescuing social change from the cult of technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Toyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PublicAffairs</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Policing in Black and White: Ethnic Group Differences in Trust and Confidence in the Police</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Tom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Tyler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="322" to="342" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inequality, trust, and civic engagement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Eric</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mitchell</forename><surname>Uslaner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Politics Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="868" to="894" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pre-and Post-Welfare Reform Media Portrayals of Poverty in the United States: The Continuing Importance of Race and Ethnicity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bas W Van Doorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Politics &amp; Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="142" to="162" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William Julius</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wilson</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The inner city, the underclass, and public policy</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Chicago</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987">1987. 1987</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Chicago</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving the safety of homeless young people with mobile phones: values, form and function</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jill</forename><surname>Palzkill Woelfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Iverson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Hendry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Batya</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brian</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Gill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of the Human Factors in Computing Conference</title>
				<meeting>of the Human Factors in Computing Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1707" to="1716" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Income, Race, and Class: Exploring Socioeconomic Differences in Family Technology Use</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarita</forename><surname>Yardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Bruckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. of CHI</title>
				<meeting>of CHI</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3041" to="3050" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
