<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Always On(line)? User Experience of Smartwatches and their Role within Multi-Device Ecologies</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Marta</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Cecchinato</surname></persName>
							<email>m.cecchinato@cs.ucl.ac.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
							<email>anna.cox@ucl.ac.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
							<email>jon.bird@city.ac.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">UCL Interaction Centre University College London London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>WC1E 6BT</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">UCL Interaction Centre University College London London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>WC1E 6BT</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">HCID Research Centre City</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University London London</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>EC1V 0HB</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Contextual Smartwatch Use CHI 2017</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>May 6-11</addrLine>
									<postCode>2017</postCode>
									<settlement>Denver</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country>USA METHOD</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">Contextual Smartwatch Use CHI 2017</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>May 6-11</addrLine>
									<postCode>2017</postCode>
									<settlement>Denver</settlement>
									<region>CO</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Always On(line)? User Experience of Smartwatches and their Role within Multi-Device Ecologies</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3025453.3025538</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:02+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Smartwatches</term>
					<term>wearable</term>
					<term>autoethnography</term>
					<term>context-aware</term>
					<term>notifications</term>
					<term>user experience</term>
					<term>device ecologies</term>
					<term>multidevice experience</term>
					<term>cross-device interaction H.5.m. Information interfaces and presentation (e.g., HCI): Miscellaneous</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Users have access to a growing ecosystem of devices (desktop, mobile and wearable) that can deliver notifications and help people to stay in contact. Smartwatches are gaining popularity, yet little is known about the user experience and their impact on our increasingly always online culture. We report on a qualitative study with existing users on their everyday use of smartwatches to understand both the added value and the challenges of being constantly connected at the wrist. Our findings show that users see a large benefit in receiving notifications on their wrist, especially in terms of helping manage expectations of availability. Moreover, we find that response rates after viewing a notification on a smartwatch change based on the other devices available: laptops prompt quicker replies than smartphones. Finally, there are still many costs associated with using smartwatches, thus we make a series of design recommendations to improve the user experience of smartwatches.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>Users now have access to a wide ecosystem of devices, including desktop, mobile and wearable technologies that enable them to stay in contact with others and keep up to date with information. Smartwatches have seen an increase in popularity over the last few years, particularly since Pebble's successful crowdfunding campaign in 2012 <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24]</ref>. Market figures show that worldwide shipments of smartwatches are expected to grow from 15.1 million in 2015 to 25.95 million by 2019 <ref type="bibr">[41]</ref>. The appeal of the smartwatch is the promise of swift delivery for timely information straight to the wrist, and consequently this paper focuses on the communication use of smartwatches (e.g. email notifications, social media, messaging). Because smartwatches are worn, they enable people to be notified in situations where other mobile devices, such as smartphones, would be typically switched off or put away in pockets and bags. They therefore have the potential to increase expectations of being always available. However, it is still unclear what the added value is of having notifications on the wrist rather than on another mobile device. More importantly, how does this influence our always online culture?</p><p>Research on smartphone notifications has shown that users deal on average with more than 60 notifications per day, and attend to them within minutes, primarily due to social pressure <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>. Other work has highlighted the addictive nature of checking smartphones <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[43]</ref> with people even reporting checking their email on the toilet <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. However, smartphones are not used in isolation, rather they are often part of a multi-device ecology that involves parallel or sequential use of different devices <ref type="bibr">[23]</ref>. As these device ecologies grow, what effect will this have on expectations of availability? Our understanding needs to be updated to include recent technologies and uncover their role among device ecologies.</p><p>Most smartwatch research has focused on hardware and software improvements (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36,</ref><ref type="bibr">44]</ref>). Work exploring the user experience of smartwatches has primarily relied on survey responses from non-smartwatch users <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref> or observing the interactions of users who are provided with a smartwatch for only a brief period of time <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[35]</ref>. However, with some exceptions <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39]</ref>, little has been done to understand the user experience of existing users for whom novelty effects are less prominent. We argue that it is important to update our understanding of smartwatch use among existing users, as well as understand the role of these new devices in shaping expectations in an increasingly always online culture. Moreover, we strongly believe that when studying a particular device, researchers must consider the broader use context in which the interactions take place, by taking into account other devices and applications.</p><p>Therefore, this paper reports on the first extensive study investigating existing users' situated experience with smartwatches within a wider ecology of devices. We used a mixed method qualitative approach, combining an autoethnographic diary study and semi-structured interviews with 17 early adopters (average use: 8 months) to uncover perceived benefits, issues and unmet needs when using a smartwatch, along with how it is used in combination with other devices. Our findings help to understand the benefits and drawbacks of owning a smartwatch within a multidevice ecosystem, and inform future improvements for its user experience. Finally, we make a number of contributions that confirm and extend previous work:</p><p>• We provide an understanding of existing users' situated smartwatch use in the context of communication device ecologies. By doing so, we discuss how having a smartwatch always on the wrist can lead to expectations of being always online and how users manage this. • Extending previous work <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39]</ref>, we provide insight into users' preferences regarding what, how, when and where notifications should be delivered on wearable devices and how wearing habits affect these preferences. • We consider how the design of smart wearable devices could be improved to better support users' values and preferences around notifications and availability.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RELATED WORK</head><p>We live in an age where being always online, not only is the norm, but can also be expected <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>. One of the many consequences is the sense of addiction we can get when checking our phones at all times <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[43]</ref>. In fact, research on mobile notifications has shown that we receive around 60 notifications per day <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>, that communication notifications hold a highest value to users <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>, and that subsequent task resumption is slower <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> and can reduce productivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref>.</p><p>This idea of being constantly connected is strongly linked to the ability to access information on any device, however, little work has been done to understand multi-device experiences in the real world. Jokela et al. <ref type="bibr">[23]</ref> found that different devices are used in parallel or sequentially, depending on the task. Some work has also looked at the use of smartwatches in combination with other devices, yet this is limited to input and output modalities, where the watch is just considered "an extra screen" ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref> p. 2155). This is the case of Duet <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref> where the watch is used as an input or output display to interact with a smartphone. In fact, most smartwatch research has focused on hardware and software improvements (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36]</ref>), and two questions remain unanswered: (i) how do smartwatches fit in the existing plethora of devices users have access to, and (ii) how do smartwatches affect constant connectivity.</p><p>Research on smartwatch use in the wild and with existing users is still very limited. Pizza et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[35]</ref> found that attending to notifications was the second most popular use of the device (17% of interactions), after checking the time (50% of interactions). In their study, the physicality and materiality of the device showed that interactions could be hands free, but also that the device has an "always-available na-ture" ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[35]</ref>, p.5462) (i.e. it is always on the user). Interestingly, they found that only 3% of the watch uses were followed by phone usage. Interactions with the watch were reported as a way of reducing time spent on the phone, and also as a way to balance availability to others with one's own concerns and demands. However, these were not existing users, and thus the types of interactions recorded may have resulted from novelty effects <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[17]</ref> and inexperience.</p><p>Only two studies discuss preliminary findings from interviews with existing smartwatch users. Cecchinato et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> discuss the importance of aesthetic choices for wearables, use of smartwatches in everyday life, and the added value of glancing at notifications. Similarly, Schirra and Bentley <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref> focus on purchase motivations, application use and smartwatch use in public spaces. They also noted that notifications were pushed to the watch "without using filtering options provided by the smart watch to further limit the amount of notifications they receive" ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref>, p.2154).</p><p>More recent work has specifically looked at the use of notifications on smartwatches, however, findings are generally not based on existing users. Shirazi and Henze <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref> found that the importance of a notification depends on both the app it comes from and the device it is delivered to. The authors come up with the interesting concept of differentiating notifications based on the device the user wants to view them on, but lack a discussion around what this may entail and the granularity of notification controls. Giang et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[16]</ref> looked at the impact of smartwatch notifications compared to smartphone ones in a driving scenario. Their findings show that smartwatches may be more detrimental to driving performance compared to phones, highlighting potential differences in interactions with the two devices. However, this may only apply to drivers or specific contexts.</p><p>Smart wrist-worn devices introduce the opportunity to explore new research areas of mobile user experience because, unlike mobile devices, wearables are more discreet and can allow minimal interference between the user and their current activity. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first study that reports findings on why and how existing smartwatch owners use the device in real life, as well as uncovering the role smartwatches have in increasing the expectation that users are always online. Therefore, our study answers the following research questions:</p><p>• What are the benefits and challenges of wearing a device that is always online? • How do smartwatches fit into users' wider multi-device ecologies? • How can the design of smartwatches be improved in order to better fit user needs?</p><p>their in-depth qualitative nature and the ability to provide insight into user experience. As advocated by <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30]</ref>, conducting an autoethnography allowed us to gain first-hand situated user experience of a device that is not (yet) widespread or researched, as well as provide a more nuanced understanding of the insights coming from interviews.</p><p>Autoethnography. The first author conducted a two-month autoethnography starting from when the device was first unpacked (from mid November 2014 to mid January 2015), in order to cover a broad sample of everyday activities. Data was collected through daily diary entries using the One-Note app, and included descriptions of use and non-use of the smartwatch, pictures of interaction with the device, short captions of the researcher's feelings and comments received from friends and family. Reactions and comments were prompted when possible and reported as quotes. Given the lack of literature on the topic at the time of data collection (2014), in addition to providing insight into realistic user experience, the autoethnography was also used to inform the question for interviews.</p><p>Interviews. We conducted 17 explorative semi-structured interviews between winter 2014 and spring 2015 with smartwatch users and stopped once saturation was reached <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref>. Recruitment used a variety of media: flyers, social media paid advertisements, local meet-ups, a stand-up comedy event, and by word-of-mouth. When signing up for the study, potential participants completed a recruitment survey to screen for type of smartwatch and length of ownership. Interviews lasted on average 50 minutes and took place over Skype, with the exception of two, which took place in person in our offices. Questions covered motivations for purchase, initial set up and changes made over time, everyday use and non-use, specific use of notifications, aesthetics and form factor, reactions and social context, perceived benefits of smartwatches, issues and unmet needs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>As part of the autoethnography, the first author -a woman in her late twenties -collected comments from 60 people (friends and family) The median age was 32, ranging from 12 years old to 78 years old. Of them, five had a smartwatch and several were aware of what a smartwatch was through knowing someone who had one or via the popular press. Comments and quotes were recorded to gain a richer understanding of the perceived usefulness of smartwatches among a wider sample of users and non-users. We will report findings from the autoethnography using A0 to refer to the diary entries of the first author, and using A1-A60 to report comments from friends and family.</p><p>Interview participants (n=17, referred to from here on as P1-P17) were all male, with ages ranging from 23 to 68 (median: 31). All participants were or had been knowledge workers and had a technology-related job. Occupations included: four students (three PhDs, one MSc), three UX researchers, three commercial managers, a facilities manager, a software engineer, a chief innovation officer, an imple-mentation consultant, a digital producer, a professor, and a retired teacher. Most participants (n=15) were educated to undergraduate degree level or higher. Fourteen participants lived in the UK, two lived in the USA, and one lived in Australia. All interview participants were entered into a prize raffle for one of three Amazon vouchers.</p><p>Despite our efforts in trying to reach out to women to take part in our study, the only woman who signed up opted out before the interview took place. As many articles in the popular press discuss, the majority of smartwatches, and particularly those available at the time of the study, are generally criticised as being too "masculine" and "bulky", suggesting that their appearance may have made smartwatches less attractive to women (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[14]</ref>). However, the gender balance of our sample is not so surprising given that market researchers found that in 2014 71% of smartwatch users were male, and average age was skewed towards the 18-34 years old bracket <ref type="bibr">[42]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Analysis</head><p>Interviews were transcribed and diary entries were collated for data analysis. Initial findings from the interviews can be found in <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. Both the autoethnography and the interviews were coded and analysed using thematic analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> to find consistencies in themes and patterns of use across the two data sets. Initial themes from the autoethnography were organised in preparation for the interview analysis, to uncover overlapping codes, themes, and experiences.</p><p>Findings from the autoethnography were generally confirmed in the interviews, thus, to avoid redundant explanations, we will primarily report interview data, which provides more grounded evidence. However, where more relevant, we will use autoethnography data to provide evidence.</p><p>Although participants did mention other use cases (e.g. fitness tracking, time keeping, etc.), we will focus the following section on the use of smartwatches for communication.</p><p>After describing general motivations for wanting a smartwatch, we will present our findings following the pipeline of how users interact with smartwatches for communication: receiving a notification, managing availability, and replying to messages. Throughout, we will highlight those aspects that users considered a benefit. Finally, we will discuss costs associated with having a smartwatch.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FINDINGS</head><p>In the initial survey, participants were asked to list all their devices, categorised by type (smartphone, smartwatch, tablet, laptop, desktop PC, activity tracker, other wearable). On average participants had 5.59 devices each (min: 3, max: 9, median: 5 almost 8 months (min: 3 weeks, max: 25 months, median: 5 months) and wore them "always" (n=8) or "most of the time" (n=9). Thirteen participants also owned traditional watches (i.e. non-smartwatches), of which seven owned more than one and only five had stopped wearing them all together. Based on a 5-point Likert scale survey answers, P6 still wore all his watches "most of the time", alternating between them, P9 and P1 wore traditional watches "sometimes", and the remaining five participants wore them "rarely" (e.g. only for formal occasions such as weddings).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Motivation for Wanting a Smartwatch</head><p>Findings from both the interviews and people talked to during the autoethnography suggest that users are interested in owning a smartwatch "because it's cool to play with" [A21] or because they want to be one of the first ones to try a new technology, "because it was promising things that we never experienced and we are not clear how it will make our life easier or more difficul." <ref type="bibr">[P8]</ref>. Through the autoethnography we were able to collect reactions from non-users of smartwatches and their reasons for not wanting one. The latter were usually motivated by scepticism and related to not feeling the need to be constantly connected or not perceiving the added value compared to a smartphone: "why would I need it if I could use my phone?" [A19]</p><p>Interview participants identified themselves as early adopters and often recognised the limitations that go along with this. Despite having curiosity as their main motivation and few expectations, participants did find value in the smartwatches, as P8 explains: "After getting it, I found it's a lot more useful than I thought." However, three participants did have particular motivations that went beyond the appeal of a new device, and were looking forward to "being more connected" [P2]. For example, P9 wanted to be more responsive to his girlfriend: "I guess the main reasons was curiosity.</p><p>[…] But also the secondary motive my girlfriend used to keep calling me and I would never pick up 'cause I keep my phone on silent so I thought it could be handy to make notifications easier to get hold of.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>" [P9]</head><p>Receiving Notifications</p><p>Overall, receiving notifications on smartwatches was considered the main benefit, as P2 explains: "I like the idea of being more connected generally […] everything is just a little bit of a convenience, [an] improvement of what you have before". The types of notifications allowed on smartwatches by participants were primarily communicationrelated (e.g. email, SMS, iMessage, WhatsApp, Facebook messenger, calls, Skype) but also included social media (e.g. Twitter, Facebook), news and information (e.g. BBC, weather, Google Now cards), health data (e.g. Fitbit), and other (e.g. calendar events, alarms, to-do lists, IFTTT <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[21]</ref>).</p><p>Participants from both the interviews and the autoethnography had a clear idea of what sort of notifications they wanted, how they wanted to be notified, when they wanted notifications and where they were happy to be notified. We discuss each below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>What: Priority Notifications</head><p>Participants wanted to be in control over what they were notified about on their smartwatch, and this was generally different from notifications on their phone, as expressed also in the autoethnography: "I'd like to be able to control on which device [phone vs. smartwatch] I see the notification. It's becoming redundant like this" [A0]. Despite initially allowing most or all notifications on their smartwatch, mirroring those on the phone, more than half our participants (n=9) turned off at least some notifications after an initial novelty period (which varied between an hour and a few weeks). Seven participants disabled email notifications on their smartwatch altogether; four allowed only personal email, one of whom enabled only priority personal emails; and six participants had both work and personal email notifications enabled, one of whom only had priority emails coming through. Overall, the reasons participants reported for turning off these notifications mirror those found in the autoethnography: they found them annoying, or wanted to be less distracted. How: Glanceable Information Participants found that the major benefit of having a smartwatch was that by quickly glancing at their wrist they could decide whether to interrupt their current activity or not deal with the notification (be it reading the whole message, replying, deleting, etc.). This was consistent across the different models of smartwatches and apps used, ranging from those that allow seeing the whole message to those that only preview the first few lines. All participants bar one [P6] also agreed that glancing at their smartwatch was less rude and more socially acceptable than looking at their smartphone. In particular, being able to check the smartwatch without interrupting the flow of any on-going social interaction or being too distracted from the current task was seen as a major benefit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>When, Where and Wear: Contextual Alerts</head><p>Another feature participants desired were contextual notifications, whereby they could retain control of when and where they received notifications, something that current smartwatches do not fully support. Participants had different interpretations of what they considered contextual. For example, some (n=5) were more keen on having locationbased notifications, such as knowing about the next train when nearing the station, while others (n=6) wanted to have different types of notifications enabled depending on the activity they were involved in (e.g. not receiving social media alerts when working). As a result, participants created rules around when and where to be notified, some of which were automated using the existing settings, while others were manually enabled at the time of need.</p><p>The most frequent automated setting used was muting the watch at certain times, such as at night. As P11 puts it, being able to mute your device is an important feature that is not always advertised, probably for fear of reducing engagement with the device: In a similar way, when P5 reached home, not only would he take his watch off, but he would also turn the Bluetooth off on his phone, cutting that 'always connected' thread between devices: "I'll turn the Bluetooth off on my phone, start charging the Moto360 -the minute I come in the door I'm done with it. If I go out again I'll turn it back on." [P5]</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">"it'</formula><p>A few participants (n=3) found that the watch itself was something that reminded them of work, so they did not wear it at the weekend. P17 compared his wearing habits with his two different smartwatches. He originally had a Pebble, which he wore most of the time, until he got the Apple Watch which he then wore all the time. When probed about the reasons, he explained: "you know, I didn't the Pebble all the time]. I wore it during the week, but and holidays I one of my normal watches." [P17]. He goes on to explain how he only used it for notifications and he did not receive as many at the While his notifications not have changed since owning the Apple Watch, he now used his new to replace the Fitbit he owned and track his physical</p><p>In this case, the affordance of the watch clashed with one of the participant's values: despite not wanting to a connection to the world the weekend, tracking his physical activity superseded previous habit not wearing the watch.</p><p>participants did not necessarily want to take off their smartwatches would instead off the connection or even the device from time to time to get some distance from online world. For example, P11 stated, "Sometimes I wear it while it's turned off because I don't want to any notifications at all." P15 provides more explanation of similar behaviour:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>"Sometimes if I'm at work I'll turn my off on my phone, so if I turn it on and I get everything up then I find that quite distracting, but over the weekends I don't find it distracting at all." [P15]</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Managing Availability</head><p>Once a user receives a notification, he or she is faced with between three options: the notification, dismiss it, or read it. In addition, reading a notification can done on the watch or on another device, depending on the app. Deciding which device to use, in turn, opens difoptions for further actions, such as replying. smartwatches generally offering limited reply functionali-(depending on the model), we found participants took advantage of not always being able to reply to help them their availability.</p><p>Participants used notification settings to gain not a sense of control of how, when, and where to allow interrupbut also a sense of increased flexibility and control when to reply, as notes from the autoethnography ex- This gained flexibility in when to reply to messages was particularly welcomed when it allowed participants to view without having sender being notified the message had been read. Information such as when a person last online or whether a message has been read is known as an awareness cue communication apps mentioned by participants, such as WhatsApp and Facebook Messenger, include read receipts. For example, WhatsApp introduced this feature in the fall of 2014, by a message is marked as 'read' two blue ticks apnext to it <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[10]</ref>. when viewed on a smart-WhatsApp messages are not marked as 'read' on the phone, and the same happens with similar features in other apps. smartwatches work in the same way as the notification centre in a smartphone, where the user can preview a message without actually opening it. The only difference is that while on the phone the user can only see part of the message, on the watch one can scroll through the conversation, depending on the app. Because of this difference between devices, participants were more aware these cues and expressed mixed feelings about them.</p><formula xml:id="formula_1">the</formula><p>With messaging platforms, and particularly those with awareness cues, there is an underlying that people will reply as soon as they read a message. As P11 explained, "[when the person does not reply to the call] going online on Skype, or sending [a message]</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Viber or WhatsApp because I can see the other person is online. So WhatsApp they will reply to me when they see it. I think it's much faster compared to an [P11]</head><p>Another participant, P6, expressed his absolute dislike for cue features in messaging apps that tell the other when a message is read, complaining about how they create or increase the expectation of being constantly</p><p>In fact, he reports on being criticised, "I a lot of flak from my girlfriend and other people" not being responsive and quick enough: During the autoethnography, the first author discovered that that the sender would not know whether she had read the WhatsApp message made reading the message on watch suddenly more appealing than taking out the just in case she decided did not want to reply there and then. Another participant, explicitly mentioned awareness cues with respect to the watch. His expesomewhat contrasts of P6 </p><formula xml:id="formula_2">would</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Replying to Messages and the Cross-Device Experience</head><p>After receiving a notification a smartwatch and deciding reply to a message, a user has to select which of their devices they will use to compose a reply. Different smartwatches afford different degrees of reply, from no reply (e.g. Basis Peak), using canned messages Pebrelying on voice interaction Moto360), or even QWERTY-keyboards Samsung Gear S). Other devices can be used to reply to messages received on a course smartphones, and occasionally other devices such as tablets and laptops/PCs can also be used if app that sent the notification works cross-device. These are becoming more frequent: for example email IM like WhatsApp, messenger, and Slack.</p><p>Smartwatches generally prompted replies to urgent or negotiating a better time to communicate. As P3 explains, "I usually only reply on my watch if it's an element of urgency or it's very short and easy to reply. Usually if I reply from my watch it's just a couple of participants that while prior to owning a smartwatch they were not good at replying to immessages, they have since improved, like P9: "I'm a lot more timely in replying to her now to text and</p><p>The distance that a smartwatch from a smartphone extends also to the ability to make interactions politer or simply negotiate availability by letting someone know when is a better time, without having to pull out the phone, which would either interrupt the current task/social or draw the user into checking other makes those communications simpler and in some cases more polite.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I've you know a few quick responses for text, like 'ok', 'I'm busy I'll get back to you', I don't have to pull the phone out in a number of situa-</head><p>[…] where it's just physically awkward, but also situawhere it's socially awkward. mostly reply from the watch in situations where the reply is either simply or letting people know I can't reply. Just because someone wants to be synchronous doesn't that I am going to be.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>" [P13]</head><p>In contrast, when the message was not considered important or urgent, participants' responsiveness using other devices such as smartphones and laptops depended on their availability and initialisation time (i.e. the time to boot a device and start an application). the following quotes, P1 nicely explains reply behaviour, comparing smartwatches, smartphones, and eventually laptops: smartphones slower responses to nonurgent notifications because the burden of pulling out the and unlocking it to respond was not justified. This selective responsiveness across devices can help users align behaviour to their values not being constantly available), such as delaying a reply to a more appropriate</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">"</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Contextual Smartwatch</head><p>CHI 2017, May 6-11, 2017, Denver, CO, USA time. However, we observed how users' behaviours and could be challenged if there was a readily available device. P1 explained how he was less likely to respond on his phone when he a notification on the watch, but tually, I'm far more likely to respond if I'm on my laptop it's way more easy to type on that. So if it up on my watch 'this happened' then I'll flip open the iMessage my laptop and respond. Whereas if I'm away from my laptop I can't be arsed to get the phone out and send some-</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">[P1]</formula><p>this cross-device experience can also cause is-In our case, P6 found himself with redundant notifications on several devices and ultimately disengaged with the smartwatch: "so what I ended up doing was to mute all that came in. When I did that, it pretty ended all the about it. I stopped looking at the device, it was just the time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>" [P6]</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Costs Associated with Smartwatch Use</head><p>Along with smartwatches providing the benefit of buying time by enabling users to decide whether to delay a reand thus by not pulling out their smartphone, smartwatches are also associated with negative</p><p>In addition to monetary costs associated with purchasing an aesthetically pleasing smartwatch (and a data for some models), and 'battery costs' with having "another thing to charge?!" [P7], smartwatches can also pose a threat to privacy and attention.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Privacy Cost</head><p>Despite most participants (n=14) not being disturbed by having personal information displayed their wrists for others to potentially view, some (n=5) did voice concerns that this could information to other people. example, "sometimes when I text my family in a work environment that made me think that the notification could be seen if my wrist is turned outwards, a personal message could be by someone the table from me, when I don't really want it". P7 a friend who had a Pebble and did not wear it at work precisely he did not want others to read his messages and "it has been an issue." [P7] One participant found it weird that his friends could read his messages on his wrist, but explained: "it's a risk you take if you wear your screen on you that someone is going see your screen" [P11]. However, another participant experienced some issues a friend as a result of messages being visible on his smartwatch:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ex of my friend was messaging me we've been good friends for the last 10 or 15 years -when he saw the messages […] he was really... his first question was are you messaging her -what's the need? We have broken now, so you shouldn't be friends' […] the reason why it happened was because he happened to see what those messages are, and in a social context I guess you value your and when it's all there for everyone to see it's not the best. […] you should have a way to tweak that." [P6]</head><p>These findings suggest that privacy settings should better considered the design of notifications on wearables.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Attention Cost</head><p>In addition to being distracting the user, smartwatches may be distracting or attention grabbing for others as well, the autoethnography was valuable uncovering these On several occasions, real-world interactions were interrupted by somebody pointing out something was happening on the watch, mainly out of curiosity for the device. This was also the case for P3's friend who owned a Pebble: "sometimes […] his work mates know he's got it, they'll say 'you've got a call' and he's like <ref type="bibr">'yeah</ref> In the autoethnography, one person explicitly mentioned how the watch had distracted her during a semi-"I found it distracting during the seminar. You were playing with it and then you were resting your head on your and the screen was lit up." [A1]</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DISCUSSION</head><p>In this paper, we provide insights how smartwatches are used by existing users, how they fit within existing deecologies, and how they can impact both the smartsense of availability as well as other people's expectations of availability. By qualitative methods, we confirm and extend previous findings, along with presenting several novel insights.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Designing Smartwatch Notifications</head><p>notifications a smartwatch considered the benefit by the existing users recruited in our study, previous findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39]</ref>. However, we also extended existing findings in a number of novel ways.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Previous work on mobile notifications identified how users</head><p>aware of their disruptive nature, yet want to maintain nonetheless <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr">26]</ref>. However, not all mobile notifications are treated equally, with some (primarily communication ones) being considered more valuable Whereas Schirra and Bentley <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref> that notifications in their sample were being pushed to the watch, we found that once novelty effects wore off, participants disabled at least some notifications on their watch, but left on their phone. in turn allowed them to create some distance from their phone, rather than just being "an screen" ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref> p. 2155). As smartwatches worn, it is not a great surprise that users want to limit the amount of they receive and the implications of prefneed to be considered carefully.</p><p>Pielot et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref> uncovered how smartphone users find it to not have notifications, though they can have negative effects. Their study on disabling notifications for one day made people aware of wanting more control over settings. Similarly, we found that additional notification control can be gained by using a smartwatch that filter out notifications and distractions, and even completely them when the device is taken off. As a way of exercising control over notification settings, we Contextual Smartwatch CHI 2017, May 6-11, 2017, Denver, CO, USA found that participants removed their watch, idea presented by Pizza al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[35]</ref> of a smartwatch hava distinctive and materiality to it. Taking off the watch is a act that can have a strong metaphorical meaning to the user, almost as if he or she were taking the digital handcuff that as long as it is always it keeps them connected to the online world. This in turn can the expectations of availability. smartwatch designs should leverage on the device materiality and affordances to support users' values. For example, allowing components that communication funcwith other features (e.g. activity tracking).</p><p>Ultimately, our participants wanted smartwatches to have specific features to them in control of notification they received. Specifically, wanted notifications to be (i) glanceable, (ii) priority-filtered, and (iii) contextual. Most commercial smartwatches already support glanceable information, however this is not the case for smart wearables such as jewellery, which often only haptic alerts and no screen <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr">37]</ref>. More importantly, we have seen how the smartwatch screen can be distracting bystanders and therefore the type of glanceable information displayed on the screen needs to be considered carefully. Alternative solutions have been proposed, such as more intimate notifications that can come in the of vibrations <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref> subtle peripheral light alerts <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>, but these type of alerts still lack salient information such as and topic.</p><p>Priority and contextual notifications are considered a desir-</p><p>feature not yet fully supported by existing devices. found that participants prioritised and filtered the notificathey received by creating manual and automatic rules what and how to be notified. While and textual notifications have been suggested before (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29]</ref>), our findings go a step further and point towards usefulness of geo-fenced notifications on a smartwatch, on virtual fences physical locations where alerts can be enabled to determine where one should, not, be notified. For example, this could be introduced in future smartwatch designs by allowing users to be notified based sender, topic, or even location. To optimise this, notifications settings should be decentralised from specific apps, perhaps leverage instead on starred contacts.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Delivering the Cross-Device Experience</head><p>Previous work identified the importance of providing cross-device features, such as differentiating notifications based on the device the user wants to view them on or keeping track of where they were first viewed Building on this line of work, we found that depends not only on the level of urgency, but also on the devices available and the type of awareness cues sent or not to the sender. Viewing a notification on a smartwatch allowed a delay in replying, depending on the importance of the message and devices available, but independent of the of reply allowed on smartwatch (e.g. using responses vs. full-QWERTY keyboard). While smartwatches afford a specific kind of response short and urgent -replies on smartphones and laptops depend on many more factors. We found that the initialisation time was a major barrier to switching from a smartwatch to compose a reply on another device. Matthews al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref> found that smartphones' initialisation time was generally quicker than laptops' and therefore users preferred completing a task on their phones if possible. However, our results suggest that this is not always the case and importantly, that device switching also depended on application in use. As Jokela al. <ref type="bibr">[23]</ref> point out, and our study confirms, being able to access the same application across multiple devices is a strongly desired feature.</p><p>However, our study suggests that this cross-device experience needs to be delivered appropriately to avoid negative such as overall disengagement. On one hand, need to avoid occasions abandonment, such as the case of P6, who decided to stop using the smartwatch notifications due to redundancy issues. On the other hand, designers should keep in mind users' values and needs. Nudging the user to respond on the nearest device might not always be the best solution, or one that is in line with their values. It can not only cause further interruptions, but also provide situations further challenge one's desire to disconnect.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Managing through Frictions</head><p>a society that encourages people to always online and available <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>, smartwatches people receiving notifications in more contexts than any other mobile device. Although they have the potential to be digital handcuffs that other people's expectations of availability, they also enable users to connect more selectively to only those things they consider important and can reduce users' compulsion to reply immediately to notifications. Our ings suggest that using smartwatches users manage their availability and can time spent on other devices and consequently helping with issues of mobile <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[43]</ref>. Pielot et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref> that it is those same we cannot live without create expectations towards timely responses. By focusing on smartwatches among multi-device ecologies, we found that seeing notifications on the smartwatch reduces feelings of missing out, but also helps users their values by being in control of when to reply. This is partly due the limited which are seen positively as a means to create distance, and partially to the greater control over the of awareness cues sent out. It should be noted that benefits were not always perceived by those communicating with smartwatch users: for example, some peoexpected even more timely replies they knew notifications were being delivered to the other person's wrist, thinking that users might prioritise alerts.</p><p>on the concept of as presented <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">11]</ref>, we now characterise the kinds of strategies our</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Contextual Smartwatch</head><p>CHI 2017, May 6-11, 2017, Denver, CO, USA participants used in order to regain control over their availability. some users did welcome the notifications and regardless of time and place, others wanted to shield certain situations from any Therefore, see how these strategies can relate to microboundaries (e.g. disabling notifications when out for microboundaries enabling 'do not mode at night); digital microboundaries disabling selected notifications only on selected devices); and microboundaries (e.g. deciding when not to wear smartwatch or carry a device). strategies, or microboundaries, are examples of sign frictions user-designed strategies that help users shift from mindless interactions technology (e.g. addictively emails) to more conscious of engaging with a device and the information it provides. While microboundary strategies have been noted across a number devices <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7]</ref> we identified a large number of them being by our participants with their smartwatch. This might that the use of smartwatch can nudge users to think more carefully about their interactions perhaps our sample is particularly aware work-life boundary issues (e.g. not wanting work notifications during non-working hours). Thinking about these aspects can help inform how new smartwatches or smart wearables should be designed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>AND FUTURE WORK</head><p>our sample consists of male adopters, confirming previous work, our findings around the use of smartwatches for communication purposes the floor to future work with a more heterogeneous sample. We tried to recruit a diverse sample and have provided eviof that, including sampling users with a diverse set of owned for varying amounts time. Future work should investigate long-term use of smartwatches and of abandonment, as previous has observed that phenomena other kinds of wearables Efforts to a more gender-balanced sample should be made when investigating aesthetics and form factor, given the of wearables and their highly personal value.</p><p>We call for further work to investigate specific contexts of use and behaviours. For example, studies could use logged across devices to understand reply times. Some initial work to see if viewing notifications on smartwatches are faster than on smartphones has been done simulating drivbehaviour and smartwatches were found to require glances. As smartwatches become more popular and the novelty effect wears off, these findings need updating.</p><p>importantly, as cross-device applications become more prominent, whole device ecologies, including laptops, smartphones and smartwatches should be studied.</p><p>Other interesting contexts of use are meetings and working environments. Our findings support the idea that there is a strong value in using smartwatches during meetings to keep with information. Some research has already been done in this area, for example using smartwatches to provide peripheral awareness during videoconference meetings <ref type="bibr">[25]</ref>. Other work has explored the use of smartwatches augment interactions office environments, with implications for managing availability This work points towards a new level of cross-device experience and we call for further in this direction.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONSIDERATIONS DESIGN</head><p>Although are not representative of all smartusers, they provide insight on what existing users see as the major benefits and drawbacks. As new models released and sales figures grow, we beour insights can help inform how new models should be redesigned, before adoption becomes more mainstream.</p><p>particular, help have more control of their cations and availability, we make some suggestions.</p><p>Decentralising Notification Settings. Notification settings should leverage on users' contacts lists and starred contacts, rather than on single apps, in order select when, where and how to be notified certain people. For example, different level or category of pricould be assigned to a user's contacts always notify me for this person, or notify me only during hours/days for this person). Designing Smartwatch Affordances. The materiality of the smartwatch and the symbolism of wearing it can be to inspire new shape shifting or modular that align with users' and behaviours. For examhaving modular components that help users disconnect from notifications but still track steps, could cater for users like P17 who changed his wearing patterns he upgraded his smartwatch and abandoned his activity tracker. This has important implications also for managing availability and shifting general expectations people might have or perceive.</p><p>wearable nature of smartwatches people to be notified even when other mobile devices might not be at hand. As a result, users can feel always online and more For some this may increase their productivity and enhance their social lives but for others smartwatches may like digital handcuffs. In this paper, we investigated how existing users manage smartwatches and how they use in conjunction with other devices. main finding is the value perceived in being able to quickly glance at information, without it being considered rude or too disrupand deciding whether to interrupt the current task. most users, wearing a smartwatch led them to carefully people and information streams that were able to them and where and how they could be notified: having a device that enabled them to be 'always on' made them aware of when they wanted to be 'off'. We suggested for smartwatches to facilitate user control over their notifications.</p><p>work is funded by UK EPSRC DTG studentship.</p><p>Contextual Smartwatch CHI 2017, May 6-11, 2017, Denver, CO, USA</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>So the Pebble serves as an extension of the phone that lets me know that something is going on and has the added benefit of finding out in a more convenient way what that something is. It gives me a little bit of distance; […] I can't answer it because I have no microphone, but at least knowing what's going on can be useful. I can decide is it worth running to grab the phone." [P13]</figDesc><table /><note>"It's made my life easier in terms of managing notifications and seeing which ones are duds and which ones are actually ones I want to deal with." [P9] Contextual Smartwatch Use CHI 2017, May 6-11, 2017, Denver, CO, USA "I don't let myself be interrupted. […]</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>May 6-11, 2017, Denver, CO, USA just</head><label></label><figDesc>using a smartwatch for day-to-day meetings for several reasons. For example, checking the time in a meeting is considered socially acceptable, especially if this is done on a smartwatch rather than a phone: "People will think that you are just possibly checking the time, or looking at something as opposed to actually getting some information through it. I think it's a little less rude I guess." [P17]. Getting useful information such as emails or when the next appointment is due seems crucial for staying on time and up to date: "It makes sense to check the time and contemporarily see how long until the next meeting." [A0] More interestingly, during meetings other people could take advantage of a user's smartwatch and send timely and contextual messages. This was the case of P8, who considered his colleague "smart" when they sent a message during a customer meeting so it would appear on the smartwatch. Although this may not have been as intentional as the participant led us to believe, it still portrays a realistic scenario: to keep [the watch] off, put it on the table. Just keep it far from my hand. That's it."[P8]    </figDesc><table><row><cell>Contextual Smartwatch Use</cell><cell>CHI 2017,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>m</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>attending an event or a place that's a little more dressy I've</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>got more of a dressy watch which I wear" [P3]), some par-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>ticipants (n=6) purposefully decided not to wear it because</cell></row><row><cell>Some participants (n=5) preferred having a more active role</cell><cell>they did not want to be constantly connected. For them,</cell></row><row><cell>in deciding when notifications should be disabled and thus</cell><cell>having the smartwatch on, meant they were also online and</cell></row><row><cell>manually changed the settings from time to time. For ex-</cell><cell>potentially available. P8 provides a detailed account:</cell></row><row><cell>ample, P4 would disable his notifications whenever he went on holiday, but also if he went out for dinner with friends: "I have from time to time stopped certain notifications… [for example] when I've been out for dinner with a friend or something like that." [P4]</cell><cell>"I try to use it while I'm driving [or] I'm in the office, but once I'm home I can just disconnect from my smartwatch. I think I'm one of the people who fell into the trap with the ability to work really remotely and have business emails on my mobile phone. It makes me keep checking it when I</cell></row></table><note>s quite inconvenient if you forget to put it in sleep mode and then people start talking to you on Facebook and then your wrist vibrates, that's quite annoying! […] If you put it in sleep mode the only thing that will interrupt you is your alarms. [...] They don't tell you that you need to do that, but you do need to do that basically. It's on the watch from the beginning." [P11]The Case of Meetings. Meetings were a particular context that participants frequently mentioned when discussing notifications. Although smartwatch use in formal meetings (e.g. job interviews) or when giving a presentation was dismissed for fear of it being distracting, participants were very keen on"So normally we mute our phones and my phone is in my pocket, but when I was discussing something with the customer […], a colleague of mine wanted to remind me of something to mention […]. So he simply sent me an SMS to my phone, my phone is in the pocket, in my [hung up] coat, but then I got the message simply on my watch, and looking at the watch is never rude, or never offending compared to looking at a mobile phone, while in a meeting. So because he was not actively participating in the discussion, he managed to send me that SMS so just with a glimpse on my watch I knew what he wanted to remind me of and then I picked it up and managed not to forget it." [P8]Wearing habits. Depending on the context, deciding whether to wear the smartwatch was another way to control when and where to be notified. While not wearing the smartwatch could sometimes be a result of aesthetics and fashion preference on certain occasions (e.g. "I had taken it off a couple of days ago because […] I didn't want to look too much like a techno-nerd [for an event]" [P1] and "if I'check my personal email. […] and then I start to get worried […] when it's not the time for it at all. I should wait till tomorrow. […] [Interviewer: So why do you take your watch off?] It's just to decide to stay away from the phone,</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>watch has also changed my sense of availabildespite having a notification device strapped to my wrist which could potentially make me feel more compelled reply, I feel it buys me time. on the watch could help me decide if I needed to reply."</figDesc><table><row><cell>participants, like shared similar thoughts and ex-</cell></row><row><cell>plained how the smartwatch prevented them from mindless-</cell></row><row><cell>completing habitual actions:</cell></row><row><cell>"[having the smartwatch means] spend less time on a de-</cell></row><row><cell>vice. You know what happens… if I open the phone to check</cell></row><row><cell>email then there are other things that you could very easily</cell></row><row><cell>into doing. You know, replying. Whereas on a smart-</cell></row><row><cell>watch you can't reply, so it's very much just reading and</cell></row><row><cell>dismissing a notification, so it's actually made tech-</cell></row><row><cell>nology less intrusive." [P5]</cell></row><row><cell>Awareness Cues</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>stay away from Messenger and WhatsApp and the reason</figDesc><table><row><cell>Contextual Smartwatch</cell><cell>CHI 2017, May 6-11, 2017, Denver, CO, USA</cell></row><row><cell>for that I HATE the available thing with the tick</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>ARGH! It's just so annoying! It's just added pres-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>to have all of that" [P6]. then goes on to</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>systems with emails, in relation to the added</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>of availability and connectedness.</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>"The best part of email is that you don't have that kind of</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>For some reason, just comes there and</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>you know how important an email is, but with messages it's</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>not like that, it's just so instant, in case if you don't get back</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>to them now, the context is lost. If they sent you a message</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>now, if you got back to them in a week or two then it sorts</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>defeats the whole purpose of instant messaging. So I</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>think that's the reason why you have that added pressure</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>and I really don't like to a have the pressure. In case if you</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>reply to them that's a bad thing to do socially." [P6]</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Office Smartwatch: Development and Design of a Smartwatch App to Digitally Augment Interactions in an Office Environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yannick</forename><surname>Bernaerts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jo</forename><surname>Steensels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Vermeulen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2014 companion publication on Designing interactive systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2014 companion publication on Designing interactive systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ambient Interaction by Smart Watches</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Kirste</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bodo</forename><surname>Urban</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. PETRA&apos;</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Virginia</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Research in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>in psychology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">from an interruption: Investigating speedtradeoffs in task resumption strategy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Brumby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Back</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal Experimental Psychology: Applied</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="107" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Cecchinato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Smartwatches: The Good , the Bad and the Ugly? Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2133" to="2138" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marta</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Cecchinato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">check my emails on the toilet&quot; Email Practices and Boundary Management. MobileHCI</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Workshop on Socio-Technical Practices and Work-Home Boundaries</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Marta E Cecchinato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">9-5? Professional Differences in Email and Boundary Management Practices. of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3989" to="3998" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Semi-precious: The best smart</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Charara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-09-07">2016. September 7. 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>from precious-the-best-smart-jewelry-582</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Duet: Exploring Joint Interactions on a Smart Phone and a Watch</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Xiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tovi</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 32nd annual conference on Human factors in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the 32nd annual conference on Human factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="159" to="168" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Blue ticks on WhatsApp: What really mean</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Collinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.bbc.co.uk/newsbeat/article/29933261/blue-ticks-on-whatsapp-what-they-really-mean" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014-09-07">2014. September 7</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design Frictions for Mindful Interactions: The Case for Microboundaries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Anna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sandy</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marta</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Gould</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cecchinato</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference Abstracts on Human Factors</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference Abstracts on Human Factors</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1389" to="1397" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Ioanna Iacovides, and Ian Renfree</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A tool for practice and education</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jo</forename><surname>Sally</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 6th ACM SIGCHI New Zealand international conference on Computer-human interaction</title>
				<meeting>the 6th ACM SIGCHI New Zealand international conference on Computer-human interaction</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating episodes of mobile phone activity as indicators of opportune moments to deliver notifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Greenhalgh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Benford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th International Conference on Human Computer Interaction with Devices and Services</title>
				<meeting>the 13th International Conference on Human Computer Interaction with Devices and Services</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="190" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Why Women Aren&apos;t Buying Smartwatches</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Fumo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-09-07">2016. September 7, 2016 from</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">we there yet? Data saturation in qualitative research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patricia</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Fusch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lawrence</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Ness</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Report</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1408" to="1416" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Driver Engagement in Notifications: A of Visual-Manual Interaction between and Smartphones</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Giang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Hoekstra-Atwood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Donmez</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">58</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2161" to="2165" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nadia</forename><surname>Berthouze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Tracking physical activity: problems related to running longitudinal studies with commercial Proceedings of the 2014 ACM International Conference on Pervasive and Computing Adjunct Publication</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="699" to="702" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Give me five minutes!&quot; Feeling Time Slip By</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marta</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Cecchinato</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Adjunct Proceedings of the 2015 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing and Proceedings of the 2015 ACM International Symposium on Wearable</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nadia</forename><surname>Bianchi-Berthouze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Bird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Barriers, Workarounds, and Customisation. Proceedings of the ACM Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="617" to="621" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Houben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicolai</forename><surname>Marquardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">of the 33rd on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1247" to="1256" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">If This Then That</title>
		<ptr target="https://ifttt.com/" />
		<imprint>
			<date>September 19</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Shamsi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Iqbal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Horvitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Notifications Awareness : A Field Study of Alert Usage and Proceedings of the 2010 ACM conference Computer supported cooperative work</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="27" to="30" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Diary Study on Combining Multiple Information Devices in Everyday Activities and Tasks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Denver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tero</forename><surname>Jokela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P O</forename><surname>Box</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Olsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P O</forename><surname>Box</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">May 6-11, 2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3903" to="3912" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Contextual Smartwatch Use CHI 2017</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Latest Pebble campaign snags thirdmost-funded slot on Kickstarter</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Haje</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kamps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://techcrunch.com/2016/06/30/pebble-" />
		<imprint>
			<date>September 7</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Pace Not Dictated by Electrons&quot;: An Study of Work Without Email</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ville</forename><surname>Mäkelä</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Marlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Live Meetings at a Glance. of the ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing Companion</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Gloria J Mark, Stephen Voida, V Cardello</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2016. 2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Com-Systems</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">No smartphone is an island: the of places, situation and other device on smart use</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tara</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Pierce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harry</forename><surname>Road</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">San</forename><surname>Jose</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>RJ10452. 10452</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The of availability: understanding the economic of constant connectivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melissa</forename><surname>Mazmanian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ingrid</forename><surname>Erickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>of 32nd annual ACM conference on Human factors in systems</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abhinav</forename><surname>Mehrotra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Veljko</forename><surname>Pejovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jo</forename><surname>Vermeulen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Hendley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mirco</forename><surname>Musolesi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">My Phone Me: Understanding People&apos;s Receptivity to Mobile Proceedings of the 2016 CHI Conference Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1021" to="1032" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gaining empathy for non-routine mobile device use through autoethnography</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aisling</forename><surname>Ann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O'</forename><surname>Kane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yvonne</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ann</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Blandford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 32nd annual ACM conference on factors in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the 32nd annual ACM conference on factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Interpreting and Acting on Mobile Cues</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Antti</forename><surname>Oulasvirta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Renaud</forename><surname>Petit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mika</forename><surname>Raento</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tiitta</forename><surname>Sauli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-10">2007. October 2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="135" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The time famine: Toward a of work time</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Leslie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Perlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An In-Situ Study of Mobile Phone Notifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Pielot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Church</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rodrigo</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Oliveira</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 16th international conference on interaction with mobile devices &amp;</title>
				<meeting>the 16th international conference on interaction with mobile devices &amp;</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="233" to="242" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Do Not Disturb A Day Without Notifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Pielot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luz</forename><surname>Rello</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Abstracts of the ACM CHI&apos;15 Conference on Human in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1761" to="1766" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefania</forename><surname>Pizza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Donald</forename><surname>Mcmillan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Airi</forename><surname>Lampinen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Smartwatch in vivo. the 2016 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Henning</forename><surname>Pohl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Justyna</forename><surname>Medrek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Rohs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">ScatterWatch: Subtle Notifications via Indirect Scattered in the Skin. of the international conference on Human-computer interaction with mobile devices and services companion</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thijs</forename><surname>Roumen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Simon</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Perrault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shengdong</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">NotiRing: A Comparative Study of Notification Channels for Wearable Interactive Rings. the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Large-scale assessment of mobile notifications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alireza</forename><surname>Sahami Shirazi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Niels</forename><surname>Henze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tilman</forename><surname>Dingler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Pielot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dominik</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Albrecht</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 32nd annual ACM conference on factors in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the 32nd annual ACM conference on factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding Uses of Consumer Smartwatches</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Schirra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bentley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2151" to="2156" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>It&apos;s kind of an extra screen for my phone</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Demographic Divide: Fitness Trackers and Smartwatches Attracting Very Different Segments of the Market</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alireza</forename><surname>Sahami Shirazi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Niels</forename><surname>Henze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://bit.ly/1IRegAj" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Assessment of Notifications on Smartwatches. of the 17th International Conference on Interaction with Mobile Devices and Adjunct, 41. Statista</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2015. 2014. 2015. September 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Global smart watch unit shipments from to 2019. Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Is mobile addiction overlooked</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Turel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Serenko</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">of the ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">41</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shimmering Smartwatches: Exploring the Smartwatch Design Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cheng</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kent</forename><surname>Lyons</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Ninth International Conference on Embedded, and Embodied Interaction &apos;14</title>
				<meeting>the Ninth International Conference on Embedded, and Embodied Interaction &apos;14</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="76" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
