<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Are You Dreaming? A Phenomenological Study on Understanding Lucid Dreams as a Tool for Introspection in Virtual Reality</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Kitson</surname></persName>
							<email>akitson@sfu.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Simon Fraser University Surrey</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Thecla</forename><surname>Schiphorst</surname></persName>
							<email>thecla@sfu.ca</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Simon Fraser University Surrey</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Riecke</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Simon Fraser University Surrey</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="CA">Canada</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Are You Dreaming? A Phenomenological Study on Understanding Lucid Dreams as a Tool for Introspection in Virtual Reality</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3173917</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T04:58+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Virtual reality</term>
					<term>design</term>
					<term>lucid dreaming</term>
					<term>introspection</term>
					<term>wellbeing</term>
					<term>positive technologies H.5.m. Information interfaces and presentation (e.g.</term>
					<term>HCI): Miscellaneous</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Virtual reality (VR) is resurging in popularity with the advancement of low-cost hardware and more realistic graphics. How might this technology help others? That is, to increase mental well-being? The ultimate VR might look like lucid dreaming, the phenomenon of knowing one is dreaming while in the dream. Lucid dreaming can be used as an introspective tool and, ultimately, increase mental well-being. What these introspective experiences are like for lucid dreamers might be key in determining specific design guidelines for future creation of a technological tool used for helping people examine their own thoughts and emotions. This study describes nine active and proficient lucid dreamers' representations of their introspective experiences gained through phenomenological interviews. Four major themes emerged: sensations and feelings, actions and practices, influences on experience, and meaning making. This knowledge can help design a VR system that is grounded in genuine experience and preserving the human condition.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>Technology is becoming more and more ingrained in our every day lives, yet it is only recently that HCI researchers, technologists and designers have paused to think about how these technologies could be used to better our lives and increase our well-being <ref type="bibr">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">23,</ref><ref type="bibr">53,</ref><ref type="bibr">61]</ref>. While many mobile applications designed for this purpose exist <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[43]</ref>, one area that is still largely unexplored is virtual reality (VR). VR offers a low-cost and high quality simulation of environments and situations, which could be a powerful way to generate positive change in a non-threatening way because users can explore and play out situations they normally would not be able to do in real life. VR is unique in that it can completely immerse its users, that is provide the psychological experience of being completely absorbed in a physical or mental activity such that one loses sense of time and the outside world <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[32]</ref>. Immersion has been shown to increase presence, the physical feeling of being in the simulated environment, which in turn enhances the effectiveness of the experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">14,</ref><ref type="bibr">51]</ref>. However, the question remains how to design for an effective VR experience that can elicit positive mental well-being? There exists a real life phenomenon that takes people into a simulated world that feels completely real and might generate a sense of positive well-being: lucid dreaming. Lucid dreaming is defined as knowing one is dreaming while in the dream <ref type="bibr">[39]</ref>. Once lucid, lucid dreamers have the ability to explore, shape, or create the environment as they see fit. Lucid dreaming, it seems, is the ultimate virtual reality in this respect because the lucid dreaming experience is only limited to one's imagination. As far as these authors could find, there does not appear to be any literature that focuses on lucid dreaming experiences specifically to inform the design of virtual reality experiences.</p><p>We conducted a phenomenological study of nine active and proficient lucid dreamers. We interviewed the lucid dreamers about their experiences of lucid dreaming particularly focusing on lucid dreams involving introspection in order to answer the following research questions:</p><p>Main question: What are people's experiences of introspection in lucid dreaming? Sub-questions:</p><p>1. What images, sounds, and other sensory stimuli are present during moments of introspection in lucid dreaming?</p><p>2. What are their relationships to the "feeling tone" and intensity of the emotional stimuli?</p><p>3. How might these experiences inform the design of an immersive virtual reality introspective experience? experience involving introspection: sensations and feelings, actions and practices, influences on experience, and meaning making.</p><p>There are two main contributions of this work:</p><p>1. Design considerations for introspective virtual reality experiences; 2. Interviews with proficient lucid dreamers that ground technological systems in a human experience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RELATED WORK</head><p>The work presented in this paper intersects multiple fields: it builds on positive technologies, focusing on virtual reality, and incorporates the real-life phenomenon of lucid dreaming in the context of introspective practices. These fields are briefly presented below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Positive Technologies</head><p>There has been a recent importance put upon deigning for increased mental health and well-being in the HCI community <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[23]</ref>, with new research areas evolving such as Positive Technology <ref type="bibr">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr">50]</ref> and Positive Computing <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref>. Currently, there exists several overlapping well-being tech movements among designs and technologists, which Mossbridge <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[43]</ref> has summarized in a review of Transcendence Technology. One focus of this research is on user experience (UX) and recognizing the importance of considering the human condition when designing for technologies <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[23]</ref>. That is, how can we design technologies that actively support well-being and human potential?</p><p>In this study, we seek to ground design recommendations in real human experience through phenomenological interviewing of a very personal "virtual" world of lucid dreams.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Virtual Reality</head><p>Virtual reality is defined as the "model of reality with which a human can interact, getting information from the model by ordinary human sense such as sight, sound, and touch and/or controlling the model using ordinary human actions such as position and/or motion of body parts or voice" <ref type="bibr">[27:31]</ref>. It has existed for decades, though it is only recently that the latest generation of head-mounted displays (HMDs) have become more affordable and accessible to the general public. Moreover, VR has the unique capacity to completely immerse its users in any environment, a component closely linked to presence or the feeling of being in the virtual space. Presence has been deemed central to a VR experience, often used as a "gold standard" or having validity. Some researchers have argued that presence is an important goal in transferring VR application data to the "real world" <ref type="bibr">[42]</ref>. VR could act as a medium through which people can increase their mental well-being if there exist high levels of presence <ref type="bibr">[20]</ref>.</p><p>Already, VR has been used for therapeutic purposes, such as PTSD treatment <ref type="bibr">[54]</ref>, anxiety treatment <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[46,</ref><ref type="bibr">47]</ref>, and pain management <ref type="bibr">[25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">60,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">66]</ref>. Moreover, VR has been used in a variety of stress-reduction and meditation or mindfulness-like applications <ref type="bibr">[52,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">56,</ref><ref type="bibr">62]</ref>. It is clear that there is potential for VR to support well-being. However, the way in which designers and technologists create these experiences while keeping the human condition intact remains an open question.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Lucid Dreaming</head><p>Lucid dreaming, "dreaming while knowing one is dreaming" <ref type="bibr">[37]</ref>, is one phenomenon that we can draw parallels to a VR experience. It is a genuine human experience that places a person in a "virtual" reality, i.e., their dream, which feels just as real as their waking reality. At the same time, lucid dreamers are aware that they are in a dream and that nothing in the dream has real-life consequences, much like that of a VR experience. Some researchers have dismissed the validity of lucid dreams, stating there was no evidence lucid dreams were distinct from rapid-eye movement (REM) sleep <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[41]</ref>. However, several behavioural studies have since provided evidence that lucid dreams were possible <ref type="bibr">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">38,</ref><ref type="bibr">39]</ref>. More recently, technological advances have allowed researchers to record lucid dreaming with EEG, EMG, EOG, and fMRI <ref type="bibr">[17]</ref>.</p><p>Psychophysical studies <ref type="bibr">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr">42]</ref> support the view that what people experience during REM sleep and lucid dreaming is the same as if actually experiencing it during waking life. This means that lucid dreaming could be used as a therapeutic tool because one can essentially do anything within the limits of their imagination, and that experience will have similar effects as if one experienced it in waking life. The parallels of lucid dreaming and VR are uncanny; by learning what enables lucid dreamers to have such powerful introspective experiences, we might also learn some valuable guidelines for recreating similar experiences in VR.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Introspection</head><p>One way lucid dreaming, and thus VR, could be used as a therapeutic tool is for introspection -the examination or observation of one's own mental and emotional processes <ref type="bibr">[5]</ref>. Introspection can provide privileged access to our own mental states -including sensory, bodily, cognitive, and emotional -that are not mediated by other sources of knowledge, so that one's experience of the mind is unique; and this can be beneficial in a clinical and general sense <ref type="bibr">[34]</ref>. Moreover, introspection can increase the quality and quantity of information people have about themselves and break down the barrier of the ego that affects how people process information about themselves <ref type="bibr">[9]</ref>.</p><p>Many dreamers report that they use lucid dreaming for introspection, such as dealing with psychological issues or spiritual growth <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[55]</ref>. And, researchers have suggested that applications of lucid dreaming could include nightmare reduction, treating depression, and rehabilitation <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">[59]</ref>. However, learning the techniques of lucid dreaming takes time and discipline, and one may not even experience a lucid dream until a month into keeping a dream journal, setting an intention each night to lucid dream, and doing reality checks -such as checking how many fingers you have sporadically throughout the day <ref type="bibr">[36]</ref>. Additionally, many people still feel skepticism towards lucid dreaming because of dream report inaccuracy <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[41]</ref> and its ties to spirituality.</p><p>One could potentially induce lucid dreaming through frontal low current stimulation of gamma activity. A research group stimulated a certain area of the brain with transcranial alternating current and it was effective ~70% of the time in giving naïve participants lucid dreams [63] However, the mere induction of lucid dreams ignores the many benefits that surround the practice of lucid dreams and the ultimate goal of being present or aware of your surroundings and ego in waking life <ref type="bibr">[36]</ref>. Approachable ways to introduce the concepts of introspection are important in generating true and genuine experiences with technology so that we can keep the human condition and experience intact.</p><p>We propose investigating the experiences of introspection in lucid dreaming so that we can inform the design of an immersive technological system (VR) that can be used as a tool for introspection in order to help people explore or understand their internal states, ultimately creating a more positive sense of mental well-being.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>STUDY METHODOLOGY</head><p>The goal of this phenomenological study was to describe the essence of what it is like to introspect in lucid dreams. The experiences gleaned from describing what it is like to introspect in lucid dreams and its context could be useful for designing a similar experience in the format of an immersive technological system in virtual reality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>We interviewed nine participants who are currently active and proficient lucid dreamers. LaBerge [37] recommends the following when selecting lucid dreamers as participants:</p><p>(1) verify that informants understand the concept of lucid dreaming by requiring the inclusion of a recognition phrase in a sample lucid dream report and</p><p>(2) use highly trained participants who are skilful and accurate observers of their conscious experiences.</p><p>In an entrance survey, we determined that the average time participants have been actively lucid dreaming is 20 years, and the average frequency of lucid dreams is 1 per week. Participants (6F, 3M) were the age of majority where the research was conducted, with an average age of 35 years <ref type="bibr">(19-57 years range)</ref>. We posted online advertisements on social media groups (e.g., Facebook and Twitter) and lucid dreaming forums. Participants for this study were naïve to this study and did not have prior relationships to us in order to decrease any potential power imbalances and increase the validity of their reports.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Research Site</head><p>The interview took place in a quiet and undisturbed place, where there were little distractions and the participant could focus on the interview. The interview was in a neutral location as to not create an imbalance of power between the researcher and the participant. If possible, the interview was conducted at a place where the participant was comfortable and relaxed, in order to create an environment that allowed them to open up about their experience. Some interviews were conducted over online video conferencing for the participant's convenience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Collection</head><p>From a quantitative perspective, researchers are concerned with discovering facts about the phenomenon and assume a fixed and measurable reality. However, the nature of dreams, especially the content of dreams, is dynamic and a negotiated reality; this is much better suited to qualitative methods, which are more concerned with understanding human behaviour from the informant's perspective and does not assume a fixed reality <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">44]</ref>. It is very difficult to conduct research relating to dream content for a variety of reasons, most notably is that we cannot watch dreams while they are happening and the dreamer cannot report them while the dreams are happening. Therefore, there is no way to have objective evidence concerning the content of the dreams. Some quantitative researchers have used neuroimaging techniques, such as EEG and fMRI, to study which areas of the brain are active during dreams <ref type="bibr">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">29,</ref><ref type="bibr">64</ref>]. However, one could argue that this is fundamentally different than collecting data on what the dreamer actually perceives. Most dream researchers believe the best way to study dreams is through content analysis of dream reports, which can be from sleep laboratories, psychotherapy relationships, personal dream journal, and anonymous reports <ref type="bibr">[15]</ref>. In order to gain a rich understanding of the phenomenon, this research needs to emphasize the context in which introspection in lucid dreaming occurred and the meanings of these lucid dreams for participants.</p><p>Using qualitative methods to study lucid dreams and their experiences with introspection, we intended to discover from the participants what kinds of sensations, feelings, and experiences they had during introspective lucid dreams, as well as the setting and conditions that lead to their experiences. Fallman argues for a philosophy of technology in HCI, building on Ihde's phenomenology of relations between humans, artifacts and the world, and Borgmann's suggestion to rethink the relationship and correspondence between "useful" and "good" technology <ref type="bibr">[18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">19]</ref>. In this same line of argument, we sought to give a new lens in which to provide guidance concerning how to incorporate specific values, namely introspection, in designing VR experiences. Phenomenology in particular has direct relevance to design <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[24]</ref>; several researchers have shown how phenomenology has been and can be used both as a theoretical stance and as a research approach <ref type="bibr">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">16,</ref><ref type="bibr">31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">65]</ref>.</p><p>We used semi-structured interviews that lasted 25 minutes to one hour in order to discover what participants have experienced in terms of introspection in lucid dreaming and what contexts or situations have typically influenced or affected these experiences. This phenomenological interview consisted of three main domains: contextualization (natural attitude and life world), apprehending the phenomenon (modes of appearing, natural attitude), and clarifying the phenomenon (imaginative variation and meaning) <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref>.</p><p>Interviews were audio recorded using the "Voice Recorder" app on a Samsung Galaxy S6 smartphone or Quicktime built-in audio recorder in order to be as unobtrusive as possible. It is important that the tone and feeling of the participants' experiences also be taken into account when analyzing the data due to the very personal nature of the phenomenon. We wrote a reflection and debrief after each interview in order to capture any behaviours, tone, feeling, or impressions from the interview. Video recording could also serve the same purpose, though it is unclear if a visual component will add anything to the data and, given the personal nature of the study, a camera can feel more intrusive. Audio recordings of the interview and interview's notes were imported into NVivo 11 for Mac, a qualitative data analysis software, and transcribed to text.</p><p>All interviews were kept anonymous. Contact information was stored on the university's server. The university's Institutional Review Board approved this study, and the participants signed informed consent forms. A demographic questionnaire was administered online using Fluidsurveys and was completed before the interview.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis Methods</head><p>The method of analysing phenomenological data mentioned in Creswell's Qualitative Inquiry and Research Design book <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[11]</ref> was used for this study, which is essentially a synthesis of <ref type="bibr">Moustakas' and Giorgi's "psychological phenomenology" [26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">44]</ref>. Here, we identified the main categories or meaning units and composed a textural description to capture what the experience of introspecting while lucid dreaming is like for participants, a structural description of the phenomenon, and a description capturing the essence of the phenomenon. Finally, we used these descriptions to inform design recommendations for introspective experiences in virtual reality. Quotes are followed by P#, where # denotes the participant's ID.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RESULTS</head><p>From nine verbatim transcripts, four main categories or themes emerged across participants: sensations and feelings, actions and practices, influences on experience, and meaning making. Next, we will discuss our findings for each of these four main themes where we will highlight key insights.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Sensations and Feelings</head><p>Experiences of bodily sensations were prevalent in lucid dreams relating to introspection. These senses mapped closely to what participants had experienced in waking life, such as touch, smell, taste, sound, vision, and sense of space. There was a sense of clarity and heightened awareness of the environment when participants became lucid in their dreams. Lucid dreams were described as visually vivid, intense, bright, and graphic. One participant even likened their dreams as better than Avatar, a film renowned for its cutting edge visual effects and psychedelic qualities: "It's better than Avatar… the thing I love about it the most is that it's just I get to see the environment that I love. So, really rich, thick kelp forests with sea dragons and cuttle fish and octopus, fishing, glowing neon lights." -P8 Visuals seemed to be the primary sense in which participants experienced their lucid dreams, and even without any other sense present they still felt like they were immersed in the dream. In terms of other senses, lucid dreamers could smell, taste, and touch as if their dreams were real. There was a sense of complete immersion in the dream and at the same time lucid dreamers knew it was not actually real. In fact, even though there were many inconsistencies in the lucid dream, such as flying without wind, sound without a source or hands with too many fingers, this did not deter participants from accepting those inconsistencies and still having the feeling of presence as if in the real world. There too were senses that could not be explained in terms of our everyday experiences, or rather our language could not account for such an experience that is outside the realm of anything we have experienced before: Though some sensations cannot be described, the sensation around transitioning into the lucid dream straight from a waking state was described in detail by P9. They were able to witness and remember the transition into sleep with all the bodily sensations that come with that experience. Here they describe imagining being on a boat in the sea and remaining conscious of their bodily state while at the same time transitioning into this other world: "In those 20-30 seconds… I could actually I started to hear the waves crashing on the boat and it just became more and more clear and I could sort of feel the boat moving in the sea and I could start to see all the mountains appear, but it was weird because I also felt my body on the couch, so it was like I was between two worlds. And slowly, as time passed… I could feel the vibrations, I sort of feel myself on the couch but it was just drifting away and my awareness started shifting into the boat and before I knew it, in maybe a minute or two, I was in the sea. Like it was clear as day. It was like the real world but I was actually just sitting on my couch." -P9</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">"</formula><p>The feeling of realness and presence existed even with knowing they were still actually on their couch. Visuals and vibrations were not immediately thrown at this participant, but rather there was a build up and an easing into the dream space. This way of transitioning was so powerful for the participant that they felt in awe of the experience once they were in the lucid dream. Their imagination had come to life before their eyes.</p><p>In terms of emotions and affective states, many participants reported positive feelings of bliss, happiness, freedom, peace, lightness, and childlike-wonder and playfulness. This is particularly prevalent in lucid dreaming experiences of flying. In fact, almost all participants reported that they often flew in their lucid dreams because it was a fun experience, something they could not do in real life, and provided a means of letting go of any frustrations or worries:</p><p>"I also have these feelings of intense happiness and bliss and peacefulness and also exhilaration. I love flying and I love being out of control in my environment." -P8 Flying brought about feelings of both peace and excitement, perhaps from the flowing feeling from physically gliding through the air paired with the exhilaration of a superhuman like experience. These lucid dreamers liked to push the boundaries of what is possible and, in doing so, could experience something otherworldly; that experience was so powerful that it could have a positive influence on lucid dreamer's affective state. Another feeling lucid dreamers seem to experience often was a sense of control over everything, omnipotence, empowerment, and limitlessness. Participants reported that they could move objects with their mind and that feeling of control gave them a sense of power: "I just wake up going like I'm omnipotent! I love the telekinesis because it just feels so effortless as well." -P7</p><p>Because lucid dreamers could control and manipulate the dream environment with their will, they could create or mould the experience to their liking, which was very empowering. The experiences that lucid dreamers tended toward were often magical or living out a fantasy, whatever that may be. For one participant, this meant going to a grocery store and gorging on their favourite foods or foods they would normally restrict in real life:</p><p>"I can eat whatever I want. I went to the freezer section because I wanted a freezer cake, not like a regular cake but a whole thing of freezer cake. And then, someone had bought a calzone but then didn't want to eat it so it was like in front of me. So, I ate a whole calzone. I ate mac and cheese. There's always mac and cheese at Whole Foods. When I was eating a bunch of stuff and I woke up and I was like that was so exciting, like that's something I wish I could do; everything's free in Whole Foods and the carbs don't affect my blood sugar and whatever. So, I had a field day." -P2</p><p>From this account we can see that lucid dreams were a way for them to experience something they would not normally be able to in real life, which may sometimes be due to physical restrictions. Moreover, any experience in a lucid dream does not have real world physical consequences, such as caloric intake, falling from a great height, or swimming with whales. Lucid dreams provide a safe and private space for people to explore different sensations and feelings without fear of judgment, and this allows them to really let go and find a sense of peace and state of nonsuffering.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Actions and Practices</head><p>Participants reported acting within their lucid dreams by exploring, creating, playing, problem solving, and interacting with dream objects and characters. Exploring often involved nature, such as rocketing into outer space or swimming with dolphins:</p><p>"I think for me especially the ocean it speaks volumes to me for reasons I've spent a lot of time in and around the ocean and exploring it as a child. And I love it. I mean, to start off, I'm an ecologist, so I love the environment. I love nature and I explore the terrestrial environment all the time, but the ocean is one that I can't really get to in my waking life." -P8 Lucid dreamers could manipulate the dream space so that they could explore facets of the world unknown or unreachable to them. But it was not only physical spaces that lucid dreams could explore; they could also explore the nature of their own minds. One participant, P9, recounted a lucid dream in which they attempted to push the limits of what was possible in a lucid dream by counting down from ten in order to "go deeper" in the lucid dream. What they found was a dream scene of greater perceived "realness". The "realness" of the dream within a dream seemed to truly stay with this participant because, as they explained, it felt like a deeper level of being. Going even deeper, this participant found themselves in a dream scene of blood, gore, and violence, which they interpreted as going deeper into sub consciousness to the more primitive parts of human nature. It appears that exploring both physical and conceptual spaces is a large part of the experience of lucid dreaming for these participants. Some participants would also create in a lucid dream. For example, one participant described walking through a gallery in their lucid dream and seeing all these beautiful paintings they could not have possibly created themselves, but in actuality it was their own mind that created them: "I can't paint. I can't paint whatever, hopeless. But, there was a period of time when in my dreams when I said, you know, I want to go into a gallery and I want to see paintings in that gallery. I want them to be abstract. I want them to be beautiful… So, I wander through this gallery and I see all these paintings. I'm sure if I could have painted them, I'd be probably one of the most successful painters on the planet, but they're absolutely incredible. My mind has put them together for me; they didn't exist until I saw in the gallery and asked for them to be there when I went and saw it." -P1</p><p>It is incredible what the mind is capable of when we test its limits and are in a space where we believe anything is possible, such as in a lucid dream. One could be the next Picasso or Cezanne if they were given the space to explore and create without the limitations impositions commonly placed on them in real life. There was a magical quality to being in the lucid dream space, where the lucid was aware that it is all a dream and at the same still received psychological benefits as if having actually done or experienced those things in the dream.</p><p>lucid dream also provided the space for problem solving or taking action in the dream to change it into a more positive experience. For a few participants, it was common have nightmares. But rather than become frightened, they became lucid and realized they could take control of situation to either escape or make it into a scene. There was a confrontation with the dream space itself, and a conscious decision to change their own mind into a more positive state: think it was a couple years ago it was a zombie dream. I was watching a lot of Walking Dead, so it started off as a nightmare and then it became kind of fun.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>I realized that I could hover above it and I wasn't in danger and I could kind of watch it as if it was happening -like sometimes the dreams turn into kind of like I'm watching a movie or something. It's entertaining and I don't want to wake up." -P4</head><p>What participants do or how they interact in their lucid dreams showed that they had some agency and sense of control that was both empowering and fun. Lucid dreams were a playful space to explore and experiment within the confines of one's own mind. And, it was not only the of the lucid dream that to be important, but also the practices surrounding lucid dreams. all of the participants reported some sort of practice in attempting to increase their lucidity. This included more and scientific approaches such as reality continuously questioning the nature of reality in real life in that when you were in the dream space you would do same and realize you were dreaming, taking keeping a dream journal, and tracking bodily Reality checks were important to establishing lucidity for participants because it was one way of being certain they were dreaming, e.g., plugging your nose and attempting breathe (P2). were more spiritual and approaches as well, including lighting incense, oneself to the experience and letting go of the ego meditation or yoga, and focusing on the breath mindfulness practices. Many of these practices, by participants, been demonstrated to help lucidity in the literature Whichever of helping to induce lucid it is clear that was some preparation or ceremony surrounding the One participant spoke to the importance of going into a lucid dream:</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>think ceremony is probably most specific because it [lucid dreaming] doesn't mean anything if you're not using it for a certain reason, right? So… getting into the state of ceremony because I think ceremony teaches us</head><p>and that's I guess probably even with technology, like even just turning on, having to make your bed or something like that, having time to lay down, having cushions, be comfortable, all sorts of ceremony, right? So, those states of taking the time to do this, to get so that we are ready and we can get into the state. <ref type="bibr">[Ceremony]</ref> just tells your mind, like I'm getting into the state now, something different, it's not the pay attention and allow our spirit to show up."</p><p>Setting an intension and focusing attention seem have a profound impact on the level of lucidity, and ultimately the of the lucid dreaming experience. It is rare that a lucid dream will occur at all if one is not creating a habit or around it, much less the fanciful awe-inspiring ones by the most dedicated and experienced lucid on Experience Focused Attention</p><p>Lucid dreaming and the practices surrounding it have with other introspective and often participants would be using these other introspective methods in tandem with lucid dreaming. A common reported amongst participants was meditation:</p><p>meditations that are like a body scan or deep type of thing, that's like you know, relax your head, relax your shoulders, doing that type of thing… tried one… Bilateral stimulation. So, that's what this is called, it's like a ticking or beat that alternates between your ears and its supposed tone, it's used as a treatment for people with, who have experienced trauma, like helps people through or heal trauma or something… I felt more aware of dream and I don't if it's linked to that or because I thought it would them or something. I don't know if it did. But, I remember specifically, the morning dream that I after listening to that meditation, I felt more aware of it." -P5 aware of the present moment and focusing on the is the most commonly reported type of meditation amongst these lucid dreamers. practice of lucid dreaming was about aware of reality what was real what was not in order to gain and control what was happening in the dream space. So, these two practices compliment each other: both attempting achieve greater awareness of what was in the environment and the self. One participant even mentioned a called Dream Yoga -an extension of lucid dreaming only more of a spiritual practice, founded in Buddhism, where one studies the mind using the medium of dreams <ref type="bibr">[30]</ref>. Lucid dreaming, on the other hand, does not have as many spiritually oriented methods and, might appeal to a wider audience. One type of meditation P5 mentioned is bilateral stimulation, which could involve tones that alternate between left and right of the head, and reported to decrease and increase attentional flexibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[13]</ref>. Decreased and increased attention could be linked to this participant's lucidity in dreams, they profess to not be sure if this was a placebo effect or not.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Negotiating with Reality</head><p>experiences that seemed to be linked to participants' lucid dreams, but were distinct experiences, were the following: out of body experiences (OBEs), astral projections, and false awakenings. OBEs are as perceiving the self outside one's body, often from a distance and are Astral projections are like OBEs, except they are voluntary. Finally, false awakenings are vivid and convincing dreams that feel as if one has yet the dreamer is unaware they are still dreaming. This is in contrast to lucid dreaming where dreamers are they are dreaming while in the dream. All of these experiences seemed be either extensions or side effects lucid dreaming practices. is, when one plays with and consciousness in lucid dreaming practices, sometimes the mind can turn that around and give the of one's body or that one is awake when still dreaming. Furthermore, when one is an experienced lucid dreamer, they can push the boundaries of the dream and do things like go out of their own (dream) body: </p><formula xml:id="formula_1">"</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Setting an Intention</head><p>In addition to these related practices to lucid dreaming, these participants would often use psychology treatments or conditions to enhance or sense of their lucid dreams. already mentioned by P9, was to count from ten, similar to hypnosis -a state of where a person is more suggestible. P2 explicitly said they used hypnosis as a way to your thoughts, to make yourself think how you want to think in order to increase your confidence or feel better". These of introspection, like hypnosis, seemed to help lucid dreaming because of ability to be in a more suggestible space and suspend disbelief in order to or accomplish the Cognitive therapy (CBT) was another treatment mentioned by a participant that complemented lucid dreaming in its ability to look at a situation or thought logically:</p><p>was like the breaking down of the in CBT and looking at things more logically, [that] kind of felt like how I dealt with my dreams. You know, when not lucid everything is an illusion and you're not reality until you think about it logically. You realize… everything is figment of my imagination." P2</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Gaining Control</head><p>They were able to use the techniques from CBT to bring about a sense of clarity and heightened awareness in their lucid dreams, and in doing so had a much richer and meaningful experience. In terms of psychological conditions, one participant likened lucid dreaming to a mental condition characterized by losing with external reality: in this state where you can't, like with psychosis, see reality and you can't snap out of it. But then that rational part of your mind can be reasoned with a bit. So, I've tried to be like <ref type="bibr">[this]</ref>, you know when dreaming and you can suddenly realize you can it." -P4</p><p>P4 was describing the struggle of becoming lucid a dream, where they fighting their own mind to take of the dream space. They equated this struggle to psychosis because their sibling experiences psychosis sometimes and perhaps it was way for them to relate to understand condition, but also a way to what lucid dreaming was like namely, it partly a negotiation for control and knowing was real. of these experiences were separate from lucid dreaming, but were nonetheless both related to and had an on lucid dreams. understanding these influences, we can begin to determine what enhances the experience, what are the prerequisites, and what are its limitations. From the accounts of these nine participants, it like focused attention and self-awareness help to enhance lucid dreams. Setting an intention, negotiating with reality, and gaining control appear to be aspects of dreaming. Finally, lucid dreaming be used to experience your wildest fantasies, it can be used to rehearse situations, or solve problems. it is limited in its ability to go deep and connect with the most inner aspects of being; for that you have meditation, dream or astral projecting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Meaning Making</head><p>Though lucid dreams cannot reach the deepest and most secret parts of being, can still bring about and meaning. It was the case for all that they experienced some sort of experience, shift or change in perception, to self or others, or from lucid dreaming. Lucid dreaming for some participants be a way gain access to sub consciousness because their waking body was asleep. described interacting with dream characters where they would ask these dream characters who they were and what they represented to them in the dream. Often, there would be no answer or the character would represent an internal conflict or aspect of the self. Other participants reported interactions dream as well. P2 told a story about a lucid dream where they confronted a dream character about why they felt and a response that they was a reflection on their own state of and the act of acknowledging those feelings actually them to feel better:</p><p>"I asked her what she bad about, and she said inferiority. I said what would make you feel inferior? She said people. I asked her if she didn't feel when she was alone? She kind of fell over sad didn't answer. The whole thing made me sad especially because why would this person who's a movie star feel bad or inferior to other people? I felt like crying a few times. So, I guess [this was] someone who I think is really great but at the same time they feel And… I think it's like the part of me that feels it struggles between feeling really good and feeling bad about myself." -P2</p><p>These dream characters did not only have to be human P8 talked about communicating and making friends with animals in their lucid dream. Speaking with these was a way this participant to connect on a deeper level, if speaking to best friend"; in doing so might create a sense of positive well-being. Another participant, P6, also experienced animals as characters. However, in this case, it was not so much about able to in a different way as in the previous example, but more an allegory for their mother's passing: "My mom was sick so I had her dog for a And I had lucid dreams that beautiful lady was kissing it would mean that my dog would have to go pee. I this lady that I encountered that was very beautiful she was wrapped in chains and she was saying let go [P6], let me go... And I watched her cross the street, she got hit by a car, her guts were like all around her… it took me a little while <ref type="bibr">[to know what]</ref> that vision was about here because I forgot that I her [the mother] as that lady who I had been seeing, not the dog. I feel like she was telling me to let her go, but I think I held on a little bit longer."</p><p>Interacting with dream characters was one apparent and way of seeking meaning in a lucid dream. Another was for one to use lucid dreaming as training grounds in order to build in the real world. This could the form of confronting a fear or escaping a nightmare. P4 and P7 both had lucid dreams with zombies, but were able to apprehend the scary situation by recognizing it as a and laughing at it or flying away. P7 would use lucid dreams as a way to practice sports like snowboarding and out different moves to gain confidence to do them in the world. This practice because the lucid dreaming space felt so real, so it felt like they were there doing it. way to gain confidence was to do in the lucid that one would not think was or that one had never done before; through experience, one could and grow, carrying that of accomplishment over to the world:</p><p>was sitting on this concrete thing in my kayak [attempting to get] over into the far pond and I had to jump. And I was like I don't know if I can do this. But then I just gave myself confidence and just kind of with it and I managed to do this strange kind of jump. And it was such a moment that sat with me for like the whole next day… because I was like it's just that confidence, confidence to do it, you know, and actually that feeling."</p><p>though the dream space was not happening in reality, the participant was aware of this fact in the dream, the still had an effect on their confidence long after waking. And, for a few of the participants in this study, it a very powerful and overwhelmingly positive effect. They had the ability to take the dream for what it was, even all its inconsistencies and bizarreness, and make what they could from it. though, diving into the depths of one's mind fairly surprising and frightening aspects. A few participants to go into the deeper parts of their mind. P1 described a dream space they called "the field", which was an electrical field of that sent dreadful, terrible sensations down their spine. P2 was in a lucid dream and to meditate, which to them meant rid of the entire external environment and focusing on themselves. However, this to be very intense experience it felt too black, too isolating, and too quiet. To be alone with the self is not really something most of us experience, so when P2 encountered that it was too much to handle at the time. P9 also experienced a very intense lucid dream where they wanted to go deeper into their mind, like the within a dream idea by the movie Inception:</p><p>around me was lot of blood and gore and violence… my theory was that because I went a lot deeper into the subconscious it was sort of like I saw more primal parts of human nature and that was all the gore and violence."</p><p>Lucid dreams were a chance for the lucid dreamer to actively search out experiences and draw meaning from These dreams could symbolic or carry meaning depending on if wants to or not. Some of the participants were not interested in finding a meaning or purpose, but would rather have fun or be entertained. Others were very interested in figuring out what the in the represented or find answers to unlocking life's this difference of intent for lucid reflecting that people's own dreams can mean not like a black cat bad luck, but that are very personalized and we can draw meaning them if we wish or choose to say it means nothing at all. The point was that make meaning, they choose to see something in a seemingly random and strange world dreams. And, that is not nonsense; is a real feeling that lucid dreamers take with them into real life.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DISCUSSION</head><p>The accounts of introspection described by lucid consistent with the descriptions of self-healing, and self-awareness in the literature Here, we have four themes that on the essence of what it is like to introspect in lucid dreams: Sensations and in dreams what the lucid dreamer and felt physically during their lucid dreams, as well as what they felt emotionally during their lucid dreams; Actions and Practices where ceremony was important surrounding the practices of lucid dreaming involving exploration, problem solving, discovery, and creation; Influences on Experience explained that many lucid had introspective practices and experiences such as meditation, to nature, and sense of curiosity that has them to gain greater or in lucid dreams; and Meaning Making where lucid had the opportunity to go deep within themselves or analyse the content of their dreams to create their own meaning.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Description</head><p>Lucid dreaming, to the accounts of our is knowing you are a dream while and then having the to take control of that dream and mould it to whatever fantasy, situation, feeling, or space one desires. In doing so, the lucid dreamer themselves from the laws and bounds of waking life, feels "very tranquil, blissful". In terms of introspection in lucid dreams, there is a vividness and clarity that surrounds the experience; the lucid dreamer can do as they please in a safe environment without judgement repercussions imposed in the real world. There is a to one's thoughts and feelings, uncover "secret knowledge" only to that individual. Lucid different and very personal for everyone, and at the same time the essence of the phenomenon is common across each of the participants here. most of interviewed here, it be a connection, a lens, and a way of communicating with the self.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Implications</head><p>There exist studies that have described the of lucid dreaming, but unique to this study is the specific focus on whereas prior studies investigated experiences of lucid dreaming in a broader sense Having participants provide detailed and rich descriptions of their experiences with introspection in lucid dreams data that can be utilized generating design a virtual reality helps with introspection, with the ultimate goal of improving mental</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Results</head><p>and feelings vividness and clarity generated through lucid dreaming practices be to the context of echoing prior work on VR Our findings show that visuals are very important to the experience, especially ones that are vivid, it immerses the user in the environment and ultimately creates the feeling of realness. Other senses such as taste, and smell contribute to the experience, which is in keeping with previous research Yet, if any senses missing or somehow different from those experienced in the real world, then that does not the experience because there is an acknowledgement that this environment is not real and so same affordances and laws may not apply. of this finding might be the strong focus on graphical quality in VR is perhaps not as important as thought <ref type="bibr">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr">49]</ref>. that the environment is real does not seem to be as important to the immersiveness of the experience itself. Moreover, accuracy of the environment does not seem to be necessary for the feeling of realness is sufficient that there be awareness of the present environment. These findings are supported by previous work, that realistic is no longer immersive VR's <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>.</p><p>In terms of what users might like to in VR and how designers the lessons from our lucid dreaming participants to create experiences give a sense of exploration and an open environment there is the feeling of possibility. The experience be fun, playful, and childlike in nature to encourage exploration and wonder. should consider the medium of VR and think about what experiences normally would not be able to do in the real world; this may look like something fantastical such as flying, as suggested by et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">57]</ref>, seeing another part the world people would normally not have access to. reports from lucid dreamers indicate that some people may wish to interact and change things in the environment and others may not. In any case, users feel like they are control these interactions, which generates feelings of and confidence that can carry over into the real world. This benefit of bodily control was also found by and colleagues our results, we found that the transitions and experiences surrounding a VR experience are important in a safe without judgement or in the real world, for its uses to the unfamiliar. finding is supported by Patibanda and colleagues' to "ease-in" users for VR <ref type="bibr">[48,</ref><ref type="bibr">58]</ref>. as our bodies are gently eased into sleep and into a lucid dream as a seamless experience, so too should the transition into out of VR. The user is aware they are sitting on their living room couch their office chair, but they are invited into world they must suspend their disbelief that this is all unreal and then be open to the possibilities that such a world offer. To make this leap as easy as possible, as designers we might about tools of introspection from other domains such psychology, spirituality, and mindfulness. These tools awareness, discipline, considering another perspective, of ego, and letting go of what we think we know is possible. these aspects are incorporated into the of introspective VR experiences, then positive and outcomes like those seen from lucid dreaming might be possible. Therefore, when transitioning into VR, think about the surrounding environment is there a seamless transition? Can the user feel safe enough to let their guard and truly immerse them selves in experience? When transiting out of VR, there is again the to the real world eases the user between worlds and allows space for reflection.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Insights</head><p>Ceremony around an introspective experience in lucid helps to ease the transition into the dream space, so VR designers might also think about what ceremonies or the users are undergoing in order to prepare them for the virtual world. Ceremony seems to bring meaning to the experience because the going into it is more mentally and physically ready and open.</p><p>The space of the virtual environment itself might be quite abstract or feel empty and vast, like some lucid dreamers reported while they meditated in the dream. Nature is a in lucid dreaming and it also has close ties to human connection, so including those aspects can help in creating a sense of peace and awe. Furthermore, an abstract world space for the user to provide their personal meaning interpretation, which is important in exploring one's and feelings or uncovering "secret knowledge" that is personalized to that individual. And, an environment where the user is bodiless can provide the right conditions for letting go of the ego, the outer sense of self and focusing inward. design considerations for introspective VR experiences taken from accounts of lucid dreaming are promising because echo those considerations already forth in the VR literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">43]</ref>. However, these design considerations have presented here have not yet been put into practice. Though VR and lucid dreaming have many commonalities user experience, it may be the case that there are other factors at play that VR cannot account for in introspective experiences. For instance, VR experiences are under complete control of the designer lucid dreams ebb and flow on the spot depending the dreamer's mental state. So, until we have reliable computer interfaces combined with VR, then that is limitation of the technology. Further research is required to test the validity of our design considerations eventually put more robust set of design guidelines for introspective experiences in virtual reality on human experience. It is essential that this technology itself in genuine experience in order to the human condition.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONCLUSION</head><p>Virtual reality could be the platform that allows its users to introspection and a positive impact on wellbeing because of its potential to provide an immersive space that feels real despite its user knowing it not. A completely immersive VR experience draws may parallels a real life "virtual" phenomenon people already namely lucid dreaming. By using qualitative research methods to study introspection in lucid dreaming, we described essence of this phenomenon as well as the context in which it occurs. The descriptions generated to develop design an immersive virtual reality system that will be used as a tool introspection. From preliminary findings, there are four themes: Sensations and Feelings, Actions and Practices, Influences on Experience, and Meaning Making. it seems like lucid dreaming can be used as an effective tool introspection and be helpful as a new lens which to look through in designing for introspective virtual reality</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>…you don't use your senses in your dreams. You have an impression of what the senses are like. Like a really distorted thing is vision; you can get into it, you can get lucid and you look out and you see something… so that the sense are, uh, I suppose the only way we know the world now. So, in a lot of dream states are the only way you can reference it. You want to see this and touch that and taste that and feel it." -P1</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS</head><p>to the lucid dreamer their time.</p><p>Mark T. Bevan. 2014. A method of phenomenological health research 24, 1: 136-144.</p><p>Botella, Rosa Maria Banos, and Veronica</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Positive Technologies for Improving Health and Well-Being</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Positive Psychology in Practice, Carmel Proctor</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="219" to="234" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-51787-2_13</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reality: How Much Immersion Is Enough?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bowman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Mcmahan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="43" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s real about virtual reality?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Brooks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/38.799723</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1109/38.799723" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Graphics and Applications</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">16</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Byrne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Introspection. Philosophical Topics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="79" to="104" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Balance ninja: towards the design of digital vertigo games via vestibular stimulation. 159-170</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Byrne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Mueller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://researchbank.rmit.edu.au/view/rmit" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-11-19">2016. November 19. 2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">38669</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Positive Computing: Technology for Wellbeing and Potential</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">Calvo</forename><surname>Rafael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction Positive Computing: Technology That Fosters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rafael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Calvo Dorian</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors Systems (CHI EA &apos;15)</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors Systems (CHI EA &apos;15)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2499" to="2500" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Overcoming the Barriers to Self-Knowledge: Mindfulness as a Path to Seeing Yourself You Really Are</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="173" to="186" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1745691612462584</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1745691612462584" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A phenomenological approach to with technology: current state, promise, and directions for research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sebnem</forename><surname>Cilesiz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Technology and Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="487" to="510" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s11423-010-9173-2</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Qualitative and Research Design: Choosing Among Five Approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Creswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<publisher>SAGE Publications</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Immersive Is Enough? A Meta-Analysis of the Effect of</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeremy</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Cummings</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Immersive on User Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="272" to="309" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bilateral Stimulation of the Amygdala Treats the Component of Posttraumatic Stress Disorder Upregulation of the Neuropeptide Y System</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Naomi</forename><surname>Dengler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Viktor</forename><surname>Sayre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Bartanusz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">Mark</forename><surname>Jimenez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Papanastassiou</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Neurosurgery</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="207" to="207" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of perception and presence on emotional a review of research in virtual reality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Georg</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Alpers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Peperkorn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Youssef</forename><surname>Shiban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Mühlberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">26</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Methods and measures for study of dream content. and practices of medicine</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">William</forename><surname>Domhoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="463" to="471" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Where the action is: the of embodied interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Paul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, Mass</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Neural Correlates of Dream Lucidity from Contrasting Lucid versus Non-Lucid REM Sleep: A Combined EEG/fMRI Case Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Dresler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Renate</forename><surname>Wehrle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victor</forename><forename type="middle">I</forename><surname>Spoormaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Holsboer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Axel</forename><surname>Steiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hellmuth</forename><surname>Obrig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Philipp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Sämann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Czisch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5665/sleep.1974</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5665/sleep.1974" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Persuade Into What? Why Human-Computer Interaction Needs a Philosophy of In Persuasive Technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fallman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s">Lecture Notes Computer Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="306" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-540-77006-0_35</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The New Good: Exploring the Potential of Philosophy of Technology to Contribute to Human-computer Interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fallman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing (CHI &apos;11</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing (CHI &apos;11</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1051" to="1060" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Virtual reality in the assessment, understanding, and treatment of health disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Reeve</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ehlers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Spanlang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gackenbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Laberge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sleeping Brain: Perspectives on Lucid Dreaming</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mind</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer Science &amp; Business Media</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sleeping Brain: Perspectives on Lucid Dreaming</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Gackenbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Laberge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conscious Mind</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Positive Technology, and Design: Shaping a Future in Which Technology Promotes Psychological Well-Being</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Gaggioli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Riva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dorian</forename><surname>Peters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rafael</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Calvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Emotions and Affect in Human Factors and Human-Computer Interaction</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Elsevier</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="477" to="502" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-0-12-801851-4.00018-5</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shaun</forename><surname>Gallagher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Phenomenology. Encyclopedia of Human-Computer Interaction</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Paint with Me: Stimulating Creativity and Empathy While Painting with a Painter in Virtual</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gerry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Graphics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1418" to="1426" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Phenomenology and research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amedeo</forename><surname>Giorgi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985">1985</date>
			<pubPlace>Duquesne</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">of Virtual Environments: Design, Implementation, and</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kelly</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Hale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kay</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Stanney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lucid dreams : an elecrophysiological and psychological study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">M T</forename><surname>Hearne</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Liverpool Retrieved</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978-12-12">1978. December 12. 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dream Drugstore: Chemically Altered States of Consciousness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Allan</forename><surname>Hobson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Yoga: Illuminating Your Life Through Lucid Dreaming and the Tibetan Yogas of Sleep</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Holecek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Sounds True</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Technics and Praxis: A Philosophy of</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ihde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<publisher>Springer Science &amp; Business Media</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring and Defining Experience of Immersion in Games</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charlene</forename><surname>Jennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Cairns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samira</forename><surname>Dhoparee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Epps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Tijs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alison</forename><surname>Walton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ijhcs.2008.04.004</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2008.04.004" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Hum.-Comput. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="661" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The VR Book: Human-Centered for Virtual Reality. for Computing Machinery and Morgan &amp; Claypool</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Jerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://search.proquest.com/openview/78d62f13ea0ccc8" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Psycho-Analysis</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">395</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1982-12-12">2016. 1982. December 12</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Introspection, empathy and the semiof mental health</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lucid dreaming: Evidence and and</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Laberge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/S0140525X00574020</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/S0140525X00574020" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brain Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lucid Dreaming: A Concise Guide to Awakening in Your Dreams and in Your Life</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Laberge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>ReadHowYouWant.com</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lucid dreaming: Paradoxes of consciousness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Laberge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Varieties of anomalous experience: Examining the scientific evidence</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Carde</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lynn</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><surname>Krippner</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2nd ed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">dreaming: Physiological correlates of consciousness during REM sleep</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Laberge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lynne</forename><surname>Levitan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Dement</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Mind Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2-3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="251" to="258" />
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lucid Psychophysiological studies of during REM sleep</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Laberge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">D P</forename><surname>Verifield</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Josef</forename><surname>Lotte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christoph</forename><surname>Faller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yann</forename><forename type="middle">Gert</forename><surname>Guger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anatole</forename><surname>Pfurtscheller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Lécuyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Leeb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Combining BCI with Virtual Towards New Applications and Improved BCI. Practical Brain-Computer Interfaces</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heidelberg</forename><surname>Berlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="197" to="220" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-642-29746-5_10</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dreaming and Skepticism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Norman</forename><surname>Malcolm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/2182186</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/2182186" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Philosophical Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="37" />
			<date type="published" when="1956">1956</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean-Louis</forename><surname>Mestre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Vercher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1201/b11612-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1201/b11612-8" />
		<title level="m">Virtual Reality</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Designing Transcendence New Design Science and Reflective Practitioner</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Mossbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Clark</forename><surname>Moustakas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florian `floyd'</forename><surname>Mueller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gunnar</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Thorogood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O'</forename><surname>Shannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Volker</forename><surname>Brien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wulf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s00779-006-0133-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s00779-006-0133-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ubiquitous Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="633" to="645" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Opriş</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Pintea</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<pubPlace>Azucena García-Cristina Botella, Szamosközi, and</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Virtual reality exposure therapy in anxiety disorders: a quantitative meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">and Anxiety</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="85" to="93" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Affective outcomes of virtual reality exposure therapy for anxiety and specific phobias: A meta-analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Albert</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Parsons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rizzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/doi" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Behavior Therapy and Experimental</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="250" to="261" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Life Tree: the Design of Breathing Exercise</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rakesh</forename><surname>Patibanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florian</forename><forename type="middle">"</forename><surname>Floyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">"</forename><surname>Mueller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matevz</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Duckworth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="31" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Lean and Elegant Self-Motion Simulation in Virtual Reality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Riecke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Schulte-Pelkum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Franck</forename><surname>Caniard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Bülthoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.kyb.mpg.de/publication.html?publ=2904" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Virtual Reality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Riva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rosa</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Ba?os</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cristina</forename><surname>Botella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brenda</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Wiederhold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Gaggioli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Technology: Using Interactive Technologies to Positive Functioning. and Social Networking</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="69" to="77" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Riva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fabrizia</forename><surname>Mantovani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Claret</forename><surname>Samantha Capideville</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alessandra</forename><surname>Preziosa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Francesca</forename><surname>Morganti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniela</forename><surname>Villani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Gaggioli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cristina</forename><surname>Botella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mariano</forename><surname>Alcañiz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Affective Interactions Using Virtual Reality: The Link between Presence and &amp; Behavior</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="45" to="56" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inner Garden: Connecting Inner States to a Mixed Reality Sandbox for Mindfulness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joan</forename><forename type="middle">Sol</forename><surname>Roo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Renaud</forename><surname>Gervais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeremy</forename><surname>Frey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Hachet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;17)</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1459" to="1470" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Inner Garden: An Augmented Sandbox Designed Self-Reflection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joan</forename><forename type="middle">Sol</forename><surname>Roo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Renaud</forename><surname>Gervais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Hachet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2839462.2856532</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2839462.2856532" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the TEI &apos;16: International Conference on Tangible, and Embodied Interaction &apos;16)</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">570</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Virtual reality exposure therapy for combat-related posttraumatic stress disorder</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Rothbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Albert</forename><forename type="middle">"</forename><surname>Skip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">"</forename><surname>Rizzo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joann</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1749-6632.2010.05691.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1749-6632.2010.05691.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1208</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="126" to="132" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Applications of lucid dreams: An online study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melanie</forename><surname>Schädlich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Erlacher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.11588/ijodr.2012.2.9505</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.11588/ijodr.2012.2.9505" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Dream Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="134" to="138" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Shaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Diane</forename><surname>Gromala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Meehae</forename><surname>Song</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Meditation Towards Self-In Meta-Plasticity in Virtual Worlds: and Semantics Concepts press)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Mura, G., Hershey, PA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IGI Global</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wings flying in immersive VR #x2014; Controller type, sound effects and experienced ownership and agency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Sikstrom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>De Gotzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Serafin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Virtual Reality</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="282" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Poster: Paving the into virtual reality-a transition in five stages</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Sproll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Freiberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timofey</forename><surname>Grechkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Riecke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/xpls/abs_all.jsp?arnumber=65" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">3D User Interfaces (3DUI), 2013 IEEE Symposium on</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-05-23">2013. May 23. 2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="176" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clinical Applications of Dreaming Therapy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Isaac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Taitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Lucid Dreaming: New Perspectives Consciousness in Sleep [2 volumes]: New on Consciousness in Sleep</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xin</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Diane</forename><surname>Gromala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Riecke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Shaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Loughin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mehdi</forename><surname>Karamnejad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Usability Comparisons of Head-Mounted vs</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Immersive Desktop Displays for Pain Management in Virtual Reality</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Virtual reality in the treatment for mental health problems: An systematic review of recent evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lucia</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Valmaggia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leila</forename><surname>Latif</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kempton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">236</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="195" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Maria Rus-Calafell</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sonic Cradle: Designing for an Immersive of Meditation by Connecting Respiration to</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Vidyarthi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Riecke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Diane</forename><surname>Gromala</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Designing Interactive Systems Conference &apos;12</title>
				<meeting>the Designing Interactive Systems Conference &apos;12</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="408" to="417" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ursula</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Romain</forename><surname>Holzmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Allan</forename><surname>Hobson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Walter</forename><forename type="middle">Judith</forename><surname>Koppehele-Gossel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ansgar</forename><surname>Klimke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Induction of self awareness dreams through frontal low current stimulation of activity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nitsche</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="810" to="812" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/nn.3719</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/nn.3719" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ursula</forename><surname>Voss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Romain</forename><surname>Holzmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Inka Tuin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lucid dreaming: a state of consciousness with features of both waking and nondreaming</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Allan</forename><surname>Hobson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1191" to="1200" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Authentic Professional In Professional Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Webster-Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-90-481-3947-7_5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-90-481-3947-7_5" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Virtual Reality and Interactive Simulation for Pain Medicine</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brenda</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Wiederhold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wiederhold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="S182" to="S188" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1526-4637.2007.00381.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1526-4637.2007.00381.x" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
