<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Everything We Do, Everything We Press: Data-Driven Remote Performance Management in a Mobile Workplace</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Lyndsey</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Bakewell</surname></persName>
							<email>l.l.bakewell@lboro.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Loughborough University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Konstantina</forename><surname>Vasileiou</surname></persName>
							<email>k.vasileiou@bath.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bath</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Bath</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kiel</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Long</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Northumbria University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Newcastle upon Tyne</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>
							<email>m.m.atkinson@exeter.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Exeter</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Exeter</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Rice</surname></persName>
							<email>helenrice@work-4-me.co.uk</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Manuela</forename><surname>Barreto</surname></persName>
							<email>m.barreto@exeter.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Exeter</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Exeter</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><surname>Barnett</surname></persName>
							<email>j.c.barnett@bath.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Bath</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Bath</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Mike</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
							<email>m.wilson2@lboro.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Loughborough University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Loughborough</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Shaun</forename><surname>Lawson</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Northumbria University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Newcastle upon Tyne</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Vines</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Northumbria University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Newcastle upon Tyne</settlement>
									<country key="GB">UK</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Everything We Do, Everything We Press: Data-Driven Remote Performance Management in a Mobile Workplace</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3173945</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Remote monitoring</term>
					<term>performance management</term>
					<term>occupational health</term>
					<term>quantified workplace</term>
					<term>qualitative study H.5.m. Information interfaces and presentation (e.g. HCI): Miscellaneous</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>This paper examines how data-driven performance monitoring technologies affect the work of telecommunications field engineers. As a mobile workforce, this occupational group rely on an array of smartphone applications to plan, manage and report on their jobs, and to liaise remotely with managers and colleagues. These technologies intend to help field engineers be more productive and have greater control over their work; however they also gather data related to the quantity and effectiveness of their labor. We conducted a qualitative study examining engineers' experiences of these systems. Our findings suggest they simultaneously enhance worker autonomy, support co-ordination with and monitoring of colleagues, but promote anxieties around productivity and the interpretation of data by management. We discuss the implications of datadriven performance management technologies on worker agency, and examine the consequences of such systems in an era of quantified workplaces.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>INTRODUCTION</head><p>The field of HCI has been increasingly interested in the implications of data-driven lives. Studies of personal informatics have explored how the tracking of data might support people to live healthier <ref type="bibr">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr">36]</ref> or more sustainable lives <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[29,</ref><ref type="bibr">73]</ref>. The rising use of smartphones and wearables has supported the emergence of a movement surrounding 'The Quantified Self' <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[45]</ref>. People are becoming increasingly accustomed to self-monitoring and self-tracking aspects of their lives and making sense of the resulting data <ref type="bibr">[43]</ref>. It was perhaps inevitable that these ideas would extend into the workplace, and now we see consideration of what datadriven and quantified workplaces could and should look like <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[48,</ref><ref type="bibr">49,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">52]</ref>. The notion of a data-driven workplace poses opportunities and challenges for HCI research. It can support the utilization of data to make workers more productive (e.g. suggesting more effective route plans to workers in warehouses <ref type="bibr">[77]</ref>); it can build awareness of the practices of colleagues <ref type="bibr">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr">63]</ref>; it can support decision-making on issues related to workplace comfort and the health of staff <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>; and ultimately the collection and presentation of data related to worker activity can be used for performance management <ref type="bibr">[77]</ref>. At the same time questions have been raised around how the quantification of workplaces removes worker agency <ref type="bibr">[61]</ref>, provides new forms of controlling workers <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[40,</ref><ref type="bibr">62]</ref> and accounts for work in ways that are decontextualized and artificially objective <ref type="bibr">[62]</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we study an occupational grouptelecommunications field engineers-that has experienced the introduction of a suite of new smartphone applications and related data-driven performance management. The work of a field engineer typically involves driving between locations, completing 'jobs' related to testing, installing and repairing telecommunications equipment, and reporting back on this work. It is work usually performed alone, involving large amounts of travel, and the completion of a designated number of jobs each day. Mobile technologies and equipment have long been central to field engineers' work. However, mobile applications are not just enabling new, more efficient workflows but also drastically changing the nature of the work itself. Mobile, location-based scheduling means that engineers now start and end their work days from their home; location monitoring, job reports and app analytics all support remote performance management; interactions with colleagues are rare, serendipitous or mediated via telecommunications; and the replacement of bulky equipment with app-based alternatives means they are now highly reliant on their smartphone for all forms of communication and tasks.</p><p>We conducted a qualitative study to examine how the introduction of these technologies has been experienced by telecoms field engineers. Through interviews, workshops, and probe activities with 23 engineers, we examined their working patterns and the roles new smartphone applications play in the management and completion of their work. Our contribution to the field of HCI is three-fold. First, we offer a qualitative account of an occupational group experiencing significant changes to their workplace through the introduction of new data-driven performance management technologies. Second, we explain how location-based and remote monitoring technologies foster concerns around control and agency, induce fears around worker performance, and lead to creative workarounds and adoption of the technology. Third, we draw out critical implications for the introduction of these technologies by discussing the ways they affect worker autonomy, engender worker resistance, and create new forms of unaccounted work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>RELATED WORK Workplace Monitoring and Performance Management</head><p>The transformative impact of new technologies on the workplace has long been established in the computer supported cooperative work research. Fieldwork in the print industry <ref type="bibr">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15]</ref> demonstrated how the introduction of workflow and networking systems can disrupt the 'workflow from within'. New systems necessitate additional 'articulation work <ref type="bibr">' [66]</ref> so that altered work practices continue to produce desired outcomes, and often leads to restructuring and re-ordering of workflows and re-configuring structures in ways that ultimately generate new organizational designs. Practices and technologies of workplace monitoring and performance management have also attracted intense academic interest. The sociological literature on monitoring (e.g. <ref type="bibr">[27]</ref>) often frames it as a form of surveillance and control, highlighting the politics of such ventures and the disempowerment of workers. Occupational and management psychology literature instead highlights the ways in which monitoring of performance can enhance and benefit the workplace. Early studies of workplace management established that surveillance and monitoring are central to the role of managers and supervisors <ref type="bibr">[26]</ref>, and practices (such as monitoring the time workers clock in and out, the quantity of their output, and setting goals for them to achieve) have been long-established measures of labor. Information technologies have also long been implicated in the measurement and monitoring of worker productivity: automating the logging time spent doing certain tasks <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>, monitoring their locations [50] and collating and visualizing worker outputs for performance review <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>.</p><p>Opt-in monitoring technologies have shown positive responses from workers-especially in environments involving close collaboration <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[68]</ref> and lone working <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[59]</ref>. For instance, <ref type="bibr">[9]</ref> note that workplace presence awareness systems (e.g. MyUnity) that accommodate individual preferences and 'thresholds' around privacy facilitate communication among a dispersed workforce and foster a sense of community. Such technologies can also facilitate collaborative problem-solving and troubleshooting among mobile workers and infuse a sense of social connectedness in lone workforces <ref type="bibr">[58]</ref>. Indeed, when troubleshooting and presence awareness systems leverage 'opportune moments' for interruption (e.g. based on workers' physiological <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[31]</ref>, cognitive and affective states <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">56]</ref>) and also utilize design features that support critical communication (e.g. implicit knowledge sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[32]</ref>), collaboration and problem-solving is further improved and group work is enhanced.</p><p>Nevertheless, the top-down introduction of such systems often leads to concerns around privacy and invasiveness <ref type="bibr">[78,</ref><ref type="bibr">79]</ref>. In some cases, workplace monitoring technologies have been demonstrated to have a negative influence on the wellbeing of workers <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> with increases in both physical and psychological strain <ref type="bibr">[71]</ref>. Workplace monitoring can also impact morale <ref type="bibr">[41]</ref>, perception of workloads <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, and relations between staff and managers <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[64]</ref>. They can also raise concerns over the decontextualized and depersonalized nature of data gathered for the purposes of monitoring <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[40,</ref><ref type="bibr">62,</ref><ref type="bibr">70]</ref>, and its value or fairness as a measure of performance and success of an individual <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>. Furthermore, as interactions between workers and management get mediated by data, pre-existing tensions or misunderstandings can be intensified <ref type="bibr">[61]</ref>. Perhaps unsurprisingly, there are welldocumented examples of how workers resist, circumnavigate, and workaround monitoring technologies that are felt to be burdensome or invasive <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr">62]</ref>.</p><p>In the specific context of mobile work there has been a recent rise in systems that support remote monitoring. Some examples are framed explicitly as responding to concerns over the vulnerability of lone workers <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[59]</ref>. Others focus on monitoring the driving of vehicles, measuring the economy or quality of driving <ref type="bibr">[62]</ref>, or if workers maintain a set schedule <ref type="bibr">[61]</ref>. However, business and management literature highlights that employers and managers often have concerns over how remote workers might "slack off" <ref type="bibr">[17]</ref> or engage in counter-productive behavior <ref type="bibr">[34]</ref> as they are not under the watchful eye of employers. As such, there is a growing suite of mobile applications that exist to remedy (but also perpetuate) this lack of trust, enabling mobile and remote workers to clock-in and out of work <ref type="bibr">[74]</ref>, to sign-in and out of locations and jobs <ref type="bibr">[39]</ref>, and to alert if they take too long on breaks or go beyond set geographical boundaries <ref type="bibr">[24]</ref>.</p><p>Finally, the possibility that the technology-facilitated monitoring of remote workers could be "perceived and resented as surveillance" [25 p39] has long been recognized as a concern. Akhtar and Moore <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> argue that workplace technology of this kind neutralizes labor relations, rendering the power and politics of labor (c.f. [27]) invisible. Such observations form part of a broader critical engagement with the 'quantified workplace <ref type="bibr">' [49]</ref>: a topic which formed the basis for a workshop discussion at CSCW 2016 <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[48]</ref>. In HCI we have seen studies of how the quantification of work can both promote reflection upon work practice but also feelings that the real work of an occupation is not being recognized <ref type="bibr">[62]</ref>. Yet, as noted by <ref type="bibr">Moore [53]</ref>, despite the long-contested use of digital technology to monitor worker performance and productivity, quantification and algorithmic or data-driven work appear to be on the rise. Perhaps most prominently, these trends appear to clearly materialize in the case of ondemand workforces <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[40,</ref><ref type="bibr">51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">72]</ref> emerging within the rapidly evolving landscape of 'gig' or platform economy <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[37]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Mobile and Lone Working, and Occupational Health</head><p>There has been considerable research on the impact that lone, remote working has on employees. The occupational health literature highlights how mobile workers, especially those spending large amounts of time driving, experience increased risk of musculoskeletal symptoms and lower levels of mental health due to long working days, high work demands, and lowered interaction with colleagues <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr">20]</ref>. Mulki et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[55]</ref> identified that feelings of isolation in such workers could occur due to multivariate issues including a lack of personal contact with colleagues, losing a sense of camaraderie, and feelings of being 'left out'. Relatedly, <ref type="bibr">Orr [57]</ref> noted the role that serendipitous meetings and breaks played for developing communities of practice and care between otherwise distributed team members.</p><p>The above highlight how mobile and lone workers often experience a lack of social connectivity, control, and selfefficacy in their work, experiences which subsequently relate to stress and anxiety <ref type="bibr">[35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">69]</ref>. Theoretical models in the field of organizational psychology postulate that high job demands and a low sense of control <ref type="bibr">[35]</ref>, and imbalanced social exchanges and reciprocity in the workplace coupled with insufficient social support <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[69]</ref>, constitute stressors and are linked to employee distress. These propositions are in line with <ref type="bibr">Dirks and Ferrin's [21]</ref> observation that working with a manager with whom trust and reciprocity has not been established has detrimental effects on worker wellbeing, and results in feelings powerlessness.</p><p>Given the above, we might assume that telecoms field engineers are at risk of at least some of these work stressors because of limited contact with colleagues and remote relations with management. Considering the work on performance monitoring technologies, it might be expected that occupational health risks for this population may be further exaggerated through the addition of more stressors. However, equally, new technologies might instead support greater control and recognition of work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>THE WORK OF A FIELD ENGINEER</head><p>Our research was conducted with a telecommunications company based in the UK. One of the subsidiary's main responsibilities is to manage the local access network that connects customers (businesses and private homes) to their local telephone exchange-starting at the 'main distribution frame' in an 'exchange' and ending at the 'network termination point' at the customer's premises. The field engineers install and maintain the physical wiring and network that connects properties to the national network. Typical 'jobs' for a field engineer might include: visiting a customer's home to install a new telecoms line, connecting a broken telecoms line to a nearby terminal, or visiting local exchanges to install new cabling to connect a new line to the national network. In total, there are approximately 14,000 field engineers working for the company across the UK, who complete just under 30,000 'jobs' each working day. As such, engineers are very visible customer-facing staff for the company. However, an engineer can easily have relatively little contact with customers throughout their day; much of their work at exchanges is done in isolation and often it is not necessary to physically access a customer's property in order to connect or reconnect it to the telephone network.</p><p>Because of the nature of their work, the field engineer spends a large amount of time on the move between jobs. Engineers are provided with a dedicated company van and, since the introduction of location tracking, most engineers take the van home with them at the end of each day. This means that their work day starts and ends from the moment they 'clock-in' and 'clock-out' of their shift in their van. As such, the engineers can have little physical contact with fellow field engineers, and even less with their managers, on a day-today basis. Their primary contact with their team and manager is via monthly conference calls. A consequence of this is that mobile technology is central for the engineers to communicate and coordinate with colleagues.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>The Field Engineer's Smartphone</head><p>Location-based and communications technologies have substantially changed the field engineer's work. However, it is the introduction of smartphones that has perhaps changed the role most drastically. Prior to smartphones, engineers would carry a range of bulky equipment with them in their vans to enable them to receive jobs and log their completion, check phone lines and wiring, and identify faults. As well as taking up space in vans, this equipment was seen to be poorly integrated with one-another and other systems. Therefore, in 2013 the company we conducted our studies with introduced a range of applications that ran on iPhones. While the range of apps is too numerous to discuss here, some of the key ones discussed by participants in our study include:</p><p>Your Jobs: Sends engineers their jobs for the day, which they can access early in the morning. They also use this to report on job progress, bring up notes related to previous work done at the same location, and to log the job as 'complete'. It also gives expected time slots for the completion of jobs.</p><p>Ask for an Assist: Engineers use this to request an 'assist' from another engineer who is nearby and might have necessary skills and equipment. The number of assists an engineer requests via the app is logged.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>See Your Team:</head><p>A map-based application that allows the engineers to see where their colleagues are and see how they are progressing with jobs.</p><p>Connected: A company specific hybrid of Facebook or Twitter which allows engineers to share 'updates' and information that can be viewed by other staff. It was introduced as a means of helping staff feel connected to oneanother and part of a larger team.</p><p>Your Performance: This presents engineers with charts and visualizations of their performance to date in relation to specific performance indicators on a weekly, monthly, and annual basis. Indicators include the number of assists received, the number of jobs completed compared to a quota, customer feedback, how many jobs they have completed that then had to be re-opened, among others. During our study, engineers could also view the data of other team members and look at their own performance in relation to colleagues.</p><p>QuickTest: Allows engineers to conduct a 'line' or 'circuit' test to see if a telecoms line is working. They can use this application to conduct a test without being physically collocated with a telephone line.</p><p>Each of these applications are intended to make the field engineers' job simpler or more productive. Some also aim to grant them greater control over their work-such as enabling them to schedule jobs for the day or making judgments based on their professional performance. However, these apps are also interwoven with the employer's existing performance monitoring processes and promote new indicators of worker productivity and quality. Furthermore, prior research <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[38]</ref> on similar occupations highlights how mobile technologies can in fact hinder performance, especially in relation to existing routines and practices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>METHOD</head><p>The aims of our study were three-fold. First, we aimed to gain a broad understanding of the field engineer's work, what a typical work day is comprised of, and the various challenges they face in working on their own. Second, we wished to understand how digital technologies, specifically the recently introduced smartphone applications, affect their daily work and relationships with colleagues. Finally, we aimed to identify with them aspects of their work they desired to be changed, and to explore how new technologies might address these. To examine these topics, we designed a qualitative study that employed several methods of data collection, with each stage informing the direction of the following stage. These are described below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Interviews</head><p>Initially, semi-structured interviews were conducted with 14 field engineers. Interviews began by inviting participants to share their workplace biography. They were prompted to talk about how long they have been working as an engineer, how they entered the occupation, and how the role had changed over time. When appropriate, the researcher prompted them to elaborate on the role that technologies play in helping them complete, manage and coordinate their work. Also, given the nature of the occupation as requiring extensive periods of lone working, we invited them to talk about feelings of isolation, and the role that technologies played in mitigating against these, if at all. Interviews lasted between 42 and 124 minutes (60 minutes on average).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Co-design Workshops and Cultural Probes</head><p>Following the interviews, a series of workshops and probe activities were conducted with participants to further explore themes identified in the interviews.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Workshop 1: Timelines and Magic Machines</head><p>At this first workshop, we explored more deeply the different schedules and routines field engineers work to, and the ways in which technologies support scheduling and connections with colleagues. Participants worked in pairs to create timelines of their typical work day (from wakening to sleep). We prompted participants to include both daily recurring events and one-off occurrences. Following this, participants were asked to further reflect on the events they had identified by mapping onto them feelings of 'being on my own versus being with others', 'being told versus having control' and 'frustration versus enjoyment' (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1</ref>). Once completed and discussed with the wider group, participants were placed  into new groups of two or three and invited to create 'magic machines' <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10]</ref>. This activity invited participants to identify an event from their timelines and to create a 'magic' technology that responded to and potentially alleviated identified problems. Participants were given a range of materials (cardboard, stickers, shapes, wire and stick on buttons etc.) and asked to assemble their machine (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">2a</ref>). The main purpose of this activity was to elicit further talk between participants about the nature of their work and how its conditions could be changed in the future. Once they had constructed their machine, the researchers questioned them on what it was, asking them to physically demonstrate the machine to the rest of the group.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cultural Probes</head><p>At the end of the first workshop, cultural probes <ref type="bibr">[30]</ref> were given to participants. The probe pack comprised of a customized disposable camera with 14 prompts and corresponding 'photo journal' (for participants to provide short written descriptions of their photos). In the spirit of past probe studies, the prompts were intentionally ambiguous.</p><p>The prompts also responded to the insights from the initial interviews. For example, one prompt invited participants to photograph "something that is time-consuming", while another asked for "something that you'd share with others".</p><p>Participants were asked to complete the probe responses (e.g. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">2b</ref> and 2c) in advance of the second workshop.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Workshop 2: Reflections and Corporate Fictions</head><p>The second workshop was divided into two activities designed in response to findings from workshop one. Participants were split into small groups. To start, each group was invited to review photos from the cultural probe and discuss the similarities and differences between their responses. After this, each group was provided with a 'recruitment brochure' for a fictional company called TotalComms. This brochure responded to several of the issues and ideas raised by the participants in interviews and in workshop one. The brochure contained a number of 'services' and 'benefits' that the fictional TotalComms was offering to employees. Inspired by <ref type="bibr">[76]</ref>, these ideas were purposely questionable and served to promote debate and discussion. Examples included 'Commie' (a robotic assistant and companion); a full-video monitoring system (that watched their every move, to provide assistance if needed), and 'Coq-au-van' (a luxurious company van with full cooking, washing and resting facilities). In the workshop, participants were asked to go through the brochures and annotate them to flag aspects that they liked or disliked. These were then discussed further with the workshop group.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Participants</head><p>In total, we met with 23 different field engineers across all stages of data collection. Of the 14 field engineers that participated in the interviews, only 5 could attend the codesign workshops. Therefore, at this stage we recruited a further 9 participants. For practical reasons, we split the participants into three groups for the workshops. All the participants were recruited through our ongoing collaborations with their employer. Participants ranged from 20 to 53 years of age (average age of 33). All but one identified themselves as male, representative of the organization's demographic of engineers. The participants represented diverse levels of experience with the job and period of employment in this role. Despite the range in age and periods of employment, all participants were confident with the equipment provided by the organization, due to continual training. As a thank-you for their time, all participants were provided with gift vouchers (£20 for interviews, £20 per workshop).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Data Analysis</head><p>All interviews and workshops were audio recorded and transcribed. This data was treated as a corpus upon which we conducted thematic analysis. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>, data at the sentence to paragraph level was summarized using short textual codes. Codes were compared, contrasted, integrated where necessary, and grouped together into themes. Given the iterative nature of our study, preliminary analyses were conducted following the completion of each stage of data collection (e.g. following the completion of interviews, first set of workshops) in order to inform the next stage of research. At the end of the study, the data corpus was reviewed by two authors, re-coded and thematically tied together. This final analysis is presented below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>FINDINGS</head><p>Our analysis led to the construction of 4 themes: being monitored and monitoring others; independence and (not) being in control; maintaining good performance data; and backchannels, socialization and job demands.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Being Monitored and Monitoring Others</head><p>All of the participants were aware that their phones, vans and other work systems they used were monitored, with some commenting on the wealth of data gathered about them:</p><p>We are told right from day one. Every button we press on our iPhone, everything we do is monitored, we know because of the Industry we are in. (P15, W2G2)</p><p>There was an awareness that this data would be used for the purposes of performance management and the coaching of engineers. Each engineer can continually access the data related to their performance via their work provided iPhone and laptop using the Your Performance application: The response to this kind of performance management varied greatly between participants. Three saw it as a means of better managing and improving their own performance. For example, P19 (W2G1) identified the usefulness of being presented with this data, as it "spurred him on" and let him think "I can do this" when he had challenging jobs. However, the other engineers worried about the gathering of this data.</p><p>There was a strong sense that data collected might be used against them as part of regular performance review processes. There was also a fear that this data would be examined closely if a job were to go wrong. This fear was exacerbated further by the engineers' own knowledge and awareness of the sheer amount of data being collected: It was even noted that the number of times you check on your performance is logged: "they wanted to know why we never checked on it [their performance]" (P14 W1G2). As such there was a deep awareness that although the engineers were working on their own, much of what they do was tracked, logged and used to assess the quality of their work.</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">I</formula><p>While many engineers identified these technologies as a means for the organization to monitor their activity, a few still saw some benefits. They acknowledged that the data collected was used to identify good practice and reward those that do well: "There are incentives, if we perform they reward us" (P20, W1G3); "I won a day at the races.</p><p>[…] Most improved I think it was. I must have been really bad" (P11, W1G3). A critical point brought up by participants was an awareness that the data that the apps both collected and presented back was purposely encouraging competition between them. This was often explicit in the case of managers setting competitions among team members, but induced competition was also facilitated by simply being able to view the progress of team members via the Your Performance app. All but two of the participants noted that they would keenly look at how they compared to colleagues: Again, however, the availability of this data between colleagues was contentious. This was reflected by P14, who explained that he would check other people's jobs to "have a bitch and a moan again, 'he's got cab only jobs, how come I've got these faults?'!" (P14, Int).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Independence and (not) Being in Control</head><p>All of the participants discussed extensively the ways the different applications supported a sense of independence and control, although the ways this manifested differed. For example, scheduling and balancing workloads is an important demand of the engineers' job, and was now facilitated by the Your Jobs application. The ways in which they planned their days-or their days were planned for them-differed widely however. During the first workshop, it was established that there was significant variation in the day-to-day jobs depending on length of service, contract type and level of training. Engineers who were relatively new in service were given a daily schedule referred to as a "tour". A tour comprised of six jobs to be completed over the course of the day-three for the morning and three for the afternoon.</p><p>When "on tour" engineers automatically received all their jobs via their iPhone at the start of the working day.</p><p>While the allocation of jobs was done automatically via the Your Jobs application, engineers were given some freedom around when they could conduct the jobs (but they could not move jobs from the morning or the afternoon). Participants explained that they would often schedule the jobs after considering factors such as their perceived difficulty (based on the notes contained in the job and whether the line test worked), the nature of the job (a retail, office, or residential customer, or work at a telephone exchange), and whether a job was in a rural or urban location (to avoid peak hour traffic). Engineers would also plan their tour around the time it would take to travel to jobs, with a view to avoid making their working day longer due to travelling:</p><p>We try the closest one first because we don't get paid traffic to the first job. And then you try and get the closest job when you come back. (P15, W1G1)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Try to start and end close to home because then you can do the big loop and then come back. (P2, W1G1)</head><p>This capability to allocate the order of jobs throughout the day was viewed positively by all but four participants, as it created a sense of control and autonomy over the job: You have control.</p><p>[…] You can say, 'I'm going to go there, there and there.' And just complete all them. (P2, W1G3). Others explained that having all jobs sent at the start of the day to their phone gave comfort in knowing what their day might consist of and what challenges they could face. P17 (W2G2) observed that as soon as he woke up he would check his jobs and plan his day out. After this, he would "test the line" for jobs via his iPhone, thus being more aware about how easy or difficult these jobs might be. However, despite a sense of comfort generated from this advance awareness of jobs, the risks of prolonged work hours and of work activities invading home life and personal time were also stressed. As P2 explained: Empathizing with P2's comments, P11 explained how he now leaves his work phone downstairs, turned off, to avoid doing this. There was also a concern from three participants that the freedom to schedule their days offloaded decision making and responsibility from managers to the engineers-and if they were to make a poor scheduling decision (e.g. getting stuck in traffic and resulting in being unable to a job on time) this would be held against them. As such, the of control and autonomy deriving from these systems viewed with some suspicion: problem we've got is with the task, you've got to do it anyway job], you've got no control. It might take you two or three hours, but you've still got the job so you have still got to do it.</p><p>W1G1)</p><p>For those engineers who were not on a tour schedule, jobs received one-after-the-other as their day progressed. schedule was primarily accessible to engineers that had for the organization for a longer period. Although it not offer the same freedom, less However, one important challenge engineers this schedule faced was not knowing their next job would comprise of until they requested it. This was also a for those engineers on tour if had completed all their assigned jobs sooner than expected and had time to one more. buffering symbol that appeared on the Your Jobs app requesting new job was jokingly referred to as the "wheel of doom" W1G2):</p><p>It is like Russian Roulette sometimes… One of the guys, last week, it was, at 3:30 pm he is in (anonymized place A) spun the wheel and he had a jump recovery in (anonymized place and it is literally a 5 minute job at the cab. So he had to drive the way from (A) to (B) to do a 5 minute job and then drive all way back. is what you have got to do. W2G2)</p><p>Given the competitive nature of elements of the job, the randomness of job allocations amplified concerns that some engineers got more favorable jobs than others. While was no evidence of favoritism, it fueled negative towards managers some team members, in yet more "bitching and moaning" (P14, Int) especially when a job allocation significantly impacted on performance or extended length of a work day.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Maintaining Performance</head><p>We have already seen some engineers worried about planning their days and the impact certain jobs and their may have on performance. Time continually negotiated challenge, with an awareness that poorly organizing your day and not maintaining time would to poor reported performance. each job is an estimated of time for completion, all of the engineers explained they conscious of maintaining a strict schedule which would give them the best chance to their data.</p><p>many participants and controlling their around a complex set of jobs was a continuous burden that brought on stress. Given the diversity of jobs, the unpredictability of traffic, and the temperamental nature of their work technologies, experiencing and problems a day was often inevitable it was common to get home later than expected. Occasionally, to recover from delays, all but three participants they skip breaks or eat their lunch in their vans to recoup lost time:</p><p>Depends if you are in a rush. You might want to get close to your job like you said and just sit in the van and have a sandwich.</p><p>(P11, W1G3). Four mentioned would avoid drinking too much during the day and declined offers of a drink from customers to reduce the likelihood of needing to find a restroom between jobs. One participant provided a rather extreme example of how they were caught "off guard" and used a bucket provided in the van (for digging up dirt and around electrical wiring) to themselves" avoid going on a detour looking for a bathroom. It was also noted whether they had taken their breaks was also loggedthey would make sure to register the start and end of breaks and lunches, even if they were unable to take them.</p><p>A concern regarding maintaining performance was associated with how data on their on certain jobs was being captured. The primary measures the quality of their work was feedback customers and how often an engineer would in an assist" (P12, W2G2) via the Ask for an Assist application. This latter function was available as a last resort for engineers who felt they were unable to complete a job, so that the allotted job can be "returned" and "sent back" and allocated to someone else. Engineers reported on a wide range of reasons why they may be unable to complete a job-from not being experienced enough for a specific type of fault, to not having required equipment, to being stuck in traffic or on a previous job. A returned job would usually be picked up by another nearby While all participants had used the formal to seek there was some around its value. For some was a desire to do well for the rest of the team; failure complete jobs successfully would require another team to come out to provide support or repair mistakes. Not only was this viewed negatively by there was also a fear of becoming a burden to colleagues. Furthermore, out an assist" would "go against you because it goes your stats" (P12, Int). Therefore, there was a temptation engineers to continue working on a difficult job-even at risk of extending their time and risking further performance issues-instead of requesting help. also clear that participants circumnavigated the formal processes of calling for an assist via the designated Four engineers explained how they would use the Your Team to see which of their workmates were working in the local area. P04 explained how calling in a favor from someone this way was preferable to contacting call-centre for help: know that I'll try and see how close he is to getting here and giving me a hand" (P04, Int). If their workmate is able to then officially they have to "complete" their current job then "sign in" to colleagues' job to provide the assist. not following the formal protocols for getting an assist, there was some from an organizational perspective to this process. Furthermore, as the engineer asking for help did not officially log a request for an assist, this not captured on performance data. However, it require trust from the engineer helping out with the assist, as it could negatively impact any further jobs they needed to complete.</p><p>In cases, twelve participants explained how they circumnavigate the company procedures completely, send SMSs or group messages through WhatsApp or Facebook via their personal phones to see who was nearby. In cases, of messages would involve informal advice. It also provides a way for nearby to take slight detours between jobs to help their team mates. Indeed, P13 noted that it was common practice between certain circles of workmates to informally check-in see if anyone needed help at the end of the day:</p><p>One person will end up with an hour at the end of the day where they've got no work so what they'll do is send a text message else the and say, "I'm for an hour, if anybody needs a hand, give me a call", they'll come and help you.</p><p>yeah, it's quite a common thing that they all help or all willing to help, it's really good. (P13,</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Backchannels, Socialization, and Job Demands</head><p>As noted above, social networking instant messaging such as Facebook, Twitter and WhatsApp, were used by all participants. provided a space for building personal connection" (P2, W2G1) with workmates through the sharing of jokes, experiences, and-as above-by each other with challenging jobs. All but four of the engineers saw private social networks messaging as a place where work be chatted about freely, away from the "watchful eye" of the organization's bespoke social platforms. The use of these platforms, accessed on their personal devices, gave a sense of freedom. Instant messaging private Facebook groups were also used as space where the members felt comfortable complaining their role, with P14 noting that they provide a page as well, sort of thing. Like blokes whining, moaning on there and everything." W2G3).</p><p>Lunchtime presented the most common occasion for with each other by phone. two engineers preferred spending lunches on their own, phone up colleagues on their team, or their families and non-work mates, to check-in and chat. Others made an effort to seek fellow engineers and physically meet with them. A common practice was to drive to one of exchanges, as that provided a likely location where other would be having lunch after completing jobs:</p><p>At lunchtimes you've got your exchange, and every town's got an exchange, so you go there and if there's a van in the car you do of, oh there's somebody there, so you go and have a chat. (P1, Int) P1 went on to explain that he enjoyed going to the exchanges it was opportunity to meet engineers from other teams. of the participants, however, preferred to spend time with their core group of pals. While those groups who instant messaging Facebook to chat would sometimes co-ordinate meet-ups via these, there was also a on the See Your Team to locate workmates for social reasons:</p><p>We can see where all the team are, I know I do it and a few other do it, when we're about to set lunch we sort of see who's around us and we agree to meet up at a café or a restaurant a McDonalds and we have our lunch, a quick chat. Int) in general socialization with colleagues was desired the engineers, there were preferred the solitude and quiet time that lunch and breaks provided. Furthermore, for those that did desire social interactions with workmates there was a frustration that their ability to do so heavily hindered by their tight schedules. lunch and breaks-finding somewhere to buy lunch, finding safe legal locations to spending time looking for the location of workmates and getting to that location-all ate scarce break periods. these reported examples, exchanges while working was had to be deliberately planned, relied on serendipity, and was highly dependent on asynchronous messaging. participants recognized that some of the company's apps (like Connected) were intended to keep them in touch with other, these were time consuming to engage with an already busy day. Furthermore, all but two that when they did get the chance they would use personal to chat with where they from the monitoring protocols of the company.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DISCUSSION</head><p>Our findings highlight how technologies can impact on a remote, mobile and primarily lone workforce. The technologies that the field engineers use during their work clearly have attributes. They support engineers to work more independently, can present them almost real-time information about their jobs, and enable them to perform their greater flexibility. However, these applications also a range of practices and issues impact their work, the felt quality of workplace, and relationships others. We discuss these issues in the following concluding sections.</p><p>with Colleagues and apps came with new forms of unrecognized work in regard to managing relationships other people as well as the personal sentiments surrounding this relational Primarily, they placed new burdens on engineers in managing their relationships with colleagues.</p><p>we illustrated, Ask for an Assist them to proactively seek help from colleagues when they in difficulties. While these systems speed up support seeking facilitate problem-solving and troubleshooting especially when their design accounts for workers' collaborate (e.g. based on criteria of optimal <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">56]</ref>), our study showed that technologies were also utilized means of logging activity and performance; those that seek help too often are underperforming (or at least that is how it felt). Therefore, is not surprising that engineers attempted to circumnavigate these formal processes. However, even that sometimes with a cost as they lost face to a co-worker (in an where expert practical skill is privileged <ref type="bibr">[46]</ref>). Perhaps worse, findings show that workers occasionally ended feeling as though are a burden to others, wasting their time, and potentially causing them their own performance problems. While there may have been when an could a colleague give them a quick informal assist, being under constant monitoring, and therefore potentially for detours, seriously inhibits otherwise naturally occurring prosocial behavior within the workplace.</p><p>As such, the formalization of lending a hand through these coupled with its quantification for productivity measurement reasons, to worry, anxiety and-in many reported cases-an active 'non-use' of the technology by carrying on trying to the job yourself. Bernstein the 'transparency paradox' performance management technologies, where workers engage with timeconsuming behaviors to hide aspects of their work; a practice saw emerging when continued doing jobs they unable to complete, concealing their problems, or instead spent time seeking informal help which, itself, may have taken longer to achieve than the formal routes.</p><p>the will to both seek and give help to others inhibited by processes of social comparison where is fostered through locating one's own in relation to team members. While we a large amount of co-operation between team members, the system of rewards installed alongside these promoted individual over team benefits.</p><p>we can extend these concerns to other sorts of management issues, such as interactions with customers. The field engineer occupation is unusual as it covers technical skills with customer-facing work. In the words of the of participants, they are "the face" of the enterprise. While this has always been the case, some new of field engineer apps place them in contact with customers; customers get updates based on the location of driver's van, engineers are meant to contact customers en route, and customers have engineers' details if they have any questions (and indeed, in one case, a participant reported having a phone call from a customer asking for advice on what Internet he should Such interactions customers brought into even relevancy given problems engineers sometimes face with technical issues with their devices; they find themselves having to to customers that their job cannot completed due to the engineers' telecoms problems. But perhaps most is that exchanges with customers are also assessed, and ultimately implicated in performance management, since customers' assessment of the engineer one more, constantly performance indicator.</p><p>the case of colleagues and we see how the technologies that support this mobile workplace introduce situations where employees have to carefully regulate their or in other words engage in forms of emotional <ref type="bibr">[33]</ref>. Occupational health literature notes that such labor is particularly impactful on workplace stress when unexpected or out of one's own control <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[54]</ref> particularly when there a lack of co-worker <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[67]</ref> or social support <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Accountability, and Intensification of</head><p>One of the key benefits of the occupation to several engineers was that they had a strong feeling of independence and autonomy in how they managed and completed their day.</p><p>the strong motivational force of perceived control, flexibility, and autonomy in the has also been documented in emerging of work organization, such in the gig economy At the same time, it was clear our findings that there was a considerable amount of work that occurred in negotiating this flexibility. While apps like Jobs introduced some and control, it also 'articulation work' [66] to plan routes, make about job ordering, and to breaks into days. highlights that a 'flexible' workplace, enabled by remote monitoring and scheduling systems, on one hand provided feelings of autonomy and a greater space for choice on the other promoted anxiety around retaining that control. able to schedule parts of a brought with it a new form of making the wrong choice of route, or your day incorrectly, or putting a long job first, impact your day and black mark on your profile. At the same time, aspects that were out of control-such as unexpected traffic, unavailability of equipment at a location, or being repeatedly assigned tough left unrecognized by these performance data In line with work, there is a sense that the qualitative aspects of their labor that go into managing their schedule fail to be recognized, or simply go ignored [62], suggesting the decontextualization of work under datadriven performance evaluation systems Furthermore, opacity of how jobs are algorithmically through the 'wheel of doom' mistrust both towards managers and to peers. This ties with research highlighting the concerns of on-demand workers around the fairness and accuracy of algorithmic evaluation <ref type="bibr">[41,</ref><ref type="bibr">51]</ref>.</p><p>The suite of apps introduced to the field engineer role intended to simplify elements of day-to-day work. It reduced physical labor related to carrying around significant amounts of bulky equipment, both within their vans or into customers' homes. It also meant that aspects of that were very as waiting on the phone to a job, or searching for notes related to a job-were made simpler. the simplification of these aspects of job space intensify the core aspects of this would perform considerable amounts of outside of their contracted hours, planned their days carefully, conducted line tests their beds before getting up, and logging breaks and lunch when they were still working. Similar to Prasopoulou et al.'s findings some engineers started to a sense of overly extended working hours, as the workplace itself becomes dramatically in space, time and place <ref type="bibr">[75]</ref>. As Brodie and Perry note, there is a need for workers to draw 'chalk-lines' work and home activities keep some distinction in However, recognition of work into private life conditions of 'flexible' work to obscure and might be even within a socio-cultural context of work pre-eminence <ref type="bibr">[11]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Management, Monitoring and Spaces</head><p>The field engineers clearly felt work was closely monitored, not just by their managers who had access to data but also by colleagues. some considered having access to information about their improved performance and indeed triggered informal support sharing and collaborative troubleshooting this was not always the case. were raised around the motivations colleagues looking at this data the technical nature of the role promoted sharp awareness of the sheer amount of data collected about them (even including how long they spend on certain apps, or how they are reviewing their own performance data). The managerial surveillance alongside this form of 'lateral surveillance' by colleagues <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> clearly invokes and vividly instantiates Foucault's of 'panopticon'; as a result, participants often regulated their and altered their (e.g. avoided using formal channels of support), when productivity was implicated, work conditions of omnipresent and ubiquitous surveillance.</p><p>In HCI, the study of personal informatics and the quantified has been of interest some time (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[42,</ref><ref type="bibr">65]</ref>). As mentioned the opening of the paper, there has been an interest in how technologies like these can be translated from personal to the workplace <ref type="bibr">[49]</ref>. these technologies can be framed as opportunities to study and positively the conditions of work, they can also be seen as examples of 'dataveillance' where self-tracking is imposed on workers <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[44]</ref>; or in other words, workers become usees rather than users of these systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, where consent to be monitored is inferred through the terms of their employment. In extreme cases, has been argued that such systems a 'streamlined version of the clipboard' that floor may have used in time and motion studies of bluecollar workers <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[52]</ref>. While the situation we see with the field engineers is not so extreme, we do see how the collection and of data related to productivity engages staff to more like a manager, to optimize performance, focus on their outputs. In doing so, however, Aktar and <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> note that workers themselves lose sight of the context within which their performance occurs, and the why they make decisions as they do.</p><p>we how many engineers engaged in 'non-use <ref type="bibr">' [7]</ref> of a range of systems that formally supported with colleagues. the company even provided a range of 'social' apps for its employees to use, were generally avoided they render the engineers to management, suggesting the importance of designing technologies that are attuned to workers' privacy and preferences Thus, using closed groups private platforms to share funny stories or silly pictures, to simply "moan", might be seen as a small act of in workplace where you are often alone, but being watched. resonates with findings from research with algorithmically-managed on-demand workers who often resorted to online social spaces outside 'work' platform to build a community and utilize the benefits social support and knowledge sharing. perhaps more practically, it suggests the need for ensuring that in remote mobile workplaces, workers are provided with private spaces where they are no longer under the eye of management. Providing such spaces might start averting circumnavigating of formal processes, but might support productive deviance, experimentation and focus productive work <ref type="bibr">[8]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CONCLUSION</head><p>We the of field engineers and the roles that new performance enhancement and management technologies play their workplace. Although field engineers see in these systems, they also induced feelings of disconnection from colleagues, and raised concerns about being monitored and remotely performance managed.</p><p>while these technologies simplified aspects of the work, their use simultaneously led to experiences of work intensification and perceptions of greater responsibility and accountability that rendered any gain of job control disputable. Our further highlighted the range of acts of engineers have developed and adopted to compensate for lost privacy. also saw how engineers engage in new forms of work respond to the demands of these systems in relation to the unexpected interactions they cause with colleagues and and maintain their schedules for the day. Our provides insight into the use of monitoring and remote performance management technologies in the workplace, light a commonplace yet understudied and worker occupation. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 .</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2. Examples of (a) participants creating their magic machines in workshop one and probe responses to (b) 'my workplace' and (c) 'something I am never without'.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,328.40,61.20,213.65,191.30" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 .</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1. Example of timeline created as part of the first activities in workshop one, with layers mapping different feelings in relation to daily activities and routines.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="4,42.43,52.22,254.43,180.39" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Thank you to our participants for their and our collaborating organization for aiding recruitment. This work supported by RCUK grant ES/M003558/1, funded through the Empathy and Trust in Online Communicating (EMoTICON) funding call administered by the Economic Social Research Council in conjunction with the RCUK Connected Communities, Digital Economy and Partnership Conflict, Crime and Security themes, and supported by Defence Science and Technology Laboratory (Dstl) and Centre for the Protection of National Infrastructure (CPNI).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>think you know people are tracking you and realistically everyone knows that they can't look at everyone's data all of the time. But it is there if there is a problem, someone will dig a bit deeper into it. (P15, W2G2) Then they've got another sheet which monitors the time you get in your van until the time you get to your first job, to the time you come off your first job, your second job, your third job and where you are when you close your jobs […] the phone is a monitor.</figDesc><table><row><cell>They can see when you start the ignition in your van, you start</cell></row><row><cell>moving, where you parked, where you've been, when you started</cell></row><row><cell>your job, when you took lunch, how long after your lunch you</cell></row><row><cell>were still in the exchange. (P18, W2G1)</cell></row><row><cell>(P22, W1G2)</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional in organizations: Antecedents, consequences, moderators</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Abraham</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc Gen Psychol Monogr</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">124</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="246" />
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychosocial of technological in contemporary and trade union responses</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Phoebe</forename><surname>Akhtar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Labour Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="131" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making magic machines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Andersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.13140/2.1.1280.1285</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.13140/2.1.1280.1285" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of 10 th European Academy of Design Conference-Crafting the Future</title>
				<meeting>10 th European Academy of Design Conference-Crafting the Future</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The work of watching one another: Lateral surveillance, risk, and governance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Andrejevic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Surveill Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="479" to="497" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">surveillance: An overview</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kirstie</forename><surname>Ball</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00236561003654776</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00236561003654776" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Labor Hist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Usees</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Baumer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Systems &apos;15)</title>
				<meeting>the rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Systems &apos;15)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3295" to="3298" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why study non-use</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Eric</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Morgan</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Baumer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jenna</forename><surname>Ames</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jed</forename><surname>Burrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Brubaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Dourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">First Monday</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">11</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The transparency paradox: A for privacy in organizational learning and control</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ethan</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Bernstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0001839212453028</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0001839212453028" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adm Sci Q</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="181" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">myUnity: A new platform support communication in the modern workplace</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Biehl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thea</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Van Melle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Girgensohn</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 19 th international conference Multimedia (MM &apos;11)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="801" to="802" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anti-solutionist strategies: Seriously silly fiction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Blythe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Andersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2858036.2858482</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2858036.2858482" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Systems (CHI &apos;16)</title>
				<meeting>the 2016 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Systems (CHI &apos;16)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4968" to="4978" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Living in a culture of overwork: An ethnographic study flexibility</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Bourne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pamela</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Forman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1056492613481245</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1056492613481245" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Manag Inq</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Workflow from within and without: Technology and cooperative work on the print industry shopfloor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bowers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Button</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wes</forename><surname>Sharrock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fourth European Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (ECSCW &apos;95)</title>
				<meeting>the Fourth European Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work (ECSCW &apos;95)</meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using analysis in psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Virginia</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1191/1478088706qp063oa" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Res Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing for mobility, collaboration and information use by bluecollar workers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacqueline</forename><surname>Brodie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Perry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/567352.567356</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/567352.567356" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">SIGGROUP Bull</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The of order and the order of production: Possibilities for distributed organisations, work and in the print industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Button</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wes</forename><surname>Sharrock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the Fifth European Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work (ECSCW &apos;97</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A review and of logistics performance measurement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Caplice</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yossi</forename><surname>Sheffi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1108/09574099510805279</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1108/09574099510805279" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The International Journal of Logistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supervisory orientations and salesperson work outcomes: The moderating effect of salesperson location</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Goutam</forename><surname>Challagalla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tasadduq</forename><surname>Shervani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Huber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personal Selling &amp; Sales Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="171" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">I&apos;d want burn the data or at least nobble the numbers&quot;: Towards mediated building management for comfort and energy use</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Clear</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sam</forename><forename type="middle">Mitchell</forename><surname>Finnigan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Olivier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Comber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 on Supported Cooperative and Computing (CSCW &apos;17</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 on Supported Cooperative and Computing (CSCW &apos;17</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2448" to="2461" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">health and wellbeing of remote and workers: Final report</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joanne</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Crawford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Maccalman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>603- 00911</idno>
		<ptr target="http://www.bohrf.org.uk/downloads/224E05_Final_Report-December_2009.pdf" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The health and well-being of remote and mobile workers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joanne</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Crawford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Maccalman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Craig</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Occup Med</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="385" to="394" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trust in Meta-analytic findings and implications for and practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kurt</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Dirks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Donald</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ferrin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>DOI: 9010.87.4.611</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Appl Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">87</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="611" to="628" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working around technologiesprofessionalism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katia</forename><surname>Dupret</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/ntwe.12093</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/ntwe.12093" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Work and Employment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="174" to="187" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ResViz: Politics and design issues in visualizing academic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><forename type="middle">Sebastian</forename><surname>Mellor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Olivier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pete</forename><forename type="middle">David</forename><surname>Kirk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Comber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>DOI: 24</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.exaktime.com/time-clock-app/gps-tracking/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2016 CHI Conference Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;16)</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surveillance in The case of teleworking</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Ben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fairweather</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Bus Ethics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="49" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Henri Fayol. 1949. and Industrial Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Pitman and Sons</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">and punish: The birth of the prison</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Foucault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
			<publisher>Vintage Books</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Persuasive technology real world: A study of long-term use of activity sensing devices for</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Fritz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elaine</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gail</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zimmermann</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Factors in Computing (CHI &apos;14)</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Factors in Computing (CHI &apos;14)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="487" to="496" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why and did we throw Probing on Reflection through the Food Waste Diary</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eva</forename><surname>Ganglbauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geraldine</forename><surname>Fitzpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florian</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33 Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems &apos;15)</title>
				<meeting>the 33 Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems &apos;15)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1105" to="1114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Gaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tony</forename><surname>Dunne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elena</forename><surname>Pacenti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Cultural probes. Interactions</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="29" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intelligent interruption management using electro dermal activity physiological sensor for collaborative</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nitesh</forename><surname>Goyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Fussell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">the ACM on Interactive, Mobile, Wearable and Ubiquitous Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3: Article 52. DOI</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alicia Grandey. 2000. regulation the workplace: A new way to conceptualize emotional labor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nitesh</forename><surname>Goyal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gilly</forename><surname>Leshed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Dan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fussell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2556288.255722933</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;14)</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samantha</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kaila</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Simpson</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Reeshad</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;14)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="110" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Effects of implicit sharing in collaborative analysis</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2016. I can&apos;t steal from a if I work from home: Conceptual and measurement-related issues associated with studying work behavior in a telework setting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ronald</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dalal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Vega</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Performance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="190" />
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Job demands, decision latitude, and mental Implications job redesign</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Karasek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Adm Sci Q</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="285" to="308" />
			<date type="published" when="1979">1979</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lullaby: A capture &amp; access system for understanding the sleep</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Kay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eun</forename><forename type="middle">Kyoung</forename><surname>Choe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jesse</forename><surname>Shepherd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Greenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nathaniel</forename><surname>Watson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sunny</forename><surname>Consolvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kientz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2370216.2370253</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2370216.2370253" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2012 ACM on Ubiquitous Computing &apos;12</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The rise of the economy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Kenney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Zysman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Science and Technology</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making place&quot; to make IT work: Empirical of HCI for mobile CSCW</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steinar</forename><surname>Kristoffersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fredrik</forename><surname>Ljungberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the International ACM SIGGROUP Conference on Group Work (GROUP &apos;99)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI: Sync</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="276" to="285" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Working machines: The of algorithmic and data-driven management on human workers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Min</forename><forename type="middle">Kyung</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Kusbit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Evan</forename><surname>Metsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 33 Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing (CHI &apos;15)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1603" to="1612" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Electronic in the workplace</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samantha</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Kleiner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1108/01409170310784014</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1108/01409170310784014" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Management Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="72" to="81" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A stagebased model of personal informatics systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anind</forename><surname>Dey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jodi</forename><surname>Forlizzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;10)</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;10)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="557" to="566" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-tracking cultures: Towards a sociology of personal informatics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deborah</forename><surname>Lupton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2686612.2686623</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2686612.2686623" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of 26 th Australian Computer-Human Interaction Conference on Designing the Future Design (OzCHI &apos;14)</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="86" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diverse domains of selves: Self-tracking modes and dataveillance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lupton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="101" to="122" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The quantified self</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deborah</forename><surname>Lupton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Technology, affordances and occupational identity amongst older telecommunications engineers: living to black-boxes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Mackenzie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abigail</forename><surname>Marks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kate</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0038038515616352</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0038038515616352" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sociology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="732" to="748" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Focused, aroused, but so distractible: A perspective on multitasking and</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gloria</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shamsi</forename><surname>Iqbal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mary</forename><surname>Czerwinski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2675133.2675221</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 18 th ACM on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW &apos;15)</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="903" to="916" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Let&apos;s talk about the workplace</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Afra</forename><surname>Mashhadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fahim</forename><surname>Kawsar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Akhil</forename><surname>Mathur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Casey</forename><surname>Dugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Sadat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shami</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the th ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work Social Computing Companion</title>
				<meeting>the th ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work Social Computing Companion</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">16</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Quantified workplace: Opportunities and challenges</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2 workshop on Workshop on Physical Analytics &apos;15)</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Mathur</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geert</forename><surname>Van Den Broeck</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Afra</forename><surname>Vanderhulst</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fahim</forename><surname>Mashhadi</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><surname>Kawsar</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="41" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hands on the wheel: Navigating algorithmic management and drivers&apos; autonomy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laurel</forename><surname>Mcnall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Stanton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10869-010-9189-y51</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10869-010-9189-y51" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the</title>
				<meeting>the</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">38</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Private eyes are watching you: Reactions to location sensing</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Information Systems (ICIS December</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Seoul, South Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Moore</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1461444815604328</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1461444815604328" />
		<title level="m">The quantified self: What counts in the neoliberal New Media Soc 18</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2774" to="2792" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The quantified self in precarity: Work, technology and counts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Phoebe</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dimensions, and consequences of emotional labor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Feldman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.jstor.org/stable/259161" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Acad Manag</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="986" to="1010" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Workplace isolation, and job performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jay Prakash William</forename><surname>Locander</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hensel</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">of Personal &amp; Sales Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reducing users&apos; mental effort due to notifications in multi-device mobile environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Okoshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ramos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jin</forename><surname>Hiroki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anind</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Nakazawa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hideyuki</forename><surname>Dey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Tokuda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2750858.2807517</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2015 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Computing (UbiComp &apos;15</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="475" to="486" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">about machines: An of a modern job</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Orr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
			<publisher>Cornell University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ask an Expert: Mobile workspaces for collaborative troubleshooting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sharoda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joe</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Paul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bolinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/HICSS.2015.60</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on System (HICSS &apos;15)</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="442" to="451" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of location based service Galileo system</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jun-Jie</forename><surname>Peng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ISCSCT.2008.33</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of International Symposium on Computer Science and Computational (ISCSCT &apos;08)</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="737" to="741" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digitally driven: location based services impact the work practices of London bus drivers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elpida</forename><surname>Prasopoulou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Athanasia</forename><surname>Pouloudi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Niki</forename><surname>Panteli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Doi: Pritchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Vines</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pam</forename><surname>Briggs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lisa</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Olivier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2702123.2702307</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2702123.2702307" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the on Human Factors in Computing (CHI 3617-3626. DOI: W. Pritchard, Pam Briggs</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2014. 2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1885" to="1894" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of the 33 ACM Conference Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;15)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Enhancing personal informatics through social sensemaking</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Puussaar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Clear</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3025453.3025804</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3025453.3025804" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;17</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personal tracking lived informatics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linda</forename><surname>Rafnsdóttir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Margrét</forename><surname>Lilja</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 32 annual ACM conference on Human Factors in Computing (CHI &apos;14)</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alistair</forename><surname>Doi: John Mattias Rost</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">Chalmers</forename><surname>Morrison</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><surname>Chalmers</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="210" to="221" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>EPM technology and the work environment. New Technology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kjeld</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liam</forename><surname>Bannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Taking CSCW Supporting articulation work</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-84800-068-1_3</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Support Coop Work</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Employee and customer perceptions of service in Replication and extension</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bowen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0021-9010.70.3.423</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Appl. Psycho</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">70</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="433" />
			<date type="published" when="1985">1985</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The whereabouts Early testing of a situated awareness device</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abigail</forename><surname>Sellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Eardley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shahram</forename><surname>Izadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harper</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">6</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1125451.1125694</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/1125451.1125694" />
		<title level="m">Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing (CHI EA &apos;06)</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1307" to="1312" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adverse health effects conditions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Siegrist</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Occup Health Psychol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<publisher>DOI</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Driver performance appraisal GPS terminal measurements</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Baris</forename><surname>Şimşek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fatma</forename><surname>Pakdil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Berna</forename><surname>Dengiz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Murat Caner</forename><surname>Testik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.trc.2012.07.006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.trc.2012.07.006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">A conceptual Research Part C: Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="60" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pascale</forename><surname>Carayon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<pubPlace>Katherine J. Sanders, S</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Employee stress and health complaints in jobs with and without performance monitoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Legrande</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/0003-</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/0003-" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Appl Ergon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">We&apos;ve bin watching you&quot;: Designing for reflection and social persuasion to promote lifestyles</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rannie</forename><surname>Teodoro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pinar</forename><surname>Ozturk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mor</forename><surname>Naaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Winter</forename><surname>Mason</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janne</forename><surname>Lindqvist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.timesheetmobile.com/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 17 th ACM conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing (CSCW&apos;14)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Rob Comber, Julia Miebach, Jack Weeden, Nicole Kraemer, Shaun Lawson, and Patrick</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2014. 2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2337" to="2346" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems &apos;12)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Time thieves and invaders: Technology, work and the organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Towers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linda</forename><surname>Duxbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Higgins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1108/09534810610686076</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1108/09534810610686076" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">of Organizational Change Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="593" to="618" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Questionable concepts: critique as resource for with eighty somethings</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Vines</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Blythe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Lindsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">Andrew</forename><surname>Monk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Olivier</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Systems (CHI &apos;12)</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1169" to="1178" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wearables in the workplace</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Business Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013-09">2013. September 2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The impact of privacy concern on adoption of location-based services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tao</forename><surname>Zhou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1108/02635571111115146</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1108/02635571111115146" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ind Manage Data Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="212" to="226" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Where is the line between benign and invasive? An examination of barriers to the acceptance of awareness monitoring systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jane</forename><surname>Zweig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Webster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/job.157</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/job.157" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J Organ Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="605" to="633" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
