<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Constrained Life in a Multifarious Environment -A Closer Look at the Lives of Autistic College Students</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><roleName>Md</roleName><forename type="first">Shameem</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
							<email>ahmeds@wwu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Md</forename><forename type="middle">Monsur</forename><surname>Hossain</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Cody</forename><surname>Pranger</surname></persName>
							<email>codypranger@gmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Ashima</forename><surname>Shrivastava</surname></persName>
							<email>ashimashrivastava94@gmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Gildner</surname></persName>
							<email>joegildner0@gmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Mcculloch</surname></persName>
							<email>seannmmcculloch@gmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Moushumi</forename><forename type="middle">2022</forename><surname>Sharmin</surname></persName>
							<email>moushumi.sharmin@wwu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Monsur</forename><surname>Hossain</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Mitch</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kim- Ball</surname></persName>
							<email>mitchkimball16@gmail.com</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><surname>Constrained</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Western Washington University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Flexport Inc</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Western Washington University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Mitch J Kimball Expeditors</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<address>
									<settlement>Pantheon Platform, San Francisco</settlement>
									<region>CA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="institution">VMWare</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>Washington</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="institution">Allan Institute of Brain Science</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>WA</region>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Western Washington University</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Constrained Life in a Multifarious Environment -A Closer Look at the Lives of Autistic College Students</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3517788</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:02+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>ASD</term>
					<term>Autism</term>
					<term>College Students</term>
					<term>Fitbit</term>
					<term>Mobile Phone</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>For many students, attending college is a dramatic but necessary change. To gain a better understanding of experiences that are unique to autistic college students, we conducted a mixed-method study with 20 students (10 autistic and 10 neurotypical). We collected physiological, contextual, experience, and environmental data from their natural environment using Fitbit and smartphones. We found that stress patterns, emotional states, and physical states are similar for both groups. Our autistic participants prioritized academic success over everything else, often intentionally confining their movements among academic, resident, and work locations to engage themselves with academic work as much as possible. They had a small number of friends, always preferring quality over quantity and sometimes regarding friends as close as family members. To maintain a better social life, they extensively used social media. They slept more than neurotypical participants per day; however, they experienced lower sleep quality.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Human-centered computing → Accessibility; Empirical studies in accessibility.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>The Autism and Developmental Disabilities Monitoring (ADDM) network of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) estimated that about 1 in 54 children in the USA has been diagnosed with autism spectrum disorder (ASD) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. In the USA, over half a million children with ASD will be in their adulthood over the next decade <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2]</ref>, and 45% of them will pursue post-secondary degrees <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3]</ref>. Unfortunately, only 38.8% of post-secondary students with ASD will complete their degrees <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b2">3]</ref>. To prevent this significant dropout, we need to understand the experience of post-secondary (college) autistic students, the challenges they face, and their current practices of addressing these challenges. Prior studies shed light on this topic <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref> by using qualitative methods (e.g., surveys, interviews), which offered critical insight into their experiences. However, such research offers limited detail of the unique experience of autistic college students, which we aim to address by analyzing and comparing data collected from interviews and field studies from autistic and neurotypical college students. While interviews enabled us to learn about the overall college experience, data collected from the field study offered important details pertaining to these experiences. Analysis of data from neurotypical and autistic participants enabled the identification of unique experiences of each group in the college setting.</p><p>The advancement of smart and wearable technologies has enabled us to collect users' physiological (e.g., heart rate, sleep, step count), contextual (e.g., location, time of the day), experience (e.g., stress values, emotional states, physical states, social engagement), and environmental data (e.g., sound, light) from the natural environment. Such objective, continuous, and contextual data has offered unique opportunities to identify important details about everyday life experiences and identify factors contributing to complex behavioral and health issues, which may guide the design of evidence-based interventions <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">35]</ref>. Researchers have been using smartphones and wearable technology for the management of behavioral health issues in areas such as smoking and addiction management <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>. Research in these areas has inspired us to investigate the effectiveness of combining objective data collected from the natural environment with subjective data collected via interviews and surveys to identify factors contributing to the challenges of autistic college students. Such combined data may assist in the design of evidence-based interventions that may help autistic students better address their challenges and aid policymakers in designing a better college experience for all students.</p><p>We conducted a mixed-method study <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[30]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[31]</ref> with 20 college students (10 autistic and 10 neurotypical) from two US-based postsecondary institutions. Our study consisted of a pre-interview, followed by a week-long field study, and a post-interview for each participant. From the field study, we collected 1,737,625 units of heart rate, 318,863 units of geo-location, 315,345 units of step count, 1,146.3 hours of sleep, and 442 EMA (Ecological Momentary Assessment) responses, answering 5,336 individual questions using Fitbit and smartphone. In this paper, we make the following contributions:</p><p>• Our study demonstrated the feasibility of collecting large amounts of objective, continuous, and personalized data from autistic college students from their natural environment using lightweight, commercially available wearable sensors. • The analysis of the field study data and qualitative interviews helped us get deeper insights into the lives of autistic students. We compared data collected from both neurotypical students and autistic students and identified the similarities and differences between these two groups. While some of our findings contradicted the current literature, other findings confirmed the current understanding. For the latter, we offered critical details and different perspectives that were missing in the existing literature.</p><p>Our research involved collecting sensitive data and included discussions on topics that were emotional and difficult. During the study, we tried our best to maintain an open and positive environment for all participants. In this paper, we strive to keep an open and neutral tone when reporting our findings. We are aware of the ongoing disagreement related to how autism should be reported/addressed (people first vs. identity-first language) <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref>. We also asked our participants about their preferences, and none of them suggested a strong preference for one over the other. We respect these varying perspectives. However, to ensure that readers don't need to go back and forth between these two perspectives, we decided to use the identify-first language in our paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED WORK 2.1 Autism and College Students</head><p>In 2014, Gelber et al. conducted a systematic literature review to understand the experience of autistic college students <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. They analyzed 18 case studies with two experimental intervention studies and reported that autistic students feel anxious, lonely, and depressed and require support for both academic and non-academic issues. In 2017, Anderson et al. conducted a similar systematic literature review <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>. They analyzed 23 studies and found that autistic students experience more difficulty related to non-academic issues (e.g., social interaction, mental health, sensory sensitivities, and daily living skill) than academic issues (e.g., understanding abstract concepts, group work, presentation, and poor concentration while studying). In 2018, Anderson et al. conducted an online survey (N=59), which was distributed to autistic students and reported that autistic students struggle with both academic and non-academic aspects due to a lack of support <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The authors also pointed out that autistic students are concerned with anxiety, loneliness, and depression, which were supported by another online survey (N=56) distributed to autistic college students in the USA in 2018 <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. In 2019, Nuske et al. conducted a systematic literature review to understand the experiences of autistic individuals and their family members, especially during the transition period to higher education <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[69]</ref>. They analyzed 11 articles and leveraged the biological theory model for their analysis. They found that the challenges of autistic individuals were related to autism's core features, self-disclosure and awareness, and mental health and wellbeing. McLeod et al. conducted an online survey and collected data from 3,073 college students (95 ASD) from 14 public universities in the USA <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[70]</ref>. They compared autistic students with their neurotypical peers using the following metrics: academic performance, social relationships and bullying, and physical and mental health. They found that autistic students showed substantially poor results in all these metrics. They also reported that autistic students suffered from stigma and social rejection related to their disability rather than autism's core features. They utilized the same survey data to compare the six physical and mental health outcomes of these two groups (ASD vs. neurotypical college students) <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">[71]</ref>. They found that autistic students showed worse outcomes in case of self-reported physical and mental health, depression, and anxiety.</p><p>Jennifer Sarrett conducted a survey (N=66) followed by an online focus group (N=31) to understand the accommodations autistic students received and the accommodations they desired <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. Around one-third of the participants who utilized services at their institutes were not satisfied with the provided services and expressed a need for additional support and services such as increased autism awareness on campus, sensory-friendly spaces and practices, and access to mentorship programs. White et al. reported that, unfortunately, many neurotypical students who were knowledgeable about autism still showed negative attitudes toward autistic students <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>. Gobbo and Shmulsky reported that along with neurotypical students, faculty, advisors, and disability officers should understand the challenges faced by autistic students and utilize appropriate strategies to accommodate their needs <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>. Accardo et al. conducted sequential mixed methods (non-experimental survey, followed by semi-structured interviews) to understand the preference of autistic students in terms of their accommodations and support services <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. They reported that autistic students preferred to have extra time during tests, to receive a copy of instructor notes, to be able to do priority registration, to get academic coaching, to have access to faculty office hours before the course registration begins, and to have more personalized access to support.</p><p>Lucas and James examined the mentorship programs in the colleges from ASD and MHC (Mental Health Conditions) perspectives <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. Their mixed-method study (online questionnaires and interviews) revealed that such a mentorship program is beneficial for both types of students (ASD and MHC); however, to make the mentorship program more effective, a tailored partnership between mentor and mentee is required. Rather than including college students in their studies, Elias and White wanted to know the perspective of the parents of students with ASD and Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. Surveying 99 parents of college students with ASD (N=52) and ADHD (N=47), the authors aimed to identify the needs of these students and reported that parents in the ASD group requested two specific services for their college-going children: social interaction training and independent living training. Stephanie Pinder-Amaker suggested that improved secondary and post-secondary education systems may achieve fluid transitions <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref>. DeNigris et al. conducted an online survey followed by interview sessions with both college students with ASD and neurotypical college students to understand and compare bullying experiences during college <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>. More specifically, the authors aimed to examine if the 'double empathy problem' contributed to the risk of being bullied and reported that 21% of autistic students were bullied in college.</p><p>Experience in college life is not restricted to academic activities only; consequently, focusing on academic perspectives alone may offer an incomplete view of the experience of students' college life. Several studies mentioned above also relied upon subjective data, which provided a critical understanding of the experience and opinion. We extend this thread of research by collecting both objective and subjective data related to life at college, which offers new findings and confirms previous findings with new insights about the academic and non-academic aspects of the lives of autistic college students.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Autism, College Students, and Wearable Technology</head><p>The prevalence, affordability, and portability of mobile and wearable technologies have inspired researchers to focus on utilizing such technologies to help autistic individuals. Many of the researchers focused on the challenges of children with ASD, and only a few research focused on using wearable devices for autistic adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>.</p><p>Zheng and Motti utilized a user-centric design process to develop WELI (Wearable Life), a mobile and wearable app, to help postsecondary students with Intellectual and Developmental Disabilities (IDD) <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24]</ref>. They conducted eight studies with 58 participants (37 assistants, 21 students). The two-year-long study helped the researchers to finalize WELI's features (intervention, mood regulation, reminders, checklists, surveys, and rewards). Simm et al. followed a participatory approach and iteratively developed a prototype of a digital stretch band called Snap <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>, which helped autistic adults to manage their anxiety. Victor Dibia designed a smartwatch application called FOQUS to assist adults with mental health conditions (ADHD, attention deficiency) to reduce their anxiety and stress <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>. Based on an initial survey, Cirillo included three different features in FOQUS: Pomodoro time management technique, mindful meditation, and message-based priming <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[36]</ref>.</p><p>These studies utilized wearable devices and smartphone apps to help adults with mental health conditions. None of these studies mentioned above used wearable devices to collect objective, continuous, and personalized data from the natural environment. Access to such information can offer critical insight into their college experience. It can also aid in the design of the evidence-based intervention, which can improve the experience of autistic students. Our study aims to fill this gap.</p><p>Some recent studies measured the heart rate variability of autistic individuals. However, these studies were conducted in lab settings for a limited amount of time, where ECG data was measured using an ECG recording device <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[44,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">63,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">64,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">72,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">77]</ref>. For instance, Dijkhuis et al. conducted a lab study with 51 young autistic adults and 28 typically developing control users <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">[72]</ref>. In the study, all participants had to complete a public speaking task (around 25 minutes long). The authors measured their heart rate and heart rate variability (HRV) by placing two ECG electrodes on the chest of the participants. The authors didn't find any significant group differences in baseline HR, HRV, HR reactivity, or self-reported emotional awareness. However, the authors reported that autistic young adults displayed considerably lower HRV reactivity than typically developing controls.</p><p>There is a significant difference between the studies mentioned above and our study. Instead of the lab setting, we conducted our field study in the natural environment of autistic college students. For each participant, we collected continuous data for at least one week. Finally, we used Fitbit, a commercially available wearable device, to collect heart rate information, which many individuals use in their daily lives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHODOLOGY 3.1 User Recruitment and User Profile</head><p>We conducted our study in two mid-size post-secondary institutions (∼16,000 and ∼13,000 students) in the USA from February 2018 to June 2018 and from Oct 2018 to April 2019. We conducted the study during typical academic weeks, excluding final exam week and the first week of class, to ensure that well-known stressors (e.g., moving to campus, final exams) will not influence the data. After receiving IRB approval, we advertised our study through flyers, posters, and social media to recruit participants. We also collaborated with a local autism center to recruit eligible participants. We discussed the research goal and nature of the study with psychiatrists and therapists working in the autism center and shared recruitment materials with them to share with potential participants. We answered questions regarding study design, the technology used, and data collection with the autism center staff and shared our contact information so that they could reach out to the research team for any follow-up questions. In addition, after completing the post-interview with individual participants, we requested them to share study information with eligible and potentially interested participants.</p><p>We recruited 20 participants (10 autistic, 10 neurotypical) who were at least 18 years of age pursuing their post-secondary degrees. Twelve participants were male, seven female, and one non-binary. Of the ten autistic students, two identified as female, and one identified as non-binary. The disparity in the diagnosed population of male and female autistic individuals may contribute to the imbalance in our participants from different gender categories. All autistic participants in our study are in level 1 or high-functioning (self-rated), verbal, and academically high-achievers (self-reported GPA of 3 or above, except P17). Of the neurotypical participants (m=5, f=5), we have a better gender balance. Eighteen participants were between 18 to 25 years old, one participant was between 30 to 35 years old, and the remaining participant didn't disclose her age. Our participants came from different academic degree programs (e.g., Computer Science, Cyber Security, Finance, Marine Biology, Physics, Political Science, Accounting, Anthropology, Geology, and Sociology) and multiple levels of study (e.g., freshman, sophomore, junior, senior, and associate degree). All autistic participants reported being "clinically diagnosed" with autism. One of the primary goals of this study is to understand the feasibility of using wearable sensors for collecting data from the natural environment from autistic students, and as such, we stopped recruitment when we gathered data from 10 autistic participants, aiming to identify the potential strength and limitations of our study mechanism. To create a balanced dataset for analysis, we also collected data from 10 neurotypical students. While collecting data from more participants would offer stronger insight, we believe that our current sample size was sufficient to answer our research questions. See Table <ref type="table">1</ref> for summary demographic information of the participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Study Design</head><p>For each participant, our study involved three phases: a preinterview, a one-week-long field study, and a post-interview.</p><p>3.2.1 Pre-Interview. We conducted a preliminary semi-structured interview to learn about participants' overall experiences in college settings. Pre-interview questions focused on 1) Demographic information, 2) Academic experience, 3) College life expectations and experience, and 4) Challenges faced during college life. Two or three members of the research team conducted the pre-interview in a closed office space. Participants were given the consent form before the interview and assured that they could skip answering any questions and stop the interview session at any time if they desired. One of the research team members asked the questions while the other took notes. A few participants skipped answering one question (related to bullying experience), but none terminated the interview or opted out of the study. See Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">2</ref> for sample questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Field Study.</head><p>For the field study, we gave each participant a Fitbit Charge 2 (https://www.fitbit.com/global/us/charge2), a commercially available wearable device, and an Android smartphone with our app installed on it. We chose Fitbit as this is one of the most popular commercial smartwatches, and the use of Fitbit will not draw additional attention to our participants. For example, in 2020, 31 million active users used Fitbit products at least once a week <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">[58]</ref>. We asked participants to wear the Fitbit all the time (except during showers) and to carry the smartphone while they were awake. The smartphone app prompted EMA (Ecological Momentary Assessment) questionnaires three times a day to collect information about the participant's self-reported stress, emotional states, and social engagement. Our choice of using EMA was inspired by prior research that effectively used EMA to gather data from the natural environment in the domains of addictive management and mental health conditions <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">33]</ref>. EMAs were also successfully used to gather data related to stress factors and coping mechanisms from adolescents with high functioning autism <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26]</ref>, indicating that EMAs would be an effective data gathering tool from our target population. In our research, we used EMAs to collect data that would be difficult to collect objectively using sensors or introduce privacy risks. For example, wearable cameras would help collect data about social engagement but would compromise the privacy of the participants and the individuals who interacted with them during the study period. However, such data were important to collect as they provided an important context in understanding participants' mental states. While the benefits of using EMAs are many, we were also cautious about how many EMAs can be triggered without overburdening the users and disrupting their daily lives. To address this, we designed EMAs in a way that would require less than a few minutes to complete. To make the EMAs intuitive and meaningful, we made the questionnaire dynamic where each question depended on the responses to the previous questions.</p><p>We requested each participant to select three specific time windows when they would prefer to receive these EMA prompts. While delivering more EMAs would enable us to collect more data and would help with the analysis, it would also result in participation fatigue, which we aimed to avoid. In our design, EMAs were prompted at the pre-selected time windows, and participants could respond to them at that time or later when the participants became available.</p><p>We did not prompt participants to respond to the EMAs after they were delivered to limit interruption on their daily activities. See Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">2</ref> for sample EMA questions and Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> (left) for a sample screenshot of the EMA app. The app also enabled participants to report their stress information proactively. Participants had full right and control to turn the wearable and the app off if they did not want to share any information. However, none of them stopped sharing data during the study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3">Post-Interview.</head><p>After the field study, each participant returned for a post-interview to discuss their experience with the wearable and the data collection app. We also showed participants their data collected using the wearables and asked questions to verify data accuracy for stress, sleep, and step count, to learn details for different locations visited, and to discuss emotional states reported in the EMAs. See Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">2</ref> for sample questions asked during postinterviews. We also showed each participant a set of visualizations (provided by Fitbit and created by the research team, see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> (center and right) during the post-interview. All participants confirmed that sensor data accurately reflected their physiological condition, location, and activities that occurred during the field study. P9's mother was with them during the post-interview as per their request. P9 expressed an interest in sharing the interview experience with their mother and asked the research team if it would be okay for her to be in the space. Although she was not part of the interview process, she voluntarily chimed in to clarify some answers provided by P9.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Data Collection and Analysis</head><p>3.3.1 Data collection from the field study. We collected data from the field by using the smartphone app and Fitbit. We used the Fitbit API to collect heart rate, step count, and sleep duration. As mentioned before, all data were collected during typical academic weeks, excluding final exam week and the first week of class, to ensure that well-known stressors (e.g., moving to campus, final exams) will not influence the data. During the field study, we did not contact or remind the participants about wearing or carrying the sensors.</p><p>During the field study, participants had access to all data and associated representations. In total, we collected 1,737,625 units of heart rate data (on average, 86,881 data points per participant) and 1,146.3 hours of sleep data collected from a total of 146 days. We excluded the sleep data of participant 11 from the analysis as this participant forgot to wear Fitbit all night except one night during the study. We used the Fitbit API to quantify the sleep quality in each sleep cycle (e.g., deep sleep, light sleep, Rapid Eye Movement (REM), and awake time). Also, we collected 315,345 units of step count from Fitbit. Our smartphone app collected participants' precise locations every 20 seconds, resulting in 318,863 data points. All data was uploaded to a secure server in near real-time if an internet connection was available. Otherwise, the app stored the data locally on the device as a fallback. The Fitbit device synchronized the data in 15 minutes intervals if the internet was available. We collected 170,801 units of light data (brightness) and 1,402,779 units of sound data (amplitude) using the study phone. We received 442 EMA responses (ASD: 201, Neurotypical: 241), responding to 5,336 individual questions (ASD: 2,366 and Neurotypical: 2970). We also received 112 stress values proactively self-reported by our participants using the mobile app.</p><p>3.3.2 Qualitative Data Analysis. Both pre-interview and postinterview sessions were audio-recorded (with participants' consent) and later transcribed by members of the research team. We imported transcripts into Atlas.ti <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43]</ref>, read those transcripts, and applied qualitative analysis technique <ref type="bibr">[74]</ref>. In the first coding cycle, we applied initial coding (also known as open coding in the grounded theory <ref type="bibr">[75]</ref>). In this cycle, we reflected deeply on the interview contents and identified concepts, experiences, and interactions repeatedly mentioned in the transcripts. In total, we identified 46 codes from the pre-interviews (e.g., College-Challenges, College-Expectation, Participant-Recreation, Academic-Challenges, College-ImportanceOfDegree) and 34 codes from the post-interviews (e.g., StressLevel, HighStress-Cause, HighStress-Impact, Sleep, Social Media). In the second coding cycle, we applied axial coding to determine the high-level themes after comparing and consolidating these initial categories. Finally, we used theoretical coding (also known as selective coding in the grounded theory [75]) to build relationships among the themes we identified in the axial coding phase. Three members of the research team participated in the coding phases. There were a few disagreements that we resolved via discussion. Since there were only a few disagreements among the three coders, we did not compute inter-coder reliability, an approach used in <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> which had similar situations like us and mentioned that the major approaches of grounded theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38,</ref><ref type="bibr">75]</ref>  We showed these visualizations to our participants during the postinterview sessions to validate the accuracy of the data and asked them to clarify data points or their EMA responses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.4">Participants' Privacy and Security.</head><p>We conducted all interviews in closed-door rooms, and all data were referred to by codes assigned to the participants. We also attached codes to represent the data collected by Fitbit and smartphones. During data collection, to ensure the privacy of the participants and the people who interacted with them, we only recorded audio amplitude and not the actual audio. We also informed the participants that they could turn off the data collection app and take off the Fitbit at any time if they wanted to. None of our participants turned off the app or took off the Fitbit during the field study. We kept all codes and all personally identifiable information securely in a password-protected place, limiting access to the members of the research team only. To maintain participants' privacy, we didn't disclose any identifiable information and reported all data either in an aggregated manner or using pre-assigned codes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">FINDINGS</head><p>In this section, we report findings from our mixed-method study combining qualitative and quantitative data. Qualitative data enabled us to learn about participants' opinions and experiences through interviews, EMAs, and self-reports. For qualitative data, we primarily report the experiences of autistic participants and include quotes only from them. We provided quotes from the neurotypical participants whenever we found them relevant and necessary. It is important to note that the findings that we report, and their implications are based on our study participants, which are small (10 autistic and 10 neurotypical students). As such, the findings we report may not be reflective of all autistic college students. In addition, we report data on stress, sleep, and navigation pattern, which can depend on personal characteristics as well as on neurodivergence. Despite the small participant size, we collected millions of data points, which enabled us to identify patterns. We found significant differences between autistic and neurotypical participants for some quantitative data (e.g., navigation patterns), while we didn't see much difference for other data (e.g., stress). We report all quantitative findings irrespective of whether there were differences between data from autistic and neurotypical students.</p><p>As the focus of our research is to gain a better understanding of the experience of autistic college students, we believe that even when there are no differences between autistic and neurotypical participants' data, these results still convey valuable insights about actual living practices and experiences of autistic college students.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Perceived Stress Intensity and Stress Management Practices</head><p>During the week-long field study, our participants reported their stress values in two ways: by answering EMA and by proactively reporting stress values. We want to clarify that four participants (P9, P16, P18, and P20) had the devices more than one week. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> shows the stress reported by our participants. Here, "# of stress reported" means how many times the participants reported their stress values. For instance, autistic participants reported stress 211 times (30 times self-reported +181 times via EMA), while neurotypical participants reported 309 times (82 times self-reported + 227 times via EMA). We found that, on a scale of 0-9 (0 is the lowest stress, 9 is the highest stress), neurotypical participants showed a slightly lower average stress (3.51, std. dev= 2.68) as opposed to autistic participants (3.56, std. dev=2.36). When we consider EMA report only or a combination of both EMA and self-reported stress,  our findings contradict the findings of the current literature. The average stress reported by neurotypical participants (EMA only: 3.14, std. dev = 2.32; EMA + Self-reported Stress: 3.24, std. dev = 2.42) was higher than the average stress reported by autistic participants (EMA only: 2.82, std. dev = 2.48; EMA + Self-reported stress: 2.93, std. dev=2.47). Although these results are not significant at α =0.05 after doing the t-tests, they still offer interesting perspectives that contradict the current literature.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> shows the stress histogram for both groups. In this figure, X-axis represents the stress value (0-9), and the Y-axis represents the frequency of how many times a stress value was reported by the participants. Here we observe that our autistic participants reported lowest stress (stress value: 0) 48 times (48/211=22.75%), medium stress (stress value: 5) 13 times (13/211=6.16%), and the highest stress (stress value: 9) 2 times (2/211=0.95%). On the contrary, our neurotypical participants reported lowest stress (stress value: 0) 45 times (45/309=14.56%), medium stress (stress value: 5) 24 times (24/309=7.76%), and the highest stress (stress value: 9) 7 times (7/309=2.27%). We also found that our autistic participants reported 154 times (72.99%) lower stress value (0-4), while neurotypical participants showed 218 times (70.55%) lower stress value (0-4).</p><p>We analyzed the heart rate data collected through Fitbit during the field study (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">4</ref>). We considered heart rate since speedup heart rate is a typical consequence of a stressful situation <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[67]</ref>. We collected 1,737,625 units of heart rate data (ASD: 849,576 units, Neurotypical: 888,049 units). Here we see that the average heart rates for both groups (Neurotypical: 75.4 bpm, std. dev=18.97, ASD: 76.3 bpm, std. dev=16.6) are very similar. As exposure to bright light and loud noise typically contributed to higher stress for autistic individuals <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[47]</ref>, we also collected light and sound data through the smartphone. We collected 170,801 units of light data (ASD: 57,059 units, Neurotypical: 113,742 units) and 1,402,779 units of sound data (ASD: 606,476 units, Neurotypical: 796,303 units) and found that during the study period, our autistic participants were less exposed to bright light and loud sounds than our neurotypical participants.</p><p>During the pre-and post-interviews, we asked each participant about their stress experience, specific stressors, and stress management practices in general (pre-interview) and during the study (post-interview). This discussion helped us to understand why our findings of stress differ from the current understanding. We found that our neurotypical participants, in general, lead a spontaneous life. They didn't have specific strategies for stress management thoughts about stressors but accepted that "college life will be stressful" as a fact of life. To quote P11, "Last week I had two essays due, an exam on Wednesday, and then [another one] on Friday. . .I didn't spend the last weekend doing homework. So, it was all piling up, so it was kind of stressful. I was doing things like last-minute [on] Friday. I made plans for Friday afternoon with a friend, but I wasn't able to enjoy myself because I had something to do that night at midnight, and I waited till Friday to do it, and so I was kind of stressing out. " (P11, F, Anthropology, Neurotypical) On the contrary, our autistic participants were very aware of potential stressors and talked about using specific stress management strategies. They mentioned carefully planning their academic workloads, were more structured in their routines, and less willing to expose themselves to unknown situations and potential stressors. When we inquired about academic planning, autistic participants mentioned "extensive research" to find a manageable course load for themselves. Such research involved going through reviews on the instructors on systems such as RateMyProfessor, looking for course format (e.g., lecture, lab, exams, and presentation), and distribution of grades. All autistic participants also mentioned taking a course load that they considered manageable with their other responsibilities (e.g., work). To quote P14: "I don't want to be over-occupied. . .Right now, with 14 credits, I'm pretty comfortable with the workload that I have. Over time I'll probably try taking more credits at the same time, but I don't want to end up in a situation where I have too much to handle. " (P14, M, Freshman, Major undecided, ASD) When asked about places they typically visit for socializing or events they attend, our autistic participants mentioned only going to locations that are less likely to trigger anxiety. Such 'appropriate' places were not crowded or cluttered, relatively quiet, and known to be devoid of heavy human traffic. To quote P1, "[I] rarely [go to bars], but only if my friend is going. But I like a quiet bar. There is a cabaret that I like, but that is the most violent [place]." (P1, M, Senior, Political Science, ASD)</p><p>Our autistic participants mentioned a dislike for 'group work.' As part of their 'stress management strategy,' they were actively looking for ways to avoid 'group work. ' Several autistic participants had difficulty communicating efficiently with classmates. It took a while for them to open up and understand their group mates, which they believed impacted their ability to contribute effectively. Another reason that made group projects undesirable is an apparent 'lack of motivation' or 'seriousness' from other group members.</p><p>The following quote reflects their opinions about academic group work:</p><p>"Honestly, I hate group projects. They are so stressful, especially when you don't know anybody [in the group]. . .We have to put each other's grades in each other's hands. It is really stressful. . .It would just be easier to do it on your own. " (P17, non-binary, Freshman, Marine Biology, ASD) These different aspects made group work one of the most challenging and stressful aspects of the college experience for our autistic participants. Hence, our autistic participants mentioned trying to look for courses that don't require group work whenever possible. P7 said that she "avoided group settings as much as possible" because she "only gets stressed when there's disagreement, and you have to fight for your answers or accept that you're wrong. " For classes that had mandatory group work, our autistic participants mentioned trying to ask for accommodations from professors to work alone.</p><p>In summary, we speculate that the 'lower experienced stress intensity' in our autistic participants is a result of awareness of stress and potential stressors and careful planning by our autistic participants and not coincidental that contradicts the stance on the stress of existing literature.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Emotional and Physical States Experienced at College</head><p>Our participants reported momentary (current or in-the-moment) emotional states through EMA (). The participants were given options to choose from (Neutral, Happy, Anxious, Frustrated, and Sad). If none of these options reflected their momentary emotional state, they could select the 'others' option with an explanation. Both groups reported either being Happy or Neutral most of the time (ASD: 66.8%, Neurotypical: 67.5%). The other three emotional states also did not vary much: Anxious (ASD: 18.6%, Neurotypical: 19.6%), Frustrated (ASD: 6.5%, Neurotypical: 9.6%), and Sad (ASD: 1.5%, Neurotypical: 3.3%). We also found that our autistic participants reported 13 emotional states (6.5%) as 'Others, ' which included tired, annoyed, contemplative, focused, impatient, lost in thought, preoccupied, relieved, and stressed. Our data indicated that autistic and neurotypical students did not have many differences in their self-reported emotional states.</p><p>Our participants also reported their momentary physical state through EMA (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_5">6</ref>). The participants were given two options to choose from (well-rested and exhausted). If no options reflected their current physical state, they could select the 'others' option with an explanation. Both groups reported being well-rested most of the time (ASD: 59.0%, Neurotypical: 60.4%). They had a similar pattern for 'exhausted' physical state (ASD: 30.3%, Neurotypical: 31.3%). Although there was no option for 'Tired, ' both groups reported different forms of this physical state (e.g., a bit tired, mildly tired, etc.) as the 'others' option. The table shows that the 'tired' option has a similar pattern (ASD: 5.6%, Neurotypical: 6.3%). However, autistic participants selected the 'Others' option (5.1%) more times than the neurotypical participants (2.1%). The 'others' options answered by autistic participants included: emotionally drained, energetic, fatigued, fine, groggy, hungry, and neutral. On the contrary, the options provided by neurotypical participants were: early morning haziness, getting over a cold, hungover, and in between rested and exhausted. In summary, we didn't find much difference between these two groups about their self-reported physical states.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Navigation Pattern</head><p>We collected location information using GPS sensors resulting in 318,863 data points (ASD: 139,685, Neurotypical: 179,178). After plotting these GPS data points to the location plotter of our visual analytic tools, we found that autistic participants primarily focused on academic activities in their day-to-day lives. Their navigations were highly focused on various academic buildings, work (when applicable), and home. Data collected from neurotypical students show a clear difference as they visited many places outside their academic buildings and home (e.g., trips to other cities). The geographical areas traveled by neurotypical participants were different from autistic participants. The of autistic participants were concentrated in and around their academic and living areas, while neurotypical participants covered a much larger area spanning several nearby cities.</p><p>This focused navigation also contributed to relatively less physical activity for autistic participants, supported by the step count data. Existing research recommends that each person should complete 10,000 steps per day to maintain good physical health <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[73]</ref>. We collected 315,345 units of step count (ASD: 171,345, Neurotypical: 144,000) (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_6">7</ref>). We found that neither of these two groups, on average, fulfilled that 10,000 steps goal. The average daily step counts were 8,142 and 5,168 for our neurotypical and autistic participants, respectively. Results from the t-test revealed that the t-value is -2.44, the p-value is .013, and the result is significant at p &lt;.05.</p><p>Our participants also self-reported their current location during the field study through EMA (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_7">8</ref>). We received 440 self-reported locations (ASD: 199 and Neurotypical: 241). Our data showed that autistic participants stayed at home, dormitory, or school 86.93% of the time, while neurotypical participants stayed at those places 77.18% of the time. The table shows two significant differences between these two groups. Our neurotypical participants visited the houses of parents, grandparents, or friends 10.37% of the time, while our autistic participants never reported any such visits during their week-long field study. Also, our neurotypical participants were at work 5.39% of the time, while our autistic participants were at work only 0.5% of the time. The other places for autistic participants were grocery stores, the department of licensing, furniture stores, and parking lots. On the contrary, the other places for neurotypical participants were grocery stores, gyms, on the road, soccer fields, and restaurants and cafes.</p><p>In summary, the navigation pattern and step count information combined with self-reported location information collected via EMAs indicate a difference in navigation style between our autistic participants and their neurotypical peers.</p><p>During the post-interview, we showed all participants their navigation data on our visual analytic tools, and all participants agreed that the navigation data were accurate. Our neurotypical participants mentioned spending their free time hanging out with friends, engaging in outdoor activities, attending special events (concerts), visiting friends and family in and out of town, and going to bars and gyms. On the contrary, our autistic participants reported spending their time primarily in academic buildings and their homes and needed trips to grocery stores. To quote P14, "I do my tutoring. So [I] usually [go to] just home, school, then tutoring then home again. It's just my every day. I went grocery shopping once or twice." (P14, M, Freshman, Major undecided, ASD) Our neurotypical participants mentioned going to various places on weekends while autistic participants mentioned relaxing at home, which is highlighted by the following quote:</p><p>"I usually stay home on Saturday and Sunday. " (P4, M, Junior, Physics, ASD) Analysis of the pre-and post-interview data revealed that most of our autistic participants considered attending college a top priority, to be able to pursue a career that they prefer, which will ensure financial independence. These considerations made academic activities highly important to them. Unlike our neurotypical participants, they often viewed socialization as a 'responsibility' rather than an opportunity to relax and often skipped them in favor of preparing for academic activities and maintaining academic success. To quote P9, "Studying is your duty because you want to get an education and pursue a career that catches your interest. But if you want to meet people or interact, it's like a side thing you have to do. " (P9, M, 2nd year Associates Degree, Cyber Security, ASD) None of our autistic participants mentioned missing a class or showing up late for a class unless they had a medical condition. The following quote highlights their attitude towards attending classes:</p><p>"Every time there is a class, I will attend it on time." (P10, M, sophomore, Major undecided, ASD) In summary, our autistic participants valued their academic success greatly and tried to engage themselves with academic work as much as possible, favoring them over socialization. The specific navigation style that we observed was preferred by our participants and reflected their goals and priorities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Sleep Cycles and Sleep Duration</head><p>Researchers classified sleep into two categories: Rapid Eye Movement (REM) and Non-Rapid Eye Movement (NREM) <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46]</ref>. An adult typically sleeps in four to five cycles in each sleep cycle, alternating NREM and REM sleep. NREM has little or no eye movement, while REM is wake-like and is associated with dreaming and a more activated brain <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref>. NREM is divided into four stages, corresponding to the increasing depth of sleep. REM helps to preserve certain types of memories <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27]</ref> and aids the process by which creativity forms <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref>. Fitbit classifies the four stages of NREM into two: light sleep and deep sleep. Fitbit also detects REM sleep. To detect the different sleep stages, Fitbit utilizes two separate features: the body movement of the users and their heart-rate patterns <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>. Fitbit assumes a person is asleep if they don't move for about an hour <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>. Fitbit also exploits the length of body movement (e.g., rolling over) to detect sleep behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>. A person's HRV fluctuates when they transit from NREM to REM sleep; Fitbit uses this fluctuation to detect the transition <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>. Notably, Fitbit requires at least 3 hours of sleep data to estimate sleep stages (REM, Light, and Deep) <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>. Hence, if a participant takes a short nap, that will be included in the total sleep time, but the duration for sleep stages won't be updated.</p><p>A recent study showed that Fitbit's sleep tracking accuracy is comparable to devices used in clinical sleep studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[50]</ref>. In our study, we collected sleep information along with different sleep categories from Fitbit's sleep API. Using Fitbit's sleep tracking feature, we collected 1,146.3 hours of sleep data (ASD: 615.78 hours, Neurotypical: 530.52 hours) from 146 days (ASD: 75 days, Neurotypical: 71 days). Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">9</ref> summarizes the sleep data of our participants. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_8">9</ref> shows that, on average, our autistic participants (485.3 minutes) slept 40.9 minutes more than neurotypical participants per day (444.4 minutes). Here, we considered actual sleep time per day (Time in bed per day-Awake time per day during sleep cycle). Despite this extra sleep, autistic participants had 17.8 minutes more awake time (during the sleep cycle) than neurotypical participants per day. We also found that autistic participants awake more frequently (28.4 times per day) than neurotypical participants (27.9 times per day). Typically, adults wake up 10-30 times per night <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>, that both neurotypical participants and autistic participants were following the typical range. However, further analysis revealed that 'wake-up' episodes of autistic individuals were distributed throughout their sleep cycles. In contrast, for neurotypical participants, 'wake up' episodes typically occurred in the beginning or towards the end of their sleep cycles.</p><p>Although we did not observe a significant difference between these two groups based on overall sleep length, we found a significant difference when we only considered REM (Rapid Eye Movement) sleep. REM plays a significant role in emotion regulation and memory, and too little REM has negative consequences on health <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[28]</ref>. The healthy range of REM is 20-25% of the total sleep <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. Our autistic participants had 13.5% REM (lower than the normal range), while neurotypical participants had 19.5% REM (close to the normal range). After doing the t-test on REM data, we found that the t-value is -1.38, the p-value is .09, and the result is significant p &lt;.10. We also found that our autistic participants had 27.5 minutes more light sleep and 15.4 minutes less deep sleep than our neurotypical participants.</p><p>Our participants validated their sleep data during the postinterview and discussed their opinions about sleep quality. While almost all participants had an overall idea about their sleep quality, one participant, P15, was surprised to see her sleep quality data visualization. To quote P15, "I was really surprised at how little deep sleep I get, according to the Fitbit. It was really interesting. " (P15, F, Senior, Computer Science, ASD) Other participants, while unaware of their sleep quality details, had a sense of the poor sleep quality that they experienced. For example, several autistic participants mentioned problems falling asleep and staying asleep. To quote P1: "It can take an hour to get to sleep." (P1, M, Senior, Political Science, ASD) Although our autistic participants were aware of their poor sleep quality, they were unsure about the factors contributing to such poor sleep quality. When we showed P9 that his heart rate had an spike around 2:45 am and at 3:15 am on a particular night, P9's mother, who was present during the post-interview, showed concern and wondered if her son needed to visit a doctor as prior to the interview she was unaware of her son's sleep issues. To quote her, "He (P9) tends to get up in the mornings and act like he had the best sleep ever. " (P9's mother)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Interest and Engagement in Social Activities at College</head><p>A college life focused on academic activities, and limited social interaction does not indicate a lack of interest in making friends or socialization for our autistic participants. Instead, we found that our autistic participants mentioned having 'a better social life' as one of their expectations about college. However, their perceptions about social life and friendship differed from the neurotypical participants. While neurotypical participants usually separated friends from their families, autistic participants considered friends as close as family members. To quote P9, "I think a friend is someone that you could talk to, like a family member. " (P9, M, 2nd year Associates Degree, Cyber Security, ASD)</p><p>When probed about social life expectations, all autistic participants mentioned expecting college life to be more 'inclusive and socially acceptable of autism.' They also expected to make more friends. To quote P13, "I was expecting to [be] able to find more people who have things in common with myself and being able to talk to more people." (P13, M, Freshman, Major undecided, ASD) However, P13 also reported that he had a problem with socializing earlier but not anymore because he learned the acceptable norm, which involved him accepting and adopting the standard of socialization not to be tagged as strange. To quote P13, "If everyone's acting in one way, and you're acting in a different way, I say that you're acting strangely because you're the one doing something different." (P13, M, Freshman, Major undecided, ASD) Unfortunately, P13's experience is not an exception as all of our autistic participants mentioned having similar difficulties and conscious efforts to 'make friends,' as opposed to our neurotypical participants for whom friendship 'came effortlessly' and 'something that just happens. ' Some of our autistic participants were 'actively trying' to make friends with their classmates without much success. To quote P4, "I tried to talk to them [my classmates], outside of the class or between classes. It hasn't gone very well. " (P4, M, Junior, Physics, ASD) Hence, it is not unsurprising that our autistic participants reported having a small number of friends. Also, since they considered friends as close as family members, they preferred 'quality over quantity.' Most of our autistic participants had friends who were also on the spectrum. Also, several autistic participants mentioned meeting their friends online and have never met them real life.</p><p>Transition to college often requires relocation. Hence, it becomes difficult to maintain friendships established before college. We found that our autistic participants conscious efforts to maintain their friendships established before coming to college. They primarily maintained their friendships through digital platforms (e.g., texts, Facebook, Skype, online forums). From the field study, we found that our autistic participants reported being physically alone most of the time (63.15% time). However, they actively engaged with their friends through the digital platform, even when they were alone. To quote P14, "I spend most of my time alone but also be texting friends using my phone. So, [I am] physically alone but interacting with people through non-direct means. " (P14, M, Freshman, Major undecided, ASD) P9 mentioned avoiding theater for its 'noisy environment' and typically watched movies with his friends through Skype. To get the 'theater-going experience, ' at their homes, P9 and his friends often started a movie simultaneously and communicated through Skype. Similarly, several of our autistic participants mentioned playing Dungeons &amp; Dragons (D&amp;D) with their friends over Skype or video chat. Digital platforms enabled them to maintain friendships with their friends from high school or back home and helped them to 'chill out' and have social experiences without exposing themselves to 'noise' and 'crowded environment' -potential stressors that they wanted to avoid. The following quote highlights this practice: "We use Skype. We just text our comments. One of the nice things is [that] we can begin to make comments about talking over the movie because we are just typing. " (P9, M, 2nd year Associates Degree, Cyber Security, ASD) It is interesting to note that only autistic participants reported socializing using online social platforms. While social media usage was prevalent in both groups, when asked about the use of social media for socialization, all our neurotypical participants responded negatively.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.6">Academic Activities Requiring Socialization Skills</head><p>We mentioned in Section 4.1 that our autistic participants considered 'group work' as a stress-inducing activity and tried to avoid group work intentionally and whenever possible. While much of this desire to avoid came from a perception of 'potential discomfort of socializing with unfamiliar peers' and 'mismatch of priorities,' another vital perspective also emerged that contributed to this aversion of group work. Several autistic participants avoided group activity since they were worried that they would hold their groups back by their inability to adequately express ideas or understand what others were trying to achieve. To quote P1:</p><p>"I just feel I am always a burden in group projects even though I may not, or it's just maybe harder to read what people are wanting to do." (P1, M, Senior, Political Science, ASD)</p><p>It is essential to point out that all of our autistic participants except P9 mentioned 'hating' group work. P9, who preferred group work over individual projects, explained that the ability to collaborate with others, share the workload, brainstorm, and come up with a more robust, positive solution as the motivating factors. He also clarified that group work experience could be good or bad depending on the partners, their professionalism, and attitude towards accomplishing a higher grade or learning the subject. To quote P9: "That actually made me feel good that I did have a group, a group that prioritizes well and assigns tasks to each person and, in the end, creates positive results by working together. We did a lot of work by ourselves, then we collaborated after, asked each other for feedback or suggestions, and then we put it together. I enjoyed that." (P9, M, 2nd year Associates Degree, Cyber Security, ASD)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">DISCUSSION</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Qualitative and Quantitative Data Complement Each Other</head><p>Our mixed-method study combines qualitative and quantitative data, which complement each other and help in gaining understandings that would be difficult to get using only one type of data.</p><p>Throughout our paper, we combined insights from qualitative and quantitative data to offer a detailed story of the college experience of our autistic participants. From the field study, we collected quantitative data such as stress values, emotional states, physical states, heart rate, light, and sound data utilizing Fitbit, smartphone, and EMA. The qualitative study helped us to understand that comparatively lower stress in autistic participants is a result of careful planning and is not accidental. From the field study, we collected GPS data, step count, and self-reported location data. By looking at the quantitative data only, someone might conclude that autistic college students spend all their time in classes and their homes and do not engage in any social activities. Our qualitative study revealed that for our autistic participants, academic success was critical, and they viewed socialization as a responsibility rather than an opportunity to relax. Hence, the academic-activity-focused lifestyle they chose was deliberate and carefully planned, and they were not unhappy about it. Using Fitbit's sleep tracking feature, we collected 1,146.3 hours of sleep data from the natural environment of our participants. We found that our autistic participants slept more than neurotypical participants per day. However, they had more awake time, and they awakened more frequently. We also found that our autistic participants had lower REM sleep than the normal range. From the qualitative interview, we found that although most of our autistic participants were aware of their poor sleep quality, they were unsure about the factors contributing to such poor sleep quality. The quantitative data helped them to pinpoint some of those factors. We argue that a mixed-method study enabled getting a holistic understanding of the lives of autistic college students and their unique experiences. While quantitative data collected from the field study offered critical contextual details, the qualitative data helped rationalize it.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Perceived Stress is Influenced by Personal Stress Management Capabilities, and Normalization would Offer Better Stress Awareness</head><p>Prior research showed that autistic college students showed a higher level of stress and anxiety <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">68,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">70,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">71]</ref>. Prior research mainly used semi-structured interviews <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[68]</ref> or surveys <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">70,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">71]</ref> to support their findings. As we reported earlier, our autistic individuals felt zero stress 22.75% of the time, while neurotypical participants showed zero stress for 14.56% of the time. On the contrary, autistic individuals felt the highest stress (stress value: 9) only 0.95% of the time, while neurotypical participants felt the highest stress 2.27% of the time. When we looked at the data at the individual level, we discovered that P13, a participant with ASD, reported stress nine times, and all the time, he reported zero stress. In his post-interview, he explained that he accepted stress as a fact of his life and never assigned any significance to it, which were like the sentiments offered by many of the neurotypical students. On the contrary, when we asked P15, who is also an autistic participant, about his overall stress level during the study period, he replied, "It was pretty high because it was the midterm week. " When we looked at his self-reported stress, we found that his average stress value during the study period was 5.25, which to him reflected 'high stress' episodes. These two opposite perspectives on perceived stress values from two separate autistic participants are not uncommon as stress management research indicates that individual perception about stress varies considerably <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[57]</ref>. To ensure that we limit the individual differences in perceived stress, we can adopt a technique used in <ref type="bibr">[65,</ref><ref type="bibr">66]</ref>. According to this technique, before the field study, three types of validated stressors (socio-evaluative, cognitive, and physical challenges) were induced for each participant to collect their accurate stress scores for different stress conditions. Such pre-study scores will help to normalize the perceived stress values for all participants from both groups and may offer important insight into the differences in perceived stress.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">The Uniqueness of Our Approach and Collected Data</head><p>Our collected sleep data shed light on sleep habits and patterns and reveal interesting insights. Some of our findings confirm recent clinical sleep studies conducted with autistic adults and neurotypical adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[48,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">49]</ref>. However, our study offers critical details that were missing from these recent studies, as we not only looked at the amount of total sleep but also looked at the different sleep phases, their duration, and distribution to understand sleep quality better. Prior research measured the quality of sleep using qualitative data (e.g., 5-point Likert scale, sleep diaries/questionnaires) <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[49]</ref>. Our study shows that considering quantitative data collected from the natural environment may reveal additional, more in-depth insight into sleep quality.</p><p>A few researchers collected objective sleep data. For instance, Ballester et al. conducted a study in 2012-2013 using a watch-like ambulatory circadian monitoring (ACM) system called Kronowise <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[51]</ref>. Hare et al. conducted an objective study using AW4 Actiwatch <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[52]</ref>. However, they were not able to collect REM information, which we collected using Fitbit. A few studies collected REM information of autistic individuals; however, they had to use polysomnography techniques to achieve that goal. Polysomnography usually is done within a sleep center or in a hospital. We focused on sleep habits as part of our participants' everyday life, not as a separate component. Besides, to the best of our knowledge, no study focused on the sleep data of autistic college students.</p><p>Our uniqueness also lies in how we collected data using Fitbit, a commercially available device, without significantly interfering with participants' daily lives. We tried to minimize interference by using Fitbit, a device not associated with autism and a device that did not require users to spend time on sleep clinics, and by limiting our interaction (direct and indirect) with the participants during the field study period. While it is impossible to collect physiological and sensor data from the field without interfering with the participants' everyday lives completely, we tried our best to minimize the level of interruption and interference, sometimes at the cost of collecting fewer data. Our findings suggest that commercially available lightweight wearable devices such as Fitbit may help in improving the sleep habits of autistic individuals as almost all of our autistic participants expressed a keen interest in learning more about their sleep patterns and wanted to improve their sleep habits by using Fitbit-like devices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">College Experience of Autistic Students can be Improved by Embracing Autism and Accepting Differences in Social Communication</head><p>Unlike previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>, none of our autistic participants found academic pressure challenging. Instead, several autistic participants mentioned the academic pressure was less than what they expected, were academically successful, and were mostly happy with their performances. When asked about what aspects of college they did not like, our autistic participants did not report anything specific. They mentioned time management as a challenging aspect of college and mentioned the struggle of living away with family and living with roommates, which are typical challenges encountered by any college student. Overall, autistic participants mentioned having a positive experience in college. Even with the amount of work, change in lifestyle, living independently for the first time away from family, and managing all aspects of life, they seemed satisfied and happy with their decisions to attend college. One challenging aspect of college life reported by all autistic students is the expectation surrounding social interaction (e.g., making friends, group work). Our autistic participants mentioned trying to embrace the norms set up by our predominantly neurotypical society, which impacted their experience and well-being.</p><p>Navedo et al. conducted a literature review of 21 articles and found that the most critical goal of autism-related research and technology design should be the wellbeing of autistic individuals <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">[79]</ref>. They reported that to achieve that goal, we need to create a favorable environment for autistic individuals and to understand and satisfy their drive toward certain types of information <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">[79]</ref>. It is not hard to make such an environment, as Jim Sinclair nicely articulated in his famous article and speech titled "Don't Mourn for Us" that "autism is not an impenetrable wall" <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">[78]</ref>. From our study, we also found that it is not hard to create a favorable environment for autistic students in college settings if their peers understood and embraced the root causes of their allegedly "strange" behavior.</p><p>Our findings indicate that autistic students want to participate in social activities inside and outside the classroom like their neurotypical peers but struggle to do so and would even prefer them if their peers accepted them for who they are without being judgmental. This insight opens avenues for researchers and technology developers to invest in designing tools that can aid in improving the 'social experience' of autistic college students. showed how a visualization dashboard could be useful in smoking cessation <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[53]</ref>. Our findings also indicate that such tools can help improve the experience of autistic college students. For instance, several participants loved the visuals provided by Fitbit and wanted to check the Fitbit data frequently to see if there were any changes in their heart rates, and in case those were higher than expected, they performed breathing exercises to make these drop to 'normal' levels.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5">Design Implication</head><p>An app and web-based visualization dashboard that will compile all visualizations (stress, sleep, navigation, social engagement) in a single resource can be designed to provide deeper insights into the experiences of autistic college students. Self-determination theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[54]</ref> can be the primary block of the visualization dashboard, which advocates for three basic psychological needs to motivate a person to achieve a goal. These three needs are Relatedness (one's sense of belonging to others to whom they want to be connected), Autonomy (the users can control their actions), and Competency (one's ability to achieve something). The visualization dashboard can enable autistic college students to look at their habits, experiences, and patterns across many days at different levels of granularity. The dashboard will also allow them to compare their data to other students' data (while preserving privacy), who share some similarities but also have some differences. This is how the dashboard may ensure Relatedness since it will enhance users' sense of affiliation with other college students by enabling them to compare their data with their cohorts (autistic students) and with the broader community (college students). To preserve users' options to choose, i.e., Autonomy, the dashboard may provide options for popular stress management techniques such as cognitive-behavioral therapy (CBT) <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[55]</ref> and mindfulness-based therapy <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[56]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.5.2">Managing vs. Avoiding Stress: Stress Prediction Technology.</head><p>We found that autistic participants try to avoid potential stressful events and places in an attempt to maintain a lower stress level. Lisa Damour, a clinical psychologist who specializes in education and child development, argued that individuals should confront the causes of stress and anxiety rather than avoid it since avoidance would only make stress and anxiety worse <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[59]</ref>. Although Lisa Damour's remark was not targeted at autistic individuals, we found evidence of how avoiding stressful events are negatively impacting our participants. For instance, P9 withdrew from his Anthropology class, finding it overwhelming as "many people were talking very fast. " Withdrawing from every course that presents such challenges may not be a feasible option for autistic college students who want to get a college degree.</p><p>Our findings highlighted that our autistic participants were good at planning and taking precautions to avoid stress-inducing events and locations. We speculate that if technology can correctly predict stressful events in near real-time and identify stress factors ahead of time, it will help autistic college students to manage their stress better. By providing an opportunity to reflect on stress and stressors, they would be better equipped to find stress management strategies that do not involve complete avoidance of social events. Umematsu et al. showed that N-days of multimodal data collected from a college campus (e.g., physiological signals, mobile phone usage, mobility pattern, and self-reported data from behavior surveys) could successfully forecast high/low binary stress levels of the next evening (N+1-th day) <ref type="bibr">[76]</ref>. By using LSTM (Long Short Term Memory) neural network, the authors' developed a model that achieved 83.6% accuracy. Similar technology can be used to predict stress for autistic college students, which may help them to confront and manage stress rather than avoid it.</p><p>Our study revealed that autistic students have a slightly different college experience than their neurotypical peers, and stress management technology can help minimize these differences. To design technology that may help autistic individuals to confront their causes of stress and anxiety successfully, we propose the use of the value-sensitive design (VSD) framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[60]</ref>, which is embraced by the HCI and accessibility research community <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[61,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">62]</ref>. VSD framework will help situate the stress management strategy by emphasizing the norms and ethical values of autistic college students and related stakeholders (e.g., primary caregivers, college accessibility center).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.6">Broader Lessons for HCI and Accessibility Community</head><p>In this section, we want to share a few lessons we learned from our study, which might be useful for the broader HCI community in general and for the accessibility research community. First, by using commercially available technology such as Fitbit and Android smartphones, we demonstrated the feasibility of collecting large amounts of objective and continuous data from autistic college students from their natural environments, which can offer novel findings and/or provide a different perspective. Hopefully, our study will motivate both qualitative and quantitative researchers to come together to "combine their strengths" to leverage the mixed-method technique. We believe that such a combination will obtain holistic understandings of many research areas in the accessibility and healthcare domain.</p><p>Second, the accessibility and broader HCI community have already embraced different technology to address the challenges of autistic individuals. Every year, researchers contribute to the HCI scholarship by publishing many research articles in the domain of autism. These scholarship efforts are, without any doubt, highly praiseworthy. At the same time, we emphasize that we, the HCI researchers, should have an open mind before designing assistive technology for autistic individuals. More importantly, we want to encourage other HCI researchers to revisit and reexamine some established notions about the 'technology needs' of autistic individuals. This may bring different perspectives and inspire HCI researchers to design different types of technology or adopt a different style of technology design.</p><p>Finally, through the HCI community, we want to reach out to the neurotypical researchers, designers, and educators to convey that this is high time to 'genuinely' embrace autistic individuals in every aspect of our lives. Autistic individuals want to be accepted, loved, and valued like any other neurotypical individuals, and accepting 'autism as a way of being' will make our world more inclusive.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.7">Limitations of the Study</head><p>While we collected large amounts of data from 20 college students, this is still a small sample. We also collected field data from each participant for one week. The findings reported here might not be generalizable to the broader autistic student community. Also, as mentioned earlier, autistic participants in our study are highfunctioning (self-rated), verbal, and academically high-achievers (self-reported GPA of 3 or above). As such, their experiences may not represent the entire range of experiences of all autistic college students. Besides, autism is a spectrum, which makes it challenging to identify a set or activities that can be considered as "common" for everyone in the spectrum. While these concerns are valid, we believe that our research is an essential first step in highlighting the possibilities of collecting objective data from the natural from autistic individuals utilizing smartphones and commercially available wearable sensors. By collecting both objective and subjective data and analyzing them we were able to get a more vibrant picture of the experience of autistic college students. By collecting data from both neurotypical and autistic students, we were able to identify and validate unique experiences that autistic students have, along with uncovering patterns and factors that influence their experience and contribute to difficulties faced.</p><p>As mentioned in Section 3.3.2 Qualitative Data Analysis, one of the potential limitations is that we did not compute the inter-rater agreement, which was influenced by recent work and the presence of very few disagreements during the coding phase among the raters. Computing and reporting the inter-rater agreement value would highlight the reliability of the coding process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">CONCLUSION</head><p>The goal of our research is to understand the experiences of autistic college students. We conducted a mixed-method study with 20 college students (10 autistic and 10 neurotypical). Our study highlights details about the experience of autistic students holistically that offers new insight and clarifies or contradicts current understanding. This paper broadens the understanding of the HCI, Autism, mHealth, and Accessibility research community about the experiences of autistic college students. Our findings may help researchers, designers, and educators to understand the unique needs of autistic college students and help them in creating a more inclusive environment aimed at improving the experience of autistic students.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Freshman: 5 , 9 Figure 1 :</head><label>591</label><figDesc>Figure 1: (left) Sample screenshot from the EMA data collection app, (center) Visual analytic tools -Location Plotter, (right) Visual analytic tools -Sleep Analyzer.</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,92.80,161.47,426.41,176.55" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Stress histogram of autistic (left) and neurotypical (right) participants. This histogram highlighted that both groups experienced similar stress patterns during the study.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="7,118.70,271.06,374.60,139.96" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>5. 5 . 1</head><label>51</label><figDesc>Visualization Dashboard to enhance self-awareness. Prior research showed that visualization helps individuals gain critical insights into different aspects of their lives. For instance, Feng et al.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Sample questions (*Questions asked only to autistic participants) Apart from your family members, who else is aware that you are on the spectrum? EMA How would you describe your current emotional state? Were you engaged in social interaction in the last 30 minutes? Have you participated in any group activity in the last two hours? How would you rate your current stress level? Post-Interview Did you participate in any (academic) group projects during this study? Did you participate in any social activity (club, sports) in your college during this study? On a scale of 1-5 (1= very uncomfortable, 5 = very comfortable), please rate the comfort level of the wearable. What features of wearable technology did you like/dislike?</figDesc><table><row><cell>Pre-interview</cell><cell>How important is it for you to get a college degree? Please explain why you consider it important.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>What was your expectation about college life before coming to college?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>What kinds of challenges do you face at your college?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>* Could you share with us when you were diagnosed, and what was the process of diagnosis?</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>*</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>This plotter helped in identifying participants' general movement and categories of places where they spent time (e.g., grocery, work, and library). We used a sleep analyzer to analyze users' sleep data. We also created a Physiological Data Analyzer to analyze step count and heart rate information. These visual analytic tools helped us to identify potential moments of physiological distress and the impact of sleep, group activity, or walking on stress if there were any.</figDesc><table /><note>didn't require inter-rater reliability[37].3.3.3 Visual Analytic Tools.We created visual analytic tools written in Python and d3.js to visualize and analyze the large quantitative dataset collected during the field study. Figures1(center) and 1(right) provide screenshots of the Location Plotter and Sleep Analyzer of our visual analytic tools. We used the location plotter to analyze users' locations for each day, where different colored markers indicate different portions of the day (e.g., morning, noon, and night). During the post-interview, we asked participants to highlight points of interest (e.g., home, friend's home, work).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Stress reported by participants</figDesc><table><row><cell>ASD</cell><cell>Neurotypical</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Participants' heart rate data (collected viaFitbit)    </figDesc><table><row><cell>ASD</cell><cell>Neurotypical</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Participants' self-reported emotional states (collected via EMA)</figDesc><table><row><cell>Emotional State</cell><cell>ASD (199)</cell><cell>%</cell><cell>Neurotypical (240)</cell><cell>%</cell></row><row><cell>Neutral</cell><cell>88</cell><cell>44.2%</cell><cell>75</cell><cell>31.3%</cell></row><row><cell>Happy</cell><cell>45</cell><cell>22.6%</cell><cell>87</cell><cell>36.3%</cell></row><row><cell>Anxious</cell><cell>37</cell><cell>18.6%</cell><cell>47</cell><cell>19.6%</cell></row><row><cell>Frustrated</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>6.5%</cell><cell>23</cell><cell>9.6%</cell></row><row><cell>Sad</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>1.5%</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>3.3%</cell></row><row><cell>Others</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>6.5%</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0.0%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head>Table 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Participants' self-reported physical states (collected via EMA)</figDesc><table><row><cell>State</cell><cell>ASD (195)</cell><cell>%</cell><cell>Neurotypical (240)</cell><cell>%</cell></row><row><cell>Well-rested</cell><cell>115</cell><cell>59.0%</cell><cell>145</cell><cell>60.4%</cell></row><row><cell>Exhausted</cell><cell>59</cell><cell>30.3%</cell><cell>75</cell><cell>31.3%</cell></row><row><cell>Tired</cell><cell>11</cell><cell>5.6%</cell><cell>15</cell><cell>6.3%</cell></row><row><cell>Others</cell><cell>10</cell><cell>5.1%</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>2.1%</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head>Table 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Participants' step data (collected viaFitbit)    </figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>ASD</cell><cell></cell><cell>Neurotypical</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Std. Dev</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>Std. Dev</cell></row><row><cell>Steps per day</cell><cell>5,168</cell><cell>2,992</cell><cell>8,142</cell><cell>2,429</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_7"><head>Table 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Participants' self-reported current (collected via EMA)</figDesc><table><row><cell>ASD (199)</cell><cell>Total</cell><cell>%</cell><cell>Neurotypical (241)</cell><cell>Total</cell><cell>%</cell></row><row><cell>Home/Dorm</cell><cell>137</cell><cell>68.84%</cell><cell>Home/Dorm</cell><cell>145</cell><cell>60.17%</cell></row><row><cell>School</cell><cell>36</cell><cell>18.09%</cell><cell>School</cell><cell>41</cell><cell>17.01%</cell></row><row><cell>Café / Dining Hall</cell><cell>7</cell><cell>3.52%</cell><cell>House of Parents/ Grandparents/ Friends</cell><cell>25</cell><cell>10.37%</cell></row><row><cell>Bus/Bus stop</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>2.51%</cell><cell>Work / Going to work</cell><cell>13</cell><cell>5.39%</cell></row><row><cell>Library</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>1.51%</cell><cell>Car</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>2.07%</cell></row><row><cell>Car</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>1.01%</cell><cell>Bus/Bus stop</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>1.66%</cell></row><row><cell>Park</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>1.01%</cell><cell>Restaurant</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>1.24%</cell></row><row><cell>Doctor's office</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>1.01%</cell><cell>Others</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>2.07%</cell></row><row><cell>Work</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>0.50%</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Others</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>2.01%</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_8"><head>Table 9 :</head><label>9</label><figDesc>Participants' sleep data on average per day (includes both night sleep and nap)</figDesc><table><row><cell>(minutes)</cell><cell></cell><cell cols="2">Neurotypical (minutes)</cell></row><row><cell>Mean</cell><cell>std. dev</cell><cell>Mean</cell><cell>std. dev</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Costs of autism spectrum disorders in the United Kingdom and the United States</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ariane</forename><surname>Buescher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zuleyha</forename><surname>Cidav</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Knapp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mandell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1001/jamapediatrics.2014.210</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1001/jamapediatrics.2014.210" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JAMA Pediatrics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">168</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="721" to="728" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Preface: Special Issue-College Experiences for Students with Autism Spectrum Disorder</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Logan</forename><surname>Hart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fred</forename><surname>Volkmar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-018-3463-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-018-3463-7" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="639" to="642" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The post-high school outcomes of young adults with disabilities up to 8 years after high school</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lynn</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mary</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne-Marie</forename><surname>Knockey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Camille</forename><surname>Marder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><surname>Nagle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Debra</forename><surname>Shaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xin</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Renee</forename><surname>Cameto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elidia</forename><surname>Contreras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kate</forename><surname>Ferguson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Greene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Meredith</forename><surname>Schwarting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A report from the National Longitudinal Transition Study-2 (MLTS2)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perspectives of University Students with Autism Spectrum Disorder</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anastasia</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Stephenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-017-3257-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-017-3257-3" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="651" to="665" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Brief Report: Self-Reported Academic, Social, and Mental Health Experiences of Post-Secondary Students with Autism Spectrum Disorder</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Logan</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jane</forename><surname>Hart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fred</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Volkmar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-017-3315-x</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-017-3315-x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="643" to="650" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Research to Practice: Informing the Design of Autism Support Smart Technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Moushumi</forename><surname>Sharmin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abir</forename><surname>Md Monsur Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maitraye</forename><surname>Saha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Margot</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shameem</forename><surname>Maxwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3173676</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173676" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cdc Usa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.cdc.gov/ncbddd/autism/data.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Data &amp; Statistics on Autism Spectrum Disorder</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">REM, Light, Deep: How Much of Each Stage of Sleep Are You Getting?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danielle</forename><surname>Kosecki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://blog.fitbit.com/sleep-stages-explained/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Systematic Review of Articles Describing Experience and Supports of Individuals with Autism Enrolled in College and University Programs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Gelbar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Reichow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-014-2135-5</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-014-2135-5" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of autism and developmental disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2593" to="2601" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A systematic literature review of the experiences and supports of students with autism spectrum disorder in post-secondary education</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anastasia</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Stephenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Carter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/J.RASD.2017.04.002</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.org/10.1016/J.RASD.2017.04.002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Research in Autism Spectrum Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="53" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Autism and Accommodations in Higher Education: Insights from the Autism Community</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Sarrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-017-3353-4</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-017-3353-4" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="679" to="693" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An Evaluation of Specialist Mentoring for University Students with Autism Spectrum Disorders and Mental Health Conditions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Lucas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alana</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-017-3303-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-017-3303-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="694" to="707" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Autism Goes to College: Understanding the Needs of a Student Population on the Rise</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Elias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-017-3075-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-017-3075-7" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="732" to="746" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Accommodations and support services preferred by college students with autism spectrum disorder</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Accardo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">Jay</forename><surname>Kuder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Woodruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1362361318760490</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1362361318760490" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">We Need More Power to Stand Up: Designing to Combat Stigmatization of the Caregivers of Children with Autism in Urban Bangladesh</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Abdul Kawsar Tushar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dipto</forename><surname>Iffat Jahan Antara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Priyank</forename><surname>Das</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Chandra</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International Conference on Information and Communication Technologies and Development</title>
				<meeting>the International Conference on Information and Communication Technologies and Development</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Tanjir Rashid Soron, Md Munirul Haque, Sheikh Iqbal Ahamed, and Syed Ishtiaque Ahmed</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bullying and Identity Development: Insights from Autistic and Non-autistic College Students</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danielle</forename><surname>Denigris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patricia</forename><surname>Brooks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rita</forename><surname>Obeid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Alarcon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Shane-Simpson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristen</forename><surname>Gillespie-Lynch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-017-3383-y</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-017-3383-y" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="666" to="678" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying the Unmet Needs of College Students on the Autism Spectrum</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><surname>Pinder-Amaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1097/HRP.0000000000000032</idno>
		<ptr target="http" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harvard Review of Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="125" to="137" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">College Students&apos; Knowledge and Attitudes Towards Students on the Autism Spectrum</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Devon</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ashleigh</forename><surname>Hillier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alice</forename><surname>Frye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Makrez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-016-2818-1</idno>
		<ptr target="http://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-016-2818-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Faculty Experience With College Students With Autism Spectrum Disorders: A Qualitative Study of Challenges and Solutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ken</forename><surname>Gobbo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Solvegi</forename><surname>Shmulsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1088357613504989</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1088357613504989" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Focus on Autism and Other Developmental Disabilities</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assisting Students with Intellectual and Developmental Disabilities in Inclusive Education with Smartwatches</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vivian</forename><forename type="middle">Genaro</forename><surname>Motti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3173924</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173924" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the ACM SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anxiety and Autism: Towards Personalized Digital Health</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Simm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Ferrario</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><surname>Gradinar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marcia</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Forshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Whittle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2858036.2858259</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2858036.2858259" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM SIGCHI on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the ACM SIGCHI on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1270" to="1281" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">FOQUS: A smartwatch application for individuals with ADHD and mental health challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victor</forename><surname>Dibia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2982142.2982207</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2982142.2982207" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</title>
				<meeting>the 18th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ASSETS</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="312" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wearable Life: A Wrist-Worn Application to Assist Students in Special Education</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vivian</forename><surname>Motti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Universal Access in Human-Computer Interaction</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="276" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">WeLi: A Smartwatch Application to Assist Students with Intellectual and Developmental Disabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hui</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vivian</forename><surname>Motti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</title>
				<meeting>the 19th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="355" to="356" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opportunities and Challenges in Designing Participant-Centric Smoking Cessation System</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Moushumi</forename><surname>Sharmin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Theodore</forename><surname>Weber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hillol</forename><surname>Sarker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nazir</forename><surname>Saleheen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Santosh</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shameem</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mustafa</forename><surname>Al' Alabsi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE 41st Annual Computer Software and Applications Conference (COMPSAC)</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/COMPSAC.2017.184</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1109/COMPSAC.2017.184" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Feasibility and validity of ecological momentary assessment in adolescents with high-functioning autism and Asperger&apos;s disorder</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Angela</forename><surname>Khor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kylie</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sophie</forename><surname>Reid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Glenn</forename><surname>Melvin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="37" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">About sleep&apos;s role in memory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Björn</forename><surname>Rasch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Physiological Reviews</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="681" to="766" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">Jan Born. 2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rapid-eye-movement-sleep (REM) associated enhancement of working memory performance after a daytime nap</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Esther</forename><forename type="middle">Yuet</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ying</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristy</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florence</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chia</forename><surname>Tseng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0125752</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0125752" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLoS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using mixed methods in health research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shema</forename><surname>Tariq</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><surname>Woodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/2042533313479197</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/2042533313479197" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Royal Society of Medicine Short Reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Achieving integration in mixed methods designs -Principles and practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Fetters</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leslie</forename><surname>Curry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Creswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/1475-6773.12117</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/1475-6773.12117" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Health Services Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2134" to="2156" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Creswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J. David</forename><surname>Creswell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Research Design: Qualitative, Quantitative, and Mixed Methods Approaches</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>SAGE Publications</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Fifth edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An ecological momentary assessment analysis of relations among coping, affect and smoking during a quit attempt</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Haruka</forename><surname>Minami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danielle</forename><surname>Mccarthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Jorenby</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Baker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Addiction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">106</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="641" to="650" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assessing the availability of users to engage in just-in-time intervention in the natural environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hillol</forename><surname>Sarker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Moushumi</forename><surname>Sharmin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Md</forename><surname>Amin Ahsan Ali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rummana</forename><surname>Mahbubur Rahman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bari</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing</title>
				<meeting>the ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="909" to="920" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Syed Monowar Hossain, and Santosh Kumar</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence-Based Practices in Interventions for Children and Youth with</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><surname>Odom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lana</forename><surname>Collet-Klingenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sally</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deborah</forename><surname>Hatton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/10459881003785506</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/10459881003785506" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Autism Spectrum Disorders. Preventing School Failure: Alternative Education for Children and Youth</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">54</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="275" to="282" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evidence-Based Practices for Children, Youth, and Young Adults with Autism Spectrum Disorder: A</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Connie</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Odom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kara</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Hume</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ann</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Cox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Angel</forename><surname>Fettig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Kucharczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Brock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Plavnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Veronica</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Fleury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tia</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-014-2351-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-014-2351-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comprehensive Review. Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1951" to="1966" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Agile Processes in Software Engineering and 54, 2. Nora McDonald, Sarita Schoenebeck, and Andrea Forte. 2019. Reliability and inter-rater reliability in qualitative research: Norms and guidelines for CSCW and HCI practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Francesco</forename><surname>Cirillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Pomodoro technique (the Pomodoro)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The discovery of grounded theory; strategies for qualitative research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Barney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anselm</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Glaser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Strutzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nursing research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1968">1968</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">REM sleep and dreaming: 8-20</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Edward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Pace-Schott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<publisher>Cambridge press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Which terms should be used to describe autism? Perspectives from the UK autism community</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lorcan</forename><surname>Kenny</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Caroline</forename><surname>Hattersley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><surname>Molins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carole</forename><surname>Buckley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carol</forename><surname>Povey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Pellicano</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Autism</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="442" to="462" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sleep inspires insight</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ullrich</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steffen</forename><surname>Gais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hilde</forename><surname>Haider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">427</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6972</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="352" to="355" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">Jan Born. 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">What should I know about sleep stages?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fitbit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://help.fitbit.com/articles/en_US/Help_article/2163" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2022">2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<idno>https://</idno>
		<title level="m">The Qualitative Data Analysis &amp; Research Software</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heart rate variability predicts inhibitory control in adults with autism spectrum disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Marieke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kuiper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Elisabeth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hilde</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Verhoeven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Geurts</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Biological Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">128</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="141" to="152" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The neurobiology of sleep: genetics, cellular physiology and subcortical networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Edward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J. Allan</forename><surname>Pace-Schott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hobson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature Reviews Neuroscience</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">591</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A putative flip-flop switch for control of REM sleep</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jun</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Sherman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marshall</forename><surname>Devor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Clifford</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Saper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7093</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">589</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The experience of anxiety in young adults with autism spectrum disorders</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Trembath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carmela</forename><surname>Germano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Graeme</forename><surname>Johanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cheryl</forename><surname>Dissanayake</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Focus on Autism and Other Developmental Disabilities</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="213" to="224" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sleep in adults with Autism Spectrum Disorder: a systematic review and metaanalysis of subjective and objective studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bethany</forename><surname>Morgan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fatuma</forename><surname>Nageye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gabriele</forename><surname>Masi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samuele</forename><surname>Cortese</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.sleep.2019.07.019</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sleep.2019.07.019" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sleep Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="113" to="120" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sleep determines quality of life in autistic adults: A longitudinal study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marie</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Deserno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Denny</forename><surname>Borsboom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sander</forename><surname>Begeer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Joost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kawita</forename><surname>Agelink Van Rentergem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hilde</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mataw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Geurts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/aur.2103</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/aur.2103" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Autism Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="794" to="801" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Estimation of sleep stages using cardiac and accelerometer data from a wrist-worn device</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Beattie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Pantelopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Ghoreyshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Oyang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Statan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Heneghan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sleep</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sleep problems in adults with autism spectrum disorder and intellectual disability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pura</forename><surname>Ballester</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">María José</forename><surname>Martínez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Auxiliadora</forename><surname>Javaloyes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">María-Del-Mar</forename><surname>Inda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Noemí</forename><surname>Fernández</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pilar</forename><surname>Gázquez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Víctor</forename><surname>Aguilar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Agustín</forename><surname>Pérez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luís</forename><surname>Hernández</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Richdale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ana</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Peiró</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/aur.2000</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/aur.2000" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Autism Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="66" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A comparative study of circadian rhythm functioning and sleep in people with Asperger syndrome</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Dougal Julian Hare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kate</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Evershed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1362361306068509</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1362361306068509" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Autism</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="565" to="575" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moushumi Sharmin, Mustafa al&apos;Absi, and Duen Horng Chau. 2017. mHealth visual discovery dashboard</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dezhi</forename><surname>Fang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fred</forename><surname>Hohman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Polack</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hillol</forename><surname>Sarker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Minsuk</forename><surname>Kahng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing and Proceedings of the 2017 ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computers</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing and the 2017 ACM International Symposium on Wearable Computers</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="240" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-determination theory and the facilitation of intrinsic motivation, social development, and wellbeing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Richard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edward</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Deci</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="68" to="78" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychosocial treatments targeting anxiety and depression in adolescents and adults on the autism spectrum: Review of the latest research and recommended future directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Grace</forename><forename type="middle">Lee</forename><surname>Simmons</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Gotham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Caitlin</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Conner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Isaac</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kelly</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carla</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Mazefsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current psychiatry reports</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mindfulness-based therapy in adults with an autism spectrum disorder: Do treatment effects last?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michelle</forename><surname>Kiep</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Annelies</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Spek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lisette</forename><surname>Hoeben</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Mindfulness</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="637" to="644" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Visualization of time-series sensor data to inform the design of just-in-time adaptive stress interventions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Moushumi</forename><surname>Sharmin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Raij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Epstien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Gayle</forename><surname>Nahum-Shani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sudip</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kenzie</forename><surname>Vhaduri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Santosh</forename><surname>Preston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing</title>
				<meeting>the 2015 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="505" to="516" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Number of active users of Fitbit from</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Federica</forename><surname>Laricchia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.statista.com/statistics/472600/fitbit-active-users/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2022. 2012 to 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Under pressure: Confronting the epidemic of stress and anxiety in girls</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Damour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<publisher>Ballantine Books</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A survey of value sensitive design methods. Foundations and Trends in Human</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Batya</forename><surname>Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Hendry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Borning</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="125" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Value sensitive design for neurodiverse teams in higher education</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Annuska</forename><surname>Zolyomi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">Spencer</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arpita</forename><surname>Bhattacharya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lauren</forename><surname>Milne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Munson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</title>
				<meeting>the International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="353" to="354" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Values, Identity, and Social Translucence: Neurodiverse Student Teams in Higher Education</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Annuska</forename><surname>Zolyomi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">Spencer</forename><surname>Ross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arpita</forename><surname>Bhattacharya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lauren</forename><surname>Milne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sean</forename><surname>Munson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 chi conference on human factors in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 chi conference on human factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resting heart rate variability, emotion regulation, psychological wellbeing and autism symptomatology in adults with and without autism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ying</forename><surname>Ru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cheryl</forename><surname>Richdale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mirko</forename><surname>Dissanayake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Uljarević</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Psychophysiology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">137</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="54" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reduced heart rate variability in adults with autism spectrum disorder</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rinku</forename><surname>Thapa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gail</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Alvares</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tooba</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Zaidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emma</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ian</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Hickie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shin</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Guastella</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Autism Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="922" to="930" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">cStress: towards a gold standard for continuous stress assessment in the mobile environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Hovsepian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mustafa</forename><surname>Al'absi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emre</forename><surname>Ertin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Kamarck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Motohiro</forename><surname>Nakajima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Santosh</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM international joint conference on pervasive and ubiquitous computing</title>
				<meeting>the ACM international joint conference on pervasive and ubiquitous computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="493" to="504" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Continuous inference of psychological stress from sensory measurements collected in the natural environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kurt</forename><surname>Plarre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Raij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Syed Monowar Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Motohiro</forename><surname>Amin Ahsan Ali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mustafa</forename><surname>Nakajima</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emre</forename><surname>Al'absi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Ertin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Santosh</forename><surname>Kamarck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marcia</forename><surname>Kumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Asim</forename><surname>Siewiorek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lorentz</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Smailagic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wittmers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th ACM/IEEE international conference on information processing in sensor networks</title>
				<meeting>the 10th ACM/IEEE international conference on information processing in sensor networks</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="108" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">healthy-lifestyle/stress-management/stress-andheart-health#:~:text=A%20stressful%20situation%20sets%20off</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.heart.org/en/healthy-living/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<publisher>American Heart Association</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Stress and Heart Health</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Higher Education Experiences of Students with Autism Spectrum Disorder: Challenges, Benefits and Support Needs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tinneke</forename><surname>Valérie Van Hees</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Herbert</forename><surname>Moyson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Roeyers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1673" to="1688" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Transition to Higher Education for Students With Autism: A Systematic Literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alison</forename><surname>Nuske</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fiona</forename><surname>Rillotta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michelle</forename><surname>Bellon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><surname>Richdale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/dhe0000108</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/dhe0000108" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Review. Journal of Diversity in Higher Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="280" to="295" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Experiences of College Students on the Autism Spectrum: A Comparison to Their Neurotypical Peers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jane</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Mcleod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Meanwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amelia</forename><surname>Hawbaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10803-019-03910-8</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10803-019-03910-8" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Autism and Developmental Disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2320" to="2336" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">2020. The health of college students on the autism spectrum as compared to their neurotypical peers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jane</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Mcleod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amelia</forename><surname>Hawbaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Meanwell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1362361320926070</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1362361320926070" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2320" to="2336" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emotional Arousal During Social Stress in Young Adults With Autism: Insights From Heart Rate, Heart Rate Variability and Self-Report</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Renee</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Dijkhuis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Ziermans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sophie</forename><surname>Van Rijn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wouter</forename><surname>Staal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hanna</forename><surname>Swaab</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of autism and developmental disorders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2524" to="2535" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Daily step goal of 10,000 steps: a literature review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Bernard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anita</forename><forename type="middle">Wp</forename><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jerome Cl</forename><surname>Pak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Clinical and Investigative Medicine</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="E146" to="E151" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The coding manual for qualitative researchers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Johnny</forename><surname>Saldaña</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sage</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Improving Students&apos; Daily Life Stress Forecasting using LSTM Neural Networks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anselm</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Juliet</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Corbin ; Akane</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Sano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rosalind</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Picard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/BHI.2019.8834624</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1109/BHI.2019.8834624" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sage. Terumi Umematsu</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Grounded theory in practice</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Emerging biomarkers in autism spectrum disorder: a systematic review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Frye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Vassall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gurjot</forename><surname>Kaur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohammand</forename><surname>Karim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Rossignol</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Annals of translational medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Don&apos;t Mourn for Us</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jim</forename><surname>Sinclair</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Autonomy, the Critical Journal of Interdisciplinary Autism Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strengthbased ICT design supporting individuals with autism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><surname>Navedo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amelia</forename><surname>Espiritu-Santo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shameem</forename><surname>Ahmed</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The 21st International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="560" to="562" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
