<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">3D Printed Street Crossings: Supporting Orientation and Mobility Training with People who are Blind or have Low Vision</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Leona</forename><surname>Holloway</surname></persName>
							<email>leona.holloway@monash.edu</email>
							<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-9813-0377</idno>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Victoria</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Victoria</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Butler</surname></persName>
							<email>matthew.butler@monash.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Victoria</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kim</forename><surname>Marriott</surname></persName>
							<email>kim.marriott@monash.edu</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Victoria</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><surname>3d</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Victoria</settlement>
									<country key="AU">Australia</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">3D Printed Street Crossings: Supporting Orientation and Mobility Training with People who are Blind or have Low Vision</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3502072</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:01+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Blind</term>
					<term>Maps</term>
					<term>Intersections</term>
					<term>3D Printing</term>
					<term>Orientation &amp; Mobility Supporting Orientation and Mobility Training with People who</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Figure 1: Co-designed 3D models being used to teach street crossing concepts at a workshop for blind and low vision children during the evaluation phase. Images courtesy of Guide Dogs Victoria.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Originally developed in the USA to support veterans injured during the second world war, orientation and mobility (O&amp;M) training has become an integral part of blind and low vision (BLV) people's education and support <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">56]</ref>. Specialist O&amp;M instructors teach concepts and skills enabling BLV people to confdently travel independently, thereby gaining physical access to the world.</p><p>One of the essential skills that O&amp;M training teaches is the ability to cross at street intersections <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>. For congenitally blind children, this begins with fundamental training about diferent kinds of intersections and trafc conditions. As part of this training, O&amp;M instructors frequently make use of raised line drawings called tactile maps and kits or toys to represent the intersections. Here, we investigate the use of 3D printed mapping components in O&amp;M training about street intersections. To the best of our knowledge, we are the frst to do so.</p><p>Commodity 3D printers and easy-to-use design tools like Tin-kerCAD are transforming the provision of accessible models and graphics to the BLV community. 3D printed models are increasingly used in schools to support BLV student access to STEM materials <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">57]</ref> and they are also beginning to be used for O&amp;M training <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">51]</ref>. However their use in O&amp;M training has been limited to printed street maps or plans of particular buildings or locations. Until now, 3D printed models have not been considered for teaching the concepts of street intersections at a more fundamental level: how the intersection is laid out; how the trafc moves; the information available to drivers; and how a BLV person can orient themselves to safely cross the road. All of this information is vital to complete a road crossing with safety and confdence.</p><p>We address three questions: (1) What are the most important requirements for tactile materials to teach street crossing concepts for people who are blind or have low vision? (2) Is there a need for additional O&amp;M tools to teach intersections that could be fulflled using 3D printing? (3) If so, what are the design characteristics of such 3D models?</p><p>To answer these questions, we employed a participatory design methodology with O&amp;M professionals. We conducted work across three phases (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">2</ref>):</p><p>• In the requirements gathering phase, we conducted a formative study via semi-structured interviews with 11 O&amp;M instructors to understand their current practices and to elicit how they thought 3D printed street intersection maps might be of use. • Informed by the requirements gathering phase, we moved into the co-design phase to co-create three sets of 3D materials illustrating a range of intersection formations. The designs were iterative, with constant changes and additions made in response to feedback from seven O&amp;M practitioners and two blind adults. • In the evaluation phase, we gathered more formal feedback from seven O&amp;M instructors via survey and interview. We also analysed video of sessions in which three blind children used the materials with their O&amp;M instructors.</p><p>This work provides empirical evidence of the value of 3D printed tactile street crossing models for O&amp;M training for people who are BLV. Our specifc contributions are threefold:</p><p>• Empirical evidence: Evidence for the value of 3D printed models for O&amp;M instructors when teaching BLV people about diferent kinds of street intersections. Blind children successfully used the materials to learn basic to advanced concepts relating to crossing streets safely. The 3D printed materials were rated as more usable than existing materials, and held advantages in terms of demonstrating key concepts, portability, engagement and being professional in appearance. • Design guidelines: The frst design guidelines for 3D models of street intersections and their components. For example, 3D models should be tactually distinct, with a low profle, and show only the most important features. • Availability: Provision of the fnal 3D models on Thingiverse for O&amp;M specialists to print or modify and use with their BLV clients.</p><p>Our studies have signifcant implications for O&amp;M training, providing evidence that 3D printed models can augment or replace the current use of tactile graphics and other mapping tools. More broadly, it demonstrates the value of maker technologies like 3D printing for the development of specialised tools for the accessibility community. We hope that our freely available library of street intersection components will support O&amp;M practices world-wide with consequent improvements in skills, safety and independence for BLV people.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED WORK 2.1 Orientation and Mobility Training</head><p>Intersections are becoming more complex and dangerous <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>, demanding focused attention and training. Even well-trained blind pedestrians crossing at a roundabout may wait up to three times longer than sighted pedestrians and make more risky decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>Because people who are congenitally blind do not receive information about the environment outside their immediate touch and hearing, concept building is always the frst step towards understanding <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">60]</ref>. In particular, understanding trafc movements and the driver's decision-making process is essential to be able to make safe decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22]</ref>. O&amp;M training about street crossings specifcally teaches BLV pedestrians how to locate the crosswalk and crossing location, locating and using the pedestrian push button (if available), aligning to cross, and maintaining alignment while crossing <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20]</ref>. All of these skills rely on frst having an understanding of the layout of the intersection, however, it is difcult to construct a mental map with only environmental cues and verbal descriptions <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[52]</ref>. Tactile graphics (or 3D models) are recommended for conveying spatial relationships in general <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[44]</ref> and more specifcally for teaching the spatial layout of intersections <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>, especially when working with children <ref type="bibr">[47]</ref>. In the same way, exposing congenitally blind children to maps is crucial for them to develop cognitive mapping skills <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Tactile Maps, 3D models and 3D Printing</head><p>Tactile mapping is a popular area of research and production. However, the main focus has been street maps for wayfnding, with maps covering a larger area and lacking the fundamental details required to understand individual street crossings. An exception is the Australian Symbols for Tactual and Low Vision Town Maps, which provide symbols for trafc lights, pedestrian lights and pedestrian crossings <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Much more recently, the Lighthouse for the Blind has produced a set of swell paper tactile graphics to teach the basic concepts of road crossings <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>. They include pedestrian crossings, painted line markings, lanes with direction of travel and raised medians for familiarisation. They do not include further details such as trafc lights, push buttons, Tactile Ground Surface Indicators (TGSIs) and ramps, and cannot be easily modifed to teach specifc crossings. The efcacy of using 3D printing to present tactile maps has also been explored <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">53]</ref>. Evidence suggests that 3D printing can be more successful than traditional tactile graphics for conveying some types of graphical information. This of course includes graphics that are 3-dimensional in nature <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>, but also iconography, as 3D printed volumetric symbols <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">42,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">49]</ref> decrease reliance on more abstract symbols. Both of these benefts lend themselves to the application of 3D printing for maps and plans, as well as supporting O&amp;M training more broadly. Work presented in <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref> found that 3D printed maps were preferred and facilitated better short term recall than their tactile graphic counterparts. While 3D printing has been used to create numerous street maps and building plans for the purposes of route planning and navigation [30, <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">55]</ref>, it has not yet been considered for teaching the concepts of street crossings.</p><p>A range of kits with 3D components are already available to represent street crossings. Tactile Town <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>, the Cook Kit and Citybox <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[50]</ref> were all designed specifcally for O&amp;M purposes, although the latter two are no longer available. Alternatively, toys may be re-purposed for teaching, such as Lego or toy roads and cars. Thus, while there has been much excitement about the advent of 3D printing for the creation of bespoke solutions for small user groups such as the blind community <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">29]</ref>, it is as yet unclear whether 3D printing ofers advantages over existing options for O&amp;M professionals teaching street crossings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Participatory Design</head><p>This work primarily adopts the practice of Participatory Design <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">48,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">54]</ref>. This approach to computer system development recognises the expertise of users and therefore ensures that they play a critical role in the design process <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[48]</ref>. In this instance, O&amp;M trainers are defned as the primary stakeholders because they are the people who select O&amp;M training materials and structure their teaching in relation to the materials that they have available. As the recipients of O&amp;M training, BLV people must of course also be included in the design and evaluation. The active involvement of these two groups should help ensure that the work is directed to real needs, supports user values and considers the practicalities of implementation. Moreover, involvement in and ownership of the problemsolving process means that O&amp;M professionals will be more likely to use, maintain and evolve the solutions after completion of the project <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">REQUIREMENTS GATHERING</head><p>The project was initiated in response to suggestions made at a brainstorming session with O&amp;M professionals and a blind adult. They proposed that street crossings are an important component of O&amp;M training and that 3D printed maps might be of value.</p><p>We then confrmed interest from the broader accessibility community before proceeding with project. Two 3D printed maps depicting intersections immediately outside a conference venue were presented at a workshop attended by more than 50 accessible graphics producers, vision specialist educators, O&amp;M professionals and touch readers. Discussions and feedback indicated that more formal investigation into 3D printed street crossings was warranted and provided suggestions for design principles.</p><p>In the frst formal stage of work, detailed consultation with O&amp;M instructors was sought to determine their requirements for maps to assist with teaching street crossings.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Method</head><p>Semi-structured interviews were conducted with 11 O&amp;M instructors about what mapping tools they currently use to teach concepts of street crossings and/or specifc street crossings, what features these maps require, and how they think that 3D printed maps might be used. Interviews were conducted individually via phone or video conference and each took 30 to 60 minutes.  average of 17 years experience in the profession, having worked for fve diferent organisations (n=10) and/or as independent providers (n=4). While some of the participants specialised in services for a particular age group, together they had worked with clients from babies to a 104 year old. More details regarding participants are given in Appendix D.</p><p>3.1.2 Thematic analysis. All communication was transcribed then coded using NVivo software. Three samples were coded separately by two researchers for iterative cross-checking, discussion and updating of codes. By the third sample, there was a 74% level of agreement between the two raters and no further codes were suggested. The remaining coding was performed by a single researcher for consistency.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Results</head><p>3.2.1 Current practices and tools. All of the O&amp;M instructors interviewed actively teach street crossings. This work has two main purposes. The frst, familiarisation with specifc street crossings, is taught to all but the very youngest BLV clients, and is primarily done on the actual street corner. The second kind of training teaches fundamental concepts and skills, such as typical street crossing confgurations. This is mainly taught to children and to new arrivals in the region:</p><p>"refugees and children, teaching them about road crossings was a bit diferent when you needed a tactile form to describe or get them to understand the layout of intersections.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>" [P5]</head><p>There was a surprising level of inconsistency in terms of the mapping tools and technologies used by various O&amp;M instructors, some of which are illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3</ref>. The most common methods, each used by seven of the 11 interviewees, were swell paper tactile diagrams, handcrafted tactile diagrams, Lego and magnetic boards. All methods were reported to have limitations, as summarised in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>.</p><p>Swell paper (also known as microcapsule paper) diagrams are made by drawing or printing with carbon-based inks onto specialised paper that is heated, causing the dark areas to raise to a uniform height. Only four of our 11 participants had local access to the equipment required to create their own swell paper diagrams. When available, swell paper diagrams are favoured because they are relatively quick to produce and they are portable. However, they are not durable. Concern was also expressed that, due to the high level of abstraction used in swell paper diagrams, clients require good tactile graphics reading skills to understand them, with around 15% of BLV people having poor spatial mapping skills <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>.</p><p>A range of kits are available that can be used to represent road crossings, either designed for the purpose of O&amp;M training or as toys for sighted children. These kits are used for teaching concepts, mapping specifc street crossings, and asking the client to build their own map to check their understanding. Tactile Town <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref> by the American Printing House for the Blind is the most wellknown of these kits. Made primarily of felt, with Velcro for stability and storage, the kit is lightweight, includes a wide range of pieces for customisation of crossings, and has good visual contrast. Its main disadvantage is the prohibitively high price tag and cost for overseas shipping, meaning that the kit is only owned by one of the organisations represented by our participants. Tactile Town is not suitable for young children because it has a lot of small pieces. Nor is it used with adults because it lacks details such as ramps and Tactile Ground Surface Indicators.</p><p>"We see it more as a rainy day activity type of kit rather than teaching orientation. It's not technical enough.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>" [P3]</head><p>The Cook Kit (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3b</ref>) was favoured over Tactile Town for its simplicity, durability and the inclusion of ramps. However, it is no longer available and it requires some additions and modifcationsfake grass was added, the standard fgures are not used because they are not directional, and only two corners came with the kit. Again, it is only used with young children due to its simplicity. Citybox <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[50]</ref> is another kit made specifcally for BLV people, however none of our participants had used it because they felt that the pieces were designed for European cities and could not be transferred to the Australian environment. It is no longer available.</p><p>Toys could also be used as kits for creating tactile street crossings in collaboration with the BLV client. Lego was the most commonly used toy, favoured because it clips together securely and components such as trafc lights and street furniture are available. The main drawback of Lego is that it does not show curves well. Furthermore, there was concern that some adults are reluctant to use children's toys.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>"I don't think she felt comfortable using Lego in public. " [P8]</head><p>Hand crafting is the third category of methods currently used to provide tactile representations of street crossings. The most common crafting method is a magnetic white board or metal sheet with an array of magnets, usually cut from a sheet into customised shapes (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3a</ref>). This method is portable and secure. This is closely followed by tactile drawing kits such as the Draftsman Tactile Drawing Board <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref> or the Sensational Blackboard <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>  <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3d</ref>). All hand crafting methods sufer from the fact that they can look quite messy and unprofessional. Unless a lot of time is spent on their production, most handcrafted solutions also employ a high degree of abstraction, requiring more cognitive efort from users. An extreme example is drawing directly on a BLV client's hand or back, which can be used anywhere and anytime but only communicates a very low level of information.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Required features.</head><p>We also asked O&amp;M instructors what they would like us to create with 3D printing and what features should be included. Suggestions for 'ideal' 3D printed street crossing maps could be divided into two main categories.</p><p>(1) Typical intersections: O&amp;M instructors requested durable maps illustrating typical intersections to assist with concept development. The intersections most commonly mentioned were T-intersections, 4-way intersections, roundabouts, slip lanes with trafc islands and straight roads with pedestrian refuges. Ideally, intersection maps would be A4 size. Given the typical footprint of 3D printers, 20 cm 2 was considered an acceptable compromise. (2) Customisable intersections: O&amp;M instructors requested corner pieces, similar to those found in the Cook Kit, to create custom maps representing specifc intersections. Ideally, a 1:64 scale would be used to align with the most common toy cars.</p><p>Participants were asked to name the features that they considered essential, nice to have, or not needed in a 3D model of street crossings. Their responses are listed in full in Appendix A. We concluded that the following features were most important: intersection type, footpath, trafc islands, zebra crossings, pram ramps, slip lanes, the kerb, pedestrian crossing lines and the gutter. It was felt that the base map should be kept simple to allow for easy comprehension.</p><p>Other features could then be added to the base map if important: the grass verge, trafc lanes, Tactile Ground Surface Indicators, trafc light poles, tram stops, tram tracks, landmarks and shore lines. Toy or model cars, buses and bicycles could be used to indicate trafc lane types, direction of travel and parking. A lot of other important information would be best discussed rather than conveyed tactually.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3">Required properties. Thematic analysis of communications</head><p>during the requirements gathering phase revealed that the most common properties discussed in relation to street crossing materials were: using the materials to teach concepts; being able to customise the intersection layout using interchangable pieces and removable parts; and the importance of portability. A full list is given in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">DESIGNING AND REFINING 3D PRINTED ROAD CROSSING MAPS</head><p>Using the results from the requirements gathering phase as a starting point, we conducted an iterative co-design process creating 3D printed materials to support O&amp;M training for street crossings for BLV people.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Methodology</head><p>4.1.1 Co-design Process. 3D modelling was performed in Tinker-CAD by the frst author, who is an experienced accessible formats producer. 3D printing was performed throughout the design process to check that pieces were sturdy, could be printed reliably, and were tactually distinct. To begin the co-design phase, images of the designs or photographs of the frst printed prototypes, along with a description of the materials and questions, were sent to Guide Dogs Victoria and all O&amp;M professionals from the requirements gathering phase. Two people provided feedback via remote interview and another three provided written feedback. Whenever an individual made a suggestion that aligned with comments made by at least one other person, and which did not add unnecessary complexity, the design was refned and an image or tactile sample was provided to check that their idea had been interpreted correctly.</p><p>After all of the initial feedback had been incorporated and while COVID lockdown restrictions were temporarily lifted, a full set of the materials and accessories was delivered to Guide Dogs Victoria. Two O&amp;M trainers provided their initial impressions, made suggestions for further refnements and requested more pieces. Two blind adults who read by touch also provided hands-on assessments of the materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Street Layout Puzzle Pieces</head><p>Addressing the frst requirement for typical intersection layouts, collaboration through a 3D printing group for accessibility revealed that an O&amp;M instructor at the South Australian School for Vision Impaired had already created 3D printed puzzle pieces representing the most common intersections. These are small square puzzle pieces with connectors on the edges, each demonstrating a different street layout: straight, sharp corner, T-intersection, cross intersection, cross intersection with slip lanes, and roundabout.</p><p>The puzzle pieces are intended for use by children to provide familiarity with street layouts through play. The pieces are deliberately small, printed at 5cm wide, 5cm deep and 1cm high (excluding the connectors) so that small hands can easily feel both sides of the indented road at once.</p><p>Using the same template, we added nine more street layouts mentioned by O&amp;M instructors: a rounded corner, a cross intersection with pedestrian islands in two diferent arrangements, a cul-de-sac, and straight road pieces with a pedestrian refuge, chicane, wombat crossing or zebra crossing. We modifed the connectors slightly for an easier ft but they still require some smoothing after printing. Black permanent ink was added on the road sections for contrast (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">4</ref>). Immediately upon receiving two sets of crossing pieces, O&amp;M instructors requested many more straight road pieces so that learners could create a more realistic route with greater distance between the intersections. After asking a blind adult to map out a route using the puzzle pieces, we realised that a set should also include multiple T-intersection pieces to represent side streets that need to be crossed, along with two "home" pieces with a building to indicate the start and end of a route. The set continues to grow as people suggest additional intersections for inclusion.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">1:64 Scale Road Edge Pieces</head><p>To address the second requirement for customisable intersections, a series of 3D printed street corner pieces were created at 1:64 scale (Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>). At this scale, the pieces would be able to work with the Cook Kit, which is no longer available, and could be used with standard toy cars and toy street furniture. In keeping with the Cook Kit, the main pieces were road edge pieces, representing public the area from the gutter to owned properties. These road edge pieces were were made at the maximum size possible on an Ultimaker FDM printer, at a length of 20cm, and were 5mm tall. A variety of parts were created to allow creation of straight roads, However, once the pieces were printed, it became obvious that a very large space was required to lay out an intersection. Also, because of its large size and use with toys, the set presented more like a play kit for children rather than a professional tool that could be used with adults. Through several conversations between the researchers and O&amp;M professionals, the idea emerged to create smaller scale street crossings, as described in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">1:128 Scale Street Corners and Components</head><p>The third set of materials were designed in response to limitations of the 1:64 road edge pieces. First, the size was halved to 1:128 scale. This reduction in scale meant that a single lane road could be added to a corner piece and it would ft on a standard FDM printer. It quickly became obvious that four of these pieces could be placed together to form an intersection inside a frame, which would prevent movement while being touched. This also meant that the new pieces could fulfl both requirements: to demonstrate typical intersections and be combined to create customised intersections to represent specifc crossings. The pieces are illustrated in Figure <ref type="figure">6</ref> and the key design considerations are described below.</p><p>Portability and robustness is important for O&amp;M training.</p><p>• Size was reduced to 1:128 scale for portability and compact use. Each corner measured 12.7 cm wide and 12.7cm deep. • The base measured 1.5mm thick. This was considered the minimum thickness to provide strength while minimising plastic and printing time.</p><p>Minimal detail was included for tactual simplicity.</p><p>• In accordance with the essential features requested by O&amp;M professionals in the requirements gathering phase (Appendix A), shorelines were added, i.e. grass on one side of the footpath and a fence/building line on the other.</p><p>A variety of parts were created to allow customisation for diferent intersection types and also to allow the level of detail to be built up according to the client's needs and skills.</p><p>• A variety of ramps were inserted into the street corners.</p><p>• As the scale of 1:128 is not standard, street furniture was also created: a car, bus and bicycle with a distinct front and back, along with trafc lights, stop signs and give way (yield) signs.</p><p>Pieces were designed to be tactually distinct and recognisable.</p><p>• Gutters, footpaths and the grass verge were initially raised 5mm higher than the road to create a tactually distinct edge. However, a touch reader felt that this made the ramps too steep. The height was therefore adjusted to 3.5mm in the fnal model. • Grass beside the road was represented with a low irregular 3D printed texture. The fence (or building) line on the other side of the footpath measured 8.5mm high and 4mm wide with a rounded top. Pedestrian crossing lines with rounded tops were 1mm wide and raised by 0.5mm. This was considered the minimum to be noticeable without being overly distinct, as crossing lines indicate the line of travel but are not raised in real life. • In response to feedback from an adult touch reader, the circles on the trafc lights were raised higher and with indented centres for better tactile discriminability, in keeping with perceptual studies showing that outlined tactile symbols are more easily recognised than solid symbols <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">41,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">59</ref>]. • Braille letters were added to the signs because none of the blind touch testers were familiar with trafc sign shapes.</p><p>High contrast colours were used to assist people with low vision.</p><p>• On corner pieces, the base (road) was printed in black and the flament colour was changed to teal for the upper portions. Vehicles were printed in bright orange.</p><p>The pieces were designed to ft together with stability during tactile exploration.</p><p>• A frame was constructed to neatly ft four pieces (one intersection), preventing the pieces from moving when touched.</p><p>The frst frame was created using cardboard. In response to feedback from O&amp;M instructors, a second more sturdy frame was created with magnetic backing and wooden frame. • The street sign bases, car, bus and roundabout centre were also redesigned so that a small magnet could be inserted in the base while printing. An adhesive strip magnet was added to the base of the pedestrian islands, which were too small to contain magnets. The designs for the 1:128 scale street corner components and accessories have been made available for free download from www. thingiverse.com/thing:5177801.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">EVALUATION</head><p>Several sets of the 3D printed intersection pieces were produced and provided to Guide Dogs Victoria and an independent practitioner, and a set of the puzzle pieces was self-produced by South Australian School for Vision Impaired. Feedback was provided via interview and survey, and one O&amp;M practitioner provided video recordings of some of their sessions using the materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Participants</head><p>As detailed in Appendix D, seven O&amp;M practitioners completed the survey. Four actively used the materials while the other three O&amp;M practitioners from the requirements gathering phase viewed the materials over Zoom. Three worked for Guide Dogs Victoria, two worked for diferent agencies and two were independent practitioners, all in Australia.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Survey</head><p>5.2.1 Materials. Feedback from O&amp;M practitioners was collected through unstructured interviews and an online survey. The survey frst asked for background information about the respondent, which materials they used and with whom. Respondents were then asked to rate the 3D printed materials on a 5-point Likert scale in terms of the key criteria identifed as important in the requirements gathering phase (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>). The questions are listed in Appendix B. We did not ask about afordability because costs associated with 3D printing was largely unknown to respondents. Nor did ask about removable parts, as that is a binary (yes/no) question.</p><p>We also asked eight questions from the Usability Scale (SUS) <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>, omitting the two questions relating to integration/consistency of IT systems because they were not relevant to of physical materials. The term 'system' was replaced with 'materials' as it was more appropriate and the SUS tool has been found to be robust to such wording substitutions <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. The questions are listed in Appendix C.</p><p>Respondents were then asked to nominate what materials they would have used if the 3D printed materials were not available, and to rate this existing material using the same questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2">Results</head><p>. Seven O&amp;M professionals completed the survey. Of these, four had used the 3D printed materials with clients and three had not. The respondents chose a range of diferent existing materials to rate as their preferred tool for the same purpose if the 3D printed materials were not available: two chose the Tactile Town kit <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>; two selected hand-cut magnetic sheets on a whiteboard (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">3c</ref>); there was one response each for a raised line drawing kit and a track set for toy cars; and one person did not complete this section of the survey.</p><p>shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">7</ref>, the 3D printed materials ratings were generally favourable and similar to those of existing materials in terms of the key requirements that emerged in the requirements gathering and feedback phases. Importantly, the 3D printed materials were rated particularly highly in terms of demonstrating the key concepts for street crossings, being portable, being engaging and being professional in appearance.</p><p>The SUS scores were calculated and then adjusted according to the number of questions answered, as we asked eight (instead of ten) questions in total and one respondent answered only seven. The average SUS score for the 3D printed materials was 65.9 (n=7, sd=17.8), while the average SUS score for the chosen alternative was <ref type="bibr">56.25 (n=6, sd=5.3)</ref>. Both these scores are below the average of 68, and can be described as 'marginal' <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. As seen in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_7">8</ref>, the 3D printed materials were almost always rated more highly than the existing materials. There was an outlying low score for 3D printed materials from a respondent who did not answer questions relating to an existing material.</p><p>Both sets of materials were rated poorly in terms of assistance being needed for client to successfully use them (questions 4 and 10). However, may be expected. think tactile materials always need some level of explanation and orientation for someone who's blind or has low vision. Once the person is familiar with the materials I think many people would become more profcient using them. " <ref type="bibr">[anonymous]</ref> Adjusted SUS scores with questions 4 and 10 removed were 73.2 (sd=17.2) for the 3D printed materials and 63.9 (sd=3.4) for the existing materials. The 3D printed materials would therefore rate above the average SUS score of 68 and be described as 'acceptable' or 'good' <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>.</p><p>Thus overall, the 3D printed materials were rated as equivalent or better than existing materials for teaching street crossings. However, these results should be interpreted with caution given the small number of participants and the high variance of responses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Interviews and Video Evidence</head><p>Final interviews were held with four O&amp;M professionals -one who had used the materials extensively and three who viewed the materials over Zoom. A further three O&amp;M professionals who had used the materials provided extended comments on the survey. Further, one O&amp;M practitioner video recorded fve sessions documenting their use of the materials with three children.</p><p>The interviews, survey comments and videos were transcribed and coded in NVivo using the same themes as the requirements gathering phase. Three further requirements became evident: 'play', having the right 'level of detail' and 'cleaning'. An additional two themes emerged as desired or achieved outcomes: 'learning' and 'on-site use'.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.1">New requirements.</head><p>While engagement was recognised as a major theme in the frst two phases of this project, the particular importance of play only became obvious once the materials were used with children. The O&amp;M professional who made most use of the 3D models devised a number of learning-directed games to play with the 3D models.</p><p>"You've got to make it a fun game. We're playing with people walking around models. Kids love it,  their attention back to the learning topics. But if they began to lose focus, the O&amp;M instructor was easily able to re-engage the children through play-based learning such the road to buy sweets at the shop, or voicing a siren for the 'police' car when a road rule is broken.</p><p>The level of detail was an important consideration, with a balance required between keeping the maps as simple as possible for easy interpretation, whilst still including the details required teach important concepts. Simplicity is one of the frst requirements given in many guidelines on tactile graphics design, e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">44,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">58]</ref>. This is perhaps where the 3D nature of the models was most advantageous, as things like ramps, gutters and fences can be shown very simply and intuitively in 3D but would require the use of more complex and arbitrary symbols on a tactile graphic <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>.</p><p>Ease of cleaning has become a much more important requirement with the advent of COVID-19. The 3D printed materials were thought to be relatively easy to clean by spraying or wiping them down with an appropriate disinfectant. However, cleaning would be easier if the materials were heat resistant so that they could be placed in a dishwasher. By contrast, popular tools such as swell diagrams and Tactile Town (made of felt) are much more difcult to clean.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3.2">Outcomes.</head><p>Learning and on-site use are both desired outcomes for O&amp;M practice, which can only be achieved if the materials requirements are frst met.</p><p>Learning frst emerged as a theme during the co-design phase, when even the adult touch readers revealed they had not known the shape of street signs before feeling the 3D models, and were then motivated to ask further questions about what signs drivers use. In the evaluation phase, the O&amp;M professionals spoke about building on learning, with clients needing to learn the basic concepts frst before being able to move on to more advanced concepts with the 3D printed materials. They also said that clients were able to demonstrate that they had learned new skills through their use of the materials. "It really demonstrated to me that she's got a really good understanding of that layout now, which I don't think she had as near understanding before using the model. "</p><p>Strong evidence for learning using the 3D printed materials was provided by the videos, of which three featured the same totally blind child. In the frst session, the focus was on familiarisation with the pieces and the important elements of the street environment that they represent: the road, gutter, nature strip, footpath and fence. They next looked at diferent intersection types (T versus cross) and types of pram ramps. Once these basics were understood, they were able to move on to learning about alignment for crossing from one pram ramp to the next and expected movement. The child's frst attempts to place the last two corner pieces in the frame were unsuccessful ("I have no idea. I don't know"). This contrasted with a later session when they were able to both choose and place all four corner pieces to represent the specifc intersection at their school, demonstrating that they had learned to recognise the elements on the map, understanding their relative positions and the layout of their particular intersection. Another child, who had enough vision to understand the general layout of intersections, used the 3D maps to learn about trafc movement. By the end of their session, they demonstrated a good understanding of which way to check for trafc when crossing using a pedestrian islandthis was something that they had previously struggled with. Thus, the videos showed that the 3D printed materials can be used to teach a range of important O&amp;M concepts and skills to children who are blind or have low vision.</p><p>The second desired outcome, on-site use, was largely dependent on portability. This aim was clearly met, with practitioners using the pieces for on-site learning. "60% of the lesson would be actual road crossing practice, cane skills doing that, and then that would be supported by 40% of using the models to give more explanation as we were doing it. That's what's so great about them, they are so easy and portable ... Even the frame with the four bits in it, I just put it in the garden bed we were crossing the road and came back to it. " [P2] Several of the videos showed children using the maps on the path next to a street corner. Not only were the 3D printed materials small and light enough to carry, they were also secure, inexpensive and easily replaced, so that practitioners are able to use them outdoors without worrying about the possibility of losing pieces.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">DISCUSSION</head><p>6.1 RQ1: What are the most important requirements for tactile materials to teach street crossing concepts for people who are blind or have low vision?</p><p>Thirteen key requirements for tactile street crossing materials emerged from the requirements-gathering interviews with 11 O&amp;M professionals and an additional four were revealed in the co-design and evaluation processes. These requirements are listed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>. They can be grouped into four categories: (1) support teaching the required (2) enabling preferred teaching methods; (3) accessibility; and (4) practicalities. Customisation and removable pieces were the two most important requirements so that mapping tools can be used to demonstrate both standard layouts and specifc intersections that represent a road layout familiar to learner, or represent features discussion, such as alignment at a corner with a central ramp.</p><p>In removable pieces would allow the level of detail to be increased and new concepts to be added once the basics are learnt.</p><p>6.1.2 Teaching method. Teaching with children is made much easier when materials are engaging and enable play-based learning. Ideally, tactile mapping tools for O&amp;M should construction by BLV people (client-built maps) for independence and as a means of checking their understanding.</p><p>6.1.3 Accessibility. Any materials for use people who are BLV must of course be tactually distinct for touch readers and have high contrast for people with low vision. The level of detail is also important, as unnecessary clutter complicates the reading process <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>.</p><p>is an important issue because tactile reading relies on movement and meaning that individual pieces can accidentally be pushed out of place or out of reach.</p><p>6.1.4 Practicalities. Portability was another high priority identifed in the requirements gathering phase. This relies on size, weight, durability and ease of replacement (including afordability) if pieces become lost. Ease of cleaning was another practical concern that emerged later. Finally, O&amp;M professionals want materials that are professional in appearance and do not look like toys so that they can be used with adults and children alike.</p><p>6.2 RQ2: Is there a need for 3D printed O&amp;M tools to help teach intersections?</p><p>The requirements gathering phase provided clear evidence that there are gaps in the current availability of tools suitable to teach intersections for O&amp;M, with practitioners using a wide variety of tools but fnding problems with all of them (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>). Further, in the co-design phase we were able to produce 3D printed O&amp;M tools that demonstrated the value of this technology for creating bespoke accessibility solutions. 3D printing was found to ofer the following advantages:</p><p>• 3D models are durable and lightweight, enabling portability for use at the client's home, workplace, or while exploring routes. • 3D prints look professional enough to be used with adults in public places without fear of judgement or stigma. • 3D models are engaging and can be used for play-based learning with children • 3D prints can be designed to suit the specifc context. This meant that we were able to design materials to specifcally address the key concepts for street crossings. It also means that our models can be adjusted for a variety of street layouts and trafc conditions that difer from one region to the next. • 3D printing is afordable and can be made locally for use by a single O&amp;M working in isolation or in poorer regions of the world.</p><p>As further evidence for the usefulness of the 3D models, six of the seven O&amp;M practitioners who contributed to the interviews and survey comments asked about how they could access the 3D printed materials in the future.</p><p>"What happens next then? Can I get my hands on those? When can I buy some?" [P5] And after the 3D printed street crossing materials were supplied to Guide Dogs Victoria, they began making enquiries about how to obtain further materials and have decided to apply for a grant to purchase their own 3D printer. Meanwhile, the materials are already integrated into practice outside the scope of the research project and a second workshop using the materials with a group of children is planned through the education department. An additional set of materials was requested for use by a regional O&amp;M practitioner who is unable to access more expensive (usually shared) resources. This clearly demonstrates the perceived of the materials and the 3D printing technique for creation of customised tools.</p><p>While 3D printing has the potential to supplement and enhance existing resources for teaching street crossings, we do not contend that it will replace them. For example, Tactile Town is well tested and it is both generic and with enough pieces to be used across many diferent places and teaching goals. The main advantages of our 1:128 street corners over Tactile Town are low cost, easy cleaning, ability to print locally rather than relying on international shipping, and inclusion of more technical components such as ramps.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">RQ3: What are the design characteristics of successful 3D models for supporting O&amp;M training?</head><p>Generalising our results to allow for the creation of other materials for teaching recommend the following design considerations:</p><p>• 3D models should be small enough for the combined pieces to easily ft on a table top (or on a car bonnet) • Map components should ft together so that they will not be moved about when explored tactually. We used a frame with a magnetic backing for the 1:128 street corners and connectors for the puzzle pieces. Other methods could also be considered. • The most important features to include on 3D printed are shorelines, e.g. showing the diferent sections of the streetscape most relevant to pedestrians. Further detail should be kept to a minimum or provided as add-on/removable pieces. • Maps should be readily customised, either through the provision of multiple components or via easy 3D design. • If roads are wider than fnger width, they should be lower than surrounding features to refect the act of stepping from the kerb.</p><p>• 0.5mm is the minimum height for features that must be detectable but not prominent. Important features must be taller than this. • Keep features low, both to allow easy exploration of the whole by touch <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref> and so that pieces are not bulky for portability. • All designs must be touch-tested and feedback must be incorporated. In terms of our particular designs, the 1:128 scale street corners were most popular.</p><p>"This is my favourite. " "Mine too. " [P2 &amp; P14] The O&amp;M trainer who used the 1:128 street corners with a client said that she would "defnitely" continue to use these materials as part of her practice.</p><p>The puzzle pieces were also popular, mainly because of their small size, light weight and portability. The puzzle pieces would be used for two main purposes: as a handy reference that used to explain the immediate environment, and a tool for learners to create a route, reinforcing their memory of the order of steps and allowing the instructor to evaluate their understanding.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4">The Participatory Design Process</head><p>In accordance with the principles of value-sensitive design <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>, both user groups provided diferent and important contributions that refected their needs and values. Feedback from O&amp;M instructors related mainly to functionality and teaching goals. For example, O&amp;M instructors defned which features were important to include (or exclude) and made suggestions to improve portability and to keep pieces in place. Feedback from touch readers related mainly to recognition by touch and the related understanding of concepts. For example, they requested braille on street signs and suggested that the ramps should be less steep. We had not considered the need to demonstrate concepts such as the shape of street signs and the fact that they are only written on one side. This (again) demonstrates the vital importance of integrating the perspectives of people with into accessibility research <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[37]</ref>. In accordance with that participatory design contributes to a of co-ownership so that projects will continue the immediate research scope <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref>, the O&amp;M professionals we worked with have future plans to use and develop the materials.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.5">Limitations and Future Work</head><p>Production and evaluation of materials was severely limited by lockdown conditions due to the COVID-19 pandemic. Further rollout and evaluation will be of value. This could be done both in a controlled research setting and organically, now that the materials are available online for free download and use.</p><p>We plan to work with accessible formats producers and O&amp;M professionals to develop a guide on how to best use the 3D printed materials. This will include how to 3D print the fles, how to make adjustments for regional diferences, and suggested lesson plans (and games) for using the materials with children and adults who are blind or have low vision. Touch readers should also be able to use the guide to enable independent access to the learning materials.</p><p>Location-specifc needs was raised by many of the O&amp;M practitioners in the frst phase of the study. While practitioners elsewhere will be able to modify our models for their local variations, international diferences in O&amp;M needs poses an interesting research topic for future work. Ideally, resources should be able to be shared between regions, particularly for places without the ability to create their own materials.</p><p>During the requirements gathering phase, some O&amp;M instructors requested 3D models of complex intersections that are taught frequently, such as busy intersections near public transport in the city. These were not produced as part of the current project but ofer a logical next step and could be based on our current designs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">CONCLUSIONS</head><p>Our research investigates the use of 3D printing to provide tools for O&amp;M training to convey spatial information about street crossings for people who are BLV. Interviews with 11 O&amp;M professionals revealed a surprising variety in the tools they currently use to teach street crossings, which did not fulfl all of their needs. Using 3D printing for rapid prototyping, we co-designed a range of new materials with iterative feedback from O&amp;M professionals and touch readers to ensure that their needs were met. This participatory process has also contributed to a sense of co-ownership, with plans for use and development of the materials beyond the scope of this research. The new 3D printed models can be used to achieve learning goals and hold advantages over existing materials in terms of demonstrating key concepts, portability, engagement and professional appearance. This demonstrates the value of maker technologies for the development of specialised tools for the accessibility community. We hope the freely available library 3D printable street crossing components will contribute to the safety, independence and inclusion of BLV pedestrians.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The participatory design process, with direction from Orientation and Mobility (O&amp;M) instructors and touch readers at every stage.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="3,93.40,83.68,425.20,184.87" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>3. 1 . 1</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Participants. All 11 participants were qualifed and practising O&amp;M instructors in Australia. They had a minimum of eight and</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Some tactile mapping tools currently used to teach about intersections: (a) Cook Kit (b) handcrafting -cut strips of cardboard (c) magnets on a magnetic white board (d) handcrafting -map made with confectionery on a chocolate base. Images courtesy of Guide Dogs Victoria.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="4,67.62,83.69,212.60,158.42" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: 3D printed puzzle pieces demonstrating standard street layouts, in relation to an 8-year-old's average hand size measuring 14.2cm long</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="6,331.78,243.30,212.60,171.81" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 : 1 :</head><label>51</label><figDesc>Figure 5: 1:64 road edge pieces being used with standard toys</figDesc><graphic url="image-5.png" coords="7,67.62,83.69,212.59,141.73" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 6 : 1 :</head><label>61</label><figDesc>Figure 6: 1:128 street corners confgured for a cross intersection with fgures, trafc and signals, contained within a cardboard frame. An 8-year-old's average hand size measuring 14.2cm long is shown for reference.</figDesc><graphic url="image-6.png" coords="8,67.62,83.69,212.60,141.39" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: The printed (top rows) compared with existing materials (lower rows) as rated by seven O&amp;M professionals.</figDesc><graphic url="image-7.png" coords="9,135.92,83.69,340.16,525.70" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: Adjusted scores for eight questions from the standard usability scale (SUS) for the new 3D printed materials compared with existing materials.</figDesc><graphic url="image-8.png" coords="10,67.62,83.69,212.59,139.50" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>6. 1 . 1</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Teaching the required concepts. Concept development was seen as the main use for the 3D printed intersection pieces. "[Concept development] is what I use that sort of model for. Building that understanding of what is an intersection, how does trafc fow through it, how do signs work, and I suppose also the positioning -where are you in all of this?" [P2]</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="1,53.80,243.71,504.41,157.52" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>, Methods used to tactually represent street crossings, the number of orientation and mobility (O&amp;M) practitioners who had used this method from a total of 11 interviewees, and reported advantages or disadvantages although this option was not known to all practitioners. Other handcrafting materials included fuzzy felt, foam stickers, cardboard, and even confectionery (Figure</figDesc><table><row><cell>Method</cell><cell>n Advantages</cell><cell>Disadvantages</cell></row><row><cell>Swell paper</cell><cell>7 Quick to produce; Portable</cell><cell>Requires specialist equipment; Not durable;</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>High level of abstraction</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Handcrafted tactile graphics 7 Cheap, readily available materials</cell><cell>Time-consuming to produce; High level of</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>abstraction; Can look unprofessional</cell></row><row><cell>Lego</cell><cell cols="2">7 Readily available; Easy creation by BLV Limited shapes; Social stigma</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>learners</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Magnetic board</cell><cell>7 Cheap; Readily available; Portable</cell><cell>High level of abstraction; Can look unpro-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>fessional</cell></row><row><cell>Tactile drawing kit</cell><cell>5 Portable; Quick onsite creation</cell><cell>Not well-known; High level of abstraction</cell></row><row><cell>Cook Kit</cell><cell>3 Durable; Tactually distinct</cell><cell>No longer available; Limited pieces</cell></row><row><cell>Tactile Town</cell><cell cols="2">2 Versatile with many pieces; Good visual Expensive; Missing key information</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>contrast</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Drawing on back or hand</cell><cell>2 Quick; Portable</cell><cell>Transient; Low fdelity</cell></row><row><cell>Citybox</cell><cell>0 Good tactile &amp; visual contrast</cell><cell>Specifc for Europe; No longer available</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Needs for tactile street crossing materials, as emerged from thematic analysis of communications during the requirements gathering phase, where mentions = the number of times a need was mentioned, and people = the number of people who mentioned the need. Three further needs that emerged later in the project are listed at the bottom of the table.</figDesc><table><row><cell>4.1.2 Participants. A total of seven O&amp;M practitioners (includ-</cell></row><row><cell>ing fve from Guide Dogs Victoria) and two blind adults provided</cell></row><row><cell>feedback during the co-design phase, as documented in Appendix</cell></row><row><cell>D.</cell></row></table><note>4.1.3 Feedback process. As illustrated in Figure2, the 3D designs were constantly checked by O&amp;M professionals and touch readers, allowing for rapid prototyping with refnements made in response to their feedback.</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>This work was conducted as part of a project investigating the use of 3D printing for touch readers, supported by the Australian Research Council LP170100026. Thanks are extended to our ARC Linkage Project Partners: the Round Table on Information Access for People with Print Disabilities Inc., the Department of Education Victoria, Guide Dogs Victoria, NextSense and the Royal Society for the Blind. Special thanks to the many O&amp;M staf and touch readers whose participation, insights and suggestions made this work possible.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A FEATURES WANTED ON ACCESSIBLE MAPS OF STREET CROSSINGS B SURVEY QUESTIONS</head><p>Please rate your current preferred mapping tool in terms of the following characteristics. Scale: Strongly disagree, disagree, neutral, agree, disagree, or strongly disagree.</p><p>1. CONCEPTS: The are suitable for demonstrating the most important concepts relating to intersection layouts. 2. STANDARD LAYOUTS: The materials can be used to demonstrate the intersection layouts. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>C MODIFIED STANDARD USABILITY SCALE (SUS)</head><p>Please rate the following statements. Scale: Strongly disagree, disagree, neutral, agree, disagree, or strongly disagree.</p><p>1. I think I would like to use the materials frequently. 2. We found materials to complex. The 3D printed materials were easy to use. 4. I think that clients would need help to use the materials. 7. I imagine that most people would learn to use the materials very quickly. 8. We found the materials are very cumbersome to use. 9. We feel confdent using the materials. 10. I needed to explain a lot of things before I could use the materials with the client. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>D PARTICIPANT DETAILS</head></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Street Crossing by Sighted and Blind Pedestrians at a Modern Roundabout</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Daniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Ashmead</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Guth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Wall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Long</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ponchillia</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Transportation Engineering</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">131</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="812" to="821" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factors related to speed and accuracy of tactual discrimination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Austin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Sleight</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="283" to="287" />
			<date type="published" when="1952">1952. 1952</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Australian Division of National Mapping (ADON). 1986. Symbols for Tactual and Low Vision Town Maps</title>
		<imprint>
			<pubPlace>Canberra, ACT, Australia</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An empirical evaluation of the System Usability Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Bangor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Kortum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="574" to="594" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Determining What Individual SUS Scores Mean: Adding an Adjective Rating Scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Bangor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Kortum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Usability Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="114" to="123" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009. 2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uncovering information needs for independent spatial learning for users who are visually impaired</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nikola</forename><surname>Banovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Franz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Khai</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Truong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Mankof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anind</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility (ASSETS &apos;13)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Blind Pedestrians and the Changing Technology and Geometry of Signalized Intersections: Safety, Orientation, and Independence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janet</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Barlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Billie</forename><forename type="middle">Louise</forename><surname>Bentzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tamara</forename><surname>Bond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0145482X0509901003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0145482X0509901003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Visual Impairment &amp; Blindness</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="587" to="598" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Teaching travel at complex intersections</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janet</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Barlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Billie</forename><forename type="middle">Louise</forename><surname>Bentzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sauerburger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Franck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>AFB Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="352" to="419" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA, Chapter</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Tactile Graphics Guidebook. American Printing House for the Blind</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Barth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.archive.org/details/tactilegraphicsg00john" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988</date>
			<pubPlace>Louisville, Kentucky, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Orientation aids for students with vision loss</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Louise</forename><surname>Billie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Bentzen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Marston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<publisher>AFB Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="296" to="323" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">3D printing of personalised assistive technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Nussbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Emmiger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Z</forename><surname>Major</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-94274-2_19</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-94274-2_19" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICCHP Computers Helping People with Special Needs</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Linz, Austria; SpringerLink, Switzerland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="142" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Part II</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accessibility and Mobility of Persons Who Are Visually Impaired: A Historical Analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Blasch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Stuckey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0145482X9508900506</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0145482X9508900506" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Visual Impairment &amp; Blindness</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">89</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="417" to="422" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995. 1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">SUS: a &quot;quick and dirty&quot; usability scale</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Brooke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1201/9781498710411-35</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1201/9781498710411-35" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
			<publisher>Taylor and Francis</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="189" to="194" />
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond 3D printers&quot;: Understanding Long-Term Digital Fabrication Practices for the Education of Visually Impaired or Blind Youth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emeline</forename><surname>Brulé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gilles</forename><surname>Bailly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3411764.3445403</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445403" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CHI</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating the Implications of 3D Printing in Special Education</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erin</forename><surname>Buehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Niara</forename><surname>Comrie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Megan</forename><surname>Hofmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samantha</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Hurst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2870640</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2870640" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Accessible Computing (TACCESS)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016. 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Tactile scale models: threedimensional info-graphics for space orientation of the blind and visually impaired</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gabriela</forename><surname>Celani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luis</forename><forename type="middle">Fernando</forename><surname>Milan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis Group</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="801" to="805" />
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The recognition of 3D basic patterns and tactile icons for the blind</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yu-Chen</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chun-Hsien</forename><surname>Chiang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huan-Chieng</forename><surname>Chiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/6552/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Research Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="31" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010. 2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charlie</forename><surname>Gyder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.sensationalbooks.com/products.html#blackboard" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s">2021. Sensational Blackboard. Sensational Books!</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-04">April 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cognitive Workload Demands using 2D and 3D Spatial Engineering Information Formats</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Gabriel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Dadi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><forename type="middle">R B</forename><surname>Goodrum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1061/(ASCE)CO.1943-7862.0000827</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1061/(ASCE)CO.1943-7862.0000827" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Construction Engineering Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">140</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4014001" to="4014001" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Melody Carswell</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Orientation and mobility methods: Techniques for independent travel. Guide Dogs Victoria</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lil</forename><surname>Deverell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Prentice</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<pubPlace>Melbourne, Australia</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Polly</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Edman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
			<publisher>Tactile Graphics. AFB Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Arlington, VA, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Orientation and Mobility Techniques: A Guide for the Practitioner</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Diane</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Fazzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janet</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Barlow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<publisher>American Foundation for the Blind</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Lighthouse for the Blind and Visually Impaired</title>
		<ptr target="https://adaptations.org/products/bm444-1" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-04">2021. April 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Tactile Intersection Diagrams. Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">American Printing House for the Blind (APH). 2021. Draftsman Tactile Drawing Board</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.aph.org/product/draftsman-tactile-drawing-board/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-04">April 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">American Printing House for the Blind (APH)</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.aph.org/product/tactile-town-3-d-om" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-04">2021. April 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Tactile Town: 3-D O&amp;M Kit</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Value Sensitive Design and Information Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Batya Friedman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Kahn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Borning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="348" to="372" />
			<pubPlace>Sharpe, Armonk, N.Y</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Observations on active touch</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="477" to="491" />
			<date type="published" when="1962">1962. 1962</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Map Learning with a 3D Printed Interactive Small-Scale Model: Improvement of Space and Text Memorization in Visually Impaired Students</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stéphanie</forename><surname>Giraud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Anke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Brock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J-M</forename><surname>Marc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christophe</forename><surname>Macé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Joufrais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00930</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2017.00930" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empowering Low-Vision Rehabilitation Professionals with</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stéphanie</forename><surname>Giraud</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christophe</forename><surname>Joufrais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-41267-2_9</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-41267-2_9" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Methods. In ICCHP: International Conference on Computers Helping People with Special Needs</title>
		<editor>Klaus Miesenberger, Christian Bühler, and Petr Penaz</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="68" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>Springer International</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Do-It-Yourself. Part II</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Universal Design &amp; Visual Impairment: Tactile Products for Heritage Access</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaume</forename><surname>Gual</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marina</forename><surname>Puyuelo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joaquim</forename><surname>Lloveras</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Engineering Design (ICED11)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Scotland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>The Design Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Three-dimensional tactile symbols produced by 3D Printing: Improving the process of memorizing a tactile map key</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaume</forename><surname>Gual</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marina</forename><surname>Puyuelo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joaquim</forename><surname>Lloveras</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Visual Impairment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="263" to="278" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">LucentMaps: 3D Printed Audiovisual Tactile Maps for Blind and Visually Impaired People</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timo</forename><surname>Götzelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2982142.2982163</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2982142.2982163" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility (ASSETS&apos;16)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="90" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Automatically Gener-Tactile Detail Maps by 3D Printers for Blind Persons</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timo</forename><surname>Götzelmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexsander</forename><surname>Pavkovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ICCHP: International Conference on Computers Helping People with Special Needs</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Klaus</forename><surname>Miesenberger</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deborah</forename><surname>Fels</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dominique</forename><surname>Archambault</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Petr</forename><surname>Peňáz</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wolfgang</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Zagler</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Switzerland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer International</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Part II</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Participatory Design Works: Mechanisms and Efects</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Nicolai Brodersen Hansen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kim</forename><surname>Dindler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ole</forename><forename type="middle">Sejer</forename><surname>Halskov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Claus</forename><surname>Iversen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bossen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Ditte Amund Basballe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Schouten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3369457.3369460</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3369457.3369460" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">OZCHI&apos;19: Proceedings the 31st Australian Conference on Human-Computer-Interaction</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="30" to="41" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Methods for Creating and Evaluating 3D Tactile Images to Teach STEM Courses to the Visually Impaired</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Hasper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rogier</forename><surname>Windhorst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Terri</forename><surname>Hedgpeth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leanne</forename><surname>Van Tuyl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ashleigh</forename><surname>Gonzales</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Britta</forename><surname>Martinez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hongyu</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zolton</forename><surname>Farkas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Debra</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Baluch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of College Science Teaching</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tactile picture perception in sighted and blind people</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Morton</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Heller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioural Brain Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">135</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="68" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002. 2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Living Disability Theory: Refections on Access, Research, and Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Megan</forename><surname>Hofmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Devva</forename><surname>Kasnitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Mankof</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cynthia</forename><surname>Bennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility (ASSETS &apos;20)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accessible maps for the blind: Comparing 3D printed models with tactile graphics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leona</forename><surname>Holloway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kim</forename><surname>Marriott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Butler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">198</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Examining the Conceptual Understandings of Geoscience Concepts of Students with Visual Impairments: Implications of 3-D Printing. Thesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Koehler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>The Ohio State University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">3D printing makes virtual world more real for blind learners. e-mentor</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kolitsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016. 2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="65" to="70" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cutaneous Perception of Form</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Major</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.jstor.org/stable/1412680" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="147" />
			<date type="published" when="1898">1898. 1898</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An evaluation of tactile directional symbols</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Don</forename><surname>Mccallum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Ungar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><surname>Jehoel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Visual Impairment</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="83" to="92" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kuhn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Participatory Design. Publications of the ACM June</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993. 1993</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="24" to="28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Guidelines and Standards for Tactile Graphics. The Braille Authority of North America</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.brailleauthority.org/tg/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<pubPlace>USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Braille Authority of North America (BANA</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Play and Concept Development in Infants and Young Children with Severe Visual Impairments: A Constructionist View</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Recchia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0145482X9709100408</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0145482X9709100408" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Visual Impairment &amp; Blindness</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">91</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="401" to="406" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997. 1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tactile Earth and Space Science Materials for Students with Visual Impairments: Contours, Craters, Asteroids, and Features of Mars</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Audrey</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Rule</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Geoscience Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="205" to="218" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">American Foundation for the Blind</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><surname>Sapp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<publisher>AFB Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA, Book section 2</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Concept Development</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Participatory Design: Principles and Practices</title>
		<editor>Douglas Schuler and Aki Namioka</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
			<publisher>Lawrence Erlbaum Associates</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Hillsdale, New Jersey</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Maritime Buoyage on 3D-Printed Tactile Maps</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mathieu</forename><surname>Simmonet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Serge</forename><surname>Morvan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dominique</forename><surname>Marques</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Olivier</forename><surname>Ducruix</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arnaud</forename><surname>Grancher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sylvie</forename><surname>Kerouedan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3234695.3241007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3234695.3241007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="450" to="452" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Citybox by Tactilise</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Tactilise</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_RA5skGp8Gc" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-08">2015. August 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Customizable 3D Printed Tactile Maps as Interactive Overlays</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brandon</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anind</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Dey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Siewiorek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Asim</forename><surname>Smailagic</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility (ASSETS &apos;16)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="79" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Representation of Space in Blind Persons: Vision as a Spatial Sense</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Thinus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">-</forename><surname>Blanc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florence</forename><surname>Gaunet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Bulletin</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997. 1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Automatic derivation of on-demand tactile maps for visually impaired people: frst experiments and research agenda</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Guillaume</forename><surname>Touya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sidonie</forename><surname>Christophe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jean-Marie</forename><surname>Favreau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amine</forename><surname>Ben Rhaiem</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Cartography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="91" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Participatory design: a multi-voiced efort</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bettina</forename><surname>Törpel</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CC &apos;05: The 4th Decennial Conference on Critical Computing: Between Sense and Sensibility</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="181" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Development of tactile foor plan for the blind and the visually impaired by 3D printing technique</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raša</forename><surname>Urbas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matej</forename><surname>Pivar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Urška Stankovic</forename><surname>Elesini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.24867/JGED-2016-1-019</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Graphic Engineering and Design</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="19" to="26" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016. 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">/</forename><surname>Jged-</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.24867/JGED-2016-1-019</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-01-19">2016-1-019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">American Printing House for the Blind</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Wiener</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Welsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Foundations of Orientation and Mobility</title>
		<editor>and Bruce Blasch</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>History and Theory. Third Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Debra Page Baluch, and Bradley S. 3D printing tactile graphics for the blind: Application to histology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ting</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Lo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ashleigh</forename><surname>Gonzales</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Annual Rehabilitation Engineering Society of North America Conference 2014 (RESNA). RESNA</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Arlington, VA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>4 pages</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Guide to Designing Tactual Illustrations for Children&apos;s Books</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Suzette</forename><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<pubPlace>Louisville, Kentucky</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A further contribution to the Tactual Perception of Form</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Zigler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Barrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/h0074982</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/h0074982" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Experimental Pscyhology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="192" />
			<date type="published" when="1927">1927. 1927</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Concept development of blind children</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Zweibelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Fisher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Barg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0145482X6706100703</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0145482X6706100703" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Visual Impairment &amp; Blindness</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="218" to="222" />
			<date type="published" when="1967">1967. 1967</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
