<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the Situated Practices of School Technology Leaders in the Early Stages of Educational Technology Adoption</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Seray</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Ibrahim</surname></persName>
							<email>s.ibrahim@ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University College London University College London University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Asimina</forename><surname>Vasalou</surname></persName>
							<email>a.vasalou@ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University College London University College London University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Benton</surname></persName>
							<email>l.benton@ucl.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University College London University College London University College London</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the Situated Practices of School Technology Leaders in the Early Stages of Educational Technology Adoption</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3502120</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Educational Technology</term>
					<term>Adoption</term>
					<term>Technology Leader</term>
					<term>Situated Practice</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>School-driven technological innovation has the potential to positively impact on classroom practice, yet it can also be disrupted by incompatibilities between the existing school ecology and new educational technologies. To help mitigate this disruption a particular staf member often takes on a facilitative leadership role to champion new technology initiatives. However little is known about how this technology leader role impacts on the adoption of new technologies in the classroom. Taking a situated lens, we embarked on a multiple case study of four schools who were aiming to adopt a new literacy game in the classroom. Through interviews with technology leaders and feldnotes from our site observations, we systematically analysed their actions and concerns over two academic terms. This highlighted an overwhelming concern with managing the material dimension of the technology, teacher agency and division of labour and mechanisms for communication and monitoring. Our fndings raise important considerations for HCI researchers seeking to embed their technologies into practice alongside recommendations for supporting leaders tasked with coordinating this process.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Educational technologies used in schools have the potential to contribute a number of benefts. These include improved access to digital resources for organising and monitoring learning, fostering student-centred learning, as well as ofering fexible and personalised learning materials <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">25]</ref>. When scaling up educational technology use beyond a single classroom, previous research has frequently carried out pilots which were supported by the researchers (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">30]</ref>). This has ensured the digital technology is used following a pre-determined methodology, whilst teachers receive support when needed in class. This approach has evidenced the efectiveness of new technologies and has been oftentimes a persuasive force to inform the school leadership on their technology investment decisions. However, when schools have embarked to deploy new digital initiatives that are outside the purview and care of the researcher a new set of concerns emerge. The introduction of new technologies has been found to bring signifcant challenges and incompatibilities between the existing school ecology and new educational technologies <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, placing higher demands on teachers who are already struggling to work within the confnes of limited resourcing <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9]</ref>. These tribulations can be particularly evident in the early stages of technology adoption during which new classroom practices are still forming and are thus fragile. When attempting to disentangle the challenges of introducing new technologies in school settings, prevalent discourses have focused on the social and psychological implications of technologies or separately, have considered the characteristics of the technologies independent of their practical uses <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref>. However, educational technologies and their social practices are inseparable <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref>. A 'situated lens' is therefore necessary to understand how teaching staf adopt new educational technology within their everyday practices, including the mundane practices that foster the sustained use of technology <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[42]</ref>. The present work takes this lens focusing on the role of the school technology leader. Technology leaders are champions of the technology who are responsible for motivating and supporting teaching staf in the process of adopting new educational technology in the classroom <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[33]</ref>. Previous research has shown the signifcance of leadership in whole-school technology initiatives and the roles taken that support this: e.g., organising staf development, or initiating technology policy in the school <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26]</ref>. Even though this work has contributed broad leadership recommendations, it has not shown how leadership practices are shaped within specifc school settings, their operational structures, and the social relationships developing between the technology leader and the school staf team. Given that each school has a diverse character, it is unclear how technology leaders prioritise and support others to adopt technology within the boundaries of their local setup. Also, since the technology leader has a facilitative role in new technology initiatives, a situated understanding of these practices could equip HCI researchers seeking to embed their technologies into the classroom longer term with new strategies that support leaders from a diversity of school settings. We address this gap with a multiple case study of four schools who signed up to use a new adaptive literacy game 'Navigo' designed for primary school students across multiple classes and year groups, under the direction of a technology leader tasked with coordinating the process. Combining feld notes from school observations and interviews with technology leaders, we systematically analyse a period of two academic terms when the technology was frst introduced and new classroom practices had begun to develop in order to compare and contrast the four cases. Our goal is to understand the concerns of school technology leaders and the practices they employ to support other staf when introducing new educational technologies within the classroom. Based on the four case studies, our paper makes three main contributions. First, we add to empirical research on educational technology adoption by illustrating four diverse cases of how technology leaders coordinated this process. Second, we present a systematic methodological approach for investigating school-based technology adoption by focusing on situated action. Third, we propose recommendations for HCI researchers interested in supporting technology leaders tasked with leading technology adoption in their school.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED LITERATURE 2.1 Technology leaders and school leadership</head><p>The use of technology in education can be led by motivated teachers at a small scale, or conducted as a school-wide implementation involving multiple classes and teaching staf. Research by Forkhosh-Baruch et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[16]</ref> examined the diferences between teacher-led and school-wide adoption of educational technology, showing that in both instances there were similar patterns in relation to how and when the technology was used to support the curriculum. However, in the case of the school-wide initiatives, a member of staf within the school was required to coordinate it. Taking a longitudinal multiple case study, Ottenbreit-Leftwich et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[32]</ref> interviewed newly qualifed teachers over four years to understand the process of technology adoption. Teachers' practices with technology were overwhelmingly impacted by their school structures, policies, cultures and resources, as opposed to internal enabling factors held by individuals, such as their attitudes or technical skills, which had a weaker impact. These examples illustrate the important role of technology leaders in coordinating the process of technology adoption within the complex institutional context of the school. In line with previous work which has shown that school principals delegate the leadership of technology programmes to senior staf <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[41]</ref>, in this research, technology leaders are individuals who occupy a senior role in the school and are also responsible for a school-wide technology adoption initiative. Aiming to understand which leadership approaches best supported technology adoption, Yuen et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[46]</ref> analysed models of change in 18 schools who had sought to integrate educational technology into their teaching and learning practices. They attended to several characteristics, such as school values, the perceived impact of technology, the school culture and its history of pedagogical innovation. Based on these, they identifed three clusters of leadership. Model A schools were led by a top-down management approach that ensured all staf reached a minimum level of technology competency. Model B schools were also managed top-down, although the leadership involved teachers actively in the process of adoption. Model C schools displayed multiple leadership strategies that did not necessarily involve the senior leadership team, e.g. the school principal, but instead supported teachers to implement new technology initiatives bottom-up. Model A schools tended to develop teachers' digital skills, which did not alone yield successful technology adoption within the school. In contrast, by involving teachers in the process of curriculum innovation, Model B schools successfully engaged in a process of adoption. They also displayed technology-supported pedagogical practices that were found to be more student-centred as compared with those of Model A schools. Finally, Model C schools, characterised by teachers driving the change process, were also successful in adopting technology. Technology was used to initiate and implement new ideas by both teachers and students, thus it was an empowering tool . This third cluster of schools additionally displayed a strong sense of mission and a clearly identifable vision of education that permeated practice across the school (see also <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>). The study by Yuen et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[46]</ref> suggests that efective technology leaders involve teachers in the process of technology adoption and leadership can be either hierarchical, or distributed, as evidenced through the success of both Model B and C schools. Harris clarifes that <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref> (p.174) "distributed leadership does not imply that the formal leadership structures within organisations are removed or redundant. Instead, it assumes that there is a powerful relationship between vertical and lateral leadership processes". In related work, Ertmer and Ottenbreit-Leftwich <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref> conducted a review of past research in the area of technology-enhanced learning providing further support for the importance of involving teachers to shape technology adoption initiatives. The same authors suggested that for teachers to leverage technology as a meaningful pedagogical tool, technology leaders must not only communicate a consistent and shared vision for the technology use, but also create opportunities for teachers to actively shape this vision by carving role identities within the school and including teachers in key decisions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Collaborative cultures</head><p>Alongside the collaborative relationship between technology leader and teacher, Ertmer and Ottenbreit-Leftwich <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref> discuss the importance of horizontal collaboration between teachers, for example through peer coaching <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[32]</ref>. Collaboration has generally been regarded as integral for teacher learning about technology since it can support teachers to refect on and problem solve how to use technology within their teaching practices <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32]</ref>. Meirink et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[28]</ref> investigated the specifc characteristics of teacher collaborations across fve schools undergoing pedagogical change that included technology adoption <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[28]</ref>. They identifed that teacher groups who developed sharing practices about content and instruction evidenced increased learning about the new technology. Other work by De Jong et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23]</ref> found that the school culture and institutional values go on to inform the nature of collaboration between teachers. In some of the schools they observed there were symmetrical collaborations between teachers aiming to improve teaching in line with their existing school culture. However, the school leadership in one of the schools held rigid beliefs about teaching resulting in a hierarchical approach to collaboration in which teachers sought regular feedback from the leadership in order to meet their expectations. Having little ownership over the process, these teachers expressed little desire to continue their collaboration. Therefore, collaboration approaches within teacher teams are situated, they can take varied forms depending on the culture of the school context and this may in turn have an impact on the relationship between teachers and the technology leader.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Enabling conditions orchestrated by technology leaders</head><p>Although past work has predominantly focused on the organisational dimension of schools, some research has also recognised the pragmatic, operational tasks that fall under the purview of the technology leader when planning and maintaining technology initiatives, such as professional development. Whilst many schools tend to recognise the importance of teacher development <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[46]</ref>, this has been often planned in the form of one-of training on specifc topics.</p><p>To provide efective teacher development, Kearsley <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24]</ref> argues that schools must create the space and time for teachers to practice what they learned <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24]</ref> through a range of organised opportunities such as collaboration and coaching, on-site, individualized instruction, observation of ICT integration in practice, and self-directed learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">21]</ref>.</p><p>Another operational task, that has been given less attention in the literature is the planning and maintenance of technology <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref>. Flanagan and Jacobsen <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref> highlight the importance of the material and spatial arrangement of technology through its access. Placing tablets or computers within classes, as well as introducing mobile workstations, can remove physical barriers and establish technology as part of the classroom ecology of learning resources. Other work by Rosner and Ames <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37]</ref> highlights the foresight technology leaders must have to maintain the technology when it breaks down. In a school-wide technology initiative in Paraguay, the authors reported a tension when tablets broke down and required repair. Since the school leadership had not taken the responsibility of resourcing this, over time the tablets became obsolete. Separately, Sheepmaker et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38]</ref> suggest that planning and maintaining technology projects beyond the end of planned research feldwork also encompasses attending to both the material tools and social practices within the setting. Following a three-year co-design project with neurodiverse children and teachers, the authors developed a toolkit consisting of material tools (methodological guidance) and social tools (guidance on supporting the social community).</p><p>Interviews and surveys with teachers revealed that one of the challenges reported by teachers involved having the skills to explain the technologies to the children. As such, the authors suggest that for schools to continue using technologies beyond the end of a specifed project, schools and their technology leaders must engage in creating a supporting community within which technologies can be used. multiple teachers/classes require coordination and collaboration at an institutional level in order to succeed <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[16]</ref>. To achieve this, the school leadership takes an important role in orchestrating the process, namely through a technology leader <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[41]</ref>. Previous research has shown that teachers should be actively involved in shaping the new initiative <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>, which is possible in schools with both vertical and hierarchical leadership approaches <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">46]</ref>. Technology leaders must orchestrate this involvement and collaboration <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">35]</ref> and simultaneously support a range of operational tasks, for example developing teachers' technical competence through teacher development, allocating time for planning or managing the technology <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">46]</ref>. Educational technology adoption occurs in the school's complex institutional and socio-cultural context <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">38]</ref>. From a situated lens, each school setting can have its own way of enacting leadership processes that in turn mediate the process of adopting new technology. Prior research has often employed teacher interviews to identify patterns of leadership during the adoption process (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32]</ref>) highlighting a gap in understanding technology leaders' concerns and their situated practices when leading a teaching team. Moreover, whereas research in this area has often applied an organisational lens, considering the nature of the technology leader's work as reported in Section 2, we propose that it is equally important to recognise that organisational factors, such as time or resourcing, can be intertwined with social and material considerations <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">40]</ref>. This matters, as technology adoption can only be supported when there are common understandings about how each school enacts technology leadership and how school team members take responsibility over enabling conditions and resourcing <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">46]</ref> • What are the concerns of technology leaders when leading a teaching team in technology adoption? • What are the practices they employ in leading their team and how efective are these practices in fostering technology adoption?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">MOTIVATION AND RESEARCH QUESTIONS</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">NAVIGO GAME AND APPROACH TO SCHOOL SUPPORT</head><p>The Navigo literacy game was designed to support Primary School children's acquisition of reading skills. The game covers the frst four years of the primary literacy curriculum (age 5-8). Additionally, owing to their difculties in acquiring early reading skills, the game was designed to support older children (age 8-11) with persistent reading difculties. Navigo has an Egyptian inspired narrative and the child is tasked to fnd their missing grandma by exploring a pyramid with their avatar. Entering the pyramid activates a series of game activities through which they progress towards this goal. Navigo contains over 900 game activities that cover a range of literacy skills, including phonics and phonemic awareness, exception words, reading for meaning, and reading fuency. To maintain children's interest in the game and foster transferability of learning, there are a total of 15 diferent themed game mechanics that enable children to practice the same learning objective through a variety of game activities. These mechanics include multiple-choice, matching, splitting, sequencing, hit-the-target and fll-in-the-gaps (see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> for examples).</p><p>Navigo was designed to be used in two diferent ways in the classroom. First, the game operates in an adaptive mode. To cater to the diverse language and cognitive profles of diferent ages and groups, Navigo identifes what language features each child should work on, the content they should practice for a given feature, and the most suitable game mechanic to maintain an appropriate level of challenge based on their initial user profle and subsequent performance within the game <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. Therefore, whilst a class of children are seemingly playing the same game, the content and mechanics is customised to each child's profle. Second, using Navigo's teacher tool, teachers can browse through the available literacy features and pre-assign games to the whole class, or individual students. Informed by early feedback from teachers, this functionality was vital to identify games that align with teachers' weekly learning aims (see Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>). Therefore, the teacher tool enables teachers to bypass the adaptive function through their own game choices.</p><p>Once a child has played all the teacher-assigned games Navigo automatically reverts to adaptive mode. Given its functionality, Navigo requires the setup of individual student accounts to maintain a live record of a student's performance, as well as classes associated with a teacher to allow for teacher tool game assignments.</p><p>Schools that signed up to use Navigo received a set of new Android tablets with the game installed. In addition to the software and hardware provided to the schools, the research team recognised the important role of teacher development in line with previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[43]</ref>. Initially a two-hour Continuing Professional Development (CPD) training session was undertaken with participating teachers. The CPD sessions occurred directly within the schools, linking to the idea that CPD based in school settings of teachers involved leads to better student and teacher outcomes <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. CPD was delivered face to face, as this was the key preference expressed in teacher interviews that took place at an earlier stage. CPD scaffolded the learning process to empower the teachers to develop confdence, skills and knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">44]</ref> in the process of technology adoption. In many learning contexts the dominant form of professional development remains as a 'transfer' of knowledge or 'best practices' from an expert presenter to an audience. In practice, within the education sector, this often includes a process whereby a teacher participates in an external course and then returns to school to share knowledge with colleagues. However, despite continued dominance, this CPD model is known to be unlikely to lead to improvements in teaching and learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[31]</ref> unless further active participation by all is involved <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[19]</ref>. Therefore, alongside the CPD, the research team continued to monitor the school's technology use and supported the schools as required through a designated team member. In addition to emergent questions that the teachers had, the content of the CPD and continuous support from the research team were designed to address four topics: (1) the school technology leader's role in coordinating the teaching team (2) the weekly timetabling of Navigo (3) tablet maintenance and access, i.e., storage and charging (4) training and alignment of Navigo with teachers' intended use of this technology within their teaching.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">METHODOLOGY 5.1 Context and Sampling</head><p>The research took place in a UK Primary School setting with students who were learning to read from Years 1-3 (aged 5-8 years) and those with reading difculties from Years 4-6 (aged 8-11 years). All of the schools had prior experience using technology with their students as part of their teaching. Once ethical approval was obtained through the university ethics board, eleven schools in the South of England signed up to use Navigo. As part of the sign-up process, we agreed a target number of students that each school would aim to meet and schools were subsequently provided with a sufcient number of Android tablets to enable them to fulfl this target given their particular school circumstances (e.g. timetabling allowing for tablets to be shared between classes). For this study we chose to take a case study approach, focusing on four schools that met the following criterion: planned for multiple teachers to use Navigo across diferent classes and whose work was coordinated by a technology leader. Given our research question, the unit of analysis is the technology leader. The case study approach is well suited to studying the contextual complexities of real-world settings <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[45]</ref>. Rather than seeking to identify and abstract generalisable actions that describe how technology leaders coordinate the introduction of technology, case study research recognises that actions are inextricably linked to the context, i.e., the school. As such, we investigate how technology leaders' actions are dependent on social and material circumstances <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[42]</ref>, as well as how their decisions and actions impact on the use of Navigo in the early stages of educational technology adoption.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Case studies</head><p>5.2.1 Blue School Overview. Blue is a mixed, inner city community school. The school size is considered small with one class per year group. There are approximately 30 pupils in each class, ranging from reception class through to year 6. Half of the pupils in the school are described as being from ethnic minority backgrounds although few are at the early stage of learning English as an additional language. Fewer pupils than the UK national average are described as having special educational needs and/or disabilities. The target set for this school was 100 pupils. These were formed of 83 students in Years 1-3 and 17 students with reading difculties in Years 4-6. Students were supported to take part by 8 teaching staf. There were no reported issues with the school Wi-Fi internet connectivity (which was required for accessing the game). The school was provided with 30 tablets, which were shared across classes and charged through a combination of individual and multiport USB chargers. The tablets were stored in the lockable photocopy room when not in use, in plastic storage boxes. The school had ofsite tertiary IT technical support, which was used to set up the tablets with internet connectivity and security at the start of the project. Blue technology leader: The school literacy lead acted as the technology leader. In addition to their literacy lead role, they were also the class teacher for Year 3. The involvement of the literacy lead was initiated by the school team following a university workshop that Blue staf had attended. Having established consent from the Headteacher, the staf member who attended this earlier workshop had signed up to be part of the project, indicating that the literacy lead would be their technology leader. As literacy lead, Blue was part of the school's middle leadership team. Another school contact, the school special educational needs coordinator (SENCO), acted as a second leader and intermediary with researchers for specifc activities, like establishing child consent and addressing initial technical challenges.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2">Orange School Overview.</head><p>Orange is a mixed community, inner city school. The school size is described as 'larger than most', with two classes per year group from reception through to Year 6, with approximately 30 pupils in each class. Over 80% of all pupils come from ethnic minority backgrounds with over half of all pupils learning English as an additional language. The proportion of children with special educational needs and/or disabilities is described as 'very much higher than the UK national average'. The school target was 94 pupils, which included 59 pupils from Year 3 and 35 pupils, who were described as having reading difculties, from Years 4-6. In total, 6 teaching staf supported the use of Navigo. The school was issued with 30 tablets, which were shared across classes and connected to the school Wi-Fi with no reported issues. The tablets were stored in a lockable drawer in the technology leader's ofce (the inclusion room) and charged overnight on multiport charging sockets. The school held an external contract with an ofsite IT technical support team who set up and maintained a range of technologies within the school.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Orange technology leader:</head><p>The school SENCO acted as the project technology leader. The SENCO and school became involved after being invited to take part by a member of the research team, owing to an existing relationship. In her existing role within the school, the SENCO occupied a senior leadership position.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.3">Silver School</head><p>Overview. Silver is a large inner city mixed, community school. The school is considered large with two classes per year group, and 30 pupils in each class. The proportion of pupils from minority ethnic groups and the number of pupils who speak English as an additional language is much higher than the national average. The proportion of students with special educational needs and/or disabilities is also above the UK national average. The school target was 156 pupils, supported by 15 staf members. Of these pupils, 121 were from Years 1-3 and 35 pupils with reading difculties had been identifed from Years 4-6. The school was issued with 60 tablets which were stored in a dedicated tablet storage unit and charging station, located centrally within the school. There were no reported internet connectivity issues. In addition to teaching staf, there was an onsite IT technician who ofered advice on internet connectivity and security related to the tablets. Silver technology leader: The school's literacy lead acted as the technology leader. The school had volunteered to participate after learning about the project from an existing school-university partnership. In their role as literacy lead, this technology leader held a middle leadership role within the school. The technology leader also worked with a secondary leader who was a learning mentor for the older primary aged students with reading difculties.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.4">Yellow School Overview.</head><p>Yellow is an inner city, mixed primary school. It is a new school that is sponsored by a national-level Academy Trust, meaning that the trust receives direct funding from the government for managing the school, independently of the local educational authority. The school started from reception through to Year 4 with two classes per year group, and 30 pupils were in each class. The proportion of pupils who have special educational needs and/or disabilities is above UK national average. Pupils are from a wide range of diferent ethnic backgrounds and almost half of the pupils speak English as an additional language although there are no pupils in the early stages of learning English. The school target was 133 pupils, 117 were from Years 1-3 and 16 children with reading difculties from Year 4. These pupils were supported by 5 teaching staf. The school were issued with 60 tablets stored within a lockable technology server room overnight with access to multi-port charging points. In this early stage of setting up the technologies, it was identifed that the school existing internet bandwidth was insufcient for supporting their daily school needs, as well as the additional internet requirements posed by Navigo. This issue was resolved within two months and the bandwidth was reported to be drastically increased from 50mbps to in excess of 300mbps. There was no locally identifed IT support within the school, although the technology leader worked with an ofsite IT service to address internet connectivity and storage solutions. Yellow technology leader: As literacy lead and Year 4 class teacher, the Yellow technology leader was identifed by the Headteacher. The school were recruited to the project via an existing relationship between the school and a member of the research team.</p><p>In contrast to the other schools, Yellow's technology leader did not hold a leadership role within the school's operational structure. A summary of school technology leader profles is presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">1</ref>. In each case 'P1' indicates the school's primary technology leader. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3</ref> illustrates the target number of child users agreed with each school alongside the number of active child accounts within the research period (two school terms from the start of the academic year September 2019 until mid-March 2020).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Data collection and analysis</head><p>As part of the overall procedure for introducing the new technologies into the four schools, once headteacher consent was established, the research team liaised with the school technology leader to arrange a CPD session at the start of the school term. Following this, project tablets were issued to schools and schools obtained consent from teachers, parents and children to take part in the project, which also involved creating teacher and student user accounts. Once all these steps had been taken, the research team contacted each school to arrange an interview with the technology leader. Depending on the leader's availability, this was held after the frst school term (i.e., 12 weeks) of using the technologies. Semistructured interviews were held with technology leaders across the four schools to identify leadership practices and to understand the impact these practices had on how Navigo was used in the school context. Informed by usage analytics collected through the game during the 12-week period, the interview questions were adapted towards understanding the school's plans for and experiences of using the Navigo game, as well as understanding about the facilitators and challenges that impacted on this process. Each interview lasted between 30-45mins and was structured around the following topics: 1. Technology leader expectations regarding the Navigo game; 2. How the technology leader had begun coordinating the technology adoption process; and 3. Challenges and opportunities encountered by their school team. The interviews were held initially physically in school and later via online video conferencing, owing to the pandemic. Following participants' informed consent, the interviews were recorded and transcribed. To develop a credible account that would refect the complex dynamics within each school, additional data in the form of feldnotes and game play usage data was collected and triangulated with the interviews <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref>. Field notes were captured immediately after each school visit that was carried out as part of CPD or researcher support, documenting specifc events and conversations with the technology leader and other school staf involved. Also, to produce a visual representation of the adoption and use of the Navigo game, we continuously inspected how schools engaged with Navigo by extracting usage data collected throughout children's game play using the visualisation software Tableau © <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[47]</ref>. An inductive qualitative analysis was performed to generate themes refecting technology leader concerns and actions during their adoption of Navigo. Following <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">Braun and Clarke (2006)</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, the analysis applied a constructivist view that credited the socially situated ways in which meaning was produced. Using the qualitative data analysis tool NVivo 2020 © <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[48]</ref>, our analysis was geared towards identifying the concerns expressed and steps taken by technology leaders when introducing the Navigo game within their schools.  In order to apply a systematic and rigorous analysis, all authors read through the themes and codes multiple times so that we could exhaust the diferent possible interpretations of events. Group discussion involving all authors enabled us to test out alternatives and further develop and defne the themes. Finally, the themes and codes were triangulated with the other data sources (i.e. feld notes and game play usage data) to help explain the context of why certain things happened. For example, in the case of one leader, P1:Orange, who talked about issues with resource and time management, the researcher feldnotes helped to explain why particular teachers were not using the game in class, namely because it competed with another key commitment in term 1. Similarly, game play usage data added additional contextual information about technology use as Orange teachers began using the game more frequently in term 2. In the fndings section that follows, we discuss the concerns and actions of school technology leaders.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">FINDINGS</head><p>Based on semi-structured interviews with technology leaders four schools, feldnotes and usage data, we found that technology adoption patterns and game play usage was dependent on three main themes that characterised technology leader concerns and actions. These were:</p><p>• Technology leaders' challenges with resource and time management • Teacher agency and division of labour</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>• Communication and monitoring</head><p>We frst provide an overview of technology adoption patterns in each school, then discuss the three main themes as they related to the four schools.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Summary of technology adoption patterns</head><p>In all four schools, technology leaders liaised with the research team to plan and deliver CPD. For Blue, Orange and Silver this happened at the start of term 1 and at Yellow, CPD took place half-way through the frst school term. Three schools took a simultaneous whole school approach to introduce the technologies within classes, i.e. introducing the Navigo game across all participating classes. These were Blue, Yellow and Silver. In Blue, the introduction as a whole school worked well. All participating teachers at Blue were actively involved trialling the Navigo game and would explore diferent set-ups until they found a good ft. By the middle of the term 2, Blue teachers began establishing a routine for using the game in their teaching and as game play became more established, Blue teachers also upscaled and involved more students than anticipated, as refected in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3</ref>. In Silver and Yellow, the whole school approach was not successful. In Silver, P1:Silver had nominated TAs from each of the classes to deliver the intervention. However, as there was minimal uptake from TAs, P1:Silver and P2:Silver decided to downscale their plans to involve only fve students with reading difculties, as an out-ofclass targeted intervention. In Yellow, P1:Yellow wanted to establish parental consent for all participating students before training teachers, which delayed them in starting to use the technology. Also at Yellow, there was no established storage and charging solution so the tablets quickly became unpowered and inaccessible to classes when needed. This meant they were not used. In contrast to the simultaneous whole school approach detailed above, in Orange, P1:Orange took a staggered approach by identifying teachers who would be motivated to take part prior to the CPD session, and opted to initially support one class in trialling the Navigo game. This was led by a TA requiring close support from a member of the research team. This was followed by introducing the game in a second class during the second term, as the second teacher had more time available. The TA in the frst class then acted as an expert within the school for three other teachers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Technology leaders' challenges with resource and time management</head><p>Schools were tablets to ensure the smooth operation of the Navigo game. The tablets issued ranged between per school. This technological however, introduced requirement set up and maintain the charging and storage of tablets. This resulted in an initial phase of the adoption where technology leaders were predominantly preoccupied with setting up resource management procedures and resolving any issues that arose (e.g Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>, * depicts limited game usage for frst 12 weeks of term across all schools). This concern spanned at least the frst half of the school term. Across the schools there were a range of approaches taken during this phase by the technology leaders which had implications for the subsequent use of the Navigo game. At the start of term 1, technology leaders across all four schools opted to set up their tablets in a lockable space away from the classrooms. However, this approach had its challenges which some schools tried to address. At Silver, despite P1:Silver establishing an efective joint charging and storage solution, teachers lacked immediate access to the tablets when they were needed in class. Moreover, without a way of managing the joint resource across the team, teachers were not aware whether tablets had been signed out.</p><p>Recognising this barrier, the second technology leader, P2:Silver moved a smaller set of tablets to the inclusion room. This ensured that tablets were charged and accessible for children who were receiving support within a smaller intervention group. This decision also removed the need for resource management contributing to an increased use of the game within Silver (see Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4, ±</ref>).</p><p>In contrast to Silver, P1:Blue acknowledged need for resource management from the onset and created an online shared document to manage the use of the tablets across multiple classes. Yet, despite this, tablets were often left uncharged highlighting the collective responsibility to care for the material. For Yellow there were challenges related to keeping the tablets charged. This became an insurmountable obstacle that resulted an abandonment of Navigo within that school (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>, §). As P1:Yellow explained "We had [multiport] chargers for 10 or 15 of them, and I remember when they started to die it was a bit of a challenge. . . And over time they did just die and then they never really got charged again, and that's the reason that people [teachers] weren't using them. "Managing the adoption timeline was another critical challenge for all schools. Following the CPD ofered at the start of the school year, Blue and Orange technology leaders were able to resolve the tablet resource management challenges swiftly and therefore used the frst school term to habituate new practices (e.g. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>, ¤). In beginning to use the technologies earlier on, teachers from these two schools had the opportunity to communicate emergent questions about the technology to the research team before continuing to use Navigo more independently in the second school term. In contrast, technology leaders in Silver and Yellow were more hesitant in committing dates for the introduction of Navigo, which eventually happened toward the end of the frst school term. As result, staf reported what was covered in the CPD session. Starting later also resulted in clashes with other regular school activities which were given greater importance. For example, at Silver, there was a clash with national attainment tests for some of its year groups. Therefore, schools that evidenced the most use of Navigo, tended to have technology leaders who introduced technology at an 'opportune' moment, i.e., swiftly early in the year following the CPD teacher training. Those who waited experienced tension between teachers' growing during the school term and the time investment required on their part to learn a new technology. However, whilst some technology leaders appreciated importance of using Navigo early in the frst school term, an example from P1:Orange also shows the signifcance of being fexible and appreciative of the circumstances of particular staf. Whereas one class had begun using Navigo in the frst term, P1:Orange suspended her expectations from one of the teachers who was busy organising the school nativity play until the second term, explaining a sudden increase in activity seen in term 2 within that school (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4, *)</ref>.</p><p>* All schools had minimal usage between Sep -Dec 2019 as preoccupied with tablet resource management ¤Blue usage increases as teachers begin habituating new practices ˆOrange usage increases at start of 2nd term, following end of nativity play rehearsals ± Silver usage increases when smaller set of tablets are stored in inclusion room §Yellow unable to establish game play usage throughout the two terms</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Teacher agency and division of labour</head><p>A hierarchical leadership model prevailed in three out of the four where the senior leadership team (SLT) was responsible for key decision-making which encompassed the adoption of new technology. In practice this meant that SLT staf members had control It depended on the school as to whether the technology leader was part of the SLT and this had implications for the adoption of Navigo. P1:Yellow, did not occupy a role in the SLT. They struggled to spark teachers' involvement crediting this to their lack of authority to coordinate this type of initiative: "Had SLT had more of a role. . . they would have been able to support it and actually the teachers would have responded them and listened to what they're saying and been like, "Oh, yes, I'm going to do it because I know they're going to look at it. " Whereas I don't really have the same sway with people, people were like, "Well, whatever, another teacher. " So, there's authority in some sort of, in the dynamic. "P2:Silver stepped into a leader-supporter role, aiding the main technology leader, P1:Silver, with their busy workload. Acknowledging that they were not able to exercise the same authority as their leader colleague, P2:Silver explained: "None of this can happen unless [P1: Silver] says yes. . . it needs [them] to make the decisions and to tell the classes and the class teacher and class TAs that we're doing this. And then to organise the timetable and . . . just to make sure it actually gets done." When it came to identifying teachers to involve in the new techinitiative, P1:Silver and P1:Yellow both pre-designated the teachers and TAs who would use Navigo in class. In Silver, TAs who were tasked to run group sessions did not voice their opinions about the technology during site visits, with P2:Silver recognising that TAs did not have a forum to share their views within the school. In contrast, P1:Orange took a diferent approach to selecting the team. P1:Orange approached staf who would be most likely to engage, owing to their experiences and interest in using technology in the classroom and their commitment to the initiative at the onset. This appreciation for teacher agency was expressed both P2:Blue and P1:Orange in relation to teachers' intellectual leadership within their classroom practice. As P1:Orange explained: "I have to leave that to them. I'm not going to pressure them. I think they need to decide what it is they are going to do . . .and then maybe they can think more fexibly around how they're going to use them [the technology]. " Similarly, the feld notes from Blue indicated the subtle approach taken by P1:Blue which fostered teachers' exploration before they could identify the most appropriate practical and pedagogical ft of Navigo in their classroom. However, with regards to sustaining the more practical aspects of technology, the same technology leaders in Blue and Orange promoted the teaching team's ownership of the adoption process through designated roles that also ensured there was a distribution of work. For example, in Blue, a teacher who already acted as the IT subject specialist supported with setting up the tablet charging and storage solution whilst the technology leader organised the logistics of teacher training. The technology leader's own role in contributing to this division of labour depended on whether they were using Navigo themselves. Those who used the game within their own teaching, such as P1:Blue, had a deeper understanding of its functionalities and played a critical role in advising on time management, student logins and selection of content. In contrast to Blue and Orange, within Silver and Yellow, technology leaders did not report on practices that promoted teacher agency and responsibility over the adoption process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Communication and monitoring</head><p>Technology leaders recognised importance of setting up efective ways to communicate with teaching staf since it allowed them to establish a shared understanding of the school's vision for using the technology. By regularly communicating with teaching staf, technology leaders could understand how their plans to introduce the technology ft in with the everyday routines across the school.</p><p>Communication was also the main means through which to monitor how teachers were using the Navigo game and the extent to which students were accessing the game. Given technology leaders' accountability toward the school, monitoring was also important for justifying the leader's decisions about allocating resources to the technology initiative, such as stafng and additional teacher training.</p><p>In Silver and Yellow, both technology leaders planned to introduce the Navigo game to staf from all Primary school classes. At the outset, P1:Silver and the research team agreed on using the Navigo game within each class's 'guided reading' hour. P1:Silver arranged for teachers' CPD, timetabling and made curriculum decisions. However, by the end of the frst school term it became evident that P1:Silver was not monitoring how the technologies were being used as the school's existing communication which made it difcult to work collaboratively with teaching assistants (TAs), who were expected to run the programme. Describing the school's communication mechanisms, P2:Silver commented "We communicate up and down corridors, and in the stafroom. TAs as a rule, don't generally send out a lot of emails. Most of the time, they don't have a laptop with them anyway". As the technology leaders had no established mechanism for communication and thus monitoring, they were delayed in identifying that the technology was not used by TAs throughout term 1. Similar to Silver, Yellow that introducing the technologies across multiple classes placed demand on coordination and communication, yet this challenge was not resolved. Yellow, there was an expectation the SLT would not directly intervene in teachers' lesson planning and P1:Yellow expressed that teachers were not used to being closely observed. Consequently, as P1:Yellow aligned their practices with the school's norms, there was little awareness by this technology leader of the practical challenges that class teachers were facing in using the tablet and the game.</p><p>In contrast, at Blue and Orange, where the Navigo game was introduced at a smaller scale across 2-3 classes, the technology leaders were able to better manage communication and monitoring . Owing to the small size of Blue, there were established, informal communication opportunities among teachers that allowed for face-to-face communication throughout the school day. As detailed in Section 6.3, there was also a distributed for sharing the responsiof related tasks, meaning that all teachers regularly shared their experiences with each other and raised queries with P1:Blue and the research team as needed. Therefore, P1:Blue reported a collective monitoring practice through the sharing of experiences. Through this mechanism the teaching team was then able to fnd solutions for the many interacting factors that impacted on them using the game, including tablet charging, student login processes and supporting younger students in understanding the game's mechanics. At Orange, although P1:Orange did not use the technology in their own teaching, they liaised closely with an identifed TA who was using the Navigo game in their class and was able to provide indirect guidance. By frst piloting Navigo in one class, P1:Orange was therefore more aware of the kinds of practical challenges and opportunities that other teachers might encounter since it was introduced in another class during the next term. In addition to their understanding of the operational tasks that required monitoring the second school term, P1:Orange also established fuid communication with the TA who went on to support three other teachers in the school. Communication between staf was possible owing to starting small and having regular, informal opportunities to share their experiences; drawing on existing efective communication systems within the school to perform monitoring and using monitoring as a tool to problem solve.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">DISCUSSION</head><p>The goal of this research was to understand technology leaders' practices when coordinating the introduction of educational technologies that are new to their school setting. We focused the technology leader since prior research has identifed that these leaders take on an important role in championing and supporting the introduction of new technologies <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b42">41]</ref>. Through interviews researcher feldnotes from four schools we identifed that in the main, technology leaders focused their eforts on two concerns during the early phase of technology adoption: (i) managing the material dimension of new educational technologies and (ii) embedding the technology in school time. In line with Johri (2011) <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref>, we found that the introduction of new technology raised unexpected considerations relating to the materiality of the tablet, such as its storage, charging and accessibility. Therefore, while the technology initiative had been framed around the literacy game, the technology leaders' focal concern was the tablet. Our fndings also revealed that technology leaders did not take a major role in providing the teaching team with advice on the pedagogical alignment of the game in this early stage of adoption. We discuss three considerations that impacted on how technology leaders coordinated process of technology adoption. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref> summarises the challenges associated with each consideration, alongside recommendations for HCI researchers seeking to support technology leaders in school-wide technology initiatives involving their prototypes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">Recognising tasks and distributing the workload as a team</head><p>A major concern for technology leaders was the charging, storage and access to tablets within and across classes. In some classes, the aim was to use 30 tablets simultaneously within a whole class, creating an expectation that all tablets would be charged when needed in class (Orange, Blue, and initially, Silver). Moreover, in most of the schools, tablets were stored charged in a central location away from the individual classrooms to ensure access to tablets across classes (Blue, Silver). This posed challenges, which we describe next alongside the approaches technology leaders took to resolve them. An important characteristic of efective technology leaders was the ability to refect, problem solve and put in place practices to support their teams with the challenges arising from tablet management. For example, the technology leader in one the schools (Silver) recognised that the tablets' central storage was a barrier to the whole-school technology initiative leading them to take practical steps to scale down their plans. Moving a smaller set of tablets to the school's inclusion room enabled a designated member of the teaching team to charge and access the tablets for intervention sessions with a smaller set of students. The decision to limit the initiative to a single location removed the need for shared management of the tablet resource. In contrast, within another school (Yellow), the technology leader did not employ problem solving when facing a new challenge with tablet charging, which led to the abandonment of the technology as the tablets very quickly ran out of battery charge.</p><p>Alongside their problem-solving role, efective technology leaders recognised the signifcant workload required to maintain the tablet, and took a coordinating role. These technology leaders promoted the teaching team's ownership of the adoption process <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[46]</ref> through designated roles and a distribution of tasks. In some cases, the technology leader identifed staf whose existing roles in the school ft with the new tasks that were required to sustain the use of Navigo, enabling schools to build on their existing capacity (Blue, Orange). This approach is in line with Rogers' Difusion of Innovation model <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[36]</ref>, which proposes that successful innovation involves setting up a social system for joint problem solving of a common goal. In addition to the need to distribute the workload/tasks across diferent team members, schools sharing the same hardware across classes needed to take collective responsibility over the charging of the tablets. For example, one school created a live document to manage the use of the tablets across multiple classes (Blue). Even though this approach successfully facilitated tablet sharing between classes, tablets were sometimes left uncharged by who had previously used them. Like in the case Rosner and Ames <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37]</ref>, tablet maintenance became problematic without collaboration. Therefore, technology leaders were most efective when they encouraged the teaching teams to hold a collaborative appreciation of the tablet's worth <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37]</ref> with collective responsibility and efort to maintain the technology.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2">Identifying when and how to involve teachers</head><p>Technology leaders who introduced tablet and the game at an 'opportune' e.g. either swiftly in the frst school term or as soon as teachers had more capacity, had more success in fostering teachers' adoption patterns across the two school terms. This approach to adoption aforded technology leaders with more time to refect on emergent practical issues and problem solve them early. It also established the important link between the CPD session teachers attended and their immediate use of this training practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">21]</ref>. However, our research also shows that this approach was shaped by situational operational barriers such as Yellow's internet bandwidth issue which took time to resolve. Our fndings highlight the importance of introducing new technology early in the year when schools are the least busy and new ideas can take root. Moreover, it is important to overcome practical barriers to setting up and using technology before CPD sessions are held, in order to reduce the time training and teachers' use of the technology.Alongside the importance of introducing technology at the right time of the year, considerations over the teaching staf involved were equally important. Previous work has shown that technology initiatives in schools are successful only when technology leaders involve teachers in technology adoption decisions <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">46]</ref>. In support of this, we found that leaders inviting staf who were positive about educational technology observed teachers' commitment to the technology adoption process. Indeed, two of the schools (Orange, Blue), participating teachers embraced new opportunities that the technology could bring to supporting students with their reading, and could thus be described as early adopters <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[36]</ref>. A second way that leaders established teacher involvement was through providing the creative space for the teachers to use the game within their teaching practice (Orange, Blue). This stood in stark contrast the remaining two schools where teachers had limited involvement in decision making, as was case at Silver where TAs from across all year groups were expected to take part. Our fndings suggest several implications. As early adopters develop expertise with technology, technology leaders could initiate peer coaching within their school to scale up the use of technology by involving more staf. Moreover, considering the complexities surrounding whom to involve, it is helpful for technology leaders to understand the characteristics of staf that make them good candidates for early adopters of technology within their setting. Whilst there is a large body of prior work that has considered how teacher characteristics, attitudes and beliefs infuence technology adoption (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b3">4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12]</ref>), tools are needed support technology leaders to make more informed decisions about whether to involve frst as early adopters frst, given the resources and expertise that is available locally to support technology adoption.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.3">Communication and monitoring strategies that are in line with the of the implementation</head><p>Our fndings show that when Navigo game was introduced at a small scale in 2-3 classes within the school, technology leaders were able to communicate and consequently monitor the technology initiative easily through existing informal mechanisms e.g. impromptu conversations with peers. In one of the schools (Blue), we observed a shared practice of monitoring, with staf members regularly reporting their progress and adoption barriers toward fnding joint solutions. Previous research has found that teacher collaboration can foster problem solving and learning during the adoption of educational technology <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">46]</ref>. In orchestrating collaboration, technology leaders could promote teachers' collective responsibility to monitor the efectiveness of the technology adoption and involve the teaching team identifying ways to improve it where challenges exist.</p><p>Similar to the two schools leading scale initiatives, our fndings show that technology leaders who led a school-wide adoption of the Navigo game also relied on their existing communication practices (Silver) and school culture (Yellow). However, these proved to be insufcient to monitor the material and time scheduling challenges that teachers faced in this early adoption phase. Since the technology leader and teaching staf had not jointly established a way to share these concerns, the technology leader's awareness of the challenges involved and consequently their ability to problem solve was impacted. These communication breakdowns remained an untapped opportunity to infuence the school culture, as also suggested by De Jong <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23]</ref>. Thus, school-wide initiatives involving educational technology pose an organisational challenge. Schools whose culture does not foster collaboration must engage in additional organisational change to ensure that efective communication channels and norms are established. Moreover, while the lack of monitoring in these schools was found to be problematic, as the case of Blue demonstrates, the technology leader's monitoring practice is efective only when it is followed by a solution-oriented approach highlighting the importance for staf's commitment to problem solving. To this end, new data-driven tools that visualise school and class technology usage patterns could be particularly valuable to guide technology leaders in identifying teachers who could beneft from additional support.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">CONCLUSION</head><p>We embarked on a multiple case study of four primary schools who signed up to use a new adaptive literacy game called 'Navigo'. By adopting a situated lens, we looked at how whole schools used the technology and systematically analysed the actions and concerns of school technology leaders over a period of two school terms so that we could explore how this role impacted the adoption of new educational technology in the classroom. Through interviews with technology leaders and researcher feldnotes from school visits we identifed that in line with Johri <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref>, the introduction of new technology tools raised unexpected considerations relating to the materiality and uses of the technology itself. Our empirical research makes three main contributions to a growing body HCI research that is examining how educational technologies are used in the school context. First, we describe in detail the concerns and actions of technology leaders based on empirical research involving four diverse school cases. Second, we present a systematic methodological approach for applying a situated-lens to study school-based technology adoption. Third, we propose considerations and identify recommendations for future work which we hope will be helpful for HCI researchers interested in supporting technology leaders tasked with leading technology adoption. Whilst we endeavoured focus on diferent schools, one methodological limitation we faced was understanding how technology leader concerns and actions might vary based on geographically and culturally diverse contexts. Additional work is needed that considers how these concerns may change when access to resources is varied and diferent stakeholders take a prominent role in coordinating the technology adoption process. By demonstrating what school technology leaders do during the early stages of technology adoption, it is that our research helps to map out interrelated complexities when seeking to understand about and support school teams with adopting educational technology.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :Figure 2 :</head><label>12</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Three example Navigo game mechanics (left: multiple choice, middle: sequencing, right: hit the target). ©Navigo, iRead project consortium</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,87.82,83.69,436.37,162.17" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Total number of target and active users across the four schools</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="7,127.17,196.86,357.66,172.48" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Visualisation of school usage for Navigo game across terms 1 and 2 of year</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="9,87.82,83.68,436.37,231.53" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Technology leader profles School Primary technology leader, role Secondary technology leader, role (if applicable) Yellow did not hold SLT position, unlike the other primary technology leaders.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Blue</cell><cell>P1:Blue, Literacy Lead &amp; Y3 teacher</cell><cell>P2:Blue, SENCO</cell></row><row><cell>Orange</cell><cell>P1:Orange, SENCO</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Silver</cell><cell>P1:Silver, Literacy Lead &amp; Y2 teacher</cell><cell>P2:Silver, Learning Mentor</cell></row><row><cell>Yellow</cell><cell>P1:Yellow, Literacy Lead &amp; Y4 teacher a</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>a P1:</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Summary of key challenges and recommendations for HCI researchers supporting school technology adoption</figDesc><table><row><cell>Consideration</cell><cell>Challenge</cell><cell>Recommendation for HCI researchers</cell></row><row><cell>Recognising tasks &amp; distributing</cell><cell>Problem solving and establishing practices</cell><cell>Support leaders to refect on practical steps for</cell></row><row><cell>workload as a team</cell><cell>to support tablet management</cell><cell>downscaling or adapting storage and charging</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>for specifc classes</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Collective caring for material aspects of</cell><cell>Create a collective workload by supporting schools</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>technology (e.g. charging, storage)</cell><cell>with tablet management and designated</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>roles</cell></row><row><cell>Identifying when and how to involve</cell><cell>Identifying and capitalising on the</cell><cell>Encourage school to introduce new technology</cell></row><row><cell>teachers</cell><cell>'opportune' moments for introducing a new</cell><cell>early in school year or when other</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>technology within the school year</cell><cell>'extra-curricular' activities are not happening</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>which could distract</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Minimise gap between training and use by</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>ensuring practical barriers in setup are addressed</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>before CPD happens</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Teacher autonomy over technology use and</cell><cell>Consider staf characteristics that make them good</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>identifying teachers who are committed to</cell><cell>candidates for early adoption and encourage early</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>piloting new technologies within their</cell><cell>adopters to mentor further teachers within the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>teaching</cell><cell>school</cell></row><row><cell>Communication and monitoring</cell><cell>Collective monitoring of the material and</cell><cell>Important to understand existing school</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">strategies that are in line with scale ofpractical challenges through current school</cell><cell>communication channels in advance and</cell></row><row><cell>implementation.</cell><cell>communication practices</cell><cell>encourage technology leaders to consider how</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>sufcient these are to support scaling up the use of</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>technology</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>School culture may not foster collaboration</cell><cell>Enable the creation of new communication</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>between participating teachers</cell><cell>channels e.g., through regular school wide CPD</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>sessions</cell></row></table></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>We thank all the participating school staf and students for supporting this research. This work is part of the iRead project which has received funding from the European Union's Horizon 2020 research and innovation programme under grant agreement No 731724 and an Economic and Social Research Council Postdoctoral Fellowship, under grant no. ES/P000592/1, awarded to the frst author.</p><p>We thank members of the UCL iRead team who contributed to the school recruitment, CPD and data collection: Elisabeth Herbert, Emma Sumner, Manolis Mavrikis, Yvonne Vezzoli, Kate Cowan, Minna Nygren and Andrea Gauthier, and our iRead colleagues at National Technical University of Athens: Antonios Symvonis, Chrysanthi Raftopoulou and Dionysis Panagiotopoulos. We also thank Yuanya Zhang for earlier discussions that informed the literature review.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Antonios Symvonis, and Chrysanthi Raftopoulou. 2021. Designing for &quot;challenge&quot; in a large-scale adaptive literacy game for primary school children</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Benton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Manolis</forename><surname>Mavrikis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Asimina</forename><surname>Vasalou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nelly</forename><surname>Joye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emma</forename><surname>Sumner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elisabeth</forename><surname>Herbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Revesz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/bjet.13146</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/bjet.13146" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Educational Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1862" to="1880" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Moving beyond enhancing pedagogies with digital technologies: Frames of reference, habits of mind learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Blundell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kar-Tin</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shaun</forename><surname>Nykvist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/15391523.2020.1726235</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/15391523.2020.1726235" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research on Technology in Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="178" to="196" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using thematic analysis in psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Virginia</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1191/1478088706qp063oa" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Qualitative Research in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Factors infuencing teachers&apos; adoption and integration of information and communication technology into teaching: A review of the literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Buabeng-Andoh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The second educational revolution: rethinking education in the age of technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Collins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Halverson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1111/j.1365-2729.2009.00339.x</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1111/j.1365-2729.2009.00339.x" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Computer Assisted Learning</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="18" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The impact of collaborative Continuing Professional Development (CPD) on classroom teaching and learning. Research Evidence in Education Library</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philippa</forename><surname>Cordingley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barbara</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Donald</forename><surname>Rundell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>EPPI-Centre Social Science Research Unit, Institute of Education</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">High Access and Low Use of Technologies in High School Classrooms: Explaining an Apparent Paradox</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Larry</forename><surname>Cuban</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heather</forename><surname>Kirkpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Craig</forename><surname>Peck</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Educational Research Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="813" to="834" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design for classroom orchestration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Dillenbourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.compedu.2013.04.013</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2013.04.013" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computers &amp; Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">69</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="485" to="492" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Technology for Classroom Orchestration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Dillenbourg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Jermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-4419-5716-0_26</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4419-5716-0_26" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">New Science of Learning: Cognition, Computers and Collaboration in Education, Myint Swe Khine and</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Issa</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><surname>Saleh</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="525" to="552" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Deliberate practice in teaching: what teachers do for self-improvement. Teaching and Teacher Education 15</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Constance</forename><surname>Dunn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shriner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0742-051X(98)00068-7</idno>
		<idno>S0742-051X(98)00068-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="631" to="651" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Addressing frst-and second-order barriers to change: Strategies for technology integration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peggy</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ertmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF02299597</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF02299597" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Educational Technology Research and Development</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="61" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teacher Technology Change: How Knowledge, Confdence, Beliefs, and Culture Intersect</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peggy</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ertmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ottenbreit-Leftwich</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research on Technology in Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="255" to="284" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teacher beliefs and technology integration practices: A critical relationship</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peggy</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Ertmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Ottenbreit-Leftwich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Olgun</forename><surname>Sadik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.compedu.2012.02.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2012.02.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computers &amp; Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="423" to="435" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Emine Sendurur, and Polat Sendurur</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Facilitating guided participation through mobile technologies: designing creative learning environments for self and others</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aditya</forename><surname>Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Johri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s12528-008-9004-1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s12528-008-9004-1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Computing in Higher Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="92" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2022-05-05">April 29-May 05, 2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Technology leadership for the twentyfrst century principal</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linda</forename><surname>Flanagan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michele</forename><surname>Jacobsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1108/09578230310464648</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1108/09578230310464648" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Educational Administration</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="124" to="142" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Islands of Innovation&quot; and &quot;School-Wide Implementations&quot;: Two Patterns of ICT-Based Pedagogical Innovations in Schools</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alona</forename><surname>Forkhosh-Baruch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mioduser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raf</forename><surname>Nachmias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dorit</forename><surname>Tubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://jyx.jyu.f/handle/123456789/20182" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Technology: An Interdisciplinary Journal on Humans in ICT Environments</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005-09-06">2005. September 6</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leadership, technology, and education: achieving a balance in new school leader thinking and behavior in preparation for twenty-frst century global learning environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ian</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Gibson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/14759390200200140</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/14759390200200140" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Information Technology for Teacher Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="315" to="334" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Distributed according to the evidence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alma</forename><surname>Harris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1108/09578230810863253</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1108/09578230810863253" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Educational Administration</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">46</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="188" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Use of Research to Improve Professional Practice: a systematic review the literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jane</forename><surname>Hemsley-Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Sharp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/0305498032000153025</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/0305498032000153025" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Oxford Review of Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="449" to="471" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building Diferent Bridges: Technology Integration, Engaged Student Learning, and New Approaches to Professional Development</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michele</forename><surname>Jacobsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="Retrievedfromwww.ucalgary.ca/∼dmjacobs/aera/building_bridges.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AERA 2001: What We Know and How We Know It</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Building Diferent Bridges Two: A Case Study of Transformative Professional Development for Student Learning With ogy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michele</forename><surname>Jacobsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="www.ucalgary.ca/∼dmjacobs/aera/building_bridges.html" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">AERA 2002: Validity and Value in Educational Research. Retrieved from</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The socio-materiality of learning practices and implications for the feld of learning technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aditya</forename><surname>Johri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3402/rlt.v19i3.17110</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3402/rlt.v19i3.17110" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Research in Learning Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">School-based teacher collaboration: Diferent learning opportunities across various contexts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jong</forename><surname>Loes De</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacobiene</forename><surname>Meirink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wilfried</forename><surname>Admiraal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.tate.2019.102925</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.tate.2019.102925" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">86</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">102925</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Educational Technology: A Critique</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Greg</forename><surname>Kearsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Educational Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="51" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards Evidenceinformed Design Principles for Adaptive Reading Games</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Manolis</forename><surname>Mavrikis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Asimina</forename><surname>Vasalou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Benton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chrysanthi</forename><surname>Raftopoulou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290607.3313256</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3290607.3313256" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Extended Abstracts of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI EA &apos;19</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="4" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Antonios Symvonis, Kostas Karpouzis, and Drew Wilkins</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The dearth of technology leadership coverage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Mcleod</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jayson</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Richardson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">of School Leadership</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">216</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Online Reading Support. Evaluation Report and Executive Summary. Education Endowment Foundation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><surname>Mcnally</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jenifer</forename><surname>Ruiz-Valenzuela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heather</forename><surname>Rolfe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://eric.ed.gov/?id=ED581099" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-08-29">2016. August 29</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teacher learning and collaboration in innovative teams</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Jacobiene</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeroen</forename><surname>Meirink</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Imants</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Paulien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nico</forename><surname>Meijer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Verloop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/0305764X.2010.481256</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/0305764X.2010.481256" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cambridge Journal of Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="181" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Factors Involved in the Implementation of</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raf</forename><surname>Nachmias</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Mioduser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anat</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dorit</forename><surname>Tubin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alona</forename><surname>Forkosh-Baruch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1023/B:EAIT.0000042045.12692.49</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1023/B:EAIT.0000042045.12692.49" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pedagogical Innovations Using Technology. and Information Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="291" to="308" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Designing Constructionist Futures: The Art, Theory, Practice of Learning Designs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Noss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Hoyles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Saunders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Clark-Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Benton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><surname>Kalas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://mitpress.mit.edu/books/designing-constructionist-futures#preview" />
		<editor>N. Holbert, M. Berland and Y. Kafai</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-08-29">2020. 2020. August 29</date>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="39" to="52" />
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA, USA; Cambridge, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Making Constructionism Work at Scale: The Story Of Scratchmaths</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using evidence: How research can inform public services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sandra</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Nutley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Isabel</forename><surname>Walter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Huw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Davies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2307/j.ctt9qgwt1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2307/j.ctt9qgwt1" />
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Bristol University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolution of Teachers&apos; Technology Integration Knowledge, Beliefs, and Practices: How Can We Support Beginning Teachers Use of Technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>Ottenbreit-Leftwich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janet</forename><surname>Yin-Chan Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Olgun</forename><surname>Sadik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peggy</forename><surname>Ertmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/15391523.2018.1487350</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/15391523.2018.1487350" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research on Technology in Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="282" to="304" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Contextual factors that sustain innovative pedagogical practice using technology: an international study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ronald</forename><surname>Owston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10833-006-9006-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10833-006-9006-6" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Educational Change</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="77" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Teachers&apos; perceptions of the impact of CPD: an institutional case study ed</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ed</forename><surname>Powell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Scilla</forename><surname>Furey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andy</forename><surname>Scott-Evans</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Terrell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/13674580300200225</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/13674580300200225" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of In-Service Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="389" to="404" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">In International Handbook of Information Technology in Primary and Secondary Education</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Margaret</forename><surname>Riel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Henry</forename><forename type="middle">Jay</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-0-387-73315-9_24</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-0-387-73315-9_24" />
		<editor>Joke Voogt and Gerald Knezek</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<publisher>Springer US</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="397" to="417" />
			<pubPlace>Boston, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Characteristics of Teacher Leaders for Information and Communication Technology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Difusion of Innovations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Everett</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://ebookcentral.proquest.com/lib/ucl/detail.action?docID=4935198" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-09-02">2003. September 2</date>
			<publisher>Free Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Riverside, UNITED STATES</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>5th Edition</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing for repair?: infrastructures and materialities of breakdown</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniela</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Rosner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Morgan</forename><surname>Ames</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2531602.2531692</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2531602.2531692" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 17th ACM conference on Computer supported cooperative work &amp; social computing</title>
				<meeting>the 17th ACM conference on Computer supported cooperative work &amp; social computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="319" to="331" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Leaving the Field: Designing a Socio-Material Toolkit for Teachers to Continue to Design Technology Children</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Scheepmaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kay</forename><surname>Kender</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Frauenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geraldine</forename><surname>Fitzpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3411764.3445462</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445462" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Shenton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Strategies for Ensuring Trustworthiness in Qualitative Research Projects. Education for Information</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="75" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Materiality of Learning: Technology and Knowledge in Educational Practice. Cambridge Core</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Estrid</forename><surname>Sørensen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1017/CBO9780511576362</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1017/CBO9780511576362" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Seray</forename><surname>Ibrahim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">School leaders, ICT competence and championing innovations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lindsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Annette</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Stuart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ulrich</forename><surname>Mills</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Remus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.compedu.2009.04.013</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.compedu.2009.04.013" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computers &amp; Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="733" to="741" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Human-machine reconfgurations: plans and situated actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lucille</forename><forename type="middle">Alice</forename><surname>Suchman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge; New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Teacher professional learning and development: best evidence synthesis iteration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Timperly</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">BES</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">BES</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Barrar</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">BES</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fung</surname></persName>
			<affiliation>
				<orgName type="collaboration">BES</orgName>
			</affiliation>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Auckland</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>New Zealand, and Ministry of Education</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mind in society: The development of higher psychological processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lev Semenovich</forename><surname>Vygotsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1978">1978</date>
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Massachusetts</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Yin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">study research: design and methods</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>SAGE, Los Angeles</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ICT implementation and school leadership: Case studies of ICT integration in teaching and learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Allan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nancy</forename><surname>Yuen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Law</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1108/09578230310464666</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1108/09578230310464666" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Educational Administration</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="158" to="170" />
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<ptr target="https://www.tableau.com/en-gb" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Tableau: Business intelligence and analytics software</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Qualitative Data Analysis Software | NVivo</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.qsrinternational.com/nvivo-qualitative-data-analysis-software/home/" />
		<imprint>
			<date>September 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
