<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Shifing Trust: Examining How Trust and Distrust Emerge, Transform, and Collapse in COVID-19 Information Seeking</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kim</forename><surname>Miso</surname></persName>
							<idno type="ORCID">0000-0002-9740-4989</idno>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shivani</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Stacy</forename><surname>Marsella</surname></persName>
							<email>s.marsella@northeastern.edu</email>
							<idno type="ORCID">0000-0001-7729-1748</idno>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yixuan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
							<email>yixuan@gatech.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Nurul</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Suhaimi</surname></persName>
							<email>suhaimi.n@northeastern.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Nutchanon</forename><surname>Yongsatianchot</surname></persName>
							<email>yongsatianchot.n@northeastern.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Gaggiano</surname></persName>
							<email>jgaggiano@gatech.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Miso</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
							<email>m.kim@northeastern.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Shivani</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
							<email>s.a.patel@emory.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yifan</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jacqueline</forename><surname>Grifn</surname></persName>
							<email>ja.grifn@northeastern.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
							<email>andrea@cc.gatech.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Georgia of Technology University University</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>USA, USA, USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">of Technology</orgName>
								<address>
									<country>USA, USA, USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Shifing Trust: Examining How Trust and Distrust Emerge, Transform, and Collapse in COVID-19 Information Seeking</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3501889</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:01+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>crisis informatics</term>
					<term>information behaviors</term>
					<term>trust</term>
					<term>distrust</term>
					<term>misinformation</term>
					<term>information infrastructure</term>
					<term>social media</term>
					<term>mixed methods</term>
					<term>longitudinal research</term>
					<term>COVID-19</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>During crises like COVID-19, individuals are inundated with conficting and time-sensitive information that drives a need for rapid assessment of the trustworthiness and reliability of information sources and platforms. This parallels evolutions in information infrastructures, ranging from social media to government data platforms. Distinct from current literature, which presumes a static relationship between the presence or absence of trust and people's behaviors, our mixed-methods research focuses on situated trust, or trust that is shaped by people's information-seeking and assessment practices through emerging information platforms (e.g., social media, crowdsourced systems, COVID data platforms). Our fndings characterize the shifts in trustee (what/who people trust) from information on social media to the social media platform(s), how distrust manifests skepticism in issues of data discrepancy, the insufcient presentation of uncertainty, and how this trust and distrust shift over time. We highlight the deep challenges in existing information infrastructures that infuence trust and distrust formation.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Due to COVID-19, 2020 and 2021 have been marked by a sense of confusion and uncertainty as people are required to navigate this new and emerging crisis. Scientifc communities, governments, organizations, and individuals have all been learning and adapting to changes in the crisis as it has unfolded <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[52,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b74">79]</ref>. Consequently, COVID-19-associated regulations and guidance, as well as projections and forecasts, have also shifted frequently. The conficting and, often, time-sensitive information created by varied sources and disseminated on diverse platforms has engendered a feeling of uncertainty. This uncertainty makes it difcult for people to determine which information sources are trustworthy and which platforms (e.g., social media, news outlets) they should rely on.</p><p>Meanwhile, a variety of information and communication technologies (ICTs) <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[37]</ref> and sociotechnical systems (STSs) have been created, adapted, and utilized to communicate crisis and risk information amidst the COVID-19 pandemic. (We defne STSs as interactions between people, organizations, institutions, and ICTs <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[44]</ref>). For example, well-established social media platforms have been heavily utilized by the general public to access COVID-19 information <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">[61]</ref>. Additionally, an increasing number of information platforms have been created from the ground up (e.g., crowdsourced systems, such as the COVID Tracking Project <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">[80]</ref>) or adapted from existing platforms (e.g., data trackers from news outlets <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">81]</ref> and public health authorities <ref type="bibr">[14]</ref>) to report COVID-19 data (e.g., number of cases/deaths). The COVID-19 data provided by these platforms have served as the backbone for crisis and risk information dissemination during the pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[51]</ref> and have been consumed by millions of people daily <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[5]</ref>. Given their widespread use and the central role that they play in informing the public, these platforms need to be asked one key question: to what extent do people trust the information that they provide? Amidst the COVID-19 pandemic, a growing body of work has demonstrated the importance of investigating this question <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[39]</ref>. While a majority of trust literature amidst COVID-19 has typically presumed a static, or unchanging, relationship between the presence or absence of trust and peoples' information behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[56]</ref>, little is known about the ways in which information trust changes and evolves during a crisis. Yet, information appraisals are necessarily dynamic, particularly amidst a rapidly evolving scenario like the COVID-19 pandemic. Indeed, recent work has discussed how the general public has to constantly reassess the threat of COVID-19 to public health, reexamine the efcacy of the governmental responses to the pandemic, and reevaluate their trust in the government <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">32]</ref>. However, while this work has yielded insight into the political implications of evolving information appraisals during crises, two important research gaps exist. First, this work has rarely examined the role that ICTs and STSs have played in shaping the public's trust of information. Second, little work has investigated the sociotechnical context of information trust evolution amongst traditionally-marginalized populations, such as low-socioeconomic (low-SES) communities. Yet, prior research has thoroughly established the disproportionate impact that COVID-19 has had on communities such as Black, Hispanic, and low-SES groups in the United States <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[66]</ref>. To mitigate this risk, it is crucial to ensure that these groups have access to crisis and risk information from credible resources. These disparities bring into sharp relief the importance of investigating information trust among traditionally-marginalized populations <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[69]</ref>, given the important role that information can play in mitigating the morbidity and mortality rates in these populations during a public health crisis <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">[86]</ref>. Furthermore, marginalized groups may have distinctive needs and perspectives regarding the use of, information from, and trust in a particular source <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[77,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">93]</ref>.</p><p>To address these research gaps, we conducted a mixed method study, which included a longitudinal survey and semi-structured interviews, to examine information practices and trust amidst the COVID-19 pandemic. Our survey results show that while COVID-19 information consumption on more traditional media platforms (e.g., radio, television, and newspapers) stayed consistent over time, COVID-19 information consumption via the internet signifcantly decreased over time. This decline was especially pronounced on social media. Triangulated with our interview study results, we found that our participants stopped using social media for COVID-19 information consumption mainly for two reasons: 1) their fear of being potentially impacted by the mixture of true information and misinformation, and 2) their frustration about their inability to change their social media contacts' misbeliefs and mistrust. Moreover, our study suggests that there was an association between participants' distrust and their information exposure, with lower COVID-19 information exposure levels being associated with higher levels of information distrust. Additionally, our fndings reveal how distrust arose from participants' skepticism of the information production processes, as well as their desire for clearer communication of data uncertainty, and how this distrust changed over time.</p><p>Overall, this paper contributes a situated perspective in examining how trust and distrust are shaped by existing information production, representation, and dissemination processes using ICTs and STSs, such as government websites, public media, crowdsourced systems, and social media, during COVID-19, as well as how this trust and distrust shift over time. Our work sheds light on the deep challenges in existing information infrastructures that have shaped the formation of public trust and distrust. We also provide implications for future work that guide the collaborative efort among stakeholders to improve the information infrastructure, to foster public trust, and to better prepare for future crises.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">BACKGROUND AND RELATED WORK</head><p>Trust is critical for the formation of cohesive relationships between people, organizations, and information and the technology in which relationships are relied upon <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[24]</ref>. We defne trust as a person's (the "truster") belief in and the willingness to rely on the trustee (i.e., a trusted party like an individual, an organization, information, or an information source in the digital age) 1 . Trust in a particular information source can infuence the type of information people receive, which may infuence their subsequent decisions and behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[25]</ref>. A few related concepts include distrust, defned as the extent to which the truster believes that the trustee will work against, or at least not in the best interest of, the truster [53], and mistrust, defned as misplaced trust whereby a trustee "defaults" or betrays a person's trust <ref type="bibr">[53]</ref>. In a situation of mistrust, a person fnds that while they had at one point trusted the trustee, that trustee later proves to in fact not be worthy of trust. As many trust issues surrounding COVID-19 information have arisen during the pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">49]</ref>, it is critical to examine how people form their trust, distrust, and mistrust and the way in which these beliefs evolve over time.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Factors Infuencing Trust</head><p>Much of the work in the trust literature specifcally examines the factors that determine trust by identifying the characteristics and qualities that make up both a trustee [15, <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">54,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">73]</ref> and a truster <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[8]</ref>. On one hand, the most cited characteristics of a trustee [15, <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">54,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">73]</ref> include ability (i.e., the skills, competencies, and characteristics that allow a party to be infuential in a specifc domain), benevolence (i.e., the extent to which a trustee is believed to work in the trustor's interests), integrity (i.e., the beliefs that a trustee adheres to principles that the trustor fnds acceptable), and reliability (i.e., the extent to which a source is reliable). Most work suggests that the source of crisis and risk information is the most important factor infuencing a person's trust in that information source <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">65]</ref>.</p><p>Given the abundance of information available online, researchers have increasingly studied how people develop their trust in this information. This body of work has surfaced a number of factors that impact trust formation in the context of social media information. For example, on social media, people evaluate the trustworthiness of posts mostly based on the source and content <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[65]</ref>. There is also a body of work investigating the impacts of information credibility indicators (e.g., the presence of fact-checking or if the source is a major news outlet) in social media contexts. While such indicators can help decrease social media users' propensity to share fake news online <ref type="bibr" target="#b89">[99]</ref>, prior work argues that instead of evaluating the trustworthiness of information based on its credibility, people form their opinions and judge the veracity of information primarily based on their familiarity with its source <ref type="bibr">[90]</ref>. Nonetheless, even in the context of unfamiliar accounts on social media, most users can efectively assess information authenticity and credibility, and thus the presence or absence of an authenticity indicator does not signifcantly infuence people's willingness to share information <ref type="bibr">[90]</ref>. In fact, in most cases, people do not investigate low-credibility social media posts to see how the claims were generated or why the account posted it <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[29]</ref>.</p><p>In addition to credibility, other research has highlighted the important role that social media users have as distributors of information. Specifcally, the person or account that circulates an article on social media may have a greater impact on what people think of the story than the original information producer who wrote the story <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">[76]</ref>. As such, the credibility of the information sharers infuences people's opinions about the source <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">[76]</ref>. This variation of information assessment practices is further complicated with the high uncertainty associated with crises. Prior work has found that crisis situations are associated with a pervasive distrust in "formal" sources (e.g., mainstream news media), driving people to seek information via social media and contributing to the creation and spread of conspiracy beliefs <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[43]</ref>.</p><p>To help people make more informed trust assessments online, an increasing body of literature has explored to use algorithmiccentered approaches to detect and improve the credibility of online information <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">70,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">97]</ref>. Work in HCI has begun focusing on the enhancement of information literacy and the facilitation of trusters' information sensemaking <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[27]</ref>. Our work extends this body of literature in understanding the dynamics of trust-how people form their trust and distrust during the processes of information seeking in times of crisis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">A Situated Perspective on Trust</head><p>However, a fundamental debate within the trust literature is not only what determines trust but also whether trust is rational or afective. Some trust scholars suggest that trust is an afective construct that can vary depending on the context and experiences of a person rather than simply being a rational or an objective reality <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[54]</ref>. This body of work argues that trust should be conceptualized and studied as emergent states <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[10]</ref>, or cognitive, motivational, or afective states that are dynamic and vary as a function of contextual factors, as well as inputs, processes, and outcomes. Following this perspective, trust is developed or collapsed given specifc interactions and contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[16]</ref>. This view has resonance with the similar notion of situated trust <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">36,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">64]</ref>, which emphasizes the impact that contextual factors have on the situation (e.g., trust is placed upon a specifc person for a specifc task within a particular situation). Understanding trust from a situated perspective enables trust scholars to understand the dynamics of trust and acquire a better understanding of how trust changes over time. Our work seeks to examine the evolution of trust and distrust formation amidst the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Trust &amp; COVID-19</head><p>A growing body of work has explored two broad realms regarding trust during the COVID-19 pandemic, including the infuences that the presence or absence of trust have on people's behaviors (e.g., behavioral compliance, mortality, risk perception), and the impact of the pandemic on trust <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[20]</ref>. Recent work by Melki et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[56]</ref> shows that those who trust COVID-19 news from social media, interpersonal communication, and/or clerics are more likely to believe in COVID-19 misinformation than those who trust in government information sources. Additionally, prior work has suggested that misbeliefs are more common among those who are in traditionally-marginalized populations (e.g., lower levels of education and income) <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">67,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">91,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b82">92]</ref>.</p><p>However, to the best of our knowledge, there has been a lack of research that examines situated trust during COVID-19-how trust and distrust are shaped by the emerging information platforms, and how this trust and distrust change over the course of the crisis. Specifcally, we refer to the situated trust regarding the emerging information platforms that have been built from the ground up in response to the COVID-19 pandemic-platforms that report and present COVID-19 data such as online dashboards-as well as the well-established platforms available prior to the pandemic, such as social media platforms. The emerging information systems, in particular, were initiated and rapidly built during the early stage of COVID-19 with the goal of providing accurate and timely COVID-19 data (e.g., number of cases/deaths) <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">[80]</ref>. Others have been adapted from existing infrastructure by adding new components to the existing platforms, such as the COVID-19 data trackers provided by media outlets and health-related websites (e.g., the CDC [14] and states' Department of Public Health). Additionally, unlike past work on COVID-19, which presumes a static relationship between the presence or absence of trust and people's behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[56]</ref>, we examine the dynamic relationship between information practices via ICTs and STSs, and the evolving formation of trust and distrust. Moreover, little work that studies the intersection of trust and ICTs and STSs has focused on traditionallymarginalized populations, like low-SES communities, who have been disproportionately impacted by the pandemic. Our research seeks to address these research gaps. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHOD</head><p>This paper is part of a larger project examining information practices and attitudes during COVID-19 and how these practices and attitudes vary across populations. We specifcally focus on populations that have experienced disproportionate COVID-19 morbidity, mortality, and hardship, such as low-SES adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[2]</ref>. Upon approval from the Institutional Review Board at our institution, we conducted a mixed method study that included a longitudinal survey with 177 adults and interviews with 21 participants who completed all waves of the survey study. The use of mixed methods enables triangulation, an approach to analyze results from the same study using diferent methods of data collection <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[41]</ref>. Triangulation helps enhance the validity of our research and creates a more in-depth picture of understanding the social and technological dimensions of people's information practices amidst the COVID-19 pandemic. Below we detail the methods used in the survey (subsection 3.1) and interview (subsection 3.2) components of this project.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Survey Study</head><p>We conducted a longitudinal survey from September 1, 2020 to December 21, 2020. The focus of our survey was to examine people's information seeking behaviors amidst COVID-19. Given the rapid progression of the pandemic in 2020, we expected that individuals' information practices would also change over time, which includes shifts in the platforms used to obtain COVID-19 information as well as the information received. Further, while other studies have shown how demographic diferences exist in information practices <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b82">92]</ref>, our work seeks to identify how these diferences relate to information about COVID-19. Therefore, our survey design was guided by the following overarching research questions: 1) how do people's information practices change over time? and 2) what demographic variations exist in information practices, and how do these variations difer in relation to trust and distrust towards COVID-19 information?</p><p>In the following sections, we describe in detail the survey study procedures, survey questions and measurements, and analyses.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1">Survey Study</head><p>Procedures. We conducted several rounds of pilot testing to develop and refne the survey. First, we conducted multiple rounds of informal pilot testing within the research team and through our family and friend networks. Upon revision based on their feedback, the survey was then formally pilot tested with 40 respondents via Prolifc 2 ; each participant was compensated with $4 for their time. Feedback and responses from the pilot tests were used to iterate upon and develop the fnal survey.</p><p>Our study inclusion criteria were as follows: participants were adults (aged 18+) who live in Massachusetts (MA) or Georgia (GA) and had a 2019 household income of less than $100,000. We chose this income threshold to narrow our focus to low-and middlesocioeconomic populations; doing so enabled us to investigate how information practices and attitudes vary between these two income levels. Respondents were also classifed into two income groups (low-and middle-income) 3 based on the 2020 U.S. Federal Poverty To enable exploration into the efects of information, which is expected to be correlated with the state of the pandemic, we purposefully focused on two regions which difered in policy approaches [59] and incidence patterns <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[40]</ref> at the beginning of the study (see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>). Further, our local knowledge of these regions ensured that locally-relevant questions were included in interviews and surveys. Following the inclusion criteria, participants were recruited into the longitudinal study through the Qualtrics online research panel service <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[63]</ref>. Qualtrics recruited participants from a nationally representative panel. This service helps in the recruitment process by advertising the survey study to an existing pool of respondents. These respondents have agreed to be contacted by the Qualtrics company regarding survey opportunities. Respondents complete surveys in exchange for incentives issued by the company. 4  A total of 329 participants completed and passed our quality checks in the frst survey and were invited to participate in subsequent surveys 5 . Each survey was deployed every two weeks and each deployment is denoted in this paper as a wave (i.e., Wave 1, Wave 2,..., <ref type="bibr">Wave 8)</ref>. In total, 177 participants completed all 8 waves of the surveys with an average of 92% retention rate per wave. 6   3.1.2 Survey Qestions and Measurements. We utilized survey questions that were focused on individuals' information practices during COVID-19 and their level of trust regarding the information sources. Here, we outline the questions and measures used within the survey for the scope of this paper: 7   (1) How often did you use the following platforms; i) radio, ii) television, iii) print newspaper, iv) internet-connected devices, to get information or news about the coronavirus? (1="never", 2="rarely/once a week", 3="sometimes/2-3 times a week", 4="often/4-6 times a week", 5= "every day") (2) Please choose social media platforms you used the most to get information or news about the coronavirus; i) Facebook, ii) YouTube, iii) Twitter, iv) Reddit, v) I did not use social media to get coronavirus information (0= "no", 1= "yes") 8 (3) I did not get coronavirus information from websites (0= "no", 1="yes") 9 (4) On a scale of 0 (do not trust at all) to 10 (complete trust), how much do you trust the following individuals or organizations in providing coronavirus information? i) family members, ii) friends, iii) Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), iv) Dr Anthony Fauci (Director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease), v) Local government agencies and ofcials (5) About how often did you get the information about COVID-19 number of cases and/or deaths (1="never", 2="rarely/once a week", 3="sometimes/2-3 times a week", 4="often/4-6 times a week", 5= "every day") (6) How likely do you think it is that "authorities are intentionally reporting inaccurate rates of coronavirus infections and deaths in the United States"? (1="extremely unlikely", 2="unlikely", 3="maybe/not sure", 4="likely", 5="extremely likely") </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Interview Study</head><p>Our survey data analysis was conducted from January to April 2021. To further investigate the trends in our survey data, we then conducted follow-up semi-structured interviews from April 2021 to July 2021 using Zoom 10 (an online meeting tool).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Participant</head><p>Recruitment. We reached out to all survey respondents who expressed interest in participating in a follow-up interview via email and text message, of which 30 participants agreed to participate, and 21 participants completed the interview (9 participants did not show up or cancelled the interview session). Table 1 provides an overview of the demographic information for our survey respondents and interview participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Interview Study</head><p>Procedures. We analyzed each interview participants' survey data from each survey wave to identify patterns and trends for each question listed in subsubsection 3.1.2. During the interview, participants were asked to further elaborate on their information behaviors throughout the pandemic, allowing us to explore, in detail, the patterns and trends shown in the survey results. The interview sessions were recorded for analysis purposes and lasted for approximately 80 minutes. At the end of the interview session, each participant was compensated with a $25 gift card.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3">Interview Data Analysis.</head><p>All interview sessions were transcribed verbatim. We used the General Inductive Approach <ref type="bibr">[85]</ref> to guide the thematic analysis of the transcripts. We frst read the transcripts closely to get an initial understanding of the concepts that arose in the interview data. Then, we analyzed the transcripts and created low-level codes to label concepts in the data, clustering related low-level codes to achieve high-level themes. Throughout the analysis, all authors discussed and refned the emerging themes regularly.</p><p>By analyzing both the survey and interview data, we seek convergence and complementarity-two common types of triangulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[41]</ref>. Convergence indicates a strong degree of overlap and accuracy between the data sets collected using quantitative and qualitative methods, whereas complementarity builds a richer picture of the research results by allowing the results from diferent methods to inform each other <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[41]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">SURVEY RESULTS</head><p>In this section, we present results from 177 survey respondents who completed all 8 waves of the survey. For the scope of this paper, we focus on the patterns and trends of respondents' information consumption via a variety of information platforms, as well as their use of and level of trust in information sources in subsection 4.1. We also report results regarding the information exposure and level of distrust regarding COVID-19 data in subsection 4.2. Note that in reporting our survey results and interview fndings, we use "COVID-19 data" in a very specifc context, referring to the number of COVID-19 cases and deaths. While the survey results provided some facts about respondents' trust and its association with their information practices during COVID-19, the results also prompted a series of questions that necessitated further investigation. Therefore, at the end of each subsection, we summarize questions (labeled with Q-) that we sought to examine in our interview study (section 5). Note that we use the term "respondents" for survey data and "participants" for interview data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Use of Platforms and Sources for Getting COVID-19 Information &amp; Assessment of Trust Over Time</head><p>In this subsection, we report the survey results regarding the overall information consumption via diferent information platforms (e.g., television, radio, newspaper, internet), as well as participants' use of and level of trust in diferent information sources. Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2a</ref> shows the overall trend of various information platforms utilized to obtain COVID-19 information during our survey period. Overall, our survey results suggest a high use of technology for receiving COVID-19 information. Yet, the use of the internet to obtain COVID-19 information signifcantly decreased over time (β = -0.019, p &lt; 0.001). In contrast, the use of other traditional media platforms (e.g., television, radio, and print newspaper) to obtain COVID-19 information saw no signifcant change over time.</p><p>In terms of the use of social media and websites for COVID-19 information consumption (see Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2b</ref>), our survey results show that there was a signifcant decrease in social media utilization over time (β = -0.025, p &lt; 0.001), referring to the slope of the regression line. While the types of social media platforms that were utilized varied from Facebook, YouTube, Twitter, and Reddit (see Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2c</ref>), we note a signifcant decrease in Facebook usage over time (β = -0.028, p &lt; 0.01). Similar to social media, the use of websites for gaining COVID-19 information also signifcantly decreased over time (β = -0.016, p &lt; 0.001), where the lowest usage was reported in Wave 5 (62%).</p><p>Nonetheless, our survey results also suggest trust in personal networks and scientifc communities were associated with income and education groups. Of note, income and education in our study are independent based on chi-square tests (χ 2 = 103.66, p &lt; 0.001). Specifcally, respondents with middle income and at least a bachelor's degree reported signifcantly higher trust in Dr. Fauci than respondents with low income (β = 0.133, p &lt; 0.001) and without a bachelor's degree (β = 0.072, p &lt; 0.001). Yet, those with middle income trusted their family members (β = -0.053, p &lt; 0.05) and friends (β = -0.071, p &lt; 0.01) signifcantly less than those with low income. No signifcant diferences were found in the trust of the CDC and    local government for providing COVID-19 information. Additionally, respondents with middle income received signifcantly more information via the internet (β = 0.054, p &lt; 0.05), including from websites (β = 0.126, p &lt; 0.001) and social media (β = 0.081, p &lt; 0.001).</p><p>There is no signifcant diference in the information exposure to COVID-19 data among income groups, but respondents with at least a bachelor's degree received signifcantly less information about COVID-19 data than those without a bachelor's degree (β = -0.252, p &lt; 0.05). Distrust in authorities regarding COVID-19 data reporting was found to be signifcantly less among those with higher incomes (β = -0.468, p &lt; 0.001) and higher education (β = -0.163, p &lt; 0.01). Additional characteristics of respondents' information practices are reported in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">2</ref>.</p><p>Summary: Our survey results indicate a high utilization of the internet to obtain COVID-19 information. However, this utilization decreased over time. Additionally, while the use of traditional media platforms (e.g., radio, television, and print newspaper) remained consistent, the use of social media for COVID-19 information consumption signifcantly decreased over the course of our survey period. These results motivated us to further investigate the following questions through our interview study: Qa. What drove our respondents to reduce their engagement with COVID-19 information through the internet, and Qb. Does trust play any role in explaining the decreasing trend in users' social media engagement for the consumption of COVID-19 information?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Information Consumption &amp; Distrust Regarding COVID-19 Data</head><p>In this subsection, we report the survey results of information consumption regarding COVID-19 data, as well as the extent to which individuals distrust authorities regarding this data.</p><p>Figure <ref type="figure">3</ref> shows the overall trend of information consumption about COVID-19 data among our survey respondents. Our analysis results suggest no signifcant change in the frequency of obtaining this information over time. However, the belief that authorities intentionally reported inaccurate COVID-19 data decreased signifcantly over time (β = -0.071, p &lt; 0.001), as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">4</ref>, suggesting a decrease in distrust over time. In wave 1, 62 out of 177 (35%) respondents reported "likely" and "extremely likely" in their belief that authorities intentionally reported inaccurate data, while 48 out of the 177 (27%) respondents continued to believe that the reports were inaccurate through Wave 8.</p><p>The belief that authorities intentionally reported inaccurate data was also found to be negatively associated with the frequency in which individuals received information about COVID-19 data (β = -0.114, p &lt; 0.001). In other words, the more information that individuals received regarding COVID-19 data, the less likely they were to believe that authorities intentionally reported inaccurate data. Simultaneously, the less information that individuals received, the more likely they were to believe that authorities were reporting inaccurate data.</p><p>Summary: Our survey results show that there is an association between an individual's information consumption regarding COVID-19 data and their distrust behaviors. Moreover, we found that over time, an individual's level of distrust in the reporting practices of authorities decreased signifcantly between September and December of 2020. Therefore, in the interview study, we aimed to explore two additional questions: Qc. In what ways is our participants' distrust associated with their information consumption? and Qd. Why does respondents' distrust in authorities decrease over time with regards to the sharing practices of COVID-19 data?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">INTERVIEW FINDINGS</head><p>In this section, we report our qualitative analysis results captured in the interview study, triangulated with our survey results. We focus on ways that participants articulated trust and distrust in relation to their information practices amidst COVID-19. This section also seeks to answer various questions that arose from the survey results.</p><p>To allow for a situated examination, we summarized participants' information behavior, highlighting how they received COVID-19 information and what sources they utilized (e.g., personal networks, scientifc communities, local government, and social media 11 ) in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>. We also summarized their information consumption and their level of distrust regarding COVID-19 data in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref>.    We noticed that P15's survey results showed that she only used social media for COVID-19 information during the first wave of our study but did not use it throughout the rest of the study period, as shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>. It is worth noting that she did not begin using other platforms for COVID-19 information consumption once she As one may imagine, arguments and conflict media did occur prior to the pandemic. Howev participants, it was COVID-19 that "intensified" tension and conflict on social media. For exam that she had never experienced such feelings social media. She told us that "there were not to who have been crazy prior to the pandemic in my In the remainder of this section, we frst examine what drives our participants to reduce their engagement with various information platforms (e.g., social media) to obtain COVID-19 information, including the ways in which trust plays a signifcant role in explaining this diminished usage in subsection 5.1. We then investigate how participants articulate their trust and distrust regarding COVID-19 data in subsection 5.2.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Trust in Social Media</head><p>We frst provide some brief context to help explain the reduced utilization of the internet to consume COVID-19 information (to answer Qa). Then, we specifcally discuss the role that trust plays in explaining the diminished social media engagement amongst participants (to answer Qb).</p><p>According to our participants, a lack of time (n=6) is one of the major reasons for the diminished use of the internet for COVID-19 information consumption. Since some of our participants were from low-SES households, they mentioned that they did not have the privilege to work from home during the pandemic. Many participants had gone back to work in person during the reopening phase in summer 2020. Adapting to their new lifestyle, low-SES participants (e.g., P1, P11, P14, P20) indicated that they had other things that "started to consume their life", such as going back to work in person. Furthermore, a second reason for the decrease in COVID-19 information consumption lies in information fatigue (n=6). Information fatigue is the subjective feeling of tiredness as a result of being exposed to very similar messages and news for an extended period of time <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[72]</ref>. For example, our participants mentioned that they would look at COVID-19 data and related information get in a public fight with your family [on Facebook] (P03, 55-64, Female, Associate Degree, Democrat) We noticed that P15's survey results showed that she o social media for COVID-19 information during the first our study but did not use it throughout the rest of the stud as shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>. It is worth noting that she did not beg other platforms for COVID-19 information consumption stopped using social media.   We noticed that P15's survey results showed that she only used social media for COVID-19 information during the first wave of our study but did not use it throughout the rest of the study period, as shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>. It is worth noting that she did not begin using other platforms for COVID-19 information consumption once she As one may imagine, arguments and conflict media did occur prior to the pandemic. Howeve participants, it was COVID-19 that "intensified" tension and conflict on social media. For exam that she had never experienced such feelings social media. She told us that "there were not to who have been crazy prior to the pandemic in my represents all 177 survey respondents' data (note some data points overlapped). The coronavirus does not exist, 2) The coronavirus was purposefully created and released as part of a conspiracy, 3) Hydroxychloroquine Chloroquine, and Azithromycin can be used as a treatment for the coronavirus, 4) Diluted bleach can be used as a treatment for the coronavirus, 5) The coronavirus is caused by 5G technology, 6) The thread of the coronavirus has been exaggerated by political groups who want to damage President Trump, 7) The coronavirus is being use to force a dangerous and unnecessary vaccine on Americans, and 8) The coronavirus outbreak is a populationcontrol scheme developed by Bill Gates. more often at the beginning of the pandemic, but then "after a while people get tired" and "did not have the mental energy to keep up with" this information as time went by.</p><p>However, we found that a decline trust accounted for the largest change media for consumption. Below we report fndings regarding our participants articulated their Our participants were varied in their used social non-use across waves); and 1 participant did media all during any of the waves.</p><p>One of the most infuential factors that explained the diminished social media usage for COVID-19 information consumption is the avoidance of tension and confict with others on social media networks, especially amongst family and friends. these tensions were grounded in issues of trust. Our participants described various examples of ways in which their views conficted with the views of their social media contacts (e.g., friends and families on Facebook). For example, P15 We noticed that P15's survey results showed that she only used social media for COVID-19 information during the frst wave of our study but did not use it throughout rest of the study period, shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>. It is worth noting that she did not begin using other platforms for COVID-19 information consumption once she stopped using social media.</p><p>The tension that our participants experienced while interacting with social media during the pandemic was mostly due to conficting perspectives and diferent assessments of COVID-19 misinformation. Participants felt a sense of inability to modify others' misbelief. Failing to change others' beliefs frustrated our participants. For example, P18 explained, "My perspective is diferent from my family's perspective in a lot of diferent ways, and actually I was yelling at my parents and my sister... my mom's side of the family is super religious, and on their social media, they were just complaining about the government ... not even just saying it was fake, and all this other stuf and upset because they were in New York. And you know how New York everything down. So, they were saying it was the government's way of removing religion. I'm like [this is] just bogus stuf which is crazy, but everyone has their own opinions... I don't know what to do and argue for... " (P18, 25-34, Female, Graduate Degree, Democrat) As one may imagine, arguments and conficting views on social media did occur prior to the pandemic. However, according to our participants, it was COVID-19 that "intensifed" and "reignited" the tension and confict on social media. For example, P11 mentioned that she had never experienced such feelings of frustrations on social media. She told us "there were not too many people like who have been crazy prior the pandemic in my group". Yet, during COVID-19, she indicated that she was getting angry about her Facebook contacts' posts.</p><p>I search, I get the alert about it like somebody posted. And sometimes that used to make me pissed of because the people have diferent thoughts all. So I tried not to watch this stuf Facebook because it makes angry because people knows everything don't care... make fun of the who are wearing masks or taking precautions, so try to avoid not to talk much about it on this Facebook stuf because it's a and a lot of misinformation is going to make you pissed of. It's going to be make you more angry because if I'm going to talk, it's going to mess up somewhere my relationship. I not to discuss stuf on Facebook, actually avoiding Facebook feeds [about COVID-19]... I don't want go and fght with [my social media contacts] because people who are not going to understand, they're gonna understand. If you try to make them understand, they would say like you are the racist... " 25-34, Female, Degree, Independent) Additionally, some participants (n=4) mentioned that their family who trusted social media also had a</p><p>Trust: Examining How Trust and Emerge, and Collapse 29-May 5, 2022, Orleans, USA sources outside example, mentioned, "like with parents are like very religious... So my dad information from the church and like priests will go like don't use vaccine, like this uses like abortion cells... so I'm like my parents' [I asked my parents to not to trust the vaccine misinformation], at the same time I'm just little bit of anger... I feel like I am in a where misinformation spreads easily within our " (P02, 18-24, Non binary, Bachelor degree, Democrat) These quotes from P18 a generational gap in information behaviors within social media. By generational mean disparity of beliefs and information behaviors between distinct age or generations. In other members from a younger generation in our (like P18, P02) exhibited diferent perspectives, and decisions regarding information as compared the older in lives, like their family members. Our interview data aligns with prior research that indicates that older generations have higher engagement with fake news on social media than younger generations <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[7]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.2">Using But Not</head><p>Trusting Social Media. While our survey results suggested a signifcant decrease in social media usage, there was still a large portion of survey respondents who utilized social media for COVID-19 information. However, during our interview study, we found that most participants did not trust social media for COVID-19 information.</p><p>Our fndings suggest that many of our interviewees believed that they could distinguish misinformation media. The majority of our participants (n=18) felt as though they could trace information back to its original source determine if it is credible or not. Amongst the people who continued to use social media, although they were exposed information, they did not necessarily trust it. For example, P12 mentioned, "I have a Facebook account... But I wasn't using it to make decisions. It's a little I feel like it's not representative of people's actual lives or lifestyles. I don't feel like it's necessarily something to be trusted. I value personal communication, [and] I'd rather talk to someone about what's on life than post it for everyone to see on the social media. (P12, 18-24, Female, Bachelor Degree, Independent) Like P12, many other participants (n=10) described situations where they encountered COVID-19 information on their social media feeds, indicating that they disregarded or tended to "not rely on" this information. "Not relying on" indicates that participants neither reached an adequate trust level for information from social media nor did they use it to make decisions. As such, it is important to diferentiate the "use" of social media for information from the reliance on it. For individuals who can distinguish factual information from false information on social media, misinformation may not necessarily impact their decisions and behaviors.</p><p>While some participants in our study felt they were able to identify misinformation and maintained that their social media use did not negatively impact their behavior, such self-reported assessments might be contradicted by more objective evaluations individuals' ability to distinguish between true and false information <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[95]</ref>. In such cases, this discrepancy would reveal an apparent disconnect between individuals' perceived to discriminate between fake and factual information versus their actual ability.</p><p>However, interestingly, by triangulating with our survey data, we fnd that interview participants who indicated that they could identify misinformation (e.g., P02, P08, P11, P12) were among the people who were indeed least likely to believe misinformation according to Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">6</ref>. These fndings highlight the value of combining subjective and objective assessments of people's ability to identify misinformation, as well as the value of ensuring that people's personal assessments of their abilities are not discounted.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.3">Trustee Trusting Information on Social Media or</head><p>Trusting the Social Media Platform Itself? Social media websites are information platforms where various user-created information is assembled. Users typically need to sort through posts to determine the trustworthiness of each piece of information. In this scenario, the individual pieces of information (e.g., an article, a video, or a social media feed or tweet) are considered the trustee (i.e., the trusted party). However, some participants, the focus was on the trustworthiness of the social media platform(s) itself, rather than the trustworthiness of the information within the platform. In essence, participants' past experiences with misinformation on social media platforms has produced a generalized distrust for these platforms in their entirety. As such, the trustee shifts from the pieces of information to the social media platforms themselves. Once this occurs, distrust is ingrained into the trustor (i.e., information consumer), which consequently makes rebuilding trust more challenging. Here, we discuss the mechanism through which the trustee shifts from pieces of information to the social media platform(s). We also refect on why it is important to unpack this trustee shift, as well as its implications in section 6.</p><p>Many participants (n=9) indicated that they did not trust information on social media because they realized that social media was composed of a mixture of true and false information. P09 explained, "There are lots of things that go on with social media. By the time that I decided many years ago to tune out of that, I was aware that there was a mixture of real information and fake information. And some people fnd it entertaining, but I do not, so I didn't go there. So that gave me insight not to trust social media. " (P09, 35-44, Female, Graduate Degree, Democrat) And yet, our participants were afraid that misinformation may unconsciously impact them. Some (n=2) pointed out that people tend to forget to verify the credibility of the source when they obtained information and were concerned about unconsciously falling into the "trap" of misinformation. P15 explained, "social media is so unreliable... It's just something that popped up that was fun to use to talk to your friends, [but] it's not supposed to be a news source or something reliable... [Potentially fake news] was interesting. But you stop thinking when you read it and forget the source..." 35-44, Female, Graduate Degree, Independent)</p><p>Given how quickly people ingest content, social media users also regularly encounter harmful misinformation of which they might not be aware. A large body of work provides suggestions the mixture of trustworthy information and misinformation on social media can invoke fear in people. As participants experienced challenges in spotting and diferentiating between the "facts" and misinformation, their concerns and fearfulness towards social media was deepened. For example, our participants explained how their negative experiences with social media misinformation, as well as their deep concerns about believing misinformation, led to their non-use of social media for COVID-19 information, "It is a lot of misinformation out there on social media, and it's hard to discern it, but that kind of stuf will make me anxious and afraid. It will make me nervous and put me in a place emotionally I don't want to be so [I didn't use social media for getting COVID-19 information]" (P20, 35-44, Male, Associate Degree, Republican) For some participants (e.g., P09, P15, P16, P20), their perception of social media as a mixing pot of true and false information, as well as the in their ability to discern this misinformation, generates a sense of insecurity and fearfulness among users in the social media platforms. These negative collectively contribute to their distrust in the platforms. Indeed, this interpretation of distrust is in line with work that suggests trust is an afective attribute <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[39]</ref>. Distrust carries afective orientations, and these emotions were commonly observed among our participants. This distrust also encourages disengagement in social media. As such, the distrust associated with social media shifted the focus away from the assessment of the quality of information to the social media platforms themselves.</p><p>Interestingly, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">6</ref>, we see that those who were afraid of the potential harmful efects of misinformation (e.g., P09, P15, P16, P20) also misinformation that were in the middle range, indicating this group of participants believed that certain misinformation was to "true". participants were also more to believing misinformation than others in our study-those participants in subsubsection 5.1.2 (e.g., P02, P08, P12). However, group people aware of the limitations they in distinguishing misinformation from "true" Additionally, our fndings indicate that social media distrust was built up in participants over time and was not necessarily a direct consequence of COVID-19. For example, P09 stated "I decided, many years ago to tune out of that", and P12 indicated "the social media thing [not engaging with social media] was preexisting". This indicates that feelings of social media distrust are often linked to a multitude of prior experiences with misinformation, which we refer to as an individuals' historical past online.</p><p>Summary: Collectively, we found that issues of trust were the main driver for the diminished use of social media for COVID-19 information. It was mainly feelings of inability to change others' misbeliefs and mistrust that led participants to stop using social media. Our participants experienced various tensions and conficts with their social media contacts, arising from the discrepancy between perceptions and beliefs regarding what to trust and whom to trust. While such tensions on social media existed prior to the pandemic, COVID-19 intensifed and reignited these online conficts. Our younger participants frequently reported challenges as they attempted to shift and correct their parents' or relatives' misbeliefs and mistrust. However, as a result of societal norms and a desire to maintain healthy relationships with family, our participants compromised by engaging less with social media. As such, these fndings shed light on the generational gap and relationship dynamics that play a role in online trust.</p><p>Moreover, we found that although our participants used social media for consuming COVID-19 information, most of them did not trust this information. The most commonly cited reason for social media distrust was the perception that social media is a mixture of truthful information and misinformation. These perceptions led to a sense of insecurity, fearfulness, and skepticism regarding social media among participants. Concerns regarding the potential negative impacts of misinformation led participants to feel "afraid". Consequently, we observed a shift in trustees from the information on social media to the social media platform(s) themselves. This shift indicates that addressing the perceived objective credibility of information might not be sufcient for solving the fundamental issues of trust on social media. Instead, these fndings shed light on the deep challenges around distrust in social media infrastructure that need to be addressed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Trust in COVID-19 Data: Information Production &amp; Representation Concerns</head><p>Other than the distrust in social media, we found that participants also expressed distrust in the more fundamental informationthe COVID-19 data (i.e., the number of cases/deaths). In this subsection, we seek to answer two questions based on our survey results: Qc. in what ways are our participants' distrust associated with their information exposure? and Qd. why has respondents' distrust in authorities decreased over time with regards to the sharing practices of COVID-19 data? 5.2.1 Processes of Information Production. Some participants were skeptical about the processes through which COVID-19 data and messages were assembled and constructed, referred here as the production of information. For example, P06 rated the statement that the authorities intentionally reported inaccurate COVID-19 data as "extremely (= 5) across all waves. During the interview, explained why he questioned the validity of the COVID- <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">19</ref>  P06's reasoning processes suggest that he relied on the information he received from his personal network (e.g., friends and coworkers). This serves as a baseline for him to evaluate the trustworthiness and validity of COVID-19 data. relying on information from networks runs the risk of over-generalizing individual cases. We should note that P06 relied on second-hand information learned from other people. this knowledge may stem from rumors or misinformation.</p><p>Similar P06, other participants (n=5) relied heavily on their personal experiences and environmental cues to guide their assessment of the accuracy and trustworthiness of COVID-19 information. For example, participants, like P14, felt as though COVID-19 reports did not align with their own perceptions. According to the survey result as shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>, P14 believed that the authorities intentionally reported inaccurate COVID-19 data and explained, "You see all these numbers and things like that, and I'm like all these people that I've been around and close in my life, and you know, knowing a lot of people that have gotten COVID..." (P14, 25-34, Female, High school or less, Republican) These participants indicate that they were skeptical of the production of COVID-19 information, which contributes to distrust in authorities.</p><p>While most participants who held skepticism not involved in collection of COVID-19 data, some who articulated their trust and distrust in COVID-19 data collection had frst-hand experiences dealing with this process. One participant who worked in the public health sector described his daily job:</p><p>"I made sure that birth <ref type="bibr">[and]</ref> death records are recorded properly... I work with hospitals, funeral homes, doctors, city and town clerks, anybody that has a hand in the vital record creation process or amendment process... I go out and make sure that those things get corrected educate whoever the mistakes... Mostly these days [we're] death records [because] is critical during COVID, and we were constantly trying to make sure that they were recorded properly. I don't actually clean the data, but I make sure that their records are done properly so that data is accurate. " (P08, 45-54, Male, Graduate Degree, Independent) P08 believed the COVID-19 data was trustworthy, and he trusted the authorities who provided the data. This is refected within his survey data, as well (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>). P08 rated the statement "authorities intentionally report inaccurate COVID-19 data" as "extremely (=1) across all waves. Yet, one might argue that it is the nature of P08's occupation (a member of staf working in the public health sector) that infuenced his survey responses. However, surprisingly, as an "insider" who was involved in the data pipeline, P08 also had doubts regarding the COVID-19 data, as he explained:</p><p>"And right now, because our famous reimbursement program, we're seeing a lot of COVID being added to death records. The doctor has to be okay with it, but when it does appear on the death record... [they] will reimburse family... so we're getting a lot of COVID added to record, so I'm not 100% sure what that's going to do to national statistics, but I would imagine that the numbers are going to go up as a contributor. I don't know whether or not it's a lot of people had preexisting ditions. I don't believe that a lot of people were tested at the time of death. They may have exhibited similar to COVID when they passed away from cardiac arrhythmia or something like that. So me personally, not speaking on behalf of [my employer], think that the numbers are going to be a little artifcially higher because of these programs, but it is what it is." (P08, 45-54, Male, Graduate Degree, Independent) P08's reasoning process, as well as his conclusions regarding trust and distrust, suggests that he believed the COVID-19 data in general was truthful but had doubts in the data production procedures. While P06 and P08, noted similar beliefs and concerns about economically-driven medical documentation, to the best of our knowledge, there is no credible evidence of such a trend. Instead, this viewpoint has been cited as a known conspiracy theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">22]</ref>. The fact that two participants with very diferent backgrounds and worldviews hold similar beliefs about the situation suggests that their distrust in authorities was prompted by the skepticism in the COVID-19 data production processes.</p><p>When examining participants' quotes alongside their survey results, we fnd that the justifcation for trust and distrust difers across participants. On the one hand, P06's results demonstrate his high distrust in authorities. Such distrust arises from skepticism in the validity of COVID-19 data production processes, fueled by his past exchanges with his personal networks (e.g., friends and coworkers). However, in P08's case, he highly trusted authorities thanks to his frst-hand experience interacting with the COVID-19 data production process, but he had reason to be suspicious in other respects. As such, the trust exists but is tempered by distrust. Our observations on the coexistence of trust and distrust is sometimes referred to as "bounded trust" <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[47]</ref>. This coexistence was also observed among other participants (n=4), as well. For example, P09 explained how her trust and distrust was coupled together:</p><p>"I think the data and the protocols that rolled out were the best that they could provide us, given that they were still trying to fgure out things. And I'm sure they had a desire to get it right to the best of their ability, so I trust the process that we went through... though I do think there was some suppression of data, like maybe more control that was needed from a government standpoint because they didn't want, in my opinion, people to freak out. " (P09, 35-44, Female, Graduate Degree, Democrat) We also fnd it important to highlight the clear disparity in beliefs between on the adjustment of COVID-19 data.</p><p>Things become more interesting when examining how participants' trust and distrust formation relates to their information practices, as well as the information sources, on which they have been relying. Take, for example, the results of P06, P08, and P14. Our fndings suggest that these participants possessed distinct methods of trust and distrust formation. Triangulated with our survey data, our results also suggest that the trends and patterns of their information practices are dissimilar.</p><p>First of all, with regards to information exposure, reported that he received COVID-19 information throughout the entirety of survey period, whereas P08 had high information exposure. We observe similar trends among all participants in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref>. P06's label is located at the top-left corner of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref>, indicating he had received information about COVID-19 and had high distrust in the authorities who produced COVID-19 data. P08's data point is located at the bottom-right corner of Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref>, indicating that he had received lot of information about COVID-19 and had low distrust in authorities. Although these two data points appear to be opposite extremes, more people in our study were to P06, P08, and P14 (as shown in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref>). Additionally, Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref> shows that even with the same information exposure, people greatly difered in other characteristics.</p><p>Secondly, as previously mentioned, P06 and P14 relied heavily on information from personal networks in their assessment of information. These two participants mentioned in the interview that they refrained from searching for COVID-19 information online. For example, P14 explained, "I really didn't search [COVID-19 information] because I really try to refrain from searching. I never went out looking for for information and or any of that." (P14, 25-34, Female, High school or less, Republican). Unlike P06 and P14, P08 sought out information from multiple sources, including the CDC, Dr. Fauci, the national and local government, a variety of media outlets, and personal networks, like family and friends (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_4">3</ref>). P08's interview data aligned with his survey data, as he indicated that he "currently look[s] at cases almost every day". Taken together, these fndings provide us with a "profle" of our participants, showcasing how trust and distrust formation intersects with their information practices.</p><p>Representation of Data Uncertainty. Skepticism is not only derived from the process of information production but also arises in the presentation of that data to information consumers. One challenge that arises from the wide range of COVID-19 data sources is data discrepancy-when two or more comparable datasets do not match up. COVID-19 data is widely available on the internet and is mostly open-sourced but has been published by various diferent organizations, authorities, and digital volunteers <ref type="bibr" target="#b91">[101]</ref>. The discrepancy between currently-available COVID-19 data published by multiple diferent information sources overwhelmed participants and made it difcult for them to decide whom to trust. As P20 explained, "Because it was so mixed reporting, every outlet was reporting on it, and the numbers were kind of diferent; the diferences in the numbers were like well who's telling the truth." (P20, 35-44, Male, Associate Degree, Republican) P20 was unsure who to trust regarding the publication of COVID-19 data, which is refected in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref>. To P20, there was no sufcient evidence to support his trust in authorities.</p><p>In addition, the wide range of publicly available data sources also led to the diverse manifestations of COVID-19 data visualizations. These COVID-19 visualizations were produced by diferent authorities and organizations that utilized diferent data sources and visualization techniques to present the data. These discrepancies within various COVID-19 visualizations generated confusion among some of our participants. For example, P16's survey results indicate that she believed were very likely to intentionally report inaccurate COVID-19 data (see Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_4">5</ref>). During the interview, explained how discrepancies within visualizations made her feel distrustful towards the authorities who supplied the COVID-19 data:</p><p>"If I read The New York Times, watch ABC news, watch CNN and BBC, you'll get four diferent fgures, so how can there be four diferent fgures?! And then it never you know certain things weren't cited that well." (P16, 45-54, Female, Graduate Degree, Republican) The nuanced representations raised concern among participants and led to perceptions of data inconsistency, which contributed to the overall distrust in authorities.</p><p>A few participants (n=2) described their trouble understanding the minor inconsistencies in the reported COVID-19 data. For example, P10 explained, "Most statistical information presented on the media is a little shaky if you actually have done like grad level statistics... like if they say 250 people died on Monday, then you know, on Wednesday you can't say the total is 170. How do you have less people two days later than you did on Monday? So I'm just used to it being slightly inaccurate at best. So I don't know if they intentionally misreported anything. I think it's probably a combination of a little ignorance about statistics <ref type="bibr">[and]</ref> people just rushing to put out a number for the sensation of it or to back up a story." (P10, 35-44, Male, Graduate Degree, Democrat) P10's quote demonstrates his skepticism in the media, as he believes that bias may have inherently infuenced COVID-19 data. This is exhibited in his belief that certain information outlets might just "put out a number for the sensation of it or to back up a story".</p><p>work has suggested that uneducated or low-educated viduals have difculty understanding statistics and numbers <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">48]</ref>. Yet, in our study, some of the highly-educated participants (e.g., those with graduate degrees) did not appear to realize that statistical anomalies and/or methodology changes in the data are common in times of crises. Our participants were not aware that COVID-19 data is provisional and subject to change. Therefore, the reason why COVID-19 visualizations may have shown 250 deaths, for example, but later updated to show 170 deaths for the same day might be due to the imprecise nature of recently published data, which is afected additional reporting and/or issue fxing <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[13]</ref>.</p><p>However, we argue that understanding the complexities around COVID-19 data is unlikely our participants' fault. Instead, authorities and organizations fail to highlight the uncertainty of data processing and information representation techniques, which ultimately sacrifces the clarity of the information. Altogether, this lack of transparency contributes to the manifestation of distrust in authorities among individuals.</p><p>Additionally, similar to P10, we encountered several (n=5) in which participants elaborated on their distrust of COVID-19 information, citing media biases as the main culprit for their wariness, fear, and worries. For example, P02 indicated that, "Like everything, [information sources are] pushing their own agenda, and if I'm only reading content that pushes my own agenda as well, how am I, as a consumer of content, not going to be biased?" (P02, 18-24, Non binary, Bachelor degree, Democrat)</p><p>The political positionality of an information source infuences and potentially biases the understanding and views the actors (i.e., information consumer). Of course, one could argue that no source could assume a completely "neutral" position. Yet, in the context of the COVID-19 public health crisis, our participants indicated their willingness to seek out information sources that objectively communicate COVID-19 data and/or information. For example, P18 told us she relied both the CDC and a crowdsourced sociotechnical system (i.e., the COVID Tracking Project) for COVID-19 information. She also emphasized her concerns about the mainstream media, as she explained how her trust in these media sources decreased during the pandemic:</p><p>"I got most of my news from the and the COVID Tracking project that on Twitter. [The COVID Tracking project] really just posted like daily statistics and ofer diferent links to the COVID data sources... You know, I don't really trust the mainstream media-there's kind of bias on both sides. Not that I watch Fox news or that I've ever watched it, but even CNN that whole time is so daunting. Even when they are reporting on how many cases, how many people died, it was a little overwhelming... I think the [COVID Tracking Project] Twitter account was less daunting in some ways... I could just click on it and see what I needed to see and then move on from it... Maybe, because people weren't talking about it, maybe I could just read it. And I don't know I just remember being in my own space clicking on it look okay... I just maybe a little appreciated silence of reading about it, instead of hearing them say the same thing over again..." (P18, 25-34, Female, Graduate Degree, Democrat) P18 avoided traditional mainstream media, as she was afraid that media biases inherently infuenced the messages being communicated. She noted that diferent news outlets set dissimilar tones in the communication of COVID-19 related information. The feelings and emotions (e.g., "feel daunting") that arose when obtaining COVID-19 information from CNN indicate her perception on sensationalism, or exaggerated and stories that emphasize fear. Her heightened distrust was colored by her wariness and concerns over media bias, which she considers to be inherently entrenched in the foundation of mainstream media outlets.</p><p>Meanwhile, her acceptance and engagement with emerging crowdsourced systems (e.g., the COVID Tracking Project) refects shifting interest in seeking information sources with "neutral" positionality. This COVID Tracking Project <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">[80]</ref> was created a group of digital volunteers with the goal to address the growing amount of poor quality COVID-19 data (e.g., missing data, latency, etc.). The data collected and aggregated by the COVID-19 Project was utilized by two presidential administrations and an array of federal agencies, including the CDC and the FDA, over the course of the pandemic. Some participants believed these crowdsourced systems were relatively unbiased in comparison to traditional mainstream media, which improved trust levels of these sociotechnical sources. Cognizant of the media bias and polarization of media coverage during COVID-19, some participants shifted to information platforms with less editorial components.</p><p>To better understand the relationship between individuals' information practices and their distrust, we triangulated our survey data with our interviews. Several participants (i.e., P16, P20) who had relatively high information exposure (average scores ≥ 3.0, indicating they obtained COVID-19 information at least 2-3 times per week) also tended to distrust authorities (average scores &gt; 4.0). It is worth noting that the discrepancies found in the data and visualizations indicate that these participants were seeking out and paying close attention to COVID-19 data. However, fndings suggest that exposure is necessary, not sufcient, in building their trust.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.3">Distrust in Authorities Decreases as Data Discrepancy Reduces.</head><p>During our interviews, we explored why the distrust in authorities diminished among respondents over the course of our survey period answer Qd). Some participants felt as though the discrepancies among diferent COVID-19 sources reduced over time, which ultimately improved trust in authorities among these participants. For example, P20 explained, "When I took the survey earlier, [CNN] were putting like X amount of numbers [e.g., cases], but then you turn to a nearby channel that says Georgia has a diferent amount of number... Now their reporting seems to be closer from outlet to outlet, so now I tend to trust it..." (P20, 35-44, Male, Associate Degree, Republican) P20 indicated that over time, he built up trust in authorities because the COVID-19 data discrepancies across various outlets had (partially) reduced over time. Yet, P20 was unable to specify the root cause of the COVID-19 information convergence seen across diferent sources.</p><p>Here, we provide plausible explanations. At the beginning of the pandemic, many diferent information platforms were quickly created to support collecting, aggregating, and presenting COVID-19 data to the public. These diferent organizations were collecting and reporting COVID-19 data on their own, including multiple emerging systems (e.g., the COVID Tracking Project <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">[80]</ref>, the COVID Tracker by 1Point3Acres [1]) and news outlets (e.g., the New York Times <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">[81]</ref>). At that time, there was a shortage of centralized, reliable data sources, forcing even the CDC to utilize data from these crowdsourced websites. Yet, over the course of the pandemic, the centralized platforms, namely those supported by the federal agencies, improved. These federal agencies (i.e., the CDC) were able to provide high-quality data many difinformation outlets, which many sources referred to on websites as "raw" This is refected in the COVID Tracking Project's farewell statement on their website, explaining that "as we wind down at the one-year point, we are both satisfed that the federal government is now producing enough data to replace many of our metrics and eager to turn our attention to the analysis of those areas of the data-like race and ethnicity data" <ref type="bibr" target="#b75">[80]</ref>. Over time, COVID-19 data production and presentation have become more stabilized and centralized. These perceptions of stabilization across COVID-19 information help us understand how trust has emerged and developed among our participants (i.e., P20, P16, P8, P19).</p><p>Summary: By triangulating our survey results and interview data, we found that skepticism among participants originated in both the data production and data representation processes. regards to data production, we conclude people's lack of exposure to information, as well as their reliance on personal networks, may correlate with the inability identify misinformation. In contrast, past experience in evaluating information can one's ability and willingness to establish and balance trust and distrust. Such an ability may enhance people's understanding of the limitations in COVID-19 information, ultimately helping them navigate the chronic uncertainty amidst the pandemic. to data representation, the discrepancies between information sources, as well as the inadequate transparency and clarity regarding data uncertainty, raised concerns and skepticism among participants. Understanding these issues helped us identify the mechanisms for which distrust manifests, highlighting the importance of identifying design constraints in sociotechnical systems and information infrastructure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">DISCUSSION</head><p>Our survey results and interview fndings collectively characterize a variety of factors that contribute to trust and distrust formation, taking into account people's information practices. In this section, building upon our fndings, we refect on the broader challenges of existing information infrastructure that have contributed to the trust and distrust formation. We also provide implications for future work to examine trust and information behaviors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">Deep Challenges in Information Infrastructure</head><p>Below we discuss broader issues of the existing information infrastructures that have shaped play critical roles in trust and distrust formation amidst COVID-19, and implications for future work.</p><p>6.1.1 Trusting &amp; Distrusting While Infrastructuring. Throughout the pandemic, COVID-19 data has been made available through both well-established social media platforms, as well as newlyestablished information platforms, such as crowdsourced These information platforms have integrated into the information infrastructures for crisis response. defnition, information infrastructure refers to networks of heterogeneous sociotechnical systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[46]</ref> 12 . In times of crises, a collection of information infrastructures are created and developed-sometimes referred to as "crisis infrastructure" <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19]</ref>. These platforms together constitute the multi-infrastructural contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[19]</ref> in which crisis and risk information gets distributed to the public. Our work examined how distrust manifests pants, both in terms of participants' concern, as well as their skepticism, COVID-19 data production and data representation.</p><p>Information infrastructure has a wide range of meanings [6, <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">46]</ref> can refer to diferent concepts, such as information itself, applications and software, the stands and transmission codes, or simply the people who create the information system. A more recent and one we in this paper, is using information infrastructure to refer to networks of sociotechnical systems.</p><p>We argue that a fundamental reason for their distrust lies in the "failure" of existing information infrastructures. During the pandemic, reporting and presenting COVID-19 data is challenging because of the lack of comprehensive guidelines for COVID-19 data collection <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[71]</ref>. Our participants were not even sure who held the "ofcial" data. For example, in the United States, the CDC was slow to deliver COVID-19 data at the beginning of the pandemic and needed to rely on crowdsourced <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[71,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">80,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">83]</ref>. Each state's Department of Public Health, news media outlets, and crowdsourced all had their own data practices and pipelines and difered in their data collection, data compiling and aggregation methods, as well as their visualization, and reporting techniques. Thus, the COVID-19 data and its representation were inconsistent across information outlets <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[71,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b91">101]</ref>. The failure to establish proper information infrastructure in response to the crisis led to issues of trust among our participants. COVID-19 data from these platforms often serve as "facts" that refect the near-real-time pandemic situation. As such, this data is used to guide policy-making, facilitate sensemaking around the crisis, and help the people stay informed. Likewise, it informs their risk perception and guides their behavior to mitigate risks. However, people start questioning the validity and accuracy of the COVID-19 data, they begin to lose trust and faith in the authorities who collect and report the essential data. Consequently, this distrust may further impact their perceived severity of the crisis, infuencing their decision-making and behaviors.</p><p>Meanwhile, our results also show that participants' distrust decreased over time. This decrease of distrust is partially due to the gradual way in which information infrastructures were established and improved response to COVID-19. We can further understand the evolution of trust amidst the pandemic by engaging with the concept of infrastructuring. "Infrastructuring", which originated in work by Star and Ruhleder <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[74]</ref> and was coined by Pipek and Wulf [62], emphasizes the processes and practices involved in the evolution of infrastructures. Infrastructuring in the context of the COVID-19 pandemic refers to the ways in which we are constantly revising our feelings of "trust" and "distrust" as new information infrastructures evolve. Therefore, our work demonstrates how trust and distrust evolves alongside the changes in the information infrastructure in times of crisis. By unpacking various issues of trust with regards to information platforms amidst COVID-19, our work contributes to an in-depth examination of the ways in which social media, as well as the emerging COVID-19 data platforms, enable and constrain public trust.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6.1.2</head><p>The Role of Social Media in Crisis Infrastructure. In addition, social media plays an important, yet controversial, role in crisis infrastructure. Social media can facilitate the exploration and communication of risk information during crises <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[4]</ref>. However, the spread of misinformation on social media is also problematic <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">[75]</ref>. Recent work shows that the proliferation of misinformation social media hinders and distorts individuals' consumption during crises like COVID-19 <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[60,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">78]</ref> and suggests that people's reliance on social networks has been remarkably high throughout the pandemic. Our fndings refute this aforementioned work, given that many of participants "used" social media for COVID-19 information consumption, but many did not necessarily "rely on" nor "trust" this information. Some of our participants felt as though they could distinguish misinformation and "true" information, and our survey fndings showed that they were indeed less likely to believe in the misinformation on social Other people in our study decided to avoid social media for COVID-19 information due to insecurity, fear, and skepticism regarding the harmful efects of misinformation on social media, as well as their uncertainty in abilities to discern misinformation. subsection 6.2, we further refect on the discrepancies identifed between our fndings and other work that has previously examined trust in relation to information practices.</p><p>Moreover, some decided to stop using social media platforms altogether for any and all information, leading to the non-use of social media. The topic of non-use amidst sociotechnical systems, such as social media, has gained increasing attention in HCI literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">68]</ref>. Built upon Satchell and Dourish's non-use conceptual framework <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">[68]</ref>, recent work by Grandhi et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[31]</ref> specifcally examined the diferent rationale for non-use on social media, such as active resistance, disenchantment, disenfranchisement, disinterest, replacement, and cognitive bias, all of which can lead to information avoidance. Our fndings add new insight into this emerging body of work, specifcally demonstrating the relationship between non-use and trust, as well as relating non-use to the unique challenges of sub-populations (e.g., low-SES groups) within our research focus .</p><p>Amidst the pandemic, social media ignites tension and conficts between people, causing anxiety and stress on relationships among many users according to our participants. This discord between preexisting beliefs and the beliefs of others on social media generates a strong enough sense of "incapability" and "powerlessness" among users to persuade them to adopt information avoidance behaviors as a response. work has shown that people engage with social media to maintain personal and social relationships <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[31]</ref>, yet our fndings suggest that people actually avoid social media as a way to maintain healthy relationships. This directly contradicts prior research on the relationship between social media non-use and social relationships, as reduced social media use has been shown to be positively correlated with a lower connectedness with others <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[58]</ref>. Given the stress that is induced by feelings of loneliness, it is likely that people revert to social media platforms that they previously quit <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[31]</ref>, as prior work suggested. As such, these fndings collectively indicate that the use and non-use of social media change over time and depend on specifc contexts. More research is needed to further examine the complex relationship between trust, use and non-use, physiological well-being. Moreover, it is important to point out that many topics unrelated to have and always will cause confict among individuals given the multitude of diverse perspectives on social media. However, the pandemic, by its very nature, caused these conficts among users to greatly intensify, generating extreme contention and high levels of frustration and compelling many to cease their social media use. Individual factors, such as the age diferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[33]</ref>, social norms <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[34]</ref>, and political afliation <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[34]</ref>, have been shown to infuence the belief and dissemination of misinformation. These fndings directly coincided with our interview fndings, as participants often cited tensions they experienced older individuals in their lives who had opposing views, coupled with an attempt to avoid confict and comply with social norms, as a major driver in their information avoidance behaviors on social media.</p><p>Further, the examination of non-use in our study is situated in the context of the studied populations (e.g., lower-SES communities). Prior work has shown that active resistance to social media can stem from a lack of time for the general population <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">68]</ref>. Our work suggests that additional characteristics help explain the non-use in our focused population. Our interviews uncovered that our low-SES participants lacked the time and energy to engage with social media during the reopening of 2020, as many of them worked in "essential services", forcing them to attend work physically. Additionally, prior work has not sufciently unpacked the efects of the non-use. While active resistance to using social media may have distinct positive outcomes for users, such as an increase in time for physical activity <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[31]</ref>, our fndings suggest that this same active resistance to social media platforms contributes to a reduced consumption of social media information. Our participants further described how their non-use of social media for COVID-19 information consumption was also driven by their collapsing trust in social media that occurred prior to the pandemic. For individuals with this kind of historical distrust in social media, it might be extremely difcult to rebuild their trust system in social media platforms.</p><p>It is important to note that social media infrastructure is also evolving. For example, social media platforms have improved detection of misinformation, improving the overall quality of online information <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">70,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">97]</ref>. However, targeting the quality of information is not in solving the issues of trust within social media. Our fndings shed light on fundamental issues surrounding trust, taking into account the challenges of trust revision (i.e., changing other's mistrust and misbelief), tensions and conficts between generations, and diferences among particular subpopulations. Our fndings suggest that simple interventions, such as using AI to remove misinformation on social media, may not be sufcient. Instead, we highlight the necessity to shift the focus to designing for trust revision and tension mitigation as a long-term goal establishing and reserving trust. Such explorations are especially critical during crises where many conficting values need to be assessed by the information consumers in a short amount of time. It is difcult, if not impossible, to fnd a simple solution for such a in the midst of a crisis, and thus, more research is needed to explore interventions that aid in both trust revision and tension mitigation to the crisis infrastructure.</p><p>6.1.3 Implications for Future Work. Our work examined how people's trust and distrust emerges, develops, and collapses given various types of trustees, such as authorities and information sources who report and present COVID-19 data, as well as social media in general. In fact, every information consumer is impacted by all these information sources and information platforms. The sources and platforms, together with the consumers, form a complex information fow and trust/distrust network.</p><p>We encourage more research to consider the joint impact that stakeholders have in both the information and trust/distrust networks, paying close attention to the collaborative efort required build infrastructures under time pressures. These stakeholders hold their own strengths and limitations and can thus beneft from learning from one another. For example, the New York Times COVID coverage was awarded the 2021 Pulitzer Prize for Service <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">[82]</ref>. Likewise, the COVID Tracking Project has recently been archived as an open-source data infrastructure by research institutions <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">[87]</ref>. To best of our knowledge, this was the time in the digital age that the documentation of crowdsourcing activities became a part of the key infrastructure in the country. Explicitly examining the collaboration across organizations and authorities will not only contribute to crisis informatics, HCI, and public health research but will also help document human evolution and provide a new way of preserving our history. As we start documenting and sharing lessons learned from both information providers and consumers, addressing the institutional challenges and adjusting the information infrastructure, we hope to help the general public improve their trust systems and better prepare for future crises.</p><p>Moreover, our fndings suggest that feelings of distrust among participants were deeply shaped by experiences they had prior to the pandemic. Our fndings also indicate that a shift in trustee (i.e., who and what is trusted) occurred participants, fuctuating between distrust in the information on social media and distrust in the social media platforms themselves. Temporality plays an essential role in this shift. Participants' accumulated negative experiences with misinformation are in their perception of social media platforms as a whole. In other words, small, temporal units of engagement and negative experiences with misinformation in one's past can lead to distrust in the social media platform. It is important that we seriously consider the insights gathered throughout the COVID-19 crisis to improve the crisis infrastructure and foster trust. Otherwise, as we have highlighted in this paper, trust is easily broken but difcult to regain.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Methodological Refections</head><p>Drawing upon our experiences in this research project, we conclude with refections on methodological opportunities and challenges that are important for research on trust and information behaviors. In this section, we discuss previous work focused on the association between trust and information practices to highlight the importance of mixed-methods research when assessing these relationships.</p><p>Our triangulated data sheds light on an important research gap regarding the relationship between trust and information consumption. A vast majority of previous work has explored the relationship between trust and information practices by assessing individuals' use of information sources to obtain COVID-19 information <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">50,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">56,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">60,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b86">96,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b88">98]</ref>. For example, prior research has explored the relationship between perceived trust and information sources by frst identifying if individuals "use" (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b88">[98]</ref>) or "follow" (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[56]</ref>) a particular source to obtain COVID-19 information. However, we argue that great care must be taken in what is inferred from the answers to those questions. For example, while prior work has drawn conclusions about what information sources people "rely on" based on where they have gotten information from <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[45,</ref><ref type="bibr">84,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b86">96]</ref>, our results paint a diferent picture. Specifcally, we found that despite reporting that they get COVID-19 information on social media, many of our interviewees not trust this information and did rely on it to make decisions. This raises questions about what it means to "rely" on information (e.g., simply assessing reliance as the extent to which information is gathered from a source versus how much it is used to make decisions). Such concepts must be clearly defned and measured to support accurate and robust knowledge building around these phenomena. Furthermore, our nuanced understanding of participants' use of and trust in information was surfaced only as we triangulated our survey and interview data, with our interviews allowing us to probe the trends arising in our survey. As such, we make two recommendations. First, mixed method studies are essential for truly unpacking the dynamics of information trust and distrust formation. Second, given the diferent measurements and word choices used in current COVID-19 survey studies, we believe meta-review characterizes the varied approaches to assessing information practices, reliance, and trust would be benefcial for future research.</p><p>Additionally, prior survey studies measuring perceived trust in information sources <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">50,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">60]</ref> have not specifed the particular information that respondents relied on to make eventual decisions. Furthermore, individuals' levels of trust can change over time. Therefore, assessments of trust in relation to people's information practices fail to accurately capture the dynamics of trust and distrust formation. Even longitudinal survey studies have limitations, as we cannot fully capture peoples' changing perceptions and shifting evaluations of trust. Therefore, we encourage future research to consider combining longitudinal survey analysis with repeated interviewing methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[57]</ref>, incorporating recurring interviews among the same research population to better understand how, when, and under what conditions their trust and distrust start to change. Although more time-consuming, leveraging the longitudinal survey with recurrent interviews would facilitate a deeper understanding of the capricious nature of trust.</p><p>Moreover, our results showed low-SES groups in our study had signifcantly higher trust in their personal contacts and signifcantly lower trust in Dr. Fauci. Furthermore, they utilized the internet and social media signifcantly less to gain COVID-19 information. Additionally, in our interviews, some participants from low-SES households described how their communities had suffered from mistrust issues. Their inability to change the misbeliefs and mistrust of the people surrounding them deeply disappointed our participants. Arguably, these issues may also occur within other populations, such as higher-SES groups. However, work seeks to avoid the assumption that all populations have similar concerns, perspectives, processes of trust and distrust formation. Such assumptions can be harmful to marginalized populations, generating systems that disproportionately beneft more advantaged groups <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">[94,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b90">100]</ref>. Further research is needed to investigate the prevalence and reasons behind these trends across varied demographic groups, as well as in larger sample sizes. Such research will need to overcome potential barriers to engaging marginalized populations in research studies. For example, while a concerted efort was made to reach out to all of our survey respondents who expressed interest in participating in a follow-up interview and to recruit a diverse sample of interviewees, we had higher response from respondents with higher education and income levels. In turn, we were constrained in our attempts to study the experiences of varied demographic groups. Therefore, we strongly encourage additional research that examines a broader range of marginalized groups to better understand their strengths, concerns, skepticism, and difculties regarding their trust and distrust formation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">LIMITATIONS</head><p>our survey study, as mentioned in the method, we examine only a small set of information behaviors during COVID-19 in this paper. Relatedly, due to space considerations, we did not present the survey results and interview fndings regarding the information practice and trust diferences between MA and GA respondents. We will report the geographical diferences in follow-up Moreover, our survey respondents were asked to answer their information consumption "in the past 2 weeks", may be limited by the fallible accuracy of individuals' past recollection. Additionally, we focused on the perceptions and trust people had towards social media platforms and emerging data platforms in general rather than any specifc platform. As our fndings shed light on the general issues of information infrastructure, we believe there is a need to narrow down the scope by specifcally examining issues of trust within each individual platform. In our interview study, we had a greater number of participants who received higher education levels (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>). These sample limitations restrict the generalizability of our fndings to the broader U.S. population. Still, our fndings provide important insight into the information practices and attitudes of our participants and highlight several important areas for future work to investigate.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="8">CONCLUSION</head><p>The study of the dynamics of trust is critical for handling current and future crises. Our fndings characterize 1) the ways in which the trustee (i.e., what/who people trusted) shifts from information from social media to the social media platform(s); 2) how distrust in authorities regarding COVID-19 data shifts over and 3) how the trust shifts from traditional news media to crowdsourced Trust shapes, and is shaped by, the technologies and information infrastructures in complex ways. As information providers and authorities navigate through the COVID-19 crisis and continue to improve the systems and infrastructure, we may continue to observe changes in public trust. Meanwhile, as people continue interacting with various systems that enable information exchange, we may also expect their concerns, skepticism, and distrust to redethe current design of sociotechnical systems and information infrastructures. As such, people are practicing their "trusting" and "distrusting" alongside the processes of "infrastructuring". How trust emerges, develops, and collapses relies on concrete conditions in which people utilize to seek out information within the information platforms. It is these concrete situations that determine which sociotechnical systems take root and thrive and which wither and die. The complexities that arise in the formation and evolvement trust and distrust, alongside the relationship with people's information practices, will continue to be a challenging topic; one of which deserves more research in the future.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Figure 1: An overview of COVID-19 situations of Massachusetts (MA) and Georgia (GA) in the United States: This fgure shows a brief timeline with several key dates. During our study design and deployment period, MA and GA had shown diferent trends and patterns during the pandemic (e.g., confrmed cases/deaths), as well as diferent public health policies during COVID-19. For example, the MA Governor issued an order requiring the use of masks or face coverings in public places on May 1, 2020. However, GA has never issued mask mandate policy during COVID-19. Data sources: Cases data is from Johns Hopkins University CSSE [40]; policy events are drawn from National Governor's Association [59].</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="4,53.80,92.73,504.01,179.81" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: The use of information platforms for COVID-19 information consumption during our survey period.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Figure 4: The change in distrust in authorities regarding COVID-19 data was assessed by asking respondents if they believe the authorities intentionally report inaccurate COVID-19 data.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: The relationship between the frequency of getting information about COVID-19 data (e.g., cases/deaths) and the belief in authorities intentionally reporting inaccurate COVID-19 data. Each data point represents the average of values across all waves. represents interview participants' data with an arrow pointing to the participant ID (e.g., ← PID); represents all 177 survey respondents' data (note some data points overlapped).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: How likely our participants trus ranked from lowest to highest. Misinform is the sum of their selection across a list of Unlikely=1, Not sure=2, Likely=3, Extreme tions over all 8 waves divided by the score always select Extremely Likely. Question coronavirus does not exist, 2) The coronav fully created and released as part of a cons ychloroquine Chloroquine, and Azithrom as a treatment for the coronavirus, 4) Dilu used as a treatment for the coronavirus, 5 is caused by 5G technology, 6) The thread o has been exaggerated by political groups w age President Trump, 7) The coronaviru force a dangerous and unnecessary vacci and 8) The coronavirus outbreak is a po scheme developed by Bill Gates.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_7"><head>Figure 5 :Figure 5 :</head><label>55</label><figDesc>Figure 5: The relationship between the frequency of getting information about COVID-19 data (e.g., cases/deaths) and the belief in authorities intentionally reporting inaccurate COVID-19 data. Each data point represents the average of values across all waves.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_8"><head>Figure 5 :</head><label>5</label><figDesc>Figure 5: The relationship between the frequency of getting information about COVID-19 data (e.g., cases/deaths) and the belief in authorities intentionally reporting inaccurate COVID-19 data. Each data point represents the average of values across all waves. represents interview participants' data with an arrow pointing to the participant ID (e.g., ← PID); represents all 177 survey respondents' data (note some data points overlapped).</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_10"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure 6: How likely our participants trust ranked from lowest to highest. Misinform is the sum of their selection across a list of Unlikely=1, Not sure=2, Likely=3, Extreme tions over all 8 waves divided by the score always select Extremely Likely. Question coronavirus does not exist, 2) The coronav fully created and released as part of a cons ychloroquine Chloroquine, and Azithrom as a treatment for the coronavirus, 4) Dilu used as a treatment for the coronavirus, 5) is caused by 5G technology, 6) The thread o has been exaggerated by political groups w age President Trump, 7) The coronaviru force a dangerous and unnecessary vaccin and 8) The coronavirus outbreak is a po scheme developed by Bill Gates.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_11"><head>Figure 6 :</head><label>6</label><figDesc>Figure6: How likely our participants trust misinformation, ranked from lowest to highest. Misinformation Belief Score is the sum of their selection across a list of 5-point (Never=0, Unlikely=1, Not sure=2, Likely=3, Extremely Likely=4) questions over all 8 waves divided by the score if the participant always select Extremely Likely. Questions include 1) The coronavirus does not exist, 2) The coronavirus was purposefully created and released as part of a conspiracy, 3) Hydroxychloroquine Chloroquine, and Azithromycin can be used as a treatment for the coronavirus, 4) Diluted bleach can be used as a treatment for the coronavirus, 5) The coronavirus is caused by 5G technology, 6) The thread of the coronavirus has been exaggerated by political groups who want to damage President Trump, 7) The coronavirus is being use to force a dangerous and unnecessary vaccine on Americans, and 8) The coronavirus outbreak is a populationcontrol scheme developed by Bill Gates.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Sample demographic characteristics of our survey respondents and interview participants.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="2">Demographic Response Options</cell><cell>Interview Participants (N = 21)</cell><cell>Survey Respondents (N = 177)</cell></row><row><cell>Gender</cell><cell>Female Male Prefer not to say/self-describe</cell><cell>14 (66.7%) 6 (28.6%) 1 (4.8%)</cell><cell>111 (62.7%) 60 (33.9%) 6 (3.4%)</cell></row><row><cell>Age</cell><cell>18-24 25-34 35-44 45-54 55+</cell><cell>3 (14.3%) 7 (33.3%) 6 (28.6%) 3 (14.3%) 2 (9.5%)</cell><cell>29 (16.4%) 50 (28.2%) 51 (28.8%) 28 (15.8%) 19 (10.7%)</cell></row><row><cell>Race</cell><cell>Asian Black Hispanic White Other/Mixed</cell><cell>2 (9.5%) 7 (33.3%) 3 (14.3%) 9 (42.9%) -</cell><cell>13 (7.3%) 51 (28.8%) 11 (6.2%) 99 (55.9%) 3 (1.7%)</cell></row><row><cell>Education</cell><cell>Less than Bachelor Degree Bachelor Degree and Higher</cell><cell>7 (33.3%) 14 (66.7%)</cell><cell>114 (64.4%) 63 (35.6%)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">Income group Low Middle</cell><cell>6 (28.6%) 15 (71.4%)</cell><cell>80 (45.2%) 97 (54.8%)</cell></row><row><cell>State</cell><cell>GA MA</cell><cell>13 (61.9%) 8 (38.1%)</cell><cell>78 (44.1%) 99 (55.9%)</cell></row><row><cell>Level (FPL) Guidelines [88].</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>Middle income (vs. Low income) (vs. Less than bachelor) Bachelor and higher</cell></row></table><note>Multi-level regression results on the efect of income and education on information practices during COVID-19. (Signifcance: * p &lt; 0.05, * * p &lt; 0.01, * * * p &lt; 0.001)</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_4"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>An overview of our 21 interview participants' information practices, specifcally indicating the sources they used to obtain COVID-19 information.</figDesc><table><row><cell cols="6">PID Family Friends CDC Dr. Fauci Local Gov</cell><cell>Social Media</cell></row><row><cell>P01 P02 P03 P04 P05 P06 P07 P08 P09 P10 P11 P12 P13 P14 P15 P16 P17 P18 P19 P20 P21</cell><cell>Yes Yes No No Yes No No Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No No Yes Yes No</cell><cell>Yes Yes Yes No Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes</cell><cell>Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No</cell><cell>Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No</cell><cell>Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes Yes No Yes Yes No Yes Yes Yes Yes</cell><cell>Sometimes use All-wave use All-wave non-use All-wave use Stopped use Stopped use Stopped use Stopped use Sometimes use Sometimes use Sometimes use Stopped use All-wave use Stopped use Stopped use All-wave use All-wave use All-wave use All-wave use Sometimes use All-wave use</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_6"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>They took the COVID-19 PCR test and it was negative... But at the end, there was one piece of paper [death certifcate] saying it's COVID-19. He said my dad didn't die from COVID-19 but just a heart failure... People passed [away] with the COVID-19 negative... somebody's getting paid for putting COVID-19 on [death certifcates], so that contributes to the infation number... put COVID-19 [on the death certifcate] they get so much money from the federal government now. " (P06, 35-44, Male, High school or less, Republican)</figDesc><table><row><cell>being produced:</cell><cell>data</cell></row><row><cell>don't trust [the COVID-19 data] because not every-</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>died from coronavirus. My friend's dad had heart</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>failure and died.</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">No consensus currently exists among trust scholars on which defnition of trust is the most appropriate. Leveraging the literature on trust, our defnition most closely aligns with McKnight et al.<ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[55]</ref>, Mayer et al.<ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[54]</ref>, and Currall et al.[18]. See Burke et al. 's review for more defnitions of trust<ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[10]</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">https://prolifc.co/<ref type="bibr" target="#b1">3</ref> Respondents were classifed as low-income if their adjusted household income was less than or equal to 185% of the FPL, following the eligibility guidelines for federal aid programs[89].</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="4">Incentive structures were set by the company and not the research team, and Qualtrics was unable to disclose the compensation details to us.<ref type="bibr" target="#b3">5</ref> Quality checks include 98% survey completion rate.6  Participants who dropped-out at any point of the survey were not included in the analysis since we cannot fully assess the changes in their survey responses.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="7">Checkboxes were provided for question (2) and (3).<ref type="bibr" target="#b6">8</ref> These social media platforms were selected as they were cited as the primary information sources for COVID-19 related information and news<ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[42]</ref>.<ref type="bibr" target="#b7">9</ref> News apps did not count as news websites.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="10">https://zoom.us/</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="11">In Table3: "All-wave use"= used social media for getting COVID-19 information across all waves; "All-wave non-use"= did not use social media at all across all waves; "Stopped use" = used social media during the frst 1-2 waves at most, but then stopped using during the rest of the waves; "Sometimes use"= used social media irregularly during the waves (excluding the "stopped use" behaviors).</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>material is based on work that is partially funded by an unrestricted gift from Google. This research was also supported by Northeastern University. We thank our participants for their support within our research. We also thank Niharika Mathur for helping with the interview data collection, the Wellness Technology lab at Georgia Tech for feedback, as well as our anonymous reviewers their reviews.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">COVID-19 and the impact of social determinants of health</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Elissa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Abrams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Stanley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Szefer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Lancet Respiratory Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="659" to="661" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lies kill, facts save: detecting COVID-19 misinformation in twitter</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mabrook</forename><surname>Al-Rakhami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Atif M Al-Amri</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3019600</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3019600" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ieee Access</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="155961" to="155970" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Communicating Hurricane Risks: Multi-Method Examination of Risk Imagery Diffusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melissa</forename><surname>Bica</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Demuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Dykes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leysia</forename><surname>Palen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ACCESS.2020.3019600</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Meet The Team Behind The Coronavirus Tracker Watched By Millions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melissa</forename><surname>Block</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290605.3300545</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.npr.org/2020/04/13/833073670/mapping-covid-19-millions" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Borgman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.7551/mitpress/7434.001.0001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.7551/mitpress/7434.001.0001" />
		<title level="m">Scholarship in the Digital Age: Information, Infrastructure, and the Internet</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, Mass</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>The MIT Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Aging in an era of fake news</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Nadia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Brashier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Schacter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0963721420915872</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0963721420915872" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current directions in psychological science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="316" to="323" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trust in health information sources: survey analysis of variation by sociodemographic and tobacco use status in Oklahoma</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cati G Brown-Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Lindsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Boeckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Ashley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sjonna</forename><surname>Burbank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Paulson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Beebe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JMIR public health and surveillance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">e6260</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who do you trust? The destruction of shared situational awareness and the COVID-19 infodemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deborah</forename><surname>Bunker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2020.102201</idno>
		<idno>102201. 2020.102201</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Information Management</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">55</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trust in leadership: A multi-level review integration. The leadership quarterly</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dana</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>C Shawn Burke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Sims</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eduardo</forename><surname>Lazzara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Salas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="606" to="632" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Situated trust in a physician: Patient health characteristics and trust in physician confdentiality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Celeste</forename><surname>Campos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">-</forename><surname>Castillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Denise</forename><surname>Anthony</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.leaqua.2007.09.006</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Sociological Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="559" to="582" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">VERIFY: Are doctors inaccurately reporting deaths as COVID-19-related?</title>
		<idno>CBS19. 2021</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.cbs19.tv/article/news/health/verify-covid-19-reporting-and-death-certifcates/501-cd4f1995-e342-4451" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved 2021-09-06 from</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trustworthiness Perceptions of Social Media Resources Named after a Crisis Event</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3392849</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3392849" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<editor>Apoorva Chauhan and Amanda Lee Hughes</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trust-the fundamental bond in global collaboration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Child</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational dynamics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="274" to="288" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001. 2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Tracking Covid-19 cases in the US</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cnn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.cnn.com/interactive/2020/health/coronavirus-us-maps-and-cases" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Measuring trust between organizational boundary role persons</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Steven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Currall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Judge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Organizational behavior and Human Decision processes</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="151" to="170" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995. 1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social media seamsters: Stitching platforms &amp; audiences into local crisis infrastructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dharma</forename><surname>Dailey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kate</forename><surname>Starbird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2998181.2998290</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2998181.2998290" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing<address><addrLine>Portland, Oregon, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1277" to="1289" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trust and the Coronavirus Pandemic: What are the Consequences of and for Trust? An Early Review of the Literature</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Devine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Gaskell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Jennings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gerry</forename><surname>Stoker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2998181.2998290</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Studies Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="274" to="285" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Literacy and health outcomes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Darren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nancy</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Dewalt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stacey</forename><surname>Berkman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Sheridan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Lohr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Pignone</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of general internal medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1228" to="1239" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Anti-Vax Doctor Promotes Conspiracy Theory That Death Certifcates Falsely Cite COVID-19</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ej Dickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2021" to="2029" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">source of the story: Evaluating the credibility of sources</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tristan</forename><surname>Endsley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Reep</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>date: 01-05-2014 Through 01-05-2014</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">11th International Conference on Information Systems for Crisis Response and Management</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="160" to="164" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Role of situated trust in rural sustainability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ian</forename><surname>Falk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Guenther</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5465/amr.1998.926617</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.1998.926617" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>levels of trust&quot; community profle</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Levels of Trust in Information Sources as a Predictor of Protective Health Behaviors During COVID-19 Pandemic: A UAE Cross-Sectional Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maria</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Figueiras</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jihane</forename><surname>Ghorayeb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Mariana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joã£o</forename><surname>Coutinho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Marãžco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.633550</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/fpsyg.2021.633550" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2780</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A primer in longitudinal data analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Garrett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Caitlin</forename><surname>Fitzmaurice</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ravichandran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/fpsyg.2021.633550</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Circulation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">118</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2005" to="2010" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing Information Savvy Societies: An Introduction to Assessability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Forte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nazanin</forename><surname>Andalibi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heather</forename><surname>Willever-Farr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2556288.2557072</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2556288.2557072" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Toronto, Ontario, Canada; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2471" to="2480" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI &apos;14)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Association between public knowledge about COVID-19, trust in information sources, and adherence to social distancing: cross-sectional survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ilona</forename><surname>Fridman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicole</forename><surname>Lucas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Debra</forename><surname>Henke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christina</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Zigler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2196/22060</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2196/22060" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">JMIR public health and surveillance</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fake News on Facebook and Twitter: Investigating How People (Don&apos;t) Investigate</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Geeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Savanna</forename><surname>Yee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Franziska</forename><surname>Roesner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2196/22060</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Honolulu, HI, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI &apos;20)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Belief in Conspiracy Theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ted</forename><surname>Goertzel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3313831.3376784</idno>
		<ptr target="http://www.jstor.org/stable/3791630" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="731" to="742" />
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994. 1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do I Stay or Do I Go? Motivations and Decision Making in Social Media Non-Use and Reversion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sukeshini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linda</forename><surname>Grandhi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Starr</forename><forename type="middle">Roxanne</forename><surname>Plotnick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hiltz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3361116</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3361116" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019-12">2019. Dec. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Interact. 3, GROUP, Article 235</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dutch COVID-19 lockdown measures increased trust in government and trust in science: A diference-in-diferences analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Joost Oude Groeniger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeroen</forename><surname>Noordzij</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Willem De</forename><surname>Van Der Waal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Koster</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.socscimed.2021.113819</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socscimed.2021.113819" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Science &amp; Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">275</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">113819</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Less than you think: Prevalence and predictors of fake news dissemination on Facebook</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Guess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Nagler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><surname>Tucker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/sciadv.abf1234</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1126/sciadv.abf1234" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Science advances</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Belief in Conspiracy Theories to Trust in Others: Which Factors Infuence Exposure, Believing and Sharing Fake News</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Halpern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sebastián</forename><surname>Valenzuela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Katz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Juan</forename><forename type="middle">Pablo</forename><surname>Miranda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1126/sciadv.abf1234</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Social Computing and Social Media. Design, Human Behavior and Analytics, Gabriele Meiselwitz</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Understanding information infrastructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ole</forename><surname>Hanseth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Monteiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Situated knowledges: The science question in feminism and the privilege of partial perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Haraway</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Feminist studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="575" to="599" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988. 1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Information and communication technologies, poverty and development</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Heeks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tamanna</forename><surname>Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Robert L Logan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arjuna</forename><surname>Ugarte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoshitomo</forename><forename type="middle">Sean</forename><surname>Young</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">COVIDLies: Detecting COVID-19 misinformation on social media</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Covid-19 and the &apos;Rally-Round-the Flag&apos;Efect, UK in a Changing Europe</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Jennings</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Luettu</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">2020</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">COVID-19 Data Repository by the</title>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/CSSEGISandData/COVID-19" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Johns Hopkins University ; Center for Systems Science and Engineering (CSSE) at Johns Hopkins University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved 2021-08-19 from</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">International encyclopedia of human geography. Elsevier</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Audrey</forename><surname>Kobayashi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<pubPlace>Amsterdam, The Netherlands</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reddit, Facebook, Twitter Worst For Mental Health Post-Coronavirus</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Koetsier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Youtube</forename><surname>Best</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.forbes.com/sites/johnkoetsier/2020/04/26/reddit-worst-for-mental-health-for-covid-19-news-consumption-survey-says" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conspiracy Talk on Social Media: Collective Sensemaking during a Public Health Crisis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yubo</forename><surname>Kou</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xinning</forename><surname>Gui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chen</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Pine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3134696</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3134696" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact. 1, CSCW, Article</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017-12">2017. dec 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roberta</forename><surname>Lamb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Sawyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Kling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3134696</idno>
		<title level="m">A social informatics tive on socio-technical networks</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Lazer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Ognyanova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Baum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Lin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Druckman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mauricio</forename><surname>Perlis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ata</forename><surname>Santillana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Uslu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Social media news consumption and COVID-19 vaccination rates</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A bridge too far?: Critical remarks on the concept of &quot;infrastructure&quot; in computer-supported cooperative work and information systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Charlotte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kjeld</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/oso/9780198733249.003.0006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/oso/9780198733249.003.0006" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trust and distrust: New relationships and realities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Roy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lewicki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mcallister</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bies</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5465/amr.1998.926620</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.1998.926620" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of management Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="438" to="458" />
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998. 1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Numeric, verbal, and visual formats of conveying health risks: suggested best practices and future recommendations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Isaac</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lipkus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5465/amr.1998.926620</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Medical decision making</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="696" to="713" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spreading (dis) trust: Covid-19 misinformation and government intervention in Italy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Lovari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0272989X07307271</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Media and Communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="458" to="461" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Source Trust and COVID-19 Information Sharing: The Mediating Roles of Emotions and Beliefs About Sharing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linqi</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jiawei</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Connie</forename><surname>Yuan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kelli</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Burns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Enze</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dongxiao</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Health Education &amp; Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="139" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Gathering COVID-19 Data More Important Than Ever</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Lutz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1090198120984760</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.contagionlive.com/view/gathering-covid19-data-more-important-than-ever" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Is Getting a Crash Course in Scientifc Uncertainty</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/22/health/coronavirus-covid-usa.html" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trust, untrust, distrust and mistrustan exploration of the dark (er) side</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Marsh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mark R Dibben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/11429760_2</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/11429760_2" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International conference on trust management</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg; Berlin, Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="17" to="33" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An integrative model of organizational trust</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Roger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>James</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Schoorman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/11429760_2</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of management review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="709" to="734" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995. 1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Initial trust formation in new organizational relationships</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harrison</forename><surname>Mcknight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Larry</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Cummings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Norman</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Chervany</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5465/amr.1998.926622</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5465/amr.1998.926622" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Academy of Management review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="473" to="490" />
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998. 1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mitigating infodemics: The relationship between news exposure and trust and belief in COVID-19 fake news and social media spreading</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jad</forename><surname>Melki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hani</forename><surname>Tamim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dima</forename><surname>Hadid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maha</forename><surname>Makki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jana</forename><forename type="middle">El</forename><surname>Amine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eveline</forename><surname>Hitti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0252830</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0252830" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Plos one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Social theory and social structure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>King Merton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1371/journal.pone.0252830</idno>
		<editor>enl. ed. ed.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1968">1968. 1968</date>
			<publisher>Free Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">social-media-abstinence-and-interactions. National Governors Association. 2021. Coronavirus State Actions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kaloyan</forename><surname>Mitev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sonya</forename><surname>Weinstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thuy-Vy</forename><surname>Karabeliova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wilbert</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Law</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Przybylski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/tmb0000033</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.nga.org/coronavirus-state-actions-all" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Social Media Use Only Helps, and Does Not Harm, Daily Interactions and Well-Being</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Health Information Seeking Behaviors on Social Media During the COVID-19 Pandemic Among American Social Networking Site Users: Survey Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Neely</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Eldredge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ron</forename><surname>Sanders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2196/29802</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2196/29802" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Medical Internet Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making Sense of Risk Information amidst Uncertainty: Individuals&apos; Perceived Risks Associated the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><surname>Pine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yunan</forename><surname>Whitman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kathryn</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Henne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.17705/1jais.00195</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.17705/1jais.00195" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA, Article</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2021. 2009. 2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">653</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Infrastructuring: Toward an integrated perspective on the design and use of information technology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Unlock breakthrough insights with market research panels</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Qualtrics</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.17705/1jais.00195</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.qualtrics.com/research-services/online-" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reliance, trust, and belief</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Railton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inquiry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">57</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="122" to="150" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social media in crisis management: An evaluation and analysis of crisis informatics research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Reuter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><forename type="middle">Lee</forename><surname>Hughes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marc-André</forename><surname>Kaufhold</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="280" to="294" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The disproportional impact of COVID-19 on African Americans</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maritza</forename><surname>Vasquez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Reyes</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/10447318.2018.1427832</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Health and Human Rights</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">299</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Anne Marthe Van Der Bles, and Sander Van Der Linden. 2020. Susceptibility to misinformation about COVID-19 around the world</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Roozenbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Dryhurst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><forename type="middle">Lj</forename><surname>Kerr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gabriel</forename><surname>Freeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Recchia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rsos.201199</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1098/rsos.201199" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Royal Society open science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 201199</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond the User: Use and Non-Use in HCI</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Satchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Dourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1098/rsos.201199</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 21st Annual Conference of the Australian Computer</title>
				<meeting>the 21st Annual Conference of the Australian Computer<address><addrLine>Melbourne, Aus; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>tralia) (OZCHI &apos;09)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2020. with marginalized challenges to continuity during the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Jae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luis</forename><surname>Sevelius</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gutierrez-Mock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Breonna</forename><surname>Zamudio-Haas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Azize</forename><surname>Mccree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Akira</forename><surname>Ngo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carla</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luz</forename><surname>Clynes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arianna</forename><surname>Venegas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cinthya</forename><surname>Salinas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Herrera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10461-020-02920-3</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10461-020-02920-3" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AIDS and Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2009" to="2012" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Fake news detection on social media: A data mining perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kai</forename><surname>Shu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Sliva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Suhang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jiliang</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huan</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3137597.3137600</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3137597.3137600" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM SIGKDD explorations newsletter</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="22" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Inconsistent Reporting Practices Hampered Our Ability to Analyze COVID-19 Data. Here Are Three Common Problems We Identifed</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Simon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3137597.3137600</idno>
		<ptr target="https://covidtracking.com/analysis-updates/three-covid-19-data-problems" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved 2021-09-06 from</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">COVID-19 information fatigue? A case study of a German university website during two waves of the pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Skulmowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Standl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human behavior and emerging technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="350" to="356" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trust, sensemaking, and individual responses to organizational change</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sloyan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Steps toward an ecology of infrastructure: Design and access for large information spaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">Leigh</forename><surname>Star</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Ruhleder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information systems research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="134" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996. 1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kate</forename><surname>Starbird</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jim</forename><surname>Maddock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mania</forename><surname>Orand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peg</forename><surname>Achterman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert M</forename><surname>Mason</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.9776/14308</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.9776/14308" />
		<title level="m">Rumors, false fags, and digital vigilantes: Misinformation on twitter after the 2013 boston marathon bombing</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Who shared it? How Americans decide what news to trust on social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Sterret</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Malato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Benz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liz</forename><surname>Kantor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Trevor</forename><surname>Tompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Rosenstiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jef</forename><surname>Sonderman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kevin</forename><surname>Loker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Swanson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.9776/14308</idno>
		<idno>WP-2018-001</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Norc Working Paper Series</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Technical Report</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Examining Older Adults&apos; Information Exposure, Wellbeing, and Adherence to Protective Measures During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nurul</forename><surname>Suhaimi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nutchanon</forename><surname>Yongsatianchot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yixuan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anisa</forename><surname>Amiji</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shivani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stacy</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miso</forename><surname>Marsella</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacqueline</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Grifn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://arxiv.org/abs/2112.11215Accessed" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2021" to="2033" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Impact of rumors and misinformation on COVID-19 in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samia</forename><surname>Tasnim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hoimonty</forename><surname>Md Mahbub Hossain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mazumder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3961/jpmph.20.094</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3961/jpmph.20.094" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of preventive medicine and public health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">53</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="174" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">COVID-19: Navigating Uncertainties Together</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cell</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">181</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">209</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Cell Editorial Team</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.cell.2020.03.041</idno>
		<ptr target="https://covidtracking.comAccessed" />
		<title level="m">The COVID Tracking Project. 2021. The COVID Tracking Project</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2021" to="2029" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Latest Map and Case Count</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2021/us/covid-" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The New York Times. 2021. Coronavirus in the</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>U.S.</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/06/11/business/media/pulitzer-prizes.html" />
		<title level="m">The New York Times. 2021. Pulitzer Prizes Focus on Coverage of Pandemic and Law Enforceme</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2021" to="2028" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">People are more if they get their covid news from Facebook than from Fox News, data shows</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2021/08/18/cdc-data-delay-delta-variantTheWashingtonPost.2021" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Washington Post. 2021. How CDC data problems put the U.S. behind on the delta variant</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>from David R Thomas</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">July 27. 2021. 2006. 2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="246" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A general inductive approach for analyzing qualitative evaluation data</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Explaining diferential vulnerability to climate change: A social science review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kimberley</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dean</forename><surname>Hardy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heather</forename><surname>Lazrus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Mendez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Orlove</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Isabel</forename><surname>Rivera-Collazo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marcy</forename><surname>Timmons Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rockman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Benjamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Warner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Winthrop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/wcc.565</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/wcc.565" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews: Climate Change</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Retrieved 2021-08-12 from U.S. Department of Health &amp; Human Services. 2020. 2020 Percentage Poverty Tool</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/wcc.565</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2020-03-20/pdf/2020-05982" />
		<editor>pdf Tavish Vaidya, Daniel Votipka, Michelle L. Mazurek, and Micah Sherr</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2021. 2019</date>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of California San Francisco</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Does Being Verifed Make You More Credible? Account Verifcation&apos;s Efect on Tweet Credibility</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The paranoid style in American politics revisited: ideological asymmetry in conspiratorial thinking</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sander</forename><surname>Van Der Linden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Costas</forename><surname>Panagopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Flávio</forename><surname>Azevedo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290605.3300755</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Political Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="23" to="51" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Increased conspiracy beliefs among ethnic and Muslim minorities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jan-Willem</forename><surname>Van Prooijen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaap</forename><surname>Staman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">André Pm</forename><surname>Krouwel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1002/acp.3442</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1002/acp.3442" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Applied cognitive psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="661" to="667" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efective health risk communication about pandemic infuenza for vulnerable populations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elaine</forename><surname>Vaughan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Tinker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2105/AJPH.2009.162537</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2105/AJPH.2009.162537" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American journal of public health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">99</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="S324" to="S332" />
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009. 2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Good intentions are not enough: how informatics interventions can worsen inequality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Tifany</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><surname>Veinot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ancker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/jamia/ocy052</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/jamia/ocy052" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Medical Informatics Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1080" to="1088" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evaluating information: The cornerstone of civic online reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sam</forename><surname>Wineburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Mcgrew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/jamia/ocy052</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consuming information related to COVID-19 on social media among older adults and its association with anxiety, social trust in information, and COVID-safe behaviors: Cross-sectional telephone survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frankie</forename><surname>Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chun</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tianyin</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dara</forename><forename type="middle">Kiu</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Leung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Walker</forename><surname>Siu Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wai</forename><forename type="middle">Wai</forename><surname>Au</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Angie</forename><forename type="middle">Ky</forename><surname>Kwok</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gloria</forename><forename type="middle">Hoi</forename><surname>Shum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yan</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Terry Yat-Sang</forename><surname>Lum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2196/26570</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2196/26570" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">of Medical Internet Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Misinformation in social media: defnition, manipulation, and detection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liang</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fred</forename><surname>Morstatter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Kathleen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huan</forename><surname>Carley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3373464.3373475</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM SIGKDD Explorations Newsletter</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80" to="90" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring the impacts of media use and media trust on health behaviors during the COVID-19 pandemic in China</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yi</forename><surname>Wu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fei</forename><surname>Shen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of health psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1359105321995964" to="1359105321995964" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efects of Credibility Indicators on Social Media News Sharing Intent</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Waheeb</forename><surname>Yaqub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Otari</forename><surname>Kakhidze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Morgan</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Brockman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nasir</forename><surname>Memon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sameer</forename><surname>Patil</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Honolulu, HI, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI &apos;20)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the Use of Crisis Informatics Technology among Older Adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yixuan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nurul</forename><surname>Suhaimi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rana</forename><surname>Azghandi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mary</forename><forename type="middle">Amulya</forename><surname>Joseph</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miso</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacqueline</forename><surname>Grifn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3313831.3376213</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Honolulu, HI, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI &apos;20)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mapping the Landscape of COVID-19 Crisis Visualizations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yixuan</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yifan</forename><surname>Sun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lace</forename><surname>Padilla</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sumit</forename><surname>Barua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Enrico</forename><surname>Bertini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Parker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3313831.3376862</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Yokohama, Japan; New York, NY, USA, Article</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">608</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI &apos;21)</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
