<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Hiting Pause: How User Perceptions of Collaborative Playlists Evolved in the United States During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">So</forename><forename type="middle">Yeon</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Redmond</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Blair</forename><forename type="middle">2022</forename><surname>Kaneshiro</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University Stanford</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University Stanford</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University Stanford</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Stanford University Stanford</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Hiting Pause: How User Perceptions of Collaborative Playlists Evolved in the United States During the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3517604</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:00+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>• Human-centered computing → Human computer interaction (HCI)</term>
					<term>Interaction paradigms</term>
					<term>Collaborative interaction</term>
					<term>Collaborative and social computing theory, concepts and paradigms</term>
					<term>Collaborative content creation Collaborative playlist</term>
					<term>Shared playlist</term>
					<term>Shared music</term>
					<term>Collaboration</term>
					<term>Computer-mediated communication</term>
					<term>Computer-mediated collaboration</term>
					<term>Social connection</term>
					<term>Perception</term>
					<term>COVID-19</term>
					<term>Pandemic</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Through collaborative playlists (CPs), streaming platform users have co-curated music together for various purposes for over a decade. As the COVID-19 pandemic has transformed how people come together through technology and engage with music, CPs have also taken on new roles and value. To understand how CP usage and perception have evolved since the onset of COVID-19, we conducted a mixed-methods investigation of CPs in the United States. Survey results from primarily CP users (N=142) revealed that interest in and usage of CPs have mostly increased since the pandemic, and that the role of music in connecting with others is positively correlated with the perceived impact of COVID-19. Follow-up interviews (N=9) provided additional insights into changing perceptions and usage patterns of CPs during COVID-19; for instance, fewer collaborators per playlist refects users' greater focus on strengthening social connections and relationships. Taken together, fndings and design implications on digitally mediated cocuration further elucidate the necessity for social and collaborative experiences with music supported by CPs during COVID-19.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Music plays a signifcant social role in our lives. It serves as the backdrop to social events, helps people fnd common ground for belonging and acceptance, and acts as a medium that facilitates interpersonal relationships and connections <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">52,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b85">85]</ref>. We cultivate "social relatedness" as we listen to, share, and talk about music together <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">[77,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b85">85]</ref>. One means through which social aspects of music can be experienced today is through collaborative playlists (CPs). As a list of songs that multiple users create and modify over a digital platform, the CP is an instrument in today's age of streaming platforms through which multiple users can come together to co-curate music for social functions (e.g., parties), share music, learn about each other's music tastes, and strengthen social connections <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>.</p><p>The Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) has had a profound efect around the world. With "118,000 cases in 114 countries", the World Health Organization characterized COVID-19 as a pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23]</ref>, and the United States (US) subsequently released the Proclamation on Declaring a National Emergency Concerning the Novel Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Outbreak on March 13, 2020 <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[23]</ref>. Since then, people -including those in the United States (US)have adapted to major changes in everyday life such as shelter-inplace orders, remote work and learning, and economic challenges.</p><p>Music has become especially important amidst pandemic-related social impacts -including cancellations of cultural and sporting events; social distancing measures; and an increase in mental health issues, social isolation, and loneliness <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">53,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">57]</ref>. Music has helped listeners feel a sense of connection with others <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">[73,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">80]</ref>, and nostalgic listening has been used as a means to handle difcult emotions during isolating times <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26]</ref>. Consequently, the role and usage of CPs, which have facilitated virtual music sharing, co-curation, and social connection even before COVID-19, may have changed during the pandemic, as "only user-user social features" -of which CPs are an example -"enable connectedness" <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[42]</ref>. The importance of such features that facilitate social interactions and enhance interactivity between users through the medium of music has become more pronounced with the pandemic's challenging circumstances. Yet to the best of our knowledge there is no study that addresses how the impact of COVID-19 has infuenced perceptions around CPs or compares such perceptions before and during the pandemic. Thus, the question remains: How have perceptions and experiences changed around CPs due to the COVID-19 pandemic?</p><p>In this study we seek to better understand the role of CPs during COVID-19, and to assess the implications of such fndings on future streaming platform designs. To these ends, we conducted a twopart study using a mixed-methods approach. We frst conducted a survey to answer the following two research questions:</p><p>• RQ1: How has the COVID-19 pandemic infuenced people's perceptions of and engagement with CPs, as operationalized by interest and involvement, purpose for engaging, and outcomes? • RQ2: How has one's perceived impact of the COVID-19 pandemic afected outcomes of CP usage and perceptions of social connectedness?</p><p>Based on survey results, we designed and conducted follow-up interviews to answer additional research questions:</p><p>• RQ3: How has the COVID-19 pandemic infuenced people's usage of CPs? • RQ4: How have the role and usage of CPs changed for people during the pandemic, and why?</p><p>Combining survey and interview results, we derive insights on how the role of CPs has changed with COVID-19. We fnd that those who perceive greater impact from the pandemic have even greater appreciation for the function of CPs, among other positive outcomes of CP engagement. Compared to pre-pandemic results <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>, our survey results show more positive perceptions of outcomes from CP engagement, including making listening to music more enjoyable and being more open to new experiences in general. Our interviews highlight the role of CPs in reconnecting with others and evidence the causality of CP usage with a greater sense of connectedness with others through music. Synthesizing fndings with prior literature, we present design implications for platforms to enhance the CP's role in facilitating social connections and to enable a more fulflling user experience.</p><p>This study provides important insights into digitally mediated social music interactions in a time when music plays a particularly critical role in listeners' well being and social connection, while also adding to an emerging body of human-computer interaction (HCI) literature on CPs. This research area informs the understanding of collaborative experiences more broadly, as insights on collaborative curation of CPs are translatable to other computer-mediated cocreations. Furthermore, our design implications can inform services in diferent domains towards more user-user interactions and social experiences, as people yearn to connect through music and more.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED WORKS 2.1 Music's social role</head><p>Music is an integral part of social life. Many people discover, play, share, and discuss music with others to fulfll various social functions <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[32]</ref>. Through music, people express and manage "self-identity, interpersonal relationships, and mood in everyday life" <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b58">58,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">75]</ref>. People achieve self-image goals through music <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[5]</ref>, as they use it "to alter the self-image in order to achieve an ultimate goal of changing or enhancing long-term interactions and relationships with others" <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[85]</ref> (e.g., through taste performance <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">51]</ref>). Music also helps establish collective identity, whether it is from being part of a community of followers (e.g., of a musician or genre) and gaining acceptance or afliation <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[85]</ref>, or from experiences that bring "solidarity" <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">52,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b88">88]</ref>. Social groups "get to know themselves as groups [...] through cultural activity, through aesthetic judgment" of music <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[25]</ref>. Trocchia et al. found that people consumed music for a purpose that implicated yet another social nature: Socializing <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[85]</ref>. Used "to enhance present interactions with others", music helped set the atmosphere and prepare for events <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[85]</ref> (e.g., road trips <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[19]</ref>, parties <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[18]</ref>). Music was often utilized as a topic for discussion and "for interaction when socializing", helping to facilitate interpersonal relationships <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[52,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b85">85]</ref>. Sharing music thus supports goals of cultivating "social relatedness" as well as building and maintaining relationships <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">60,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">61,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">77,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b88">88]</ref>.</p><p>Music acts as "a boundary object: Both trafcked, and, thereby, the conduit of trafc" <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[59]</ref>, where boundary objects are "both plastic enough to adapt to local needs and the constraints of the several parties employing them, yet robust enough to maintain a common identity across sites" <ref type="bibr" target="#b79">[79]</ref>. Employed in various methods of sharing (e.g., sharing-through-peeping, posting links), music is a medium that enables opportunities and occasions "to chat more freely with each other" <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[49]</ref>. Gifting music also fosters "sociality and deepen[s] relationships between people" <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[49,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b88">88]</ref>. Receiving music from others has also been found to be important -appreciated as "treats" <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[30]</ref> and perceived more positively than music recommended by systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[41,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">47]</ref>. Moreover, an existing social relationship was found to be a signifcant factor in one's decision to listen to the recommended music <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[47]</ref>.</p><p>Beyond sharing music with others, the act of listening to music, even alone, can feel social <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">55,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">76,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b86">86]</ref>. As Schäfer and Eerola discuss, this is because music can be considered a "social surrogate" (a "temporary substitute" for social activity if "direct social interaction is not possible"); people listen to music as a way to "seek company", "comfort", and "shared experience" when direct social connection is not available <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">[76]</ref>. Further, music can elicit nostalgia, which can foster social connectedness <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">[76,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b86">86]</ref>. According to McFerran and Saarikallio, some teenagers relied on music to alter their state or mood, even referring to it as a "friend" <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[55]</ref>. Lee et al.'s work compares music listening to being in the company of an empathetic friend, as it provides comfort by validating negative emotions <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[46]</ref>. As music's social role is augmented by today's technologies, from streaming platforms (e.g., Spotify, SoundCloud) to fle-sharing cloud services (e.g., Dropbox) <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[48]</ref>, our investigation focuses on how one such digital social music feature -the CP -plays a role in the COVID-19 pandemic -a time when connecting with others is especially desired.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Music in the time of COVID-19</head><p>For many, the frst wave of the COVID-19 pandemic was a time of isolation unlike any they had ever experienced <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">78]</ref>. People in the US spent more time alone in their homes and less time with friends and family <ref type="bibr" target="#b78">[78]</ref>. As per prior work by Loades et al., social isolation and loneliness increase the risk of depression and possibly anxiety, and young people, particularly children and adolescents, are likely to experience high rates of depression and likely anxiety during and even after forced isolation <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[53]</ref>. Other recent studies have found that the social environment enforced by the COVID-19 pandemic across the world has facilitated positive reinforcement of social anxiety disorder <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">[57]</ref> and "signifcantly higher than normal" rates of loneliness <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref>.</p><p>With this onset of isolation and increase in social stress, some people turned to music to cope <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">80,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b92">92]</ref>. In a 2021 UKbased study, Gibbs and Egermann uncovered a high frequency (most at least once a week) of nostalgic listening among pandemicinfuenced participants, i.e., listening to music that "evokes feelings of nostalgia through reminders of certain periods of life, places, or people" <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26]</ref>. Moreover, they found that listening to nostalgic music as a means to handle difcult emotions can have a positive impact on well being <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26]</ref>. A 2020 Spanish study analyzing the impact of the pandemic on music activity similarly found that music kept participants company and helped them relax, improve their mood, and "escape" during the pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref>. The study declares diferent practices and benefts of music among diferent demographics and personal situations, but ultimately suggests that music was very valuable in improving participants' social and mental well being during lockdown <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[9]</ref>.</p><p>Recent work by Hurwitz and Krumhansl studied how "listening niches" -referring to "the contexts in which people listen to music including what music they are listening to, with whom, when, where, and with what media" -changed among college students during the pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37]</ref>. Importantly, compared to pre-pandemic, participants reported listening to more music both in general and on Spotify during the pandemic, and a listening pattern emerged among participants as the pandemic progressed -of listening to music mostly with family, then mostly with signifcant others, then fnally with friends and roommates as they returned to school <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37]</ref>. Similar pandemic-focused work by Krause et al. found a positive association between music listening and life satisfaction juxtaposed with fndings of a negative association between TV, videos, and movies and life satisfaction during early stages of the pandemic among college students <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[43]</ref>. This aligns with the results of Schäfer and Eerola's research that while music tends to evoke feelings of nostalgia in listeners and remind them of people or moments in their life, TV watching and fction reading do not <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">[76]</ref>. These results highlight music's benefts as a unique coping medium during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>Further, research on music consumption during the pandemic within the family demographic evidenced that music activity was high for both parents and children; parents used music for both emotion regulation and to connect socially with their children during the pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">[80]</ref>. This research reinforces music's role as an agent for "building and maintaining [relationships] during a period of uncertainty and change" <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">[80]</ref> and indicates that music is an efective tool and outlet for multiple age groups, not just adolescents and young adults. Another recent study found that some music patrons turned to virtually streamed concerts as a venue to enjoy music with others <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">[87]</ref>. Vandenberg et al. identifed that these patrons enjoyed attending virtual live music events because it reinstated old positive feelings of attending in-person music events and instilled new social rituals and bonding opportunities <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">[87]</ref>.</p><p>COVID-19 has infuenced several facets of HCI including work <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[13]</ref>, education <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[64]</ref>, healthcare <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[14]</ref>, entertainment <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">[63]</ref>, creative practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[10]</ref>, and perspectives of social technologies <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[28]</ref>. Much prior research in the feld of music focuses on the pandemic's resultant increase of social isolation and loneliness, or on music listening's ability to improve well being and mental health during times of isolation. Thus, research on technologies that connect people, especially those that facilitate interactions and collaborations with others, is timely. This motivated us to better understand CPswhich constitute a specifc use case of digitally mediated social behaviors -and people's perceptions and experiences with them to contribute meaningful insights to the evolving feld of HCI during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Personal and collaborative playlists</head><p>Technological advances ofering increased portability of music playback systems and the ability for listeners to curate custom music collections have also been utilized with social aims. Since portable listening became accessible <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[24]</ref>, people have curated collections of music for themselves and for others, from mixtapes and burnt CDs to playlists -collections of songs curated on streaming platforms <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref>. It was not uncommon for people to spend hours building, and listening to, the "perfect" playlist or mixtape with themes for diferent moods, events, places, and even times of day <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[8]</ref>.</p><p>While playlists were initially developed to enable individual listeners to curate songs tailored to their personal tastes, some streaming platforms now also enable users to curate a playlist with others <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">65,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">68]</ref>. Collaborative playlists (CPs, sometimes called "shared playlists") may thus be considered mixtapes and CDs of today while also ofering additional afordances of music streaming platforms, including vast catalogs of songs <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[32]</ref>, the ability to continually update the playlist over time <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref>, and the ability to collaborate virtually over great distances. Liu and Reimer's early prototype study suggested that this medium promotes both social benefts (e.g., relationship building) and personal benefts (e.g., self-expression) <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[52]</ref>. Controlled experiments revealed that users have diferences in perceiving song-and playlist-level ownership that lead to divergence of comfort in interacting with CPs <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[69]</ref> and are impacted diferentially by positive versus negative judgments made by (fake) collaborators <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[4]</ref>.</p><p>Recent investigations of real-world CPs on commercial streaming platforms have highlighted various aspects of their usage. Park et al.'s seminal study of CP usage <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref> introduced the CP Framework, which includes three categories of purposes for engaging with CPs: Purposes related to content, consumption setting, or experience of curation (Practical); to discovery of music or of collaborators' tastes (Cognitive); and to sharing and bonding with others (Social). These CP purposes are known to evolve over time, similar to personal playlists <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">65,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">66]</ref>. CP research in the feld of computer-supported cooperative work has found that co-curation can infuence perceptions of music: Users reported being more receptive to songs outside of their taste and even feeling compelled to listen to songs they dislike when said songs are shared through CPs <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[66]</ref>. Despite the merits of CPs, research has also highlighted a tension between the desire for an engaged group of collaborators and the difculty of quality control when multiple users edit a playlist <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[66,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">67]</ref>.</p><p>As noted in previous investigations of successful CP collaborations <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[66]</ref>, playlist co-curation can be interpreted in the broader HCI context of collaborative systems -implicating such topics as collective content <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[62]</ref>, ownership <ref type="bibr" target="#b83">[83]</ref>, and social loafng <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref>. Its unique aspects of consumption patterns and creative collaboration amidst social relationships further warrant CPs separate investigation <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[66]</ref>. In particular, given prior fndings that underscore the CP's role in social connection through music <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>, we wished to understand whether this role would be more important during times of social distancing and isolation compared to past results. Moreover, we sought to understand how perceptions of the pandemic would infuence how people regard CPs in terms of their role in connecting with others as well as the outcomes and benefts from CP engagement.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHOD</head><p>This study was approved by Stanford University's Institutional Review Board, and all participants gave informed consent prior to participating. Eligibility requirements were as follows: 18 years of age or older, fuent in English, living in the United States, and using music streaming services (usage of CPs was not a requirement).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Survey Study</head><p>3.1.1 Survey Participants. Survey participants were recruited via word-of-mouth, direct emails, listservs, and social media. After removal of irrelevant or duplicate responses ( § 3.1.3), a total of N = 142 verifed responses were obtained. Participants averaged 30.7 years (SD = 10.5) in age, 49% were female, 56% had a Bachelor's degree, and participants' occupations ranged from "occupational therapist aide" to "research assistant". On a 5-point ordinal scale ranging from "none at all" to "a great deal", 73.2% of survey respondents (N = 104) felt that their in-person activities had been afected by the COVID-19 pandemic by "a lot" or more ("a little" N = 11, "a moderate amount" N = 27, "a lot" N = 66, and "a great deal" N = 38); no one selected "none at all". 94% of the responses (N = 134) were from CP users; the remaining 6% (N = 8) were non-users who were interested in engaging in CPs. Of the users, 25% engaged in CPs using Spotify; users also purportedly engaged in CPs using Amazon Music (19%), Apple Music (18%), and YouTube Music (15%). Upon completion of survey data collection from March to August of 2021, 10% of survey participants were given a $10 Amazon gift card via a rafe.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.2">Survey Design.</head><p>As we aimed to explore the ramifcations of COVID-19 on people's music experiences and engagement with CPs, we leveraged prior published research on CPs. Specifcally, we designed a questionnaire expanding upon questions used previously by Park et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref> to probe perceived and experienced purposes of engaging in CPs, as well as those about broader music experiences during the pandemic in general. To make clear to participants what was meant by "the pandemic", we provided a statement at the beginning of the survey that this "refers to the time since the onset of COVID-19 stay-at-home orders and social distancing measures, specifcally since March 13, 2020, when a National Emergency was declared in the United States." Survey questions and sub-questions analyzed in this manuscript, and their relations to questions used by Park et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>, are detailed in Table <ref type="table">1</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.3">Analysis of Survey Data.</head><p>The researchers frst manually sorted through all responses and eliminated participants who gave irrelevant responses to two or more questions, or gave clear duplicate responses.</p><p>Q1 and Q7 involved open-ended text responses. For perceived or experienced CP purposes (Q1), we used a deductive method of applying the fve established CP Framework categories <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>. Two researchers independently coded text responses according to the procedure used by Park et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>, assigning category membership for purposes (Practical, Cognitive, Social) and connotations (Utility, Orientation). Each text response could be assigned to up to fve categories (Cohen's κ = 0.953). For responses with diverging codes, coders attempted to reach consensus through discussion <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[35]</ref>. When this was not successful, a third researcher was consulted and responses were coded by majority vote (nine instances). For reports on the role music played for participants during COVID-19 (Q7), we used an inductive approach of thematic analysis. Two researchers reviewed the responses and derived codes through open coding. They then looked for connections between the codes (axial coding) and fnalized the themes through discussion <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[54,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">84]</ref>. Two researchers coded the responses independently (Cohen's κ = 0.965); each response could implicate multiple categories. As with Q1, coders discussed diverging codes to reach consensus, then consulted a third researcher to break the tie (eight instances).</p><p>For Q1, we compared membership of each CP Framework category across the present sample and the previous sample of Park et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>. As 94% of the present sample were CP users, we conducted all across-sample analyses using only the responses from CP users. We calculated chi-square tests on a per-category basis (fve categories total); each test involved a 2×2 contingency table containing counts of responses along dimensions of sample (previous study sample <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref> or present sample) and category membership (yes or no). We corrected for multiple comparisons using False Discovery Rate (FDR).</p><p>Responses to Q2-Q6 involved ordinal responses. For Q3 and Q4, we report median results and percentages of responses at each response level. For Q2 and Q5 (i.e., agreement with statements about CP outcomes and social connection through music), prepandemic response data <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref> were compared with present data. As done in Q1, across-sample comparisons involved responses from CP users only; we performed independent-samples comparisons for responses to each statement using two-sided Wilcoxon Rank Sum tests. 1 We used FDR to correct for multiple comparisons (Q2: Nine comparisons; Q5: Four comparisons). For Q2-Q5, we also investigated whether responses varied signifcantly according to the extent to which participants' in person activities were reportedly afected by COVID-19 (Q6; § 3.1.1). We stratifed the participants according to reported impact by COVID-19 ("a little", "a moderate amount", "a lot", "a great deal"). Then we conducted Kruskal-Wallis tests to determine whether each stratifed sample refected the same distribution of ordinal responses and applied FDR correction. For each test, we used the full sample of those who answered the questions (Q2, Q5: U and N i ; Q3, Q4: U only). 1 One statement in Q2 was split into two statements for the current study (also in Table <ref type="table">1</ref>); these statements were excluded from across-sample comparisons. Moreover, Q5 was adapted slightly from that used by Park et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref> to understand the impact of the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>Table <ref type="table">1</ref>: Survey questions with response type and which respondents received each question. For ordinal responses, the number of points is indicated in parentheses (e.g., 5-point scale as ( <ref type="formula" target="#formula_0">5</ref>)). Respondents are indicated as U (CP users, N = 134), N i (interested non-users, N = 8), and N n (non-interested non-users, N = 0). History of questions Q1, Q2, and Q5 is shown below each question starting with an asterisk; Q3, Q4, Q6, and Q7 are new questions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Question</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Response type Respondents</head><p>Q1: What purpose(s) might/does a collaborative playlist serve for you? Open-ended text U , N i *Same as Q1 from Park et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref> Q2: Please select the option that best represents the following statement: Collaborative playlist(s) could/have...</p><p>-diversify/diversifed my music library.</p><p>-increase/increased ways in which I discover music.</p><p>-require/required less of my time and efort to discover music that matches my taste.</p><p>-require/required less of my time and efort to discover completely new music.</p><p>-require/required less of my time and efort to manage music.</p><p>-require/required less of my efort to enjoy music.</p><p>-make/made listening to music more enjoyable.</p><p>-change/changed the music that I listen to.</p><p>-positively infuence/infuenced my music taste.</p><p>-make/made me appreciate music platforms with collaborative playlists more.</p><p>-make/made me more open to new experiences in general.</p><p>Ordinal <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(5)</ref> "Strongly agree" to "Strongly disagree"</p><p>U , N i *Adapted from Q2 from Park et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>. One statement from the previous study was modifed to capture more nuance: "Required less of my time and efort to discover music" has been separated into Questions ( <ref type="formula">2</ref>) and ( <ref type="formula">3</ref>) above.</p><p>Q3: Has your level of interest in collaborative playlists changed due to the COVID-19 pandemic?</p><p>Ordinal</p><p>"Increased a great deal" to "Decreased a great deal" U Q4: Has your level of involvement in collaborative playlists changed due to the COVID-19 pandemic?</p><p>Ordinal</p><p>"Increased a great deal" to "Decreased a great deal" U Q5: Please select the option that best represents your opinion on the following statements during the COVID-19 pandemic.</p><p>-In general, connecting with others through music has declined.</p><p>-In general, music has helped people connect with others.</p><p>-In my case, personally, connecting with others through music has declined.</p><p>-In my case, personally, music has helped people connect with others.</p><p>Ordinal <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(5)</ref> "Strongly agree" to "Strongly disagree" U , N i *Adapted version of Q3 from Park et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref> for the context of COVID-19.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Q6: To what extent have your in-person activities been afected by the COVID-19 pandemic?</head><p>Ordinal</p><p>"A great deal" to "None at all" U , N i Q7: What role is music playing for you during this COVID-19 pandemic?</p><formula xml:id="formula_3">Open-ended text U , N i , N n 3.2 Interview Study 3.2.1 Interview Participants.</formula><p>Participants who completed the survey subsequently had the option to indicate their interest in participating in future CP research. From these participants, who provided their contact information, we recruited N = 9 participants after survey completion. All but one was a CP user -a similar proportion of users to the usable survey responses. Of the eight interviewees who were CP users, two started using CPs during the pandemic.</p><p>Demographic details on interviewees are presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">2</ref>. The interviews were conducted in August 2021 over videoconferencing by two researchers, and each interview took 35-50 minutes upon obtaining participant consent. Each interview participant was compensated with a $20 Amazon gift card.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.2">Interview Design.</head><p>Based on the survey results, in our interviews we aimed to better understand the nuances of changing roles and perceptions of CPs during COVID-19. Moreover, as many text responses in the survey alluded to broader benefts of music beyond CPs, we aimed to disambiguate this general role of music from that of CPs specifcally. For these, we devised a core set of questions to frame our semi-structured interviews. We chose the semi-structured interview format because it is "well suited for the exploration of the perceptions and opinions of respondents [...] and enable probing for more information and clarifcation of answers" <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[3]</ref>. As we could not map individual interviewees to anonymized survey results, we asked interviewees how they were impacted by the pandemic, followed by CP-specifc questions. Core questions in our semi-structured interviews were as follows: (1) "Have your feelings around CPs changed with the pandemic, and if so, how?" (2) "Did your usage pattern of CPs change with the pandemic, and if so, how?" (3) "What role did the CP serve for you and your friends during the pandemic?" (4) "Can you say a little more about the role of music as a whole in your life compared to the feeling of engaging in CPs specifcally?"</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.3">Analysis of Interview Data.</head><p>Upon completion of all nine interviews, the researchers discussed answers to these main questions and identifed other salient points that emerged during the interviews. Relevant interview quotes were extracted from automated transcriptions and confrmed for accuracy by the researchers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">RESULTS</head><p>We present results with subsections dedicated to each research question. RQ1 and RQ2, which probe the infuence of COVID-19 and its impact on CP engagement, are addressed using survey results. RQ3 and RQ4, which further investigate usage of CPs and their changed role in light of the pandemic, are addressed with fndings from the interviews. Anonymized survey and interview quotes are labelled with 'S' (for 'survey') followed by a three-digit number (e.g., S006), and 'P' followed by a one-digit number (e.g., P3), respectively.  <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>, which are noted in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">3</ref>. All three purposes were evenly mentioned in the present sample: Practical (40%), Cognitive (40%), and Social (41%). Practical purposes included crafting a playlist for social events (e.g., "virtual party" (S006)) and existing relationships ("soundtrack for group social events" (S038)), around a theme ("it's fun to pick a genre or vibe" (S005)), and for its intrinsic enjoyment ("it provides a collective efort" (S057)). Cognitive purposes included discovering others' tastese.g., help "get to know my friend's music taste" (S135) -as well as new music and artists; for instance "learn about other artists I may like by things others add to the list" (S044). Social purposes included sharing of music with others and connecting, e.g., "share music with others, create a shared memory" (S042). Connotations of Utility (18%) and Orientation (38%) were also mentioned. Utility responses noted that CPs could increase convenience or efciency or decrease user efort, e.g., "it is more convenient to listen to music and share music with more people" (S037) and "reduce time to fnd music you like" (S119). Responses that explicitly mentioned a beneft to the participant (e.g., "help me listen to music efectively" (S084)) or others (e.g., "making a compilation of songs for others to listen [to]" (S050)) received Orientation codings. A number of responses mentioned multiple categories, as shown in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">3</ref>. Three responses did not ft any framework category: "Relieve the boredom of life" (S078), "relax and relieve stress" (S095), and "let's reduce the pressure a little bit" (S134).   <ref type="table">1</ref>), we found the median response to all statements was "somewhat agree".</p><p>Of nine comparisons with a pre-pandemic sample <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>, present agreement with statements of "required less of my time and efort to manage music", "required less of my efort to enjoy music", and "made me more open to new experiences in general" has increased. Moreover, while median agreement with other statements remained the same, the distribution has shifted towards greater agreement for some, including "made listening to music more enjoyable". Quantitative comparisons of pre-and during-pandemic user responses using Wilcoxon Rank Sum tests revealed statistically signifcant diferences in outcomes with respect to statements of "required less of my efort to enjoy music" (W = 5968.5, p F DR &lt; 0.05), "made listening to music more enjoyable" (W = 6055.5, p F DR &lt; 0.001), "changed the music that I listen to" (W = 5678.5, p F DR &lt; 0.05), "made me appreciate music platforms with CPs more" (W = 5711, p F DR &lt; 0.05), and "made me more open to new experiences in general" (W = 6626, p F DR &lt; 0.001). For all of these statements, agreement was higher in the present sample.</p><p>4.1.5 Perceived social connection through music declined during COVID-19. Participants reported agreement with statements about music helping to foster social connections (in Table <ref type="table">1</ref>) "during the COVID-19 pandemic". For both statements of "connecting with others through music has declined", the median response was "Neither agree nor disagree"; for both statements of "music has helped people connect with others", the median response was "Slightly agree". We compared these responses to CP users' perceptions of music's role in social connectedness prior to the pandemic -i.e., "over the past 5 years" reported by Park et al. in 2019 <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>. Results from Wilcoxon Rank Sum tests indicated that the two statements of "connecting with others through music has declined" difered significantly between samples, both in general (W = 6269, p F DR &lt; 0.001) and personally (W = 7101, p F DR &lt; 0.001); in both cases the present sample agreed more with these statements. For statements that "music has helped people connect with others", only general perceptions difered signifcantly across samples (W = 3932, p F DR &lt; 0.05), with higher agreement pre-pandemic; perceptions that music personally helped connect did not difer signifcantly (W = 4271, p F DR &gt; 0.1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4.1.6</head><p>Music relieves pressure and fulfills other roles during COVID-19. In Q7, participants provided free-text reports on the more general role of music during the pandemic. Thematic analysis led to six categories that characterized all the responses. Of these, the most-reported role of music during COVID-19 was one of "relieving pressure" (43% of responses), helping people to "calm" down, "soothe", and "relax". Music was also a "friend" to many (32%), as it provided "entertainment" and a way to "pass the time". Related to relieving pressure, music helped participants "keep sanity", "escape" from reality, and "distract" themselves (18%). Facilitating connection was implicated often (17%). Here we found that music served as a way to "connect" and "communicate" with others (e.g., "discussions"), as well as "bringing people together" leading to a sense of "community". Furthermore, music uplifted participants (15%), enabling them to feel "happy", "motivated", and "productive". Finally, music was a channel for "nostalgia" (4%), "reminding [participants] of when times were easier" and "bring[ing them] back to pre-pandemic memories".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Efects of perceived impact of COVID-19 on CP perceptions and engagement (RQ2)</head><p>The pandemic has afected diferent people in diferent ways; we surmised that aspects of CP perception and usage would vary according to this perceived impact. Interest and involvement in CPs did not vary signifcantly according to perceived impact of the pandemic (Kruskal-Wallis test, both p F DR &gt; 0.1). However, Fig. <ref type="figure">1A</ref> suggests that median agreement with certain CP outcomes did difer: Agreement with "positively infuenced my music taste" increased with perception of greater pandemic impact, and those afected "a great deal" by the pandemic agreed most that CP usage "made music listening more enjoyable" and "made me appreciate music platforms with CPs more". Quantitatively, we found only a marginally signifcant diference in agreement across impact groups for "positively infuenced my music taste" (p F DR &lt; 0.1). We also investigated whether the level of agreement varied according to the extent to which a participant felt afected by the pandemic (Fig. <ref type="figure">1B</ref>). This proved to be the case for some but not all questions: Kruskal-Wallis tests indicated that participants' agreement to statements that "music has helped to connect with others" -"personally" (χ 2 = 22.32, p F DR &lt; 0.001) and "in general" (χ 2 = 10.77, p F DR &lt; 0.05) -varied signifcantly according to how much they reported being impacted by the pandemic. However, agreement to statements that "connecting with others through music has declined" did not difer signifcantly by group (χ 2 ≤ 2.5, p F DR &gt; 0.1).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Infuence of COVID-19 pandemic on usage of CPs (RQ3)</head><p>4.3.1 CP collaborator groups have changed. In semi-structured interviews following the survey, we found that motives for CP creation, and thus CP collaborators, changed. Prior to COVID-19, inperson CPs were "really easy and fun" (P6) and were usually geared around events all collaborators would attend, such as parties where hours of music and certain vibes were needed. For this reason, P6's pre-pandemic CPs were often curated by 10 or more collaborators. However, during COVID-19, P6 usually collaborated with only two to three others, as did P8, who said that "bigger collaborative playlists went away". Collaborating in this manner led to reconnecting in a more personal way, as P6 was able to see not only "what people are listening to" but also "how they're feeling and where they're at [...] without necessarily having to talk about it". In doing so, songs were curated less for general feel-good events and more around "specifc moods and emotions" (P6). P8 often made CPs while texting or on Zoom with someone one-on-one during the pandemic ("the entire process is collaborative and curated from top-to-bottom with another person"), and this led to "a more meaningful connection". P4 similarly created a CP with just six to seven friends from high school during the pandemic, which felt more intimate than those she had created before COVID-19; she had created huge CPs with sorority mates before COVID-19 (she guessed there were "upwards of 100" collaborators on one such CP, and never listened to that playlist on her own).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">CP usage paterns changed in diverse ways.</head><p>Regarding the pre-existing use case of CPs being predominantly for in-person social events, P9 did not engage in CPs during the pandemic as much as they used to ("tends to be at a party, in-person [thing]").</p><p>Though P9 had been an avid music sharer since they were youngburning collaborative CDs in middle school, sharing iTunes libraries with classmates, and creating thematic CPs in college using Spotify -they felt that the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic had a "kind of sadness", which did not readily translate to engaging with CPs; to them, CPs were previously marked by more celebratory music and started from in-person conversations. While they had not considered CPs as "a social strategy", they thought it was a "good idea" to do so during the pandemic, and felt that CPs were "powerful and fun". However, P1 engaged diferently with CPs: A frst thing he did to "remind people I still exist" was to tweet "like this tweet if you want a playlist"; this led P1 to create 20 playlists, which he described as being both a blessing and a curse. P1 recalled that "people craved connection at the time" and he "enjoyed doing this" for them, and consequently curated CPs during the pandemic "less frequently yet much more intensely" than before. Building CPs included spending time "reordering the playlist, to make sure it was a cohesive experience" and making CP cover art to provide "a whole medium experience, not just the music". P3's engagement with CPs increased; she felt that CPs were a "regular part of my life", while before she had used them to a limited extent, primarily for family road trips. P8 also surmised that her CP engagement increased as she more frequently used Spotify. P5 felt that their personal usage pattern did not change; P6 listened to CPs a couple times, but especially less in the six months leading up to the interview.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.3">CP content, and expectations thereof, evolved during COVID-19.</head><p>The kind of music shared through CPs also changed due to the pandemic, hand-in-hand with the shift in the role of CPs. P6's contributions to CPs during the pandemic consisted "more of the actual stuf I'm listening to at the time", as opposed to before when they were "trying to create something that other people would really like" or would enjoy hearing at a party. This led P6 to share more of themselves, which ultimately made CPs feel "more personal during the pandemic because of the way that we're interacting with them". We found that this resulted in expectations and perceptions of CPs being at odds with those of personal playlists. As a tool for connecting more with others, participants were more tolerant of the random ordering and lack of coherence of CPs than they would be of their own personal playlists. P9, who usually had "a hard stop" for self-curated playlists with 10-15 songs put in a specifc order such that the playlists had a beginning and end, had diferent expectations for their "quarantine playlists" with others; they felt that the </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A little (N=11)</head><p>A lot (N=66)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A great deal (N=38)</head><p>A Collaborative playlist(s) could/have...</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>B Role of music in connecting with others</head><p>A moderate amount</p><formula xml:id="formula_4">(N=27)</formula><p>Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>: Boxplots of (A) projected and actual outcomes of CP usage (i.e., agreement with the statements "Collaborative playlist(s) could/have..." followed by Q2a-Q2j) by how much participants perceived to be afected by the pandemic (Q2) and (B) perceived role of music in connecting with others (i.e., agreement with the statements presented) by how much participants reported being afected by the pandemic (Q5). Grouping (as indicated by the colors) depends on the extent to which in-person activities have been afected by the COVID-19 pandemic (Q6). Medians are shown by thick lines and the dots represent outliers.</p><p>CPs curated during the COVID-19 pandemic were "appropriately to be", efectively refecting the uncertainty of the pandemic. They nebulous for a time that people don't know how long they're going were happy to have these CPs be "brain dumps" with no specifc ordering or genre and would shufe them, whereas they would not shufe their own monthly playlists. P6 also felt that "I don't think there's anything wrong with it being a mess", especially as they "don't often listen to playlists in order or all the way through it, especially collaborative ones". For them, it was simply "nice to just have a record of 'these are the songs that we like and that we have added during this time' ". P4 resorted to a diferent way of fnding order with CPs -not the music contained within the CPs but how they managed the CPs together as a whole. They created folders and would "drag all my collaborative playlists into one folder and then put the folder at the bottom" so that they could "maintain the vibe of my Spotify and I still get the playlist". To understand the role of CPs in a more nuanced way than CP purposes, we asked interviewees what role the CP, and music more broadly, played in their lives during COVID-19. We found that perceptions of CPs changed greatly, and that CPs came to play a role in facilitating connections for all interviewees who used them. P4, for one, did not desire to participate in CPs prior to the pandemic because they were "very picky" about their music, preferred "very organized and very themed" playlists, and thought CPs "would take away from the music I actually wanted to listen to". However, they realized through engaging in CPs through the pandemic "the beneft of it"; that CPs "helped foster sense of connection and unity between me and my friends and it gave us a way to still feel like we were together and sharing something together even though we weren't seeing each other in-person". The role of CPs morphed towards one of connection for P6 as well: Before the pandemic, the CP was "not really about reconnecting" but rather "having fun and sharing music together, and it wasn't anything super deep". P6 now saw CPs as a "way to share how we're feeling and what we were experiencing at the time when we couldn't really talk to each other especially during the pandemic and also was a way to do nice things for each other". Similarly, P1 also felt that the CPs played a role in keeping up with others and expressed that his "experience throughout COVID would have been very diferent without [CPs]", particularly the people with whom he was able to stay connected. P1 was already an extreme CP user prior to the pandemic (he "spread [CPs] like a wildfre" once he found out about them), but while mostly using CPs for events prior to the pandemic, he now saw it as a way to bond and hoped to continue using CPs in this way. Finally, P1 felt that "CPs are a great way for music to be more social compared to listening to music on your own". P7, who had never engaged in CPs prior to the pandemic, stated that the CP was "defnitely a great way to connect with each other"; he felt that the CP gave a "morale boost" to collaborators as they got to be more intimate with each other through the playlist. P9 felt that CPs were not only "another way to connect with someone far away" but also "another group activity in a time when we were looking for lots of group activities that didn't involve being in-person" in addition to playing games together online or cooking via Zoom, and additionally felt that "it was more important to engage in a social activity because it was higher stakes for everyone, since you weren't talking as much or seeing each other". This feeling compelled them to more care in choosing songs and to contribute more promptly. P3 also had a positive shift in their perception of CPs with the pandemic. Prior to COVID-19, P3 saw CPs as a form of entertainment, but now she perceives a substantial beneft from CP engagement. Through CPs, she was able to discover what music her kids think are "important or cool", which has sparked conversations that allow her to feel more in touch with their everyday lives, positively contributing to their relationship. She also expressed that, in addition to CPs being a bonding activity, they also reduce family tension on long car rides, which became a more common activity for her family during the pandemic. However, P2, a non-user, felt that their perceptions of the CPs did not change as much although she saw the potential of it, especially for "younger people".</p><p>Finally, for some, usage of CPs served as a means for reminiscing about time spent with friends; P1 felt the CP was a tool for "harvesting nostalgia to keep friendships alive" and a good way of "reminiscing" on both happy and hard memories brought up by songs in the CPs. P4 similarly mentioned that they "would listen to [the CP] a lot, especially if I was missing my friends or I was thinking about them", and further recounted that "during the pandemic [I] was around my high school and a lot of places [where] I used to hang out with my friends [...] it would put me in that nostalgic sentimental mood [...] [When] driving around or going to places that I used to go to with my friends, I would put on the playlist. " 4.4.2 CPs have supported music sharing and discovery. Interviewees also touched on Cognitive purposes from the CP Framework: P5 noted that collaborative curation was a way to discover new music when live music was not accessible during COVID-19. They related this to being "dragged along" to concerts of friends' favorite bands -not an option in the pandemic, but something that could be replicated to some extent with CPs. CPs have further enabled users to share and discover music during the pandemic by providing "a fun experience to see everybody's music tastes coming together" (P4) and a "cool <ref type="bibr">[way]</ref> to see what people are listening to" (P6). P5 merely thought of CPs as "a cool thing" but now sees them as "much more important" in facilitating music sharing; it was "hard to keep track of new releases during the virtual pandemic", but the CP aforded "a nice way to [...] stay up to date". It further enabled "a more cohesive experience" than sending individual song links via text, as CPs created a more organized and easy-to-navigate "continuous streamlined place", which gave a feeling of continuity that was easier "to go of of". P7 also gained a "deeper understanding" of their collaborators, learning about others' music tastes by discussing the music they added to the CP; they also learned about more music in general. Similar sentiments were expressed by P2 (non-user); they felt that CPs could help to "support each other" as well as fnd new music, which they listened to more of as a result of the pandemic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.3">CPs do not fully replace in-person experiences of music.</head><p>The changing role of CPs during the pandemic impacted not only curation but also listening. Some participants felt they were missing out on bonding opportunities aforded by listening to CPs with collaborators in person in a physical space like a dorm room. P1 and P8 reminisced on salient experiences listening to CPs with the friends they made them with -experiences they could not easily replicate during COVID-19. P8 shared one such memory of relaxing at a cofee shop after "a bad breakup" when her good friend, the barista, played a CP they had built together over the cofee shop's speakers to make her feel better. This experience was so moving that P8 started "crying at [her] table in the cafe". P1 and P8 both mentioned they missed these personal, social in-person listening experiences, and no interviewees mentioned such visceral listening experiences with CPs during COVID-19. P6 felt that CPs fail to forge new connections in the way that playing music has: "One of the reasons music has been really important to me is [that] through playing music I've met a lot of my best friends [...] but a collaborative playlist I don't feel really does that [...] Especially during the pandemic, it's been more of way to just keep in touch". 4.4.4 CPs and music have played an important role during COVID-19. The interviews provided both confrmatory and novel insights into the role of music during COVID-19. Emergent themes from the free-text responses were confrmed by the interviewees: P1 noted that "music on its own was a nice way to escape", P3 reported "I love music, silence is not my friend", and P7 described how music could evoke "nostalgia" and "all sorts of feelings that resonate with me". Entertainment and escape aspects of CPs also implicate opportunities for connection and discussion: P5 reports that at frst, she and her brother intended their playlist to be casual and enjoyable, almost as background music; yet she did not see this as separate or distinct from a deeper conversation around the music. The possibility of connection was also reported by P4, viewed music as a "the one thing that tends to always connect people, so I think having collaborative playlists allowed people to feel connected remotely [...] and it creates a sense of unity that was really important during the pandemic". P4 further connected the social to their personal passion for music: "Music is one of the most important parts of my life [...] I naturally connect to people through music, so I think collaborative playlists were a natural way to take a big passion of mine and extend it the people I care It's been a way to support of music in my life". Interviews also highlighted new that could during the P5, for whom is a "huge part of my life", viewed it as "an outlet to understand my own culture" and more broadly to understand culture from diferent perspectives. Music curation as a creative process was also noted by P8, who viewed "CPs as CREATING music vs listening to music as CONSUMING music". Finally, playlist curation in was described as "a large part of my engagement with music" by P9, who uses them as "memory tool [...] organizing songs is cathartic for me".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">DISCUSSION</head><p>Recent research documents the benefcial role of music during COVID-19 -for entertainment, mood regulation, social connection, and reminiscence. CPs, which ofer a means to curate and share music with others in times of social distancing, have transformed in value and during COVID-19. Specifcally, results evidence increased involvement ( § 4.  <ref type="bibr">[ed]</ref> the potential value in examining music also as a social good" <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[42]</ref>. Our work shows that the pandemic has increased the importance of CPs as an efective instrument that mediates music "as a social good". As the roles of music and CPs change, user needs and purposes for engaging with CPs also continue to evolve. Hence, understanding and designing CPs for fulflling user experiences ought to be continuous endeavors that may ultimately help both users and service providers. We interpret our fndings in relation to past research and derive design implications.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Inclusion of more social functionalities can amplify CP's role in connecting with others</head><p>Sharing and listening to music with others is a known social act. Krastel et al. found that people gain social connection through online music sites, but only through features that aford user-user interaction, such as CPs <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[42]</ref>. The importance of facilitating such connections using CPs when other forms of social interaction are not possible -and when users already gravitate towards music to boost morale during challenging, isolated times -has also been highlighted <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[11]</ref>. In both our survey and interview results, we similarly found that CPs have been primarily used to connect with others during the pandemic. Importantly, where previous work reported a correlation between CP usage and higher social connection <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>, our interview results evidence a causal relationship. Interviewees used CPs mainly to reconnect with others in times of physical distancing, to show how they were feeling and to harvest nostalgia, as frequently found by Gibbs and Egermann <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26]</ref>.</p><p>Participants notably expressed that CPs became "important" rather than simply "cool", and that these led them to feel more connected with others; 40% of survey participants also noted Social purposes for engaging with CPs. Consistent with Krause et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[43]</ref>, the more CP users felt their in-person activities were afected by the pandemic, the more they felt that music helped to connect with others (Fig. <ref type="figure">1B</ref>). Recent studies have similarly confrmed that music, in general, during the pandemic has been highly efcient in regulating mood and to a lesser degree "reducing loneliness and creating a sense of togetherness" <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27]</ref>. Our interviews suggest that CP usage, too, increases a sense of togetherness and reduces loneliness. We found music was often used as material for conversation and social interaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[52,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b85">85]</ref>. However, sharing music by sending links could feel more "personal" than doing so via CPs: "It's like I'm going out of my way to text this [...] very specifc song [to a] specifc person versus the playlist, [which is] usually [curated by] a bigger group with a lot of songs" (P4). As both the number of recipients as well as the medium through which a gift of music is delivered afect perceptions of how "personal" it is, many may have opted for more personal methods of sharing music (e.g., directly messaging one person instead of adding a song to a CP with many collaborators), leading CPs to be used less for Social purposes. Fewer in-person social events may have also contributed to this result. Moreover, the lack of social features in CPs, notably the missing feature of an embedded communication channel desired by CP users before pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[67]</ref>, may have required users to ping collaborators on a separate platform (i.e., out of context) to inform them of contributions made to the CP. This redundancy communication and context may have furthered sharing links rather than via CPs, and the current lack of such digital communication may have aforded CPs more towards in-person usage.</p><p>Insights from HCI systems that support collaboration could enable CPs to better support social interactions (e.g., translucence <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref>, communication <ref type="bibr" target="#b90">[90]</ref>). Functionalities such as "Friend Activity" on Spotify primarily encourage passive viewing of what others are listening to; the design, because is not tied to specifc collaborative contexts, afords more lurking behaviors <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[74]</ref> than active engagement. 2 Active engagement features were also found desired and lacking in the context of CPs <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[67]</ref>. Borrowing from SoundCloud, WaveForm comments 3 could be helpful in the context of CPs -collaborators can show they have heard the song and also indicate where or what elements (e.g., bass, rhythm, lyrics) resonate with them. Providing rationales as to why one has chosen to add or remove a song <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[69]</ref> could help the collaboration, as people are often curious of others' motives <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">[70,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">71]</ref>. Such additions or reimaginations of features could prompt users away from lurking behaviors and towards more interactions with collaborators.</p><p>CPs have great potential in amplifying connectedness, and could play a bigger role with more integrated social features, especially as people value this feature (i.e., appreciate music platforms with CPs more, Fig. <ref type="figure">1A</ref>) the more they are impacted by the pandemic. That people opted for more "personal" ways of sharing music over CPs suggests that the CP interface may not be optimally conducive to social interactions. While streaming platforms exist to primarily ofer access-based music consumption <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[2]</ref>, they can help users to both fnd more music and feel more connected with others through social functionalities (e.g., following feature on Apple Music 4 ). The opposite can also be true, as was evident in the removal of Spotify's chat function for its relative lack of use. 5 While the number of users may have been few, this sudden removal caused disappointment for many, and may have been short-sighted in light of the pandemic. 6  Design implication. Platform designs ought to consider features which amplify the socially connecting function that motivates much CP usage. As noted in past CP research, this could be addressed by embedding communication channels within CPs <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[69]</ref>, integrating notifcations to encourage more interaction within CPs <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[67]</ref>, and  5 "Low engagement" was the reason for removing the chat function, which some users have expressed as being "one of the best parts about Spotify". https://community.spotify.com/t5/iOS-iPhone-iPad/Bring-Back-Messages/tdp/1589818, https://musically.com/2017/02/28/spotify-is-removing-its-inbox-andmessaging-feature/, Accessed December 17, 2021. 6 https://www.reddit.com/r/spotify/comments/55ztfh/spotify_removed_messages/, Accessed <ref type="bibr">December 17, 2021.</ref> incorporating analytics around what collaborators -as individuals and as a group -may be feeling or aiming to convey with their contributions. CPs could also be designed to allow for greater social translucence <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref>, e.g., by making activity visible, showing who is listening to the CP currently as well as capturing "persistent traces of human activity" <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref>. Social presence indicators <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">[81]</ref>, history of edits <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[72]</ref>, and indication of who has listened to (and perhaps even liked) the contributions (e.g., through a like button <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">71]</ref> or "short, indexical utterances" <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[22]</ref>) may be particularly appreciated by users. Assessment of user needs should be considered when designing such functionalities. As a starting point, understanding how features could be improved by garnering insights from extreme users <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[56]</ref> may better serve platforms in the long run and satisfy users when digitally mediated social connection is critically needed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CP designs should support new users seeking social connection during COVID-19</head><p>Our study included CP users who started using CPs during the pandemic. Adoption was driven in part by greater need for virtual social options due to COVID-19. However, non-users' perceived purposes of engaging with CPs difer from those experienced by users <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref> for example, over-anticipating Cognitive purposes such as music discovery, perhaps due to that being a primary purpose of personal playlists. Non-users may not be privy to, and consequently miss out on, known social benefts of CPs. Overcoming "inertia" of starting CPs (e.g., confguration issues) <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[66,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">67]</ref> and not knowing about CPs to begin with (as some in the present sample reported) may further hinder social connection. These mismatches in perceptions may cause users seeking connection through music to fail to take advantage of the benefts of CP engagement.</p><p>Despite the importance of CPs for fostering social connection through music -the efect of which was shown to be greater the more survey participants felt their in-person activities were impacted by the pandemic (Fig. <ref type="figure">1B</ref>) -some participants still expressed a reluctance to use them. For instance, P2 (non-user interviewee) stated, "I like my own kind of music, don't really care what other people like" and thought "people could fnd [my music] silly", while P4 (user interviewee) turned on "private listening" mode to hide certain music choices from others. These concerns align with fndings from previous research <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[67,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b82">82]</ref> and also refect the afordance of separating private (i.e., visible only to certain individuals) from social spaces, as recommended in multiple works in collaborative writing <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">21</ref>, By implementing spaces that separate private vs public music (e.g., enabling users to add songs newto the CP but not share them with other collaborators), users can be less selfconscious of their choices and have time to think about an addition before making it public; it would also address the desire for CP users to "distinguish recently added/temporarily added songs from more fxed songs on the playlist" <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[67]</ref>.</p><p>Design implication. CPs could embed features that prompt interactions among collaborators, such as encouraging users to start a CP with a friend if the platform detects similar music preferences and habits (e.g., listening to the same song at the same time, similar personal playlists). The system could further CP engagement -which helps CP success -by nudging users to contribute to CPs in relation to their collaborators (e.g., "Tim and Jess haven't listened to this song but listen to similar music. Would you like to introduce them to it by adding it to the CP?"). Interventions, such as embedding private spaces that allow users to test out songs they think would ft the CP, could enhance (non-)users' psychological safety and help overcome hesitations to share music, and thereby fulfll their desire for social connection through music. In all, this would not only empower users to share more music through CPs but also increase overall engagement with streaming platforms. Further, CPs could be promoted better as a social function and prompt non-users to start their CP journey. As many individuals and communities experience periods of isolation in non-pandemic life (e.g., intensive care or immune defcient patients, seniors, remote or travelling workers, inmates), and given possible future pandemics, music streaming platforms have the opportunity to serve a prevailing need for social connection through music. These implications are also applicable to domains beyond music, as similar features can help to connect people over movies and food.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">CP platforms should enable users to include more of personal touches</head><p>Interviewees desired to make more personal touches to their CPsto enhance its role of connecting and interacting with others. Park and Kaneshiro have distinguished two forms of personalization: One that is derived "algorithmically" and another that is from and towards "social intimacy" (i.e., "personal-ization") <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[66]</ref>. Music is often used in gift giving <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[60]</ref>, which often induces this feeling of personal-ization. As mentioned in § 5.1, some participants expressed that sending music directly to individuals felt more personalized and therefore was preferred over sharing music via CPs. However, there could be thoughtful ways to induce the same sentiments within the CP, such as by enabling messages to be sent along with the music shared, a desire found among CP users in a previous study <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[67]</ref>; Nick Hornby's Songbook serves as an extreme example of the notes one might write when sharing a mixtape <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[36,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">44]</ref>. Customization can also provide a creative that afords more collaboration opportunities. The current CP implementation enables users to create CPs with interesting themes and prompts; interviewee P9 had one CP with songs relating to donuts and another with songs ordered based on how British they sounded. These affordances suggest that even more customization might be possible: Expanding upon aforementioned examples in particular, CPs could be designed to accommodate coexisting themes and subthemes (e.g., identify which songs are the "sprinkles" and which are the "donut cream") as well as enable individuals' takes to be viewed and played (e.g., play Tim's order of songs in the CP, which difers from Jessica's). Specifying and enforcing control settings for shared has been suggested in prior CP research <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[67]</ref> and could also promote further creativity (e.g., put in place a requirement for only music from female artists), as design constraints often trigger more creativity rather than restrain it <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[15]</ref>.</p><p>Design implication. Enabling customizations that distinguish CPs from personal playlists can improve user experience and increase engagement. Gifting or adding personalized notes to shared songs could further magnify personal-ization and heighten social intimacy. Customization for CP groups or individual collaborators can also convey more of users' personal touches. One interviewee, an avid CP album design cover artist, spent efort creating covers for CPs, much in the spirit of mix CDs <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[17]</ref>. Additional customizations beyond the CP cover, name, and description currently available on Spotify could include, for example, a CP taster (e.g., 15-second snippets, or "thumbnails", summarizing the vibe of the CP <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[50]</ref>). As users' purposes for sharing music via CPs vary widely, from refecting feelings to sharing diverse music, goals for CPs could be clearly defned with metrics indicating how well they have been achieved. Individual touches could involve the ability to personally organize a CP, including ways for each collaborator to specify how one song should transition into another, and allowing for parts of songs (e.g., bridges) as opposed to full songs to be added.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.4">Platform designs should support the broader role of music during COVID-19</head><p>Many recent studies found that music listening itself, regardless of social interaction, was a net positive for peoples' well being during COVID-19, e.g., Krause et al. found a positive association between music listening and life satisfaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[43]</ref>. Insights from our interviews and survey echo this with our participants regarding music as a "friend", feeling "uplifted" by music, and experiencing a "morale boost" when connecting with others through the music shared CPs during the pandemic. McFerran and Saarikallio similarly highlight listeners' perception of music as a "friend" -a strong statement worth considering in light of isolating times like our current and future pandemics <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[55]</ref>. From thematic analysis of our free-text survey responses, 32% of participants similarly referred to music as a "friend" during the pandemic ( § 4.1.6). Participants of Gibbs and Egermann frequently listened to nostalgia-inducing music, which had a positive impact on their lives and contributed to regulating challenging emotions during the pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26]</ref>. Our participants also described music as a channel for nostalgia ( § 4.1.6, § 4.4.1, § 4.4.4). While sometimes music itself facilitated reminiscence (P1), being in a location with memories also caused one to turn to the music shared together (P4). Hurwitz and Krumhansl's discussion of changing listener niches ( § 2.2) during the pandemic is applicable as well <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37]</ref>. Listener niches directly relate to CP building and listening settings, including with whom participants create CPs as well as when, where, and with whom they listen to the CP; many of these factors changed for participants during pandemic CP experiences. Moreover, listener niches have been found to shift even throughout the pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37]</ref>. Listener niches explain why Practical purpose mentions were less than previously reported <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>, with fewer social events for which to co-curate playlists -and also why there was slightly higher mention of Cognitive purposes. Though not statistically signifcant, CP users may have desired more music to consume during the pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">80]</ref> -from recreation to mood regulation -given the roles music served particularly in this time <ref type="bibr">( § 4.1.6, § 4.4)</ref>. This raises the important design consideration that social functions like CPs on streaming platforms must be built with the fexibility of listener niches in mind. How might CP experiences be designed so that they can accommodate the listener niches of many diferent user groups and also the evolving needs of any particular user group over time? Design implication. Many current attempts by streaming services to support social connection mainly encourage passive engagement. 7 Platforms should also consider functions that enable active engagement (e.g., exchange, discussion) to support users' overall engagement with music and each other. For instance, tags could convey what music means to users; knowing that others also view music as a friend or means of relaxation during COVID-19 8 could provide comfort and even inspire social connection. Depending on listener niches, which are more easily detected by these platforms, platforms could help users fnd playlists and collaborators, e.g., connecting users who are looking to music to uplift their spirits. Speaking to group nostalgia <ref type="bibr" target="#b91">[91]</ref>, platforms could implement nostalgia-based features that enhance social intimacy by encouraging collaborators to add music to a CP that a few collaborators are checking and listening to, or remind all collaborators of a CP at once to spur a conversation from their memories around the music within. This could be implemented by providing analytics of how their collective curation and consumption of music have changed over the years or by celebrating longstanding collaborations in the likes of Facebook's Friendship Anniversary videos.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">LIMITATIONS &amp; FUTURE WORKS</head><p>We limited participation to a US sample, because every country is experiencing and dealing with COVID-19 in diferent ways <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b6">6]</ref>, which could lead to diferent perceptions. Therefore, our fndings may not be generalizable to other countries. Our sample and sample size difer from pre-pandemic work that qualifes our fndings <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>. We aimed to reduce this diference by employing similar methods for recruitment and conducting semi-structured interviews to ascertain changes in perceptions and behavior in response to the pandemic. However, due to anonymity of results, we cannot make within-subject quantitative comparisons. The current sample also had more CP users than other recent CP studies. Heightened interest in CPs during COVID-19, or more time to participate in such studies, may have led more CP users to self-select into the study. We addressed this discrepancy in part by comparing only user responses across samples. Finally, our participants showed more variance of platforms used for CP engagement, and consequently the results may not be fully comparable with prior works in which CP users primarily used Spotify <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>. Interpretation of results against past research should keep this sampling diference in mind, as should future research on CPs.</p><p>Notably, we found that purposes for engaging in CPs, and the role CPs have taken during COVID-19 were signifcantly diferent from those before the pandemic. We aim to continue this line of work in understanding the dynamic perception and usage of CPs even in post-pandemic return to "normal life". Furthermore, with many music streamers found to be engaging in CPs, we can also better understand diferent usage patterns, and how platforms can support 7 For example, Blend is a new Spotify feature that enables two people "to merge their musical tastes into one shared playlist" and provides "taste match scores to see your listening preferences to your friends' ", encouraging more music homophily than heterophily <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[66]</ref>.https://newsroom.spotify.com/2021-08-31/how-spotifys-newestpersonalized-experience-blend-creates-a-playlist-for-you-and-your-bestie/, Accessed September 3, 2021. 8 Incidentally, the uncategorized purpose responses contained such sentiment of music as being supportive and relieving stress ( § 4.1.2), similar to many responses regarding the role of music during the pandemic ( § 4.4.4). them. Along with this, we can investigate musical characteristics (e.g., genre) contained in the CPs, given that content quality and order of consumption were diferent in comparison with personal playlists according to accounts from interviewees.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">CONCLUSION</head><p>COVID-19 has changed our rhythm of life, hitting pause on how we interact in-person and connect socially. As people have turned to music to cope with and fnd enjoyment in the time of the pandemic -and digitally supported interactions have evolved in importance, motivations, and usage more broadly -CPs have taken on a different meaning. To understand how perceptions, usage, and role of CPs have changed in the US during this pandemic, we conducted a mixed-methods survey (N = 142) and interview (N = 9) study. From survey responses we found that reported interest in and interaction with CPs have generally increased. Compared to a pre-pandemic sample, perceived and experienced purposes for engaging in CPs have changed somewhat, as have certain outcomes of CP usage. Perceived impact by the pandemic also modulated perceptions of CP outcomes and social connectedness through music. More detailed responses given during the interviews highlight the role of CPs and music more generally during the pandemic, as well as shifts in collaborator groups, usage patterns, and playlist These fndings underscore the evolving role of music in general -and CPs as a means of social music connection -during the pandemic. From these combined fndings we proposed design implications, including integration of more social functionalities to augment CP's role in connecting with others. These can enhance user experiences of social music playlists and augment music's inherent social role through CPs, which are shown to be a promising mediator for connectedness in our socially distant time. CPs are prime examples of computer-mediated collaborative systems and microcosms of creative, consumption-based collaboration. Therefore, insights and implications surrounding their usage during the COVID-19 pandemic extend beyond music and contribute more broadly to HCI research during a time when the world "hit pause".</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>4. 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Infuence of COVID-19 pandemic on the role of CPs and music (RQ4) 4.4.1 CPs played a role in facilitating social connections during COVID-19.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>1.1), evolving purposes and outcomes around CP engagement ( § 4.1.2- § 4.1.4, § 4.2), and changes in usage patterns ( § 4.3.1- § 4.3.3). Perceptions of how CPs foster social connections ( § 4.1.5, § 4.2, § 4.4.1), CPs' and music's roles more broadly ( § 4.1.6, § 4.4.3, § 4.4.4), emphasize the importance of understanding, and designing for, virtually social connection in the time of COVID-19. Krastel et al. posit that music consumption research has "generally ignor</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Interviewee demographics (age, gender, occupation) and start of CP usage in relation to the COVID-19 pandemic. CP users are indicated as U and interested non-users as N i .</figDesc><table><row><cell>Participant</cell><cell>CP usage start</cell><cell cols="3">Age Gender Occupation</cell></row><row><cell>P1 (U )</cell><cell>Before pandemic</cell><cell>21</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>Student</cell></row><row><cell>P2 (N i )</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>58</cell><cell cols="2">Female Hair stylist</cell></row><row><cell>P3 (U )</cell><cell>Before pandemic</cell><cell>40</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Teacher</cell></row><row><cell>P4 (U )</cell><cell cols="2">During pandemic 19</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Student</cell></row><row><cell>P5 (U )</cell><cell>Before pandemic</cell><cell>22</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Student</cell></row><row><cell>P6 (U )</cell><cell>Before pandemic</cell><cell>20</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>Student</cell></row><row><cell>P7 (U )</cell><cell cols="2">During pandemic 32</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>Unemployed</cell></row><row><cell>P8 (U )</cell><cell>Before pandemic</cell><cell>22</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Student</cell></row><row><cell>P9 (U )</cell><cell>Before pandemic</cell><cell>26</cell><cell cols="2">Female Art teacher</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>55% and 56% of responses, respectively. 25.4% of users expressed that their interest in CPs "increased a great deal", while 22% stated their involvement matched this. Only 3-4% of users stated that interest and involvement "decreased somewhat"; no user selected "decreased a great deal".</figDesc><table><row><cell>4.1.2 Purposes for CP usage largely reflect existing CP Framework</cell></row><row><cell>categories. Participants provided free-text resports on purpose(s)</cell></row><row><cell>that a CP might (non-users) or does (users) serve for them. Re-</cell></row><row><cell>sponses collectively implicated the three purposes and two con-</cell></row><row><cell>notations of Park et al.'s CP Framework</cell></row><row><cell>4.1 Infuence of the COVID-19 pandemic on CP</cell></row><row><cell>perceptions and engagement (RQ1)</cell></row></table><note>4.1.1 CP interest and involvement have increased overall. CP users gave ordinal responses indicating how their interest in and interaction with CPs changed during the COVID-19 pandemic. Both questions garnered median responses of "increased somewhat", with</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 4</head><label>4</label><figDesc></figDesc><table><row><cell>suggests that Practical and Social purposes have</cell></row><row><cell>become less prevalent (both 66% before and 41% and 40% respec-</cell></row><row><cell>tively during the pandemic), while Cognitive purposes remained</cell></row><row><cell>more similar (32% before and 39% during pandemic). Mentions</cell></row><row><cell>of Utility also remained similar (16% before and 19% during pan-</cell></row><row><cell>demic) while Orientation mentions dropped (61% before and 39%</cell></row><row><cell>during pandemic). Chi-square tests conducted on 2×2 sample-by-</cell></row><row><cell>membership contingency tables for each CP Framework category</cell></row><row><cell>confrm each of these observations, with CP Framework category</cell></row><row><cell>mentions varying signifcantly by sample for Practical (χ 2 = 6.33,</cell></row><row><cell>p F DR = 0.030), Social (χ 2 = 6.75, p F DR = 0.030), and Orienta-tion (χ 2 = 4.83, p F DR = 0.047) but not for Cognitive or Utility</cell></row><row><cell>(χ</cell></row></table><note>4.1.3 Practical and Social purposes for engaging in CPs decreased. We compared the extent to which CP Framework categories were mentioned in the present sample relative to the pre-pandemic sample as reported by Park et al.<ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[68]</ref>; as most of the present sample comprised CP users, we compared responses from users only. Inspection of 2 ≤ 0.39, p F DR ≥ 0.67).4.1.4 Some outcomes of CP engagement increased during COVID-19. Analyzing CP users' ordinal responses indicating their level of agreement with 11 statements probing potential outcomes of CP</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Example quotes from participants regarding multiple perceived or actual purposes for engaging in CPs. CP users are indicated as U and interested non-users as N i . "I use collaborative playlists when I spend time with friends who have diferent music tastes Practical, Cognitive, than I do. It allows everybody to listen to some songs they like without any hassle. " Utility S066 (U ) "The sharing of good music/art; everyone experiences music in diferent ways, and it is so cool to Cognitive, Social, see what diferent people are attracted to. Also, collaborative playlists usually introduce me to Orientation really cool artists that I hadn't heard of before (gives recognition to artists who are</figDesc><table><row><cell>Participant Quote</cell></row></table><note>"Make it easier to connect with friends through music and podcasts. " Social, UtilityTable 4: Table of counts and percentages of purposes and connotations from the CP Framework [68] implicated in CP users' responses for engaging in CPs from before (Park et al.'s study in 2019 [68], N = 38) and during (current study, N = 134) the COVID-19 pandemic. Non-user comparisons are not shown in this table as there were few in the present sample (N = 8).</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_5"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>P4 expressed "[Friend Activity] has potential for chaos, because I know sometimes people listen to playlists that are kind of secret or I've defnitely heard of drama for a lot of people who are listening to music on Spotify which is ridiculous. But sometimes I'll start a private listening session if I'm listening to music that I'm embarrassed [for others to hear] or something, but [...] most of the time it's fun to see what people are listening to." This Friend Activity functionality on the Spotify desktop app "shows you what your friends are playing, and shows your friends what you're playing." https://support.spotify.com/us/article/friend-activity/, Accessed September 3, 2021.</figDesc><table><row><cell>3 Comments on the waveform enable users to see what others "are saying</cell></row><row><cell>about tracks and exactly when they're being inspired to react, in real time."</cell></row><row><cell>https://blog.soundcloud.com/2019/07/17/see-what-fans-are-saying-with-waveform-</cell></row><row><cell>comments-on-mobile/, Accessed September 8, 2021.</cell></row><row><cell>4 https://support.apple.com/guide/iphone/see-what-your-friends-are-listening-to-</cell></row><row><cell>iphdf490a9e9/ios, Accessed September 3, 2021.</cell></row></table><note>2 </note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mizanur</forename><surname>Hasan Muhammad Baniamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohammad Tareq</forename><surname>Rahman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hasan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The COVID-19 pandemic: Why are some countries coping more successfully than others?</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Asia Pacifc Journal of Public Administration</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="153" to="169" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Access-based consumption: The case of car sharing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fleura</forename><surname>Bardhi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Giana</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Eckhardt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="881" to="898" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collecting data using a semi-structured interview: a discussion paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Louise</forename><surname>Barriball</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alison</forename><surname>While</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">of Advanced Nursing-Institutional Subscription</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="328" to="335" />
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994. 1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Conformity Behavior in Group Playlist Creation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Bauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bruce</forename><surname>Ferwerda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Extended Abstracts of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Honolulu, HI, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI EA &apos;20)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Possessions and the extended self</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Russell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Belk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="168" />
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988. 1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The COVID-19 pandemic: Efects on low-and middle-income countries</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Choon-Looi</forename><surname>Bong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Brasher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edson</forename><surname>Chikumba</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Mcdougall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jannicke</forename><surname>Mellin-Olsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Angela</forename><surname>Enright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Anesthesia and Analgesia</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Music sharing as a computer supported collaborative application</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abigail</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Sellen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Geelhoed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001. 2001</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="179" to="198" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Investigating the Culture of Mobile Listening: From Walkman to iPod</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Bull</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="149" />
			<pubPlace>Netherlands, Dordrecht</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Uses and perceptions of music in times of COVID-19: a Spanish population survey</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alberto</forename><surname>Cabedo-Mas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cristina</forename><surname>Arriaga-Sanz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lidon</forename><surname>Moliner-Miravet</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Breakdowns and Breakthroughs: Observing Musicians&apos; Responses to the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Carrie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michelle</forename><surname>Cai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nida</forename><surname>Carney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Zada</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Terry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Yokohama, Japan; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI &apos;21). Article 571, 13 pages</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Henna-Riikka Peltola, Petri Toiviainen, and Suvi Saarikallio. 2021. The Role of Music in Everyday Life During the First Wave of the Coronavirus Pandemic: A Mixed-Methods Exploratory Study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Johanna</forename><surname>Wilson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Margarida</forename><surname>Baltazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deniz</forename><surname>Duman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1469</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adaptive Radio: Achieving Consensus Using Negative Preferences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dennis</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Chao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Balthrop</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><surname>Forrest</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2005 International ACM SIGGROUP Conference on Supporting Group Work</title>
				<meeting>the 2005 International ACM SIGGROUP Conference on Supporting Group Work<address><addrLine>Sanibel Island, Florida, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="123" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>GROUP &apos;05)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2022. Topophilia, Placemaking, and Boundary Work: Exploring the Psycho-Social Impact of the COVID-19 Work-From-Home Experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janghee</forename><surname>Cho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samuel</forename><surname>Beck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Voida</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact. 6, GROUP, Article</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022-01">Jan 2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>33 pages</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Considering the Artifact Ecology When Supporting the Evolution of Practices -Analyzing the Parallel Journeys of Two Teleconsultation Software in a General Hospital</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Clément</forename><surname>Cormi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Khuloud</forename><surname>Abou-Amsha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthieu</forename><surname>Tixier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Myriam</forename><surname>Lewkowicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2022-01">2022. Jan 2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>GROUP</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efcient Constraint-guided conceptual combination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fintan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Costello</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Keane</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cognitive Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="299" to="349" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000. 2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Flytrap: Intelligent Group Music Recommendation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Crossen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Budzik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristian</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Hammond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>IUI &apos;02</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</title>
				<meeting>the 7th International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces<address><addrLine>San Francisco, California, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="184" to="185" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">More of an Art than a Science&apos;: Supporting the Creation of Playlists and Mixes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sally Jo</forename><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Annette</forename><surname>Falconer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR)</title>
				<meeting>the 7th International Conference on Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR)<address><addrLine>Victoria, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="240" to="245" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International Society for Music Information Retrieval</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring social music behaviour: An investigation of music selection at parties</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jo</forename><surname>Sally</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David M</forename><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)</title>
				<meeting>the 10th International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)<address><addrLine>Kobe, Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="747" to="752" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International Society for Music Information Retrieval</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social music in cars</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sally Jo</forename><surname>Cunningham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hasan</forename><surname>Bainbridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ali</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)</title>
				<meeting>the 15th International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)<address><addrLine>Taipei, Taiwan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="457" to="462" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International Society for Music Information Retrieval</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Neptune: A hypertext system for CAD applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Norman</forename><surname>Delisle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mayer</forename><surname>Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM SIGMOD Record</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="132" to="143" />
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986. 1986</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Awareness and coordination in shared workspaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Dourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Bellotti</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 1992 ACM Conference on Computer-supported Cooperative Work</title>
				<meeting>the 1992 ACM Conference on Computer-supported Cooperative Work</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="114" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social translucence: An approach to designing systems that support social processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Erickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kellogg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Computer-Human Interaction (TOCHI)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000. 2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Proclamation on Declaring a National Emergency Concerning the Novel Coronavirus Disease (COVID-19) Outbreak. Proclamation 9994 of March 13</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2020/03/18/2020-05794/declaring-a-national-emergency-concerning-the-novel-coronavirus-disease-covid-19-outbreak" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-09-09">2020. 2020. Accessed September 9, 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Executive Ofce of the President</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Futurehit.DNA: How the Digital Revolution is Changing Top 10 Songs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Frank</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<publisher>Futurehit, Inc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Music and identity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>Frith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Questions of Cultural Identity</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="108" to="128" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996. 1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Music-Evoked Nostalgia and Wellbeing During the United Kingdom COVID-19 Pandemic: Content, Subjective Efects, and Function</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hannah</forename><surname>Gibbs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hauke</forename><surname>Egermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">787</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Help! I Need Somebody&quot;: Music as a Global Resource for Obtaining Wellbeing Goals in Times of Crisis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roni</forename><surname>Granot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Daniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Spitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Boaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Psyche</forename><surname>Cherki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Renee</forename><surname>Loui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Timmers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonna</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Schaefer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ruth-Nayibe</forename><surname>Vuoskoski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cárdenas-Soler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>João</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shen</forename><surname>Soares-Quadros</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1038</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Virtually in this together -how web-conferencing systems enabled a new virtual togetherness during the COVID-19 crisis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janine</forename><surname>Hacker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Vom Brocke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joshua</forename><surname>Handali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Markus</forename><surname>Otto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Johannes</forename><surname>Schneider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Information Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="563" to="584" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The playlist experience: Personal playlists in music streaming services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anja Nylund</forename><surname>Hagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Popular Music and Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">38</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="625" to="645" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Facilitating mobile music sharing and social interaction with Push! Music</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maria</forename><surname>Hakansson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mattias</forename><surname>Rost</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mattias</forename><surname>Jacobsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lars</forename><forename type="middle">Erik</forename><surname>Holmquist</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">40th Annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS&apos;07)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="87" to="87" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efects of COVID-19 pandemic in daily life</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abid</forename><surname>Haleem</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohd</forename><surname>Javaid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raju</forename><surname>Vaishya</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Current Medicine Research and Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="78" to="79" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The functions of music in everyday life: Redefning the social in music psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Hargreaves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>North</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology of Music</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="71" to="83" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999. 1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">One click, many meanings: Interpreting paralinguistic digital afordances in social media</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rebecca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Caleb</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Hayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Donghee Yvette</forename><surname>Carr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wohn</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Broadcasting &amp; Electronic Media</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="187" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016. 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Music lovers: Taste as performance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Antoine</forename><surname>Hennion</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Theory, Culture &amp; Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="22" />
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001. 2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Consensual qualitative research: An update</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Clara</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Knox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Barbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><forename type="middle">Nutt</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Shirley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Hess</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ladany</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Counseling Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">52</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">196</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Hornby</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Songbook. Penguin</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Shifting Listening Niches: Efects of the COVID-19 Pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><forename type="middle">Rose</forename><surname>Hurwitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carol</forename><forename type="middle">Lynne</forename><surname>Krumhansl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1379</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">We&apos;re not just lip-synching up here&apos;: Music and Collective Identity in Drag Performances</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Kaminski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Verta</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Identity Work in Social Movements</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="47" to="76" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social loafng: A meta-analytic review and theoretical integration</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Steven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Karau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Kipling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">65</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">681</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993. 1993</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loneliness: A signature mental health concern in the era of COVID-19</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sara</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>William Ds Killgore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Cloonan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Natalie</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Dailey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychiatry Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">290</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">113117</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do Channels Matter? Illuminating Interpersonal Infuence on Music Recommendations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hyun Jeong</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">So</forename><forename type="middle">Yeon</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Minju</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kyogu</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Fourteenth ACM Conference on Recommender Systems (Virtual Event, Brazil) (RecSys &apos;20)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="663" to="668" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Music is social: From online social features to online social connectedness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zachary</forename><surname>Krastel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geneviève</forename><surname>Bassellier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jui</forename><surname>Ramaprasad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International Conference on Information Systems: Exploring the Information Frontier (ICIS 2015</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2015. 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Music listening predicted improved life satisfaction in university students during early stages of the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Krause</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Dimmock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Rebar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Jackson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">31 Songs&quot; and Nick Hornby&apos;s Pop Ideology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dave</forename><surname>Laing</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Popular Music</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="271" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Everyday Life Music Information-Seeking Behaviour of Young Adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Audrey</forename><surname>Laplante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Stephen Downie</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 7th International Conference on Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR)</title>
				<meeting>the 7th International Conference on Music Information Retrieval (ISMIR)<address><addrLine>Victoria, Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="381" to="382" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International Society for Music Information Retrieval</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">relationships and preferences for mood-congruency in aesthetic experiences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eduardo</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Chan Jean Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Andrade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Palmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Consumer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="382" to="391" />
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can we listen to it together? Factors infuencing reception of music recommendations and postrecommendation behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jin</forename><surname>Ha Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liz</forename><surname>Pritchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Hubbles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)</title>
				<meeting>the 20th International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)<address><addrLine>Delft, The Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="663" to="669" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International Society for Music Information Retrieval</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding users of cloud music services: Selection factors, management and access behavior, and perceptions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jin</forename><surname>Ha Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Wishkoski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lara</forename><surname>Aase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Perry</forename><surname>Meas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Hubbles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the Association for Information Science and Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">68</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1186" to="1200" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting social practices surrounding music</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Tuck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Leong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wright</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="951" to="960" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Application of segmentation and thumbnailing to music browsing and searching</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Sandler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Audio Engineering Society Convention 120</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Audio Engineering Society</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social network profles as taste performances</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hugo</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of computer-mediated communication</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="252" to="275" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social playlist: Enabling touch points and enriching ongoing relationships through collaborative mobile music listening</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kuanting</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Roger Andersson Reimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th International Conference on Human Computer Interaction with Mobile Devices and Services</title>
				<meeting>the 10th International Conference on Human Computer Interaction with Mobile Devices and Services</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="403" to="406" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rapid systematic review: The impact of social isolation and loneliness on the mental health of children and adolescents in the context of COVID-19</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maria</forename><forename type="middle">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Loades</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eleanor</forename><surname>Chatburn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nina</forename><surname>Higson-Sweeney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shirley</forename><surname>Reynolds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roz</forename><surname>Shafran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amberly</forename><surname>Brigden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Linney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Megan</forename><forename type="middle">Niamh</forename><surname>Mc-Manus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Catherine</forename><surname>Borwick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Esther</forename><surname>Crawley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Academy of Child &amp; Adolescent Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">59</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1218" to="1239" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Codebook development for team-based qualitative analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eleanor</forename><surname>Kathleen M Macqueen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kelly</forename><surname>Mclellan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bobby</forename><surname>Kay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Milstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cam Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="31" to="36" />
			<date type="published" when="1998">1998. 1998</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Depending on music to feel better: Being conscious of responsibility when appropriating the power of music</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katrina</forename><surname>Skewes Mcferran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Suvi</forename><surname>Saarikallio</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Arts in Psychotherapy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">41</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="89" to="97" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Bill Moggridge and Bill Atkinson</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<publisher>MIT press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, MA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Designing interactions</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">School closures and social anxiety during the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Morrissette</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Academy of Child and Adolescent Psychiatry</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Music and Adolescent Identity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Adrian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David J</forename><surname>North</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hargreaves</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Music Education Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="75" to="92" />
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999. 1999</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">On the 15-year anniversary of Napster -Digital music as boundary object</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raphaël</forename><surname>Nowak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Whelan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
			<pubPlace>First Monday</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Consuming music together: Social and collaborative aspects of music consumption technologies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O</forename><surname>Kenton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><surname>Hara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<publisher>Springer Science &amp; Business Media</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Jukola: Democratic music choice in a public space</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O'</forename><surname>Kenton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><surname>Hara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marcel</forename><surname>Lipson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Axel</forename><surname>Jansen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huw</forename><surname>Unger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Jefries</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Macer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 5th Conference on Designing Interactive Systems: Processes, Practices, Methods, and Techniques</title>
				<meeting>the 5th Conference on Designing Interactive Systems: Processes, Practices, Methods, and Techniques</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="154" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding collective content: Purposes, characteristics and collaborative practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Olsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Fourth International Conference on Communities and Technologies</title>
				<meeting>the Fourth International Conference on Communities and Technologies</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="30" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Livestream Experiments: The Role of COVID-19, Agency, Presence, and Social Context in Facilitating Social Connectedness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Kelsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dana</forename><surname>Onderdijk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bavo</forename><surname>Swarbrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maximillian</forename><surname>Van Kerrebroeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonna</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mantei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pieter-Jan</forename><surname>Vuoskoski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Maes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Leman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>25 pages</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Perceived usability evaluation of Microsoft Teams as an online learning platform during COVID-19 using system usability scale and technology acceptance model in India</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Debajyoti</forename><surname>Pal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vajirasak</forename><surname>Vanijja</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Children and Youth Services Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">119</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">105535</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An analysis of user behavior in cocuration of music through collaborative playlists</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yeon</forename><surname>So</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Blair</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kaneshiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Extended Abstracts for the Late-Breaking Demo Session of ISMIR</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social Music Curation That Works: Insights from Successful Collaborative Playlists</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yeon</forename><surname>So</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Blair</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kaneshiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">User perspectives on critical factors for collaborative playlists</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yeon</forename><surname>So</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Blair</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kaneshiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PLOS ONE</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2022-01">2022. 01 2022</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tunes Together: Perception and Experience of Collaborative Playlists</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Audrey</forename><surname>So Yeon Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jin</forename><forename type="middle">Ha</forename><surname>Laplante</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Blair</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kaneshiro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)</title>
				<meeting>the 20th International Society for Music Information Retrieval Conference (ISMIR)<address><addrLine>Delft, The Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="723" to="730" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>International Society for Music Information Retrieval</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Lost in Co-Curation: Investigating Discomforts and the Role of Communication in Collaborative Music Playlists</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond Zooming there: Understanding nonverbal interaction online</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yeon</forename><surname>So</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Whiting</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The New Future of Work Symposium</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Decoding Nonverbal Online Actions: How They Are Used and Interpreted</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yeon</forename><surname>So</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Whiting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<publisher>Springer International Publishing</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="88" />
			<pubPlace>Cham</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating, destroying, and restoring value in Wikipedia</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Reid</forename><surname>Priedhorsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jilin</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">(</forename><surname>Shyong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">) K</forename><surname>Tony</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><surname>Lam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Loren</forename><surname>Panciera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Terveen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Riedl</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2007 International ACM Conference on Group Work</title>
				<meeting>the 2007 International ACM Conference on Group Work</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="259" to="268" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Infuence of Music as a Coping Strategy during COVID-19</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ramesh</forename><surname>Bhuvaneswari</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Clinial and Applied Health Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="128" to="130" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SBV Journal of Basic</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Relationship between the level of intimacy and lurking in online social network services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pei-Luen Patrick</forename><surname>Rau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qin</forename><surname>Gao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yinan</forename><surname>Ding</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computers in Human Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2757" to="2770" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of music in everyday life: Current directions in the social psychology of music</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Peter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rentfrow</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social and Personality Psychology Compass</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="402" to="416" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How listening to music and engagement with other media provide a sense of belonging: An exploratory study of social surrogacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katharina</forename><surname>Schäfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tuomas</forename><surname>Eerola</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychology of Music</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">48</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="232" to="251" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The psychological functions of music listening</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Schäfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Sedlmeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Städtler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Huron</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">511</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013. 2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combatting social isolation among older adults in a time of physical distancing: The COVID-19 social connectivity paradox</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">Lee</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lesley</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Steinman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Casey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Public Health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">403</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Institutional ecology,translations&apos; and boundary objects: Amateurs and professionals in Berkeley&apos;s Museum of Vertebrate Zoology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">Leigh</forename><surname>Star</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>James R Griesemer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Social Studies of Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="387" to="420" />
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989. 1989</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Musical engagement and parent-child attachment in families with young children during the Covid-19 pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Selena</forename><surname>Steinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Talia</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miriam</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Lense</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">807</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the nature and development of social presence in online course discussions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Swan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Li Fang</forename><surname>Shih</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Asynchronous Learning Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="115" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The sonic composition of the city. The Auditory Culture Reader</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Jean-Paul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003. 2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="329" to="342" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What&apos;s mine is mine: territoriality in collaborative authoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Thom-Santelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Cosley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geri</forename><surname>Gay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1481" to="1484" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A general inductive approach for analyzing qualitative evaluation data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Journal of Evaluation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="237" to="246" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A typology of music consumption motivations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Philip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melissa</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Trocchia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Apps</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mcnish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Business &amp; Economics Research Journal (IBER)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">9</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002. 2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How nostalgia infuses life with meaning: From social connectedness to self-continuity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Constantine</forename><surname>Wijnand Ap Van Tilburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Sedikides</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wildschut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Vingerhoets</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">European Journal of Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">49</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="521" to="532" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The &apos;lonely raver&apos;: Music livestreams during COVID-19 as a hotline to collective consciousness?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Femke</forename><surname>Vandenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michaël</forename><surname>Berghman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julian</forename><surname>Schaap</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
			<publisher>European Societies</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social practices around iTunes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Voida</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Grinter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Ducheneaut</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Consuming Music Together</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="83" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why users do not want to write together when they are writing together: Users&apos; rationales for today&apos;s collaborative writing practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dakuo</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Haodan</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tun</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Asynchronous Collaborative Writing Through Annotations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chunhua</forename><surname>Weng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>John</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gennari</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2004 ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing</title>
				<meeting>the 2004 ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="578" to="581" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collective nostalgia: A group-level emotion that confers unique benefts on the group</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Wildschut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Bruder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Wijnand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sedikides</forename><surname>Van Tilburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Personality and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">107</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">844</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">COVID-19 and technology use by teenagers: A case study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Spring</forename><surname>Yan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Human Behavior and Emerging Technologies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
