<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Elements of XR Prototyping: Characterizing the Role and Use of Prototypes in Augmented and Virtual Reality Design</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
							<email>nebeling@umich.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Jasche</surname></persName>
							<email>forian.jasche@uni-siegen.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Research</settlement>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<address>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Science</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Elements of XR Prototyping: Characterizing the Role and Use of Prototypes in Augmented and Virtual Reality Design</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3517714</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T04:59+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>prototyping</term>
					<term>mixed reality</term>
					<term>augmented reality</term>
					<term>virtual reality, XR</term>
					<term>authoring</term>
					<term>interaction design</term>
					<term>interface design</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Current research in augmented, virtual, and mixed reality (XR) reveals a lack of tool support for designing and, in particular, prototyping XR applications. While recent tools research is often motivated by studying the requirements of non-technical designers and end-user developers, the perspective of industry practitioners is less well understood. In an interview study with 17 practitioners from diferent industry sectors working on professional XR projects, we establish the design practices in industry, from early project stages to the fnal product. To better understand XR design challenges, we characterize the diferent methods and tools used for prototyping and describe the role and use of key prototypes in the diferent projects. We extract common elements of XR prototyping, elaborating on the tools and materials used for prototyping and establishing diferent views on the notion of fdelity. Finally, we highlight key issues for future XR tools research.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Human-centered computing → Interface design prototyping; Mixed / augmented reality.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>While the Human-Computer-Interaction (HCI) community has been researching XR for decades, XR adaption to mass markets has only just started. Since hardware and software capabilities and potential application domains are evolving rapidly, keeping up with the current pace of innovation is proving difcult.</p><p>With that challenge comes a new interest in enhancing XR accessibility by creating new authoring and creativity support tools for designers with low to no technical skills. The tool gap <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref> when prototypes transition from lower to higher fdelity stages and the resulting design difculties have refueled debates about authoring tools from earlier XR tools research <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref>. With industry practitioners' increased adoption of XR, current research eforts are focusing on supporting non-technical designers, hobbyists, and enduser developers <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. However, there is relatively little research into the experience and knowledge held by experts in the XR industry, where a tool gap can also be observed <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>.</p><p>XR still has to come a long way to accomplish standardized tool chains, development processes, user interface design conventions, or good design practices <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">41]</ref>. The concepts and interpretations of the medium's principles, as well as their benefcial application, are just beginning to emerge in both academia and practice. However, a thorough understanding of practices and creativity is necessary to inform supportive design tools for creators <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>. We follow an expert designer-centered approach to boost the currently underrepresented focus on XR industry practitioners. As there is not yet a common defnition of XR, we use it as the overarching term referring to AR, VR, and MR <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">40]</ref>. Where required for clarifcation, we explicitly use AR, VR, or MR, following Milgram and Kishino's <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[31]</ref> defnitions.</p><p>In line with previous work into ubiquitous computing and interaction design <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">51]</ref> aiming at supporting the development of compelling user interfaces and creativity <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>, we investigate industry practitioners' prototypes as a "core means of exploring and expressing designs for interactive computer artifacts" <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>. Since prototypes are used as aids in thinking <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[37]</ref> and communication of ideas and concepts <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, we expect to learn more about design practices, challenges, and types of XR content in and approaches to creating better experiences for end-users. Rather than analyzing tools used for prototype creation, our research into the tool gap studies what prototypes entail and convey and why diferent prototypes are created. The research addresses the following three questions:</p><p>Q1 What roles do prototypes play in industrial XR development practices? Q2 How do designers create and use XR prototypes? Q3 Where do prototypes reach their limits and what can we learn about designing supportive design tools?</p><p>By discussing and analyzing our empirical work, our paper contributes the following:</p><p>• We provide empirical insights into prototyping practices in the XR industry, giving an overview of 23 projects and two general approaches from 17 interviewees working on professional XR projects. • We provide a taxonomy of XR prototypes consisting of classes, manifestation types, and elements of XR prototyping. This taxonomy can help in the analysis and better understanding of key prototype characteristics and how they difer from more traditional 2D prototypes, e.g., for mobile and web platforms. • We identify future directions of XR prototyping and tools research including the need to diferentiate more precisely between tools for thinking and tools for creating <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[46]</ref>; the need to focus on the diferent aspects of XR prototyping included in our taxonomy; and the need to to create shareable applications by improving prototype accessibility, e.g., by looking into solutions for explaining the surroundings and situation for which an XR experience was designed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED WORK</head><p>Our well as on studies of the role and function of prototypes in general. Consequently, we frst provide an overview of current tools research in XR design in line with identifed XR specifc design and tool challenges. Then, as a theoretical basis for our research, we proceed with an overview of the role and understanding of prototypes in design processes.</p><p>work builds on previous research into design support for XR as</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">XR Design Approaches and Authoring Tools</head><p>Recent for XR. A common focus of that work has been on empowering novice designers. Early work includes DART <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref>, a toolkit targeted at media designers to help transition 2D storyboards to 3D animatic actors, allowing designers to explore interactive stories for new AR experiences without the need for programming. A ten-year review of the use of DART by novice designers <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref> identifed major challenges due to designer backgrounds and workfows, a lack of processes and best practices, problems related to debugging, and fnally that many DART prototyping features were under-utilized.</p><p>Since DART, research has proposed many new authoring tools for both AR and VR, demonstrating a variety of prototyping techniques including physical prototyping [34, <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35,</ref><ref type="bibr">42]</ref>, immersive authoring <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23,</ref><ref type="bibr">50]</ref>, video-based editing <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b24">25]</ref>, live sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[48,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b54">53]</ref>, and asynchronous/asymmetric collaboration <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">49]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>HCI research has studied new design strategies and tools</head><p>Despite the advances in tools research, designers are still facing many challenges. Nebeling &amp; Speicher <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref> identifed fve classes of increasingly sophisticated but also complex tools. Tools such as A-Frame, Unity, and Unreal are in the highest class and often considered out of reach for novices. Tools in the lower classes are more accessible to a broader spectrum of designers as they require less training and provide layers of abstraction and automation. However, this lower barrier to entry usually also limits the fdelity that can be achieved, known as the threshold and ceiling in tools research <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref>. Ashtari et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> elicited eight common barriers to entry with three groups of novice XR creators (trained designers, domain experts, and end-user developers), from fnding the right examples and tools for XR design, to guidelines and metrics that constitute a good XR experience.</p><p>While existing studies and tools primarily targeted novice XR designers, the challenges are not unique to them. Speicher et al.'s <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref> XR expert interviews highlight the confusions regarding XR terminology, concepts, and technologies even among experts from academia and industry. An interview study with 26 professional XR creators by Krauß et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref> identifed four key roles: concept developers, interaction designers, content authors, and technical developers. An XR creator often encompasses several of those roles and faces the combined challenges of each, from contextual inquiry to deployment. The authors fnd similar challenges between novice and professional XR creators due to misconceptions about XR as a medium; a lack of tool support, particularly for spatial design in the prototyping stages; and the absence of a common language and shared concepts within development teams.</p><p>In our paper, we pick up on these attempts to highlight more professionalized practices around XR development, complementing and adding to existing research, and looking specifcally at the role prototypes play in industry development practices. Rather than focusing on the act of prototyping by developing new tools, we investigate prototypes and their meaning in a professional context. Previous work from interaction design and ubiquitous computing has taken a similar approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b51">51]</ref>. With our work, we provide a conceptual perspective on XR prototyping rooted in both practices from industry and theoretical work in HCI research. Consequently, we refect on the meaning, potential, and limitations of prototypes in XR design. We start this refection by exploring recent HCI work into what prototypes are and how they are used. This overview is provided in the next section.</p><p>Prototypes play an important role in designing software applica-</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Prototypes in Interactive System Design Research</head><p>tions in general <ref type="bibr">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16]</ref> as well as in research of relevance to interaction design practitioners <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">26]</ref>. However, conceptual refections on prototypes' XR design properties are rare. Software development prototypes can vary in form and meaning. Consequently, several attempts have been made to defne and classify them. A prominent yet controversial approach is to distinguish between low-fdelity, high-fdelity <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39]</ref>, and mixed-fdelity prototypes <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>. Low-fdelity prototypes are described as being limited in function, explorative, and easy to create, in contrast to highfdelity prototypes, which take more efort to create and deliver more refned results close to the fnal product <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">39]</ref>. Mixed-fdelity describes how prototypes can have aspects of varying fdelity and therefore do not match the defnition of low-or high-fdelity <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>. In the context of prototyping, fdelity is also associated with methods <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">47]</ref> used for creating prototypes, such as paper prototyping <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref> as a low-fdelity method. Furthermore, fdelity is aligned with the skills and resources required to operate prototyping tools <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>.</p><p>Over the past decades, several attempts have been made in interactive system design to create taxonomies of prototypes. Floyd's "three E model" <ref type="bibr">[12]</ref> focuses on prototyping as a process. According to Floyd, there are three categories of prototypes: exploratory, which focus on early stages of design; experimental, which aim to get feedback from users, or evolutionary, which are fexible regarding project contexts and requirements <ref type="bibr">[12]</ref>. Bäumer et al. add to that model by further distinguishing the results of prototyping as an activity: exploratory prototyping produces presentation and functional prototypes, experimental prototyping results in breadboards depicting technical aspects, and evolutionary prototyping creates pilot systems close to the product <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>.</p><p>Other approaches support a broader perspective. For instance, Houde and Hill <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref> argue that everything could be a prototype depending on how a designer uses it, even a brick <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>, and call for shifting attention towards the purpose of a prototype rather than the prototype itself <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>. They therefore propose a tripartite model of role, implementation, and look and feel. Opposing the free interpretation of prototypes and their manifestation, Beaudouin-Lafon and Mackay defne a prototype as being a tangible design artefact and "a concrete representation of part or all of an interactive system" <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, which also "supports creativity, encourages communication, and permits early evaluation" <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. They further propose four dimensions to analyze prototypes: representation, precision, interactivity, and evolution <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. Rather than relying on the concept of artifacts, Buchenau and Suri describe a manifestation of prototypes that requires active engagement to be understood, and they concentrate on experience during usage as well as on what a user can learn from it <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> (e.g. Wizard-of-Oz <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>).</p><p>Instead of focusing on how prototypes are being used in a design process, Lim et al's metaphor of flters <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref> aims to create a fundamental understanding of prototypes. They describe three prototyping principles: the fundamental principle of prototyping as an activity that creates manifestations that act as flters to observe design qualities, the economic principle of prototyping as a principle of efciency and efectiveness, and the anatomy of prototypes, which act as flters for traversing a design space and concretize and externalize ideas <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>. They further emphasize that there is a need both for establishing a fundamental understanding of prototypes and for further investigations into how prototypes are being used <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>.</p><p>While work has focused on what diferent types of prototypes are being used in design work and how they could be described based on their properties and forms, to our knowledge, no studies have investigated how prototypes are practically used in the context of XR-development in industrial practice. Our study does not aim to build a better or more comprehensive taxonomy for (XR) design theory. Instead it uses existing concepts as an analytic lens to observe practices and what can be learned about prototypes' rationales and use, especially in relation to the tools used to create them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">STUDY DESIGN AND ANALYSIS</head><p>We based our study on qualitative, semi-structured interviews with 17 professionals actively working on XR projects and UX design. Our questions (see Appendix A) were related to understanding prototyping in the context of projects chosen by participants and to obtaining insights into their practices, particularly how they use prototypes in their design work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Recruitment and Participants</head><p>As industry professionals were hesitant about participating in a study about their working practices, we relied on snowball sampling, which took place between February and May 2021. First, we contacted professional XR designers we personally knew, asking them to participate and distribute our request in their networks. Additionally, we recruited via local XR hubs and on social orks netw via dedicated XR design Discord Facebook groups, channels, Slack servers, LinkedIn, and Twitter. We specifcally asked for professional UX designers actively working on XR projects. Our aim was to sample a diverse group of participants regarding experience, domains, devices, and nationalities who were able willing and to discuss their design approaches and prototypes based on a project.</p><p>We recruited 17 participants (5 female, 10 male, 2 other; age groups: 18-24 (2), 25-34 <ref type="bibr">35-44 (6)</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">(6)</ref>, and 45-54 (2)) from Europe and North America (Austria (1), Canada (1), Germany <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">(9)</ref>, Ireland <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref> USA ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>)). Switzerland (1), Their average experience in the feld was 6.4 years with a maximum of 24 years and major diferences between participants in background and experience with XR, including varying coding skills (see Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Data Collection</head><p>Prior to the interviews, our participants were told that we would discuss prototyping in the context of one of their projects and were asked to choose one project. We requested that the selected project complied with non-disclosure agreements (NDAs), was recently completed or still ongoing, would ideally demonstrate the participants' use of prototypes, and covered the process until the fnal product.</p><p>We then conducted online interviews using video conferencing software with cameras switched on and participants sharing their screens to present their prototypes. Two demonstrated their prototypes via live video feeds on their target devices while describing their work. We further asked participants to share their presented prototypes with us post-study. Four participants were not able to directly share or show their prototypes due to NDAs. We therefore discussed their design approaches as detailed as possible. We discussed 25 individual projects, as summarized in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Our participants provided detailed insights into processes, tools, and prototypes for 13 projects or an overview over general approaches including the most representative prototypes for an additional ten. Two participants discussed two general design approaches with described prototypes without the context of a specifc project.</p><p>Our initial questions focused on their contributions to the project, team size, application domains, target users and XR devices or platforms. We further asked about their design experience prior to the chosen XR project before we moved on to the main interview questions (see Appendix A). We structured the main portion of the interview based on an established question catalog <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17]</ref> for context interviews, which we adapted to our research questions. We designed the questions to cover the whole design process from planning, preparation, execution, and evaluation to transfer. Finally, we asked the participants to provide their demographic information such as age, gender, educational background, years of experience in XR, job title, and current occupation. We collected 1317.87 minutes (~22 hours) of interview data (min: 32.38 min; max: 119.93 min; mean: 77.52 min). The interviews were conducted in German or English; the transcripts were translated to English by a German native speaker with a C1 skill level in English.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Data Analysis</head><p>To analyze the data, we organized each interview individually on a virtual whiteboard using Miro (e.g., Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>). First, we extracted project metadata and demographic information from automated transcripts. Based on the video data, we arranged images of provided prototypes and their verbal description in process-like mind maps to visualize how the prototypes were used and evolved over time for each interview (see as an example, Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>). Descriptions, statements, opinions, used tools, and our participants' quotes were aligned with the prototypes. This approach was repeated for each interview and resulted in 25 mind maps, each representing either a described project with prototypes (13), a general approach with Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>: A simplifed process visualization of a story-telling application for an art exhibition in a museum explained by P03. The project followed a user-centered and iterative approach, which we simplifed to see how concepts and ideas were manifested and transformed as prototypes. The depicted order is roughly temporal, fowing from left to right, showing a common transformation of prototype manifestations for handheld XR applications: sketches to storyboards, wireframes, clickdummies, and mockups. Applications on head-mounted devices often use manifestations fowing from sketches (drawn in perspective or spatial) to storyboards, spatial mock-ups, 3D renderings of the target space, XR, especially VR prototypes, to pilot systems. However, development processes are individual and based on specifc project requirements.</p><p>the most illustrative prototype (8), a specifc project with described prototypes (2) or, where no specifc project and no artifacts could be presented, a general approach (2). Some participants explained more than one project, such as P12, who detailed seven projects.</p><p>Given the exploratory nature of our study, we adopted an open coding approach to identify common themes across projects, as suggested by Strauss and Corbin <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>, without aiming to develop axial and selective codes. All transcripts were coded by one researcher. Both the resulting codes and the interim results were then discussed with two additional senior researchers to reduce bias and identify misconceptions. We performed multiple passes, each focusing on a diferent aspect, including tools, prototypes, methods, hindrances, and workarounds arising during the participants' daily work. We further extracted reasons for tool selection and the application of prototypes as well as their manifestations and fdelity.</p><p>To analyze the prototypes' common themes, we arranged them independently of their original project in a combined virtual whiteboard as a thematic mind map. We iteratively clustered prototypes regarding their depicted concepts and drew lines to neighboring clusters if a prototype described more than one aspect. By doing so, we identifed themes such as menu structure, screen structure, dynamic content behavior, and recreating aspects of the target environment. After we had arranged all prototypes in the mind map, we proceeded to combine subtopics of related aspects to overarching topics to fnally formulate ten elements addressed by XR prototypes, detailed in Section 4. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">PROTOTYPES AND PROTOTYPING IN XR</head><p>The general roles and application of prototypes in XR software development align with those of prototyping studies from other domains. Table <ref type="table">2</ref> summarizes our specifc observations in this regard.</p><p>The respective fndings are discussed in Section 6.1.</p><p>In this section, we establish our taxonomy by describing what our dataset reveals about manifestations, types and elements of XR prototypes. Furthermore, we report our fndings regarding the creation and usage of prototypes in practitioners' XR design approaches.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Taxonomy of XR Prototypes</head><p>We describe three main classes of manifestations by building on Beaudouin-Lafon and Mackay's notion of online for software-based and ofine for analogue prototypes <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. We also consider hybrid prototypes as those that consist of both ofine and online elements. Several of our participants reported switching from ofine to online prototyping approaches such as digital or digitized sketches and shared digital whiteboards due to Covid-19 restrictions, when ofine prototypes such as sketches were often digitized to be shared.</p><p>To build our taxonomy, we analyzed prototypes in terms of their manifestation to get a better overview of practices, materials, and tools originating from classic 2D graphical user interface (GUI) as well as from XR design. To learn about how ideas and features develop in XR, we also analyzed how diferent types of manifestations Table <ref type="table">2</ref>: Prototypes and their origins, target audience, project internal use, and application during development as reported by participants. Our observations are discussed in detail in Section 6.1.</p><p>be described efciently with a limited set of manifestations, for example, digital 3D objects require manifestation as online prototypes at some point to be fully graspable. Similarly spatial features require manifestation as either digital or physical models if dimensions and space are to be experienced.</p><p>We note that prototypes can manifest in various forms that are not always easy to diferentiate. As we further describe in Section 4.2, prototypes can transition between manifestations while keeping aspects of their original form. One example of such a transformation is the creation of a click-dummy based on a scribbled wireframe (sketches and drawings), which is then transformed into a click-dummy (software). The increased interactivity caused by the aforementioned transformation also increases the fdelity of this prototype. However, transforming manifestations can also negatively afect a prototype's fdelity, as discussed in Section 4.2. Communication: alignment between project team members are applied or transformed. We call this analysis structural analysis and describe the respective results in Section 4.1.1. In a second step, we characterized the diferent aspects depicted in the prototypes and described by our participants in a semantic analysis, detailed in Section 4.1.2. This analysis enabled us to understand the challenges in XR application design and how prototypes support overcoming them.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Description</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Prototypes' origin</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">Structural Analysis.</head><p>For our structural analysis of the prototypes, we organized the prototypes according to their manifestations. We identifed eight diferent manifestations: 1) sketches and drawings, 2) diagrams and maps, 3) text, 4) video and images, 5) digital assets (audio and multi-dimensional objects), 6) physical models, 7) ephemerals (prototypes without a persistent form), and 8) software. The categories and reported prototypes are further detailed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>.</p><p>In summary, XR prototypes demonstrate the need to describe ideas in space, time, and motion, often in the context of an imagined virtual environment, an existing physical environment, or a digital clone of the target real-world space. The use of physical models and especially ephemerals is prominent, and many of the challenges faced by participants were related to software tools. Some features were more easily explained in specifc prototypes, which were therefore preferred by participants, such as diagrambased prototypes to layout an application's information architecture and interaction fow, or sketches from a spectator's view to explain distances and dimensions (see Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2</ref>). Other elements could only 4.1.2 Semantic Analysis. As a second step, we performed a semantic analysis of the reported prototypes across projects with a focus on concepts and how they were depicted. We identifed ten key elements of XR prototyping: (1) spatiality, (2) physicality, (3) world-building, (4) fow -story, (5) fow -hierarchy, (6) control, (7) locomotion, (8) interactivity, (9) content, and (10) cinematography. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">4</ref> provides an overview of these dimensional elements of XR prototypes. Typically, prototypes combined a subset of those elements on difering levels of detail, depending on factors such as the designer's goal, time, skill, or requirements. For example, Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref> illustrates physicality, spatiality, and interactivity (P12). While the spatial features of the foor plan in an early stage were close to the fnal product, both the content and assets evolved and were depicted in increasing detail. Recreation of the translucent look-and-feel of XR holograms by drawing on acrylic glass (P03); arrangements of elements and lines to sketch interaction (P06) depicted in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Diagrams &amp; maps Ofine, hybrid</head><p>Used when an interaction, animation, or various types of behavior had o t be displayed over time or space; explain technical details such as nimation a curves, data structure, and camera movement.</p><p>Camera transition graph (P06) in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_3">3</ref>; map of the target space demonstrating the walking path of a user (P03).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Text Ofine, online, hybrid</head><p>Often as annotations of animations or transitions in visual prototypes such as storyboards; as a prototype itself less common but found in, e.g., the form of scripts for storytelling or story crafting.</p><p>Annotated story board (P01), descriptions (P01, P03).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>early voice over</head><p>Video &amp; images Online Images such as screenshots, photographs, or renderings; videos in the form of screen captures or experienced applications flmed from a third perspective; also function as placeholder assets in a software prototype, document application features or (target) space properties or generated to create access to otherwise closed manifestations.</p><p>Short movie for communicating the narrative of the target application (P03), video recordings from within the application to share the experience (P09).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Digital assets</head><p>Online Audio and multi-dimensional objects; content in prototypes or prototypes themselves, such as music samples, audio synthesis, voice messages to simulate vocal explanations or dialogues, and virtual 3D objects; often refned or substituted through several iterations and can be prebuilt or downloaded from platforms.</p><p>Sung and sampled music piece to acquire the support of musicians (P09); 3D hexagons arranged to prototype the structure of and interaction with an app launcher depicted in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">7</ref> (P16).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Physical models</head><p>Ofine Representation of parts or features of the application target space, such as distances, dimensions or topography; physical replicas of an exhibit or props for physical tools made of cardboard, styrofoam, wood, or other physical modeling material; physical objects or space featuring similar properties as a to-be developed virtual model, such as dimension or weight.</p><p>Styrofoam ship as a substitute for the fnal exhibit (P12) in Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref>; recreating an expensive X-ray device as wooden prop to prototype the mapping of physical and virtual properties (P17).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Ephemerals Ofine, hybrid</head><p>Prototypes that lack a persistent form when not explicitly transformed, for example, by recording them on video; such prototypes include experience prototypes <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> using Wizard-of-Oz or demonstration by example <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, and more passive and unrefned or verbalized prototypes; those prototypes are interactive and dynamic.</p><p>Referring to the same existing application and acting out envisioned changes to agree on an interaction method (P01), using physical props as reference points to understand spatial properties and gestures (P09).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Software</head><p>Online, hybrid (Spatial) click-dummies, experience scenery models in the form of grayboxed environments or (walkable) spatial 3D renderings, VR/MR prototypes ranging from mock-ups to functional prototypes implemented as pilot systems.</p><p>Grey-boxing spatial features of applications (P12) in Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref>, walkable scenery models (P06, P13) in Maya or Blender, VR prototypes in Microsoft Maquette (P15).  1) Spatiality depicts positions, proportions, scales, and distances of and between virtual and physical elements as well as the relationship between a body height and the surrounding experience.</p><p>Examples included sketches drawn in perspective, 3D models and gray-boxed or fully feshed-out experience scenery models. Figure <ref type="figure">4</ref> shows an example from P12. P03 used a sketched path over the map representation of the target space to explain the physical layout of the application. Spatial properties were sometimes represented as physical props. For example, P09 used a telescope in a bodystorming session as a physical prop to prototype interaction gestures because the telescope's size was similar to the target virtual model of a planet.</p><p>2) Physicality depicts physical aspects of an application, such as tangible or graspable objects or rooms. Figure <ref type="figure">5</ref> shows the evolution from sketch, to a placeholder prop, to the fnal physical model. Representative prototypes were, for example, sketches or storyboards and models built from various materials such as foamed plastics, wood, or cardboard (P03, P11, P17). Our participants also used sketches or tape marks on foors, objects, or walls (P11, P12) or incorporated fnal physical models from the beginning if they were available (P02, P07).  3) World-building is a concept from fction and describes "the process of building a fctional world" <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. While world-building is closely related to story-telling, it addresses diferent aspects. Worldbuilding creates a world in which a story is told. P03 reported the only prototype in our dataset that addressed the aspect of worldbuilding: his ambient prototype or application teaser was a video showing how a protagonist moves through the application's target space while a narrator explains how the future has changed how data and knowledge are stored. The narrator further sets up the context in which the application takes place and guides the user through both the application itself and its story.</p><p>4) Flow -Story denotes details about the fnal product's story. We identifed two diferent aspects to fow. Examples included annotated sketches, storyboards, text snippets, (audio) narrations, mood boards, narration scripts.</p><p>5) Flow Hierarchy focuses on menu structures and logical application fows. This is the second aspect to fow for which our participants reported wireframes, interaction or screen fow diagrams, mockups, storyboards, or designed to elaborate on the information architecture of the fnal product.</p><p>6) Control establishes how users control an application in terms of interaction techniques with or without controllers. In our dataset, this element included multi-modal interaction, such as speech or gestures, as well as the use of virtual or physical buttons or controllers. New interaction techniques were evident, which were digitally sketched-out and animated (P16) or imagined before being acted-out with props (P09) or the target controllers. Sketches and storyboards are also used to showcase control. In that case, gestures are often depicted by using hands or hand icons for gestures, colors, faded-out icons, and lines for describing movement interactive buttons or areas (see Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_2">2</ref>). There were also sketches and raycast visualizations of controllers. Speech was manifested as text or scripts.</p><p>7) Locomotion focuses on how users move and navigate through the application space and might therefore also incorporate other related aspects such as spatiality, physicality, fow -story, control. In general, diferentiation is possible between virtual and physical locomotion. Virtual locomotion happens virtually without users necessarily changing their physical location, e.g., via teleporting (P15) or moving between various virtual rooms or locations (P01). Physical locomotion requires users to physically change location, for instance, when walking through a real or virtual building. P03 used foorplans with sketched-out paths to plan the users' routes through a physical space. Both types of locomotion use similar prototypes. Our interviewees reported prototyping locomotion methods such as teleporting by being inspired by and testing with already existing applications before recreating the same or similar functionality in software tools such as Unity or, if possible, as virtual mockups, a simulation, or animation. Other prototypes used for depicting locomotion were, for example, storyboards, animated sequences, sketches drawn in perspective, VR prototypes.</p><p>8) Interactivity is closely related to locomotion and control but focuses on reactive and animated aspects of a prototype. We diferentiate between passive interactivity, such as animations and interface behavior created to increase the user experience of a system (for instance damping of movement of tag-along interface elements), and active interactivity such as reactive nudging screen elements, dialogues, and virtual or physical objects a user can interact with. Our participants reported using sketches, storyboards, existing applications demonstrating the required behavior, and animations created 3D modeling, compositing or animation software. participants also reported applying bodystorming (P09) or reenactment (P01) to iterate through interactivity alternatives. More technical aspects of interactivity were modeled as diagrams (P06). Finally, customizing and adapting the respective implementation to the fnal product requirements typically required the interactivity to be implemented in tools such as Unity and Unreal Engine. 9) Cinematography describes and investigates cinematic elements such as camera angles, camera movement, scenery, and color. The reported prototypes addressing those features were sketches drawn in perspective, detailing camera movement, or experience scenery models.</p><p>10) Content groups digital assets and inner elements that form the content of an XR application as opposed to navigation or behavior. Content is perhaps the most tangible element of XR prototypes and often used as an umbrella term to refer to a prototype's assets. Examples range from aural elements such as voice-over and sound to 2D or 3D objects and textures.</p><p>Our participants reported facing the most challenges when prototyping XR specifc elements, such as spatiality, physicality, control, locomotion, interactivity, or aspects of content. We provide more detail on those challenges in Section 5.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Creation and Usage of Prototypes</head><p>We continued our study by investigating how prototypes were created and used for communicating, documenting, and evaluating project work. Our participants reported following an iterative design approach. While some mentioned concrete process models such as SCRUM, others described their process as agile or usercentered. However, we let our participants describe their workfow based on prototypes created for specifc projects so as not to bias them by referring to formalized process models. We identifed the following six practices regarding creation and use of XR prototypes.</p><p>1) Prototypes and their manifestation were compromise of time, skill, design intent, target group, requirements, and tools. Participants often reported preferring a minimum viable approach -whatever works is used for creating prototypes. This process also included using unconventional tools or tools in an unconventional way. P03 for example reported having created a prototype using GIPHY -a free collection of gif fles and animated stickers: "I've done prototypes with GIPHY [...] just like quickly patching things together, because that was what was available and quick. Yeah, it is anything you can do quickly for certain for a particular purpose. " (P03) However, the target group was also an important factor. Based on P03's reports, there was rarely a clear distinction between projectand project-external prototypes. Few prototypes were being explicitly produced for project-internal use; they were more often built for project-external use, such as marketing material. Further, our participants reported that aligning with customers sometimes requires producing more sophisticated looking Figure <ref type="figure">6</ref>: Evolution of the physical aspects of a virtual reality experience room featuring an outdoor adventure including a rock path, hot air balloon, and a sleigh ride starting with the textual description and a foor plan (1), initial sketches of the room layout (2), initial 3D models of the surroundings (3), taped marks to create properties of the physical environment (4), and frst interactions on the rock path as a physical model ( <ref type="formula">5</ref>). This example describes how features require diferent types of manifestation to describe aspects from diferent perspectives (P12). and therefore more timely prototypes. example, P01's project was based on 360° photographs of customer's head ofce. Based on that, she built a tour in VR:</p><p>"It is hard to defne what's like a wireframing stage in VR applications because. web or mobile, you can easily keep the graphics on the same level of abstraction. But in this application, you could not keep the environment on a wireframing level since it was high-resolution and high-fdelity from the beginning. If you would combine ugly looking text with such a high-fdelity photograph, the customer would be a bit confused about the looks. This is a trust building thing. " (P01)</p><p>In contrast, we learned that experienced who knew each other well used less sophisticated prototypes, required less time for creation and to communicate alterations and behavior to colleagues, such as sketches, screenshots, acted-out interactivity based on referencing material. For example, P01 reported that, to agree interactivity and control methods with a colleague she knew well from previous projects, they both relied on a shared library of sample applications. A shared mental library necessitates at least two people sharing the same knowledge. the described case, this library was built based on artifacts such as applications, movies, experiences, and games. When P01 and other team members designed details of interaction techniques, they used ephemeral prototypes referenced, for example, Tilt Brush's menu structure to discuss how to adapt it to their application. P01 described their approach as being fast and easy (P01).</p><p>P01 also emphasized that this approach is not always possible, especially when teaming up with colleagues with whom she had no previous work experience. Such prototypes are reportedly not documented but rapidly iterated until the team members agree on a potential solution that is then developed. Consequently, prototyping does not always produce persistent results.</p><p>2) Prototyping did not always produce persistent manifestations. Building on the above observation and also as described in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, some participants detailed how they used methods based on reenactmend and story-telling to explain interactivity and create an ephemeral experience idea rather a persistent manifestation. Participants reported using such prototypes, for example, if a common ground of understanding is needed and the team lacks experience. example, P09 describes how an inexperienced developed application's interactivity that featured interacting with a planet based on props and bodystorming:</p><p>"You could walk around this 6 ft diameter planet and terraform it. And you could pick up people from the North Pole and set them down on the South Pole. my team had a really hard time in communicating what this would look like. [...] And then I went and got my telescope. And it's just nothing like a planet, it's just a telescope on a stand, and I placed it my living room and we all stood around it and we started like doing these motions of reaching around a planet. I wouldn't describe it as a light bulb moment, but all our light bulbs went on at the same time and now we understood what we were building. The artist could picture the art in their mind and the designer could picture the mechanics. " (P09) Other participants reported using such techniques if the knew each other well and a common understanding was already established. In that case, they rely, for instance, on referencing existing applications and narrating or acting out how to incorporate or change features. Finally, experienced participants reported doing several iterations of prototyping in their mind before they produce visible manifestations of their work:</p><p>"I think about which steps I would to do to reach certain actions or goals in the application. I then do several internal loops [in my brain] to see if [the UX concept] is easy enough, also for somebody unlike me, who has been doing this already for several years, but is rather doing it for the frst time. [...] A lot of things happen in my brain before I do anything with a PC or sketch with a pencil. " Finally, we noticed that the distinction between prototypes assets in XR is often blurry.</p><p>3) Prototypes were or became assets. According to the participants' reports, assets could be either a byproduct the prototyping process or the prototype itself. For instance, P15 reported using Maya, a 3D rendering software, gray-box aspects as spatiality and fow-hierarchy of an application's feature. Also, P16 developed concepts and menu structures (fowhierarchy, interactivity, content) based on assets imported into a virtual space (see also Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_5">7</ref>). Other participants reported having experimented the legibility of font sizes in virtual reality based on previously built 3D models (content, spatiality).</p><p>P15 reported that gray-boxed already resemble the ones to be used in the fnal application and are visually polished after spatial and fow-hierarchy aspects are sorted out. However, we acknowledge and emphasize that prototyping and asset creation are not the same but -as the above example shows -might overlap regarding tool usage and outcome.</p><p>We identifed several practices in terms of the use and evolution of prototypes.</p><p>4) Prototypes or their concepts were transformed in their manifestation. As described by P15 and mentioned by other participants, for various reasons, the manifestations of some prototypes are transformed during a project's progress. Reasons included creating shareable artifacts, documenting design decisions, or evaluating the current state of the project (see Table <ref type="table">2</ref>). Some transformations were because the designers needed to create an accessible, shareable, or persistent form. Such situations can be the digitization of ofine manifestations to transform them into a shareable object. However, transformations can negatively afect a prototype's XR-specifc such as spatiality, physicality, or interactivity. For example, video-recording an MR-prototype reduces fdelity of interactivity and spatiality. This reduction is bothersome if the target group lacks experience in XR and fails to fll-in the gaps caused by reduction of XR features through the altered manifestation. For instance, P09 reported on a spatial music visualization tool that had to be shared with musicians in order to convey the application's idea. He developed and iterated the application in Unreal Engine and transformed it into a shareable video:</p><p>I have worked with a musician [...] so I needed to explain this idea over and over again. [...] Even by watching a video, is hard to follow what is happening because spatialization is so specifc to how your head moves in a VR setting. [...] So I'm like doing this iteration in VR with the VR tools, increasing the fdelity in every stage and then downsampling it into a video, is a way less impressive experience. as I'm raising the bar in VR, I also raise the bar in the downsampled video experience. [...] That has been a really frustrating process it costs me social capital, every time that I bring this half-baked idea and then ask for a bunch of work. (P09)</p><p>In contrast, other transformations enhance both the interactivity and the fdelity of prototype. of our participants reported digitizing ofine to transform them into more interactive click-dummies if the project provided this functionality, which leads to the next practice.</p><p>5) Prototypes were evolved as living artifacts or away they served their design intent. Some prototypes are created once, kept alive, and over time. Our participants reported them as "living documents" (P03) that were continuously updated and sometimes required the use or creation of version control mechanisms and editing policies. Contrastingly, some prototypes are built quickly with an intended short life span -those so-called throw-away prototypes <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref> are discarded after they have fulflled the designer's intention.</p><p>In practice, both approaches of evolutionary throw-away prototypes were combined. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>, as an example of an XR application process fow, the co-existence of both types -often, throw-away prototypes were applied to identify features and design solutions, which were then incorporated in the evolutionary prototype. When discussing throw-away evolutionary prototypes, we also asked about the concept of fdelity.</p><p>6) Fidelity was often used with diferent interpretations. When we asked our participants about fdelity, we realized that there were various interpretations and applications of this concept. Some participants explained as being defned on the visual maturity level and grouped in the three stages low-fdelity, mediumfdelity, and high-fdelity through which concepts are advanced linearly. Other participants described concept of fdelity as a spectrum.</p><p>There was a general consensus that low-fdelity correlates with a low amount of invested time and efort used to create prototypes, whereas high-fdelity depicts the closeness to the fnal product and also requires greater resource investment. further saw that the fdelity of a prototype is only loosely coupled to the overall project's progress: our participants reported that prototypes of low-fdelity were produced even though the overall project was already close to production. Complementary, P01 reported having worked on a project where assets were high-fdelity from the beginning since the project was centered around already existing 360° photographs.</p><p>When we analyzed the evolution of features based on the elements of XR prototypes, we realized that prototype manifestations reported by our participants depict maturity levels of XR elements on diferent scales -even the same manifestation. For example, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>, P03's project featured an early low-fdelity MR mockup. However, specifcally observing interactivity, the maturity level was higher than those of several prototypes produced later in the project, such as screen fow diagrams or assets. Finally, we observed that fdelity was not related to a prototype being ofine, online, or hybrid. XR applications reported by our participants can -depending on the amount of virtual or physical components -consist of both virtual and physical content. Therefore, elements of the fnal product as well as their prototypes might be bound to using specifc materials, such as physical models or digital assets, whereas their fdelity can be on either end of the fdelity spectrum.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">GOOD PRACTICES AND DRAWBACKS OF PROTOTYPES TOOLS</head><p>Prototypes and the tools used for their creation are closely related.</p><p>In our dataset, we found four reasons for tools application during prototyping: creation, alteration, documentation, and evaluation. In this paper, we only provide minimum detail about designers' tool choices and use. Especially when it comes to problems, tools are often mentioned as failing to support a designer's intent or being too bothersome or overwhelming use.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Workarounds Good Practices</head><p>To get a more complete picture about hindrances in design practice, we discussed three workarounds and useful practices: 1) tools were repurposed, adapted, or enriched with personalized assets to create accessible artifacts, 2) keeping the context of use while recording ephemerals for documentation softened the efect of down sampling an experience, and 3) ready-made assets and a common design languages reduced workload and complexity. Tools were repurposed, adapted, or enriched with personalized to create accessible artifacts. Several participants reported repurposing tools for prototyping due to their availability and accessibility for customers and team since sharing XR prototypes was challenging. P01, for example, created a able storyboard in slides to share and discuss approaches with customers the target device was not yet available and the customers were inexperienced with the medium. P02 used a similar approach by repurposing Microsoft PowerPoint. While he described prototype as being very helpful when communicatwith customer on a feasible level, it was difcult to convey spatiality.</p><p>Inaccessible prototypes for designers caused by highly technical high-fdelity tools <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref> were worked around by using the experience of team members with a higher technical skill level. For example, P06 reported the developers created a widget for Unity to allow designers to tweak and adjust features such as damping in animations while running the application without the need to code. P03 further reported that his team developed a XR spatial mock-up software to enable designers to rapidly prototype applications in the target space on the target device without needing to have an additional laptop to compile application variants.</p><p>2) Keeping the context of use while recording ephemerals for documentation softened the efect of down sampling an experience. Ephemerals reportedly played crucial role when participants had to describe a design's interactive behavior. To overcome the side efect of reducing their interactivity when recording them, P03 explained his approach: Rather than just recording a video feed, a person was recorded interacting with the target device in the target space combined with the content displayed on the target device. By taking the perspective of an observer, the recordings preserve the context of use as well as the physical surroundings. Therefore, devices, and the application itself did not lose their relation to the environment.</p><p>3) Ready-made assets and a common design language reduced workload and design complexity. P06 reported that, when the team used its own design language in the form of color conventions in sketches, internal and external communication regarding and spatiality was enhanced. Furthermore, the team relied on sketching as the main communication and created mapping and animation curve whenever useful to discuss timing and animation behavior. worked well as soon as all team members and afected customers knew how to read those diagrams. Furthermore, team saved discussion and prototyping time by relying sketches and diagrams following those design language conventions. For prototyping in virtual environments, P09 mentioned that he often advised creating spatial experience models with pre-built 3D artifacts and respective tools, such as Google Blocks, because spatial sketching or drawing in 3D was hard, especially for non-artists.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Pitfalls of XR Prototyping</head><p>Participants reported several during their prototyping activities, which we grouped into the following categories: conveying feeling of XR, colors and display technology, text, time and efort from prototyping till evaluation, entry hurdles of high-fdelity tools, limitations of low-fdelity tools, lack of design conventions and interaction metaphors. We also observed that tools' limitations negatively impacted prototyping. Besides issues already documented in the literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20]</ref>, such as a high entry-hurdle for high-fdelity tools, low-fdelity tools with too many limitations, and a lack of design conventions and interaction metaphors, we identifed three additional pitfalls: 1) Conveying the feeling of XR with justifable efort was difcult, 2) display technology tampered with colors, and 3) designing legible text was difcult.</p><p>1) Conveying the feeling of XR with justifable efort was difcult. Many participants reported issues in explaining and designing the feeling of XR. For example, P06 reported sometimes creating design solutions "that look cool in but do not work or [feel] weird in Unity" (P06). Also, P01 mentioned that classic design manifestations such as storyboards lacked the power communicate the experience of spatial applications to a customer. However, storyboards were often used by our participants. Participants further explained that the problem was iterating and trying out their design solutions regarding the feeling of teleporting or walking around (locomotion, spatiality), interacting with virtual as well as physical objects (interactivity, control, physicality, spatiality), occluding virtual and physical objects (spatiality, physicality), and wearing or holding the target device (spatiality, physicality). Aside from lacking a viable way to evaluate design solutions through trial and error, P15 further explained "It's also about bringing the customer to the world they have never experienced before. They have only heard about smartglasses: 'Such a cool thing, I can work handsfree and get information projected in my environment!' But the experience, how it feels is completely missing. " (P15)</p><p>2) Display technology tampered colors. Participants who had to use colors following a corporate design styleguide reported that there are three main issues with colors for AR applications. Due to the additive screens used in XR displays, colors appear diferent from those defned for 2D media. Furthermore, textures and shaders afect their appearance, as also depicted in Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_6">8</ref>. P04 furthermore reported the issue of using black and white in a design concept: " Black is not really black because it will be transparent. Black black is more like the darkest gray possible. White is mostly like light gray, I would say, light gray is the new white. " (P04) P04 reported that performing color tests was bothersome because diferent variations had to be defned, compiled in an application, and run on the target device in multiple iterations due to a lack of tools supporting experimentation with color variations in physical space.</p><p>3) Designing legible text was difcult. Text and legibility was often mentioned as being a problematic design task due to missing spatiality or a lack of text creation features in design tools. Participants reported that both, color combinations and text sizes, were difcult to create. P04 came up with a complex workaround of rendering texts as a 3D objects in varying sizes, importing them in the virtual meeting room tool Spatial.io as assets, and evaluating diferent combinations to deduce usable combinations. P04 further mentions that this approach was time consuming but still better than asking the developers each time to try out diferent confgurations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">SUMMARY AND DISCUSSION</head><p>Our explorative describes current approaches to prototyping based on a group of 17 UX/UI designers from XR industry, who discussed with us 23 projects and two general approaches. Compared to prior work that often focused on novice XR creators, our dataset rich in the variety and complexity of XR prototypes. a summary of work, we answer our questions from Section 1 and discuss and potential future work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.1">What roles do prototypes play in industrial XR development practices? -Q1</head><p>We highlighted in Table <ref type="table">2</ref> that prototypes originated from either project-internal or project-external sources and, independent of their origin, addressed two diferent target groups: project-internal (colleagues, customers, users) or project-external stakeholders (potential customers). In our analysis, we found that prototypes serve three main roles.</p><p>(1) Answering questions about XR as a medium. Here, prototypes fulflled the role of onboarding inexperienced project members or customers and explained XR characteristics. (2) Answering questions about potential limitations of hardware and software. In this role, prototypes were applied in technical feasibility tests. (3) Answering questions about an application's specifc features. In this role, prototypes were used for communication, documentation, or evaluation of design solutions and decisions.</p><p>As our study showed, prototypes have an important function for project internal learning, knowledge exchange, and communication, similar to how prototypes are used in classic 2D projects <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22]</ref>. However, in XR, prototypes have an additional function as boundary objects for collaboration with the customer, as was frequently emphasized by our participants. Here, novelty of the medium and the central role of spatiality as a new design dimension add to the complexity and require additional explanations and knowledge exchange with customers. Existing work has already reported on the related issues regarding the difculties of recruiting experienced for evaluating XR systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref> or the need to create adaptive and interactive artifacts <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>. However, with so many prototypes being created to support onboarding to XR as a medium, new opportunities have arisen for further research on XR tools and theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref>.</p><p>In line with prior work <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>, we identifed three main classes of XR prototypes: ofine, online, and hybrid, as a combination of the two. We also highlighted eight diferent manifestations, described Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> and ten elements of XR prototypes, detailed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_3">4</ref> to form taxonomy. In line with Limet al.'s notion of prototypes as flters <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>, our taxonomy can help to structure challenges in XR design and to develop new solutions in future work. By analyzing prototypes both in terms of structure and semantics, we contribute to knowledge about their "complex nature" <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref> and enable a more efective use regarding creation and communication <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>. Our data shows that XR applications can incorporate the 10 diferent elements in varying detail and complexity. Prototypes functioned as manifested flters to observe properties those elements, whereas features describe a combination of elements.</p><p>Further, we fnd that, while maintaining the same features, prototypes can transition from one manifestation to another as a project evolves. Those transitions function as a shift in perspective through adding or removing about elements composing a feature. Resultingly, transitions afect a prototype's complexity. example, a sketch drawn in perspective depicts the element of spatiality, describing how the dimensions of virtual objects relate to a user's point of view. When being transformed into an experience scenery model, this change in manifestation adds further complexity by introducing the elements of locomotion and interactivity as well as adding a third dimension to the element of spatiality.</p><p>One of the key practical challenges we found is that participants often had diferent understandings of what denotes a prototype for example, project external artifacts were considered as not being one since they were not created by the project team members or did not comply with our participants' understandings of manifesting an idea. However, created applied those artifacts similar to how they worked with those they identifed as prototypes. Thus, despite controversial discourses in literature <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, we also classifed sketches and ephemerals as prototypes. We therefore agree with Houde and Hill's interpretation of anything potentially being a prototype, depending on how the designer uses it <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>.</p><p>Finally, we found that the manifestation type of prototypes is strongly afected by the rationale of their usage, in line with the observations summarized above, as they are artifacts the purposes of which are denoted by the respective context of use. While XR prototypes do not difer much from manifestations of 2D prototypes in that regard (as both can manifest as ofine, online, or hybrid prototypes and use similar manifestation types), they are nonetheless diferent in terms of their rationality as a means to communicate ideas about a rather novel and experimental medium with the customer, and bring the additional overhead needing to create for 6.2 How do designers create and use XR prototypes? Q2</p><p>Our study provides insights into prototyping practices in industry projects: Prototypes and their manifestations were compromise of time, skill, design intent, target group, requirements, and tools. Further, we fnd that XR prototypes did not always have persistent manifestation and that some were or became assets. Participants often transformed prototypes their concepts regarding their manifestation. Also, prototypes either evolved or were thrown awayboth types were used simultaneously over a project's course. Furthermore, we report how our participants had mixed conceptions about fdelity. Our observations comply with Lim et al.'s economic principle of design <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>: "the best prototype is one that, in the simplest and the most efcient way, makes the possibilities and limitations of a design idea visible and measurable" <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>. Our participants also often reported using ephemeral prototypes do not have a persistent form but rely on internal libraries of experiences, mental imagery <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, and discussions with colleagues. We argue that, regarding Lim et al. 's economic principle, this use is frequently for two reasons. First, XR requires prototypes a decent interactivity level to explain an application's behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>. However, expressing interactivity requires time, efort, and a certain skill level in operating highfdelity tools <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">36]</ref>. However, both that literature and our results show that those assets are not always accessible to all designers. Second, ephemerals as described by participants focused on communicating experiences <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, often by referencing shared past experiences such as known applications or movies and reenacting or recalling specifc attributes of interest. Our participants described this approach as fast and easy. Nevertheless, ephemerals are -to the best of our knowledge -rarely described in recent work <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10]</ref> or considered XR tools research. We therefore see potential for future work focusing on this type of manifestation so that a further understanding of design challenges can be developed and XR design tools can be designed to overcome the tool gap.</p><p>Our reports about the mixed application of throw-away prototypes and evolutionary prototypes is in line with previous work from the feld and similar to observations described in 2D design <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>.</p><p>Finally, our participants had diferent interpretations of fdelity, ranging from a two-stage model of low and high fdelity describing the efciency of visual design to a concept similar to a multidimensional spectrum based on XR elements. From observations, we argue that the concept of fdelity in XR design is coupled to the economic principle of design <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref> and the tool gap <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>, in addition to aspects such target audience and resources needed for prototyping. Therefore, fdelity needs to be refected in relation to a medium's properties. However, further research is required to fully understand how fdelity is represented in XR prototypes applications with similar properties, such as virtual environments and games, ubiquitous computing systems, or interfaces for voice and sound.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Where do prototypes reach their limits and what can we learn about designing supportive tools? -Q3</head><p>To conclude our investigation, we focused on good practices and pitfalls of XR prototyping and tools. Our participants reported having repurposed, adapted, or enriched tools with personalized content to create accessible prototypes. We further showed how keeping the context of use for documenting ephemerals dampened the effect of down-sampling. Finally, our participants reported having details about their work practices and additionally showcase prototypes was challenging. Hence, we had to rely on convenience sampling and not all of our 17 participants could provide in-depth insights into their work due to fears of breaking confdentiality agreements. Additionally, NDAs prevented us from including details of several prototypes used in our Furthermore, study is based on interviews and therefore relies on reports mirroring what designers say they did rather than on observing them in action. Therefore, future research would beneft from further observatory or participatory design studies. Finally, we noticed that our dataset lacks specifc types of XR, such as diminished reality <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref>; multi-sensual aspects as motion, haptics, taste/favor, and smell; or in-depth aspects of application areas such as collaborative environments, space-robustness, or outdoor experiences <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">41]</ref>. While our prototype sample might represent the current situation in industry, future work should aim to complete the proposed taxonomy by adding the perspective prototypes that are available from the literature or previous research.</p><p>ploratory study with 17 industry practitioners from the feld of XR UX / UI design. In addition to a classifcation of XR prototypes terms of their roles and function in the larger design process, we identifed eight manifestation types. Furthermore, we proposed an initial for describing XR prototypes in terms of their key with the goal of better understanding designers' challenges with new XR mediums. We fnally describe good practices and pitfalls of current prototyping approaches in XR. With our work, we contribute to the ongoing tools and design research discourses in the XR by providing detailed insights into prototyping practices in industry.</p><p>Elements of XR Prototyping used ready-made assets and a common design language to reduce workload and design complexity.</p><p>In contrast, we also reported drawbacks: Participants struggled to convey the feeling of with justifable efort and faced problems regarding display technology tampering colors and in designing legible text.</p><p>Repurposing, adapting, or enriching tools is a phenomenon of appropriation and tailorability and well presented in Computer-Supported Collaborative Work (CSCW) discourses around supporting learning and appropriation in IT-environments <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b43">44]</ref>. Due to the complexity and knowledge-intensive nature of the work to be supported, as well as the novel and often experimental characteristics of the medium, it is not clear if existing approaches and ideas from this domain will work or how they would need to be adapted for XR-related work practices. Our fndings give some insights into these aspects. They imply that there is a strong need to support tailorability and fexibility in applications as requirements and that mediums can be highly diverse across diferent projects in the XR domain.</p><p>Our fndings are in line with Stolterman et al. 's idea of building tools for designers to support both thinking and outcome <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[46]</ref>: While tools for thinking support designers in understanding the design problem and trying out various solution ideas, tools for outcome enable designers to produce artifacts of a certain quality. We fnd that our participants reported on a lack of tools for thinking rather than for production since, in the reported cases, designers were supported developers for production.</p><p>For prototyping interactivity, existing work proposes several approaches, such as Wizard-of-Oz <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43]</ref> reactive path-based programming <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[52]</ref>. As we learned in our study, prototyping interactivity can already be done if the designer has access to a collection of examples. This aspect of a shared library of interactive artifacts to further explore design solutions could be particularly useful when applied in, for instance, community-based tools.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4">Limitations</head><p>Recruit interview participants from industry willing to give us have presented the fndings from our prototype-centered ex-</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Elements of XR Prototyping CHI '22, April 29-May 5, 2022, New Orleans, LA, USA</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>Project internal: created by the project team for a specifc and project-related design goal Project external: existing applications or artifacts originating from previous projects, game or app stores, and social media Target ence audi-Project internal: end-users project team members, customers, Project external: potential customers, stakeholders Project internal use Create and evolve features of the application under development Discover potential and limitations of hardware and software Explain XR as a medium Application during development Evaluation: rarely done with end-users due to limited resources (time, money, availability of end-users), prototypes were more often evaluated with colleagues or customers Documentation: documentation of design decisions and processes</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Representation of a sketch created in Figma, provided by P06. The sketch depicts two alternatives of interacting with distant window panels: hold and drag (left) vs. click (right). This sketch depicts various elements, e.g., spatiality by showing diferent perspectives (top: ego perspective; 3rd person view: bottom), proportions, and cast shadows; interactivity by highlighting interactive areas (blue); control by showing gestures and movement paths. The font size has been altered for readability.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="6,329.97,263.72,216.22,160.87" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_3"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Diagrams and sketches depicting camera movement and transitions provided by P06 to answer cinematographic questions.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="7,77.82,510.97,192.17,114.83" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_4"><head>Figure 4 :Figure 5 :</head><label>45</label><figDesc>Figure 4: Evolution of an application from an initial grey-boxed layout (1) to the fnal product (3) (P12)</figDesc><graphic url="image-5.png" coords="8,53.80,551.73,504.40,100.06" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_5"><head>Figure 7 :</head><label>7</label><figDesc>Figure 7: A prototype created in Tilt Brush depicting an interactive app The prototype drafts elements of spatiality, control, fow -hierarchy, interactivity, and assets. (P16)</figDesc><graphic url="image-7.png" coords="11,89.84,414.47,168.17,168.17" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_6"><head>Figure 8 :</head><label>8</label><figDesc>Figure 8: Color palette tests in the Unity Emulator (P04). Due to the three-dimensionality and light efects, color palettes defned by corporations do not refect the intended color. Furthermore, when displayed on the target device, additive screens tamper with colors in AR applications.</figDesc><graphic url="image-8.png" coords="13,341.98,83.69,192.19,119.77" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic url="image-6.png" coords="10,154.68,83.69,302.64,187.27" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary of our participants regarding occupation, experience (XP) in XR in years, and background (m = Master's degree, b = Bachelor's degree, d = (German) Diploma).</figDesc><table><row><cell>ID</cell><cell>Occupation</cell><cell></cell><cell>XP (years)</cell><cell>Background</cell><cell>Project</cell><cell>Platform</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P01 AR Designer</cell><cell></cell><cell>5</cell><cell cols="3">Human-Computer Interac-Immersive tour with 360 images in Samsung</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>tion (m)</cell><cell>VR</cell><cell>Odyssey</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">P02 Research Fellow/ Devel-8.5</cell><cell>Media Informatics (m)</cell><cell cols="2">Mini-games for customers to play Smartphone</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>oper</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>while grocery shopping</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P03 Interaction Designer</cell><cell></cell><cell>8</cell><cell cols="3">Studied graphics design Educational, dystopian story-based Smartphone</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>and anthropology</cell><cell>tour through a museum's art exhi-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>bition</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P04 UX Designer</cell><cell></cell><cell>5</cell><cell>Digital Media (m)</cell><cell cols="2">Productivity application featuring nReal light</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>a calendar, tabular data, and a todo</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>list/task reminder</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P05 AR Product Designer</cell><cell></cell><cell>5.5</cell><cell>Game Design (b)</cell><cell cols="2">Explained a general approach based Smartphones,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>on a 2D smartphone app</cell><cell>Tablets, HMD</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">P06 Lead Designer/Director</cell><cell>24</cell><cell>Architecture (d)</cell><cell cols="2">Software for meetings in VR with Oculus Quest (1,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>enhanced moderator features</cell><cell>2)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P07 PhD Researcher</cell><cell></cell><cell>3</cell><cell>Software Engineer (m)</cell><cell cols="2">Monitoring and support tool for HoloLens 2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>solving the Rubik's Cube</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">P08 CEO/Producer for Interac-10</cell><cell cols="3">Entrepreneurship &amp; AI De-360 immersive documentary about WebXR</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>tive Media</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>velopment (m)</cell><cell>cacao farmers in Brazil</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P09 Principal XR Designer</cell><cell></cell><cell>4</cell><cell>Computer Science (b)</cell><cell cols="2">Immersive, spatial concert visualiza-Oculus</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>tion tool</cell><cell>Quest/device</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>agnostic</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P10 Technical Consultant</cell><cell></cell><cell>2.5</cell><cell>Computer Science (m)</cell><cell>Telemaintenance application</cell><cell>HoloLens (1, 2)</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P11 Technical Director</cell><cell></cell><cell>3</cell><cell>Computer Science (m)</cell><cell cols="2">Guided story about the history of a iPad</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>building</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P12 Experience</cell><cell cols="2">De-6</cell><cell>Media Management (d)</cell><cell>Various projects (n=7)</cell><cell>Smartphone,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>signer/Director</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Tablet, HMD</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">P13 Senior Technical Consul-8</cell><cell cols="3">Interactive Media Systems Explained a general approach with-HMDs</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell cols="2">tant/ Concepter/3D Artist</cell><cell></cell><cell>(m)</cell><cell>out showing prototypes and with-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>out project context</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P14 UX Designer</cell><cell></cell><cell>1</cell><cell cols="3">Film production, 2D ani-Explained the approach without AR HMD (e.g.</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell cols="3">mations and Visualizations showing prototypes and without HoloLens)</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(m)</cell><cell>project context</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">P15 Product Owner AR/VR 7</cell><cell cols="3">Media Informatics and Collaborative walk-through a VR HMD</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Technologies</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>HCI (b)</cell><cell>power plant</cell></row><row><cell cols="4">P16 Interaction Designer/ De-2</cell><cell>No formal degree</cell><cell cols="2">Interaction techniques development XR HMD</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>veloper</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>for XR</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">P17 PhD Research Assistant</cell><cell>6</cell><cell cols="3">Biomedical Engineering Supporting medical workers in can-HoloLens 2</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(m)</cell><cell>cer treatment procedures</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Summary of the observed and reported manifestations of prototypes.</figDesc><table /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_3"><head>Table 4 :</head><label>4</label><figDesc>Summary of the dimensional elements of XR prototypes.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Element</cell><cell>Description</cell><cell>Manifestation</cell></row><row><cell>Spatiality</cell><cell cols="2">The relation of real and virtual object regard-Sketches drawn in perspective, 3D models, gray-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>ing the distance, scale, and rotation.</cell><cell>boxed spatial layouts, experience scenery models,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>physical props</cell></row><row><cell>Physicality</cell><cell cols="2">Physical properties of an XR application, Sketches, storyboards, models built from various ma-</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>such as tangible artifacts or rooms.</cell><cell>terials such as foamed plastics, wood, or cardboard,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>tape marks on walls and foors</cell></row><row><cell>World-building</cell><cell>Background for the story telling.</cell><cell>Video (ambient prototype), script</cell></row><row><cell>Flow -Story</cell><cell cols="2">The story an XR application wants to medi-Sketches, storyboards, text snippets, (audio) narration,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>ate.</cell><cell>mood boards, scripts</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Flow -Hierarchy The logical structure of the XR application Wireframes, interaction or screen fow diagrams,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>including menus.</cell><cell>mockups, storyboards, click-dummies</cell></row><row><cell>Control</cell><cell cols="2">Interaction techniques with or without con-(Animated) sketches, acted-out or envisioned with</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>trollers</cell><cell>props or the target controller, storyboards, script, text</cell></row></table><note>LocomotionUser movement and navigation in a space, Sample applications, VRmockups, storyboards, aniincludes techniques for moving in VR, such mated sequences, sketches in perspective, sketches as teleporting on a map Interactivity Reactive and animated aspects Sketches, storyboards, sample applications, animations, bodystorming, diagrams, software prototypes Cinematography Cinematic elements such as camera angles, Sketches drawn in perspective, diagrams, experience camera movement, scenery, and color scenery models Content Digital assets and inner elements Aural elements, 2D and 3D objects, textures</note></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>We thank our participants for their time, efort, and willingness to share their work with us.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A APPENDIX: INTERVIEW GUIDELINE</head><p>The questions listed below were used as a semi-structured interview guideline. Participants were asked to explain their approach and demonstrate if available in line with one of their current projects. The data collection is further described in Section 3.2.</p><p>A. <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">1</ref>  </p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Leitfaden Usability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deutsche</forename><surname>Akkreditierungsstelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.dakks.de-retrieved" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010-12">2010. December 2019. January 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>retracted in</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Creating Augmented and Virtual Reality Applications: Current Practices, Challenges, and Opportunities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Narges</forename><surname>Ashtari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrea</forename><surname>Bunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joanna</forename><surname>Mcgrenere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nebeling</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Parmit</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Chilana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3313831.3376722</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376722" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Honolulu, HI, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI &apos;20)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental Imagery as a Design Tool</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Uday</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Athavankar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/019697297126236</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/019697297126236" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cybernetics and Systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="25" to="42" />
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997. 1997</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">User interface prototyping-concepts, tools, and experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Baumer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Bischofberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Lichter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Zullighoven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ICSE.1996.493447</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1109/ICSE.1996.493447" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings IEEE 18th International Conference on Software Engineering</title>
				<meeting>IEEE 18th International Conference on Software Engineering<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="532" to="541" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prototyping Tools and Techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Beaudouin-Lafon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><surname>Mackay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1201/9781420088892</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1201/9781420088892" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human-Computer Interaction: Development Process</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Boca Raton</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>CRC Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="137" to="160" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>1 ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DIS &apos;00). Association for Computing Machinery</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marion</forename><surname>Buchenau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jane</forename><forename type="middle">Fulton</forename><surname>Suri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/347642.347802</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/347642.347802" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 3rd Conference on Designing Interactive Systems: Processes, Practices, Methods, and Techniques</title>
				<meeting>the 3rd Conference on Designing Interactive Systems: Processes, Practices, Methods, and Techniques<address><addrLine>New York City, New York, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="424" to="433" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Experience Prototyping</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sketching User Experiences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Buxton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-012374037-3/50059-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-012374037-3/50059-6" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="139" to="141" />
			<pubPlace>Burlington</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grounding in communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Herbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Brennan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/10096-006</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/10096-006" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Perspectives on socially shared cognition</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lauren</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Resnick</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Levine</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Teasley</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Washington, DC, US</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>American Psychological Association</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1991">1991</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="149" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grounded theory research: Procedures, canons, and evaluative criteria</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Juliet</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Corbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anselm</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/BF00988593</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/BF00988593" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Qual Sociol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990. 1990</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">External Representations in Ubiquitous Computing Design and the Implications for Design Tools</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Dow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">Scott</forename><surname>Saponas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Landay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1142405.1142443</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/1142405.1142443" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">DIS &apos;06: Proceedings the 6th conference on Designing Interactive systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="241" to="250" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Workplace Warriors: Identifying Team Practices of Appropriation in Software Ecosystems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Draxler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adrian</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Boden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gunnar</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1984642.1984656</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/1984642.1984656" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 4th International Workshop on Cooperative Human Aspects of Software Engineering</title>
				<meeting>the 4th International Workshop on Cooperative Human Aspects of Software Engineering<address><addrLine>Waikiki, Honolulu, HI, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Systematic Look at Prototyping</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christiane</forename><surname>Floyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Approaches to Prototyping</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Reinhard</forename><surname>Budde</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karin</forename><surname>Kuhlenkamp</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lars</forename><surname>Mathiassen</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heinz</forename><surname>Züllighoven</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Berlin Heidelberg; Berlin, Heidelberg</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1984">1984</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designer&apos;s Augmented Toolkit</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maribeth</forename><surname>Gandy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Blair</forename><surname>Macintyre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2642918.2647369</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2642918.2647369" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedof the 27th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology</title>
				<meeting>eedof the 27th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology<address><addrLine>Honolulu, Hawaii, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="627" to="636" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>UIST &apos;14)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Rapid Development of User Interfaces: Experience with the Wizard of OZ Method</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wei-Haas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/154193128502900515</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/154193128502900515" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">the Human Factors Society Annual Meeting</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985">1985. 1985</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="474" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Collaborative worldbuilding for writers and gamers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Trent</forename><surname>Hergenrader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<publisher>Bloomsbury Publishing</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">257</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Great Britain</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chapter 16 -What do Prototypes Prototype?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephanie</forename><surname>Houde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charles</forename><surname>Hill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/B978-044481862-1.50082-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/B978-044481862-1.50082-0" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Human-Computer Interaction</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Marting</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Helander</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Prasad</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Landauer</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><surname>Prabhu</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Amsterdam</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>North-Holland</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1997">1997</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="367" to="381" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Second Edition. second edition ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ergonomics of human-system interaction</title>
		<idno>ISO/TC 159/SC 4</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Ergonomics of human-system interaction -Part 210: Human-centred design for interactive systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Geneva, Switzerland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9241" to="9210" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Standard. International Organization for Standardization</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Preece</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Sharp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yvonne</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.wiley.com/en-us/Interaction+Design%3A+Beyond+Human+" />
		<title level="m">Interaction Design: Beyond Human-Computer Interaction</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Wiley</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>4 ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supporting creative and refective processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hilary</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lucy</forename><surname>Carruthers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ijhcs.2006.06.001</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2006.06.001" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Human Computer Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">64</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="998" to="1008" />
			<date type="published" when="2006-10">2006. 10 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Current Practices, Challenges, and Design Implications for Collaborative AR/VR Application Development</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Veronika</forename><surname>Krauß</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Boden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leif</forename><surname>Oppermann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">René</forename><surname>Reiners</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3411764.3445335</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445335" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA, Article</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">454</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Research and Practice Recommendations for Mixed Reality Design -Diferent Perspectives from the Community</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Veronika</forename><surname>Krauß</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Jasche</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sheree</forename><forename type="middle">May</forename><surname>Saßmannshausen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Ludwig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Boden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3489849.3489876</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3489849.3489876" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">27th ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and (VRST &apos;21</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Osaka, Japan; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">13</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of prototypes in communication between stakeholders</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carlye</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lauf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Kotys-Schwartz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rentschler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.destud.2019.11.007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.destud.2019.11.007" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Design Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">66</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="34" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Immersive authoring of tangible augmented reality applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Nelles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Billinghurst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ISMAR.2004.34</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1109/ISMAR.2004.34" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Third IEEE and ACM International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Arlington, VA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="172" to="181" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Montage: A Video Prototyping System to Reduce Re-Shooting and Increase Re-Usability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Germán</forename><surname>Leiva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Beaudouin-Lafon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3242587.3242613</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3242587.3242613" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 31st Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology</title>
				<meeting>the 31st Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="675" to="682" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>UIST &apos;18)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pronto: Rapid Augmented Reality Video Prototyping Using Sketches and Enaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Germán</forename><surname>Leiva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cuong</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rubaiat</forename><surname>Habib Kazi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Asente</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3313831.3376160</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376160" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Honolulu, HI, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI &apos;20)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Anatomy of Prototypes: Prototypes as Filters, Prototypes as Manifestations of Design Ideas</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Youn-Kyung</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Stolterman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1375761.1375762</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/1375761.1375762" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions on Computer-Human Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">DART: A Toolkit Rapid Design Exploration of Augmented Reality Experiences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Blair</forename><surname>Macintyre</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maribeth</forename><surname>Gandy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Dow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jay</forename><forename type="middle">David</forename><surname>Bolter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1029632.1029669</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/1029632.1029669" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">UIST &apos;04: Proceedings the 17th annual ACM symposium on User interface software and technology</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Fe, NM, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="197" to="206" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Exploration of Low-Fidelity Prototyping Methods for Augmented and Virtual Reality. In Design, User Experience, and Usability. Design for Contemporary Interactive Environments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Maguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Aaron Marcus and Elizabeth Rosenzweig</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<publisher>Springer International Cham</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="470" to="481" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mediated with implementations for everyday life</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Presence Connect</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002. 2002. 2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Breaking the Fidelity Barrier: An Examination of Our Current Characterization of Prototypes and an Example of a Mixed-Fidelity Success</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Mccurdy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Connors</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Guy</forename><surname>Pyrzak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bob</forename><surname>Kanefsky</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alonso</forename><surname>Vera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1124772.1124959</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/1124772.1124959" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Montréal, Québec; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1233" to="1242" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taxonomy of mixed reality visual displays</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Milgram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fumio</forename><surname>Kishino</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEICE Transactions on Information and Systems E77-D</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1321" to="1329" />
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994. 1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Past, present, and future of user interface software tools</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brad</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Randy</forename><surname>Hudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Pausch</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Computer-Human Interaction (TOCHI)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000. 2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">XRDirector: A Role-Based Collaborative Immersive Authoring System</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katy</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yu-Cheng</forename><surname>Chang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lihan</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michelle</forename><surname>Chung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Piaoyang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janet</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3313831.3376637</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376637" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Honolulu, HI, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI &apos;20)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making Interactive Virtual Reality &amp; Augmented Prototypes from Paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katy</forename><surname>Madier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290605.3300826</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3290605.3300826" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">360</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ProtoAR: Rapid Physical-Digital Prototyping of Mobile Augmented Reality Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janet</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ao</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Rumble</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3173927</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173927" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Trouble with Augmented Reality/Virtual Reality Authoring Tools</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maximilian</forename><surname>Speicher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/ISMAR-Adjunct.2018.00098</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1109/ISMAR-Adjunct.2018.00098" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Adjunct Proceedings -2018 IEEE International Symposium on Mixed and Augmented Reality</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Munich, Germany</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="333" to="337" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Things That Make Us Smart -Defending Human Attributes in the Age of the Machine</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Donald</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
			<publisher>Addision-Wesley Publishing Company</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prototyping for Tiny Fingers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Rettig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/175276.175288</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/175276.175288" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="27" />
			<date type="published" when="1994-04">1994. April 1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Low vs. High-Fidelity Prototyping Debate</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jim</forename><surname>Rudd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ken</forename><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Scott</forename><surname>Isensee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/223500.223514</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/223500.223514" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interactions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="76" to="85" />
			<date type="published" when="1996-01">1996. Jan. 1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Theory and applications of marker-based augmented reality: Licentiate thesis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sanni</forename><surname>Siltanen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">78191</biblScope>
			<pubPlace>Finland</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Aalto University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Ph.D. Dissertation.</note>
	<note>Project code</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What is Mixed Reality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maximilian</forename><surname>Speicher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Hall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290605.3300767</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3290605.3300767" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2021. Designers, the Stage Is Yours! Medium-Fidelity Prototyping of Augmented &amp; Virtual Reality Interfaces with 360theater</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maximilian</forename><surname>Speicher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katy</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="25" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>EICS</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">GestureWiz: A Human-Powered Gesture Design Environment for User Interface Prototypes. Association for Computing Machinery</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maximilian</forename><surname>Speicher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Nebeling</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3173681</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173681" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Appropriation of the eclipse ecosystem: Local integration of global network production</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gunnar</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Draxler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of COOP 2010: Proceedings of the 9th International Conference on Designing Cooperative Systems</title>
				<meeting>COOP 2010: the 9th International Conference on Designing Cooperative Systems<address><addrLine>Aix-en-Provence, France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="287" to="308" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Nature of Design Practice and Implications for Interaction Design Research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Stolterman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.ijdesign.org/index.php/IJDesign/article/view/240/148" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Design</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designerly Tools</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Stolterman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jamie</forename><surname>Mcatee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Royer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Selvan</forename><surname>Thandapani</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://shura.shu.ac.uk/491/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Undisciplined! Design Research Society Conference</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Shefeld, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2009. 2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="19" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Shefeld Hallam University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taking the &apos;A&apos; Out of &apos;AR&apos;: Play Based Low Fidelity Contextual Prototyping of Mobile Augmented Reality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexandra</forename><surname>Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leigh</forename><forename type="middle">Ellen</forename><surname>Potter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="CHIPLAY&apos;18" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Annual Symposium on Computer-Human Interaction in Play Companion Extended</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 Annual Symposium on Computer-Human Interaction in Play Companion Extended<address><addrLine>Melbourne, VIC, Australia</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Association for Computing Machinery</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3270316.3271518</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3270316.3271518" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="647" to="653" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Extended Abstracts)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Loki: Facilitating Remote Instruction of Physical Tasks Using Bi-Directional Mixed-Reality Telepresence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fraser</forename><surname>Balasaravanan Thoravi Kumaravel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bjoern</forename><surname>Fitzmaurice</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tovi</forename><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3332165.3347872</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3332165.3347872" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 32nd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology</title>
				<meeting>the 32nd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology<address><addrLine>New Orleans, LA, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="161" to="174" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>UIST &apos;19)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">TransceiVR: Bridging Asymmetrical Communication Between Users and External Collaborators</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cuong</forename><surname>Balasaravanan Thoravi Kumaravel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Nguyen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bjoern</forename><surname>Diverdi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hartmann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3379337.3415827</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3379337.3415827" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (Virtual Event, USA) (UIST &apos;20)</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (Virtual Event, USA) (UIST &apos;20)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="182" to="195" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spacetime: Enabling Fluid Individual and Collaborative Editing Virtual Reality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Haijun</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><surname>Herscher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ken</forename><surname>Perlin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Wigdor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3242587.3242597</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3242587.3242597" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 31st Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology</title>
				<meeting>the 31st Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology<address><addrLine>Berlin, Germany; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="853" to="866" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>UIST &apos;18)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interaction design of tools for fostering creativity in the early stages of information design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yasuhiro</forename><surname>Yamamoto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kumiyo</forename><surname>Nakakoji</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Human Computer Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="513" to="535" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Issue 4-5 SPEC. ISS.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ijhcs.2005.04.023</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2005.04.023" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">FlowMatic: Tool for Creating Interactive Scenes in Virtual Reality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lei</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Oney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3379337.3415824</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3379337.3415824" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (Virtual USA) &apos;20)</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology (Virtual USA) &apos;20)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="342" to="353" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">SAVE: Shared Augmented Virtual Environment for Real-Time Mixed Reality Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yu</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kang</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qiang</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xilin</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huixing</forename><surname>Gong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jingyi</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3013971.3013979</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3013971.3013979" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 15th ACM SIGGRAPH Conference on Virtual-Reality Continuum and Its Applications in Industry -Volume</title>
				<meeting>the 15th ACM SIGGRAPH Conference on Virtual-Reality Continuum and Its Applications in Industry -Volume<address><addrLine>Zhuhai, China; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="21" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>VRCAI &apos;16)</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
