<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Monitoring Pets, Deterring Intruders, and Casually Spying on Neighbors: Everyday Uses of Smart Home Cameras</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Neilly</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Tan</surname></persName>
							<email>nhtan@uw.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Richmond</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Audrey</forename><surname>Desjardins</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sean</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Munson</surname></persName>
							<email>smunson@uw.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pierce</surname></persName>
							<email>jjpierce@uw.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Human Centered Design and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Washington</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>Washington</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Center for Long-Term Cybersecurity</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of California Berkeley</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Berkeley</settlement>
									<region>California</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">School of Art + Art History + Design</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Washington</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle, Washington</settlement>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Human Centered Design and Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Washington</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle</settlement>
									<region>Washington</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="department">School of Art + Art History + Design</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Washington</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Seattle, Washington</settlement>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Monitoring Pets, Deterring Intruders, and Casually Spying on Neighbors: Everyday Uses of Smart Home Cameras</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3517617</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:00+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Internet of Things (IoT)</term>
					<term>smart cameras</term>
					<term>surveillance</term>
					<term>privacy</term>
					<term>personal data</term>
					<term>tracking</term>
					<term>design This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution International 4.0 License</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The increased adoption of smart home cameras (SHCs) foregrounds issues of surveillance, power, and privacy in homes and neighborhoods. However, questions remain about how people are currently using these devices to monitor and surveil, what the benefits and limitations are for users, and what privacy and security tensions arise between primary users and other stakeholders. We present an empirical study with 14 SHC users to understand how these devices are used and integrated within everyday life. Based on semistructured qualitative interviews, we investigate users' motivations, practices, privacy concerns, and social negotiations. Our findings highlight the SHC as a perceptually powerful and spatially sensitive device that enables a variety of surveillant uses outside of basic home security-from formally surveilling domestic workers, to casually spying on neighbors, to capturing memories. We categorize surveillant SHC uses, clarify distinctions between primary and nonprimary users, and highlight under-considered design directions for addressing power imbalances among primary and non-primary users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Human-centered computing; • Human computer interaction (HCI); • Empirical studies in HCI;</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Variously referred to as smart products, connected devices, and Internet of Things (IoT) technologies, the range and quantity of networked, internet-connected, and data-driven things appears to expand daily. While today we have smart speakers, watches, doorbells, locks, and televisions, tomorrow we may find ourselves regularly interacting with smart kitchens, sidewalks <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[59]</ref>, showers, and toilets <ref type="bibr" target="#b91">[98]</ref>. These technologies may provide us better ways of living, working, playing, creating, and caring for others. Their use, however, also accompanies a myriad of privacy concerns, security vulnerabilities, and potentials for bias and discrimination (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">94,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b126">138]</ref>) that are still emergent, evolving, and woefully unresolved. Prior work has provided qualitative empirical studies of smart devices in general <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">77,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">90]</ref> and of specific sensing devices-including smart speakers <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">16]</ref> and activity trackers [75, <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">91,</ref><ref type="bibr">93]</ref>. In this paper, we focus on one device that has not yet been given this same level of focused, qualitative, and designoriented investigation: standalone consumer smart home cameras (SHCs).</p><p>Smart home cameras are one of the most popular and growing categories of consumer smart home and automation products. Often these devices are marketed as smart home security cameras or surveillance cameras. However, these devices are also marketed and used as more than devices for deterring or catching intruders. For example, Google Nest and Amazon Ring promotional materials depict use cases for watching pets, monitoring packages, and greeting guests (Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>). A Nest marketing campaign even created an official award contest, dubbed "The Nesties," that invited users to submit funny and awe-inspiring video clips for award categories such as "Best Dog in a Lead Role" <ref type="bibr">[27]</ref>. These marketing materials suggest benefits that extend beyond conventional home security and into the realms of entertainment, productivity, social media, and meaning-making.</p><p>Our research seeks to understand how people actually use smart cameras, and whether these uses align or diverge with promoted use cases. We see hints of a variety of uses extending beyond conventional home security across social media, market research, and news reporting. In popular culture, such clips occasionally go viral and are reported in news media-such as a heartwarming video of a young trick-or-treater filling an empty Halloween bowl with candy for other children <ref type="bibr">[82]</ref> or a video of a housecat successfully scaring off a coyote <ref type="bibr">[63]</ref>. Alongside heartwarming and jaw-dropping smart home camera videos, these devices have also reportedly been used to spy, prank, threaten, and abuse (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[21]</ref>). Somewhere in between these two extremes, prior market research suggests many people use SHCs to watch pets, guests, and family members <ref type="bibr" target="#b127">[139]</ref>.</p><p>In the future, there is every reason to expect that we will see more smart cameras. Unit sales for "smart home surveillance cameras" are expected to grow from 54 million in 2018 to 120 million in 2023 <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>, a total that excludes devices with similar functionality such as baby monitors, action cameras, and smart camera capabilities built into smartphones and other devices. In 2016, SHCs generated more retail revenue than any other home automation category and were the most common entry point to the smart home market <ref type="bibr" target="#b127">[139]</ref>.</p><p>Smart home cameras are an inherently surveillant technology that can be used to monitor, track, and record other people, often with little awareness or consent. Beyond simply recording video or audio, machine learning (ML) and other forms of image, video, and audio analytics enable SHCs to infer insightful and revealing information such as recognizing motion, people, faces, animals, vehicles, and noises including breaking glass and smoke alarms. Beyond consumer SHCs specifically, digital imaging and video analytics technologies are seen as one of the most transformative emerging technologies with applications that include driverless cars, predictive policing, patient monitoring, and neuromarketing. Many cultural flashpoints emanate from these technologies, notably concerns with facial recognition technology and implicit biases <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[36]</ref>. While not the direct focus of this study, this broader array of applications and issues provides additional motivation for our work, as our study may shed secondary insights into design opportunities, limitations, and concerns regarding smart cameras and image/video analytics more generally.</p><p>Against this backdrop, we present findings from 14 qualitative interviews with smart home camera users in the United States about their uses and experiences with these devices. Our study is motivated by the following questions:</p><p>• Q1. How and why do people use SHCs? SHC promotional materials and market research suggest that people use SHCs for reasons beyond deterring intruders including monitoring pets, kids, and family <ref type="bibr" target="#b119">[130,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b127">139]</ref> (and see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>). Our study set out to determine if these and other such uses are occurring or not, and why. • Q2. What, if any, concerns do SHC users have with regards to privacy, security, trust, and control of these devices? Prior research finds that many consumer smart home device users generally express high degrees of trust in manufacturers and service providers to protect their privacy and security <ref type="bibr" target="#b125">[137]</ref>, even as these remain a critical concern for researchers, policymakers, and governments. • Q3. How are people using SHCs in relation to othersincluding the monitoring or surveilling of family, neighbors, guests, workers, and passersby? Prior research has found tensions between primary and secondary users of some smart devices <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[80]</ref>, including perspectives of bystanders <ref type="bibr" target="#b121">[133]</ref> and usees <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref>. Our study is designed to better understand how primary users relate to other subjects affected by their SHCs. To a lesser degree, our study also directly investigates the perspectives of non-primary users affected by SHCs. • Q4. How might we approach the design of SHCs and similar technologies to better address the needs of both primary users who own and operate these devices, and other people who are surveilled and otherwise affected by these devices? Current usable privacy and security approaches focus on notice-and-consent <ref type="bibr" target="#b106">[114,</ref><ref type="bibr">115]</ref> and individual user interface controls (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>).</p><p>Yet both have been shown to have significant limitations, as privacy policies are rarely read and security warnings are often ignored. These approaches are even less applicable when considering bystanders and usees who, by definition, have limited, if any control of the system. This paper thus makes three core contributions across HCI and interaction design, and their intersections with discourses of data privacy, security, trust, surveillance, and power. First, we provide qualitative descriptions of SHC users' motivations for adopting the devices, and their actual uses and levels of comfort with these surveillant technologies to support a variety of everyday activities. Second, based on our findings we contribute two sets of concepts to aid designers and researchers with studying and improving SHCs and similar technologies. We highlight the need to treat smart cameras and other spatially sensitive and perceptually powerful technologies differently because their capabilities inherently extend across large areas and distances, and inevitably affect the privacy and security of other stakeholders. Regarding SHC and smart device users, we clarify important distinctions between primary and non-primary users, and between frontend and backend users. Nonprimary users-such as housemates, neighbors, domestic workers, or passersby-may interact with SHCs but do so with comparatively limited awareness, consent, and control compared to the primary users who own and operate them. Adding a second layer to this distinction, a backend user-such as a company or hacker-accesses a smart device that is owned and operated by a primary frontend user, who is oblivious to or only peripherally aware of the backend user and their uses (e.g., selling their data to third-party advertisers). These distinctions are indispensable in clarifying the stakeholders and stakes involved in the complex network of interactions surrounding SHCs and always-on devices.</p><p>Finally, we contribute a set of design insights and opportunities informed by the preceding contributions. At a basic level, we foreground a core ethical design dilemma: how-and to what extent-to support the needs and desires of primary users (and paying customer) in ways that are not invasive and harmful to non-primary users. While this dilemma represents a complex, wicked problem [104] that defies any clear solution, we outline several promising and under-considered directions for future design activity, including non-primary user side controls, shared and negotiated controls, and latent interactive controls and safeguards.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">BACKGROUND AND RELATED WORK</head><p>Our study sits at the intersection of four areas: <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref> consumer IoT and smart home devices, (2) privacy, security, and surveillance studies, (3) design research, and ( <ref type="formula">4</ref>) what some have recently referred to as FATE: fairness, accountability, transparency, and ethics in artificial intelligence (AI), machine learning (ML), and data science.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Related Empirical Studies in IoT</head><p>Recent work has empirically studied how people use a range of IoT devices, including voice assistants and smart speakers <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">16]</ref>, smart home automation <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">77,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">90]</ref>, home resource management tools <ref type="bibr" target="#b120">[132]</ref>, and experimental design prototypes <ref type="bibr">[53,</ref><ref type="bibr">127]</ref>. Other related areas of study include telepresence <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[73,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b97">103]</ref> and video communication <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[23,</ref><ref type="bibr">85]</ref>. IoT researchers have also notably studied issues of privacy and security <ref type="bibr">[136,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b125">137]</ref> in the context of Internet connected toys <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">[89]</ref> and smart speakers <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[80,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">86]</ref>. Some researchers have evaluated privacy perspectives with existing and novel camera technologies. For instance, Machuletz et al. discuss how the use of integrated webcam covers is dependent on user's attitudes and perceived control over maintaining their privacy [85]. Hoyle et al. also examine how wearable camera users weigh factors such as time and location to manage their privacy and to determine the sensitivity of footage captured on their lifelogging device <ref type="bibr" target="#b63">[69]</ref>.</p><p>Other empirical studies with IoT have specifically analyzed surveillance technologies. For instance, Kozubaev et al.'s work with smart technology in public housing addresses the effects of surveillance cameras in semi-public spaces, and they discuss how surveillance technologies can further exacerbate racial and economic inequalities <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[78]</ref>. Some have critically studied carceral surveillance technologies and individuals living under state surveillance <ref type="bibr" target="#b70">[76,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b90">97,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b99">107,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b112">121]</ref>. In <ref type="bibr" target="#b90">[97]</ref>, Owens et al.'s investigation on the surveillance of communication with family members of incarcerated people reveals participants' varied understandings of the extent that they are being surveilled by certain technologies, such as cameras for monitoring in-person visitation. They also assess participants' privacy concerns, attitudes, and assumptions amidst increased surveillance (highlighting the relational consequences of increased forms of monitoring and surveillance like location tracking, for example). Under admittedly different contexts, we explore similar concepts regarding users' assumptions and dynamic privacy dependencies with the smart camera as a surveillance technology. We further consider how commercial applications of pervasive technology systems afford increasing surveillance uses by creating a panoptic gaze through enabling novel sensing mechanisms.</p><p>Researchers have additionally investigated smart home and consumer IoT technologies with an eye toward the effects of surveillance on nearby others. Prior work has pointed to potentially invasive effects of common smart sensing devices on bystanders <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[48,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b121">133]</ref> and non-primary users <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[80,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b96">102]</ref>. Other work has studied bystander privacy in public spaces with phones and smart glasses <ref type="bibr">[41,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b105">113]</ref> and with drones <ref type="bibr">[134]</ref>. For example, with augmented reality glasses, bystanders express an interest in mechanisms for blocking recording and for supporting permission negotiations <ref type="bibr">[41]</ref>. Likewise, bystanders' reactions to publicly being recorded are dependent on multiple factors, such as their gender, surroundings, and what activity is captured <ref type="bibr" target="#b105">[113]</ref>. And as smart technologies blend the boundaries of public and private distinctions in the home <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">67]</ref>, it is further necessary to understand bystander privacy in domestic environments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Power Dynamics and Ethical Tensions</head><p>As such, IoT studies find privacy tensions arise between primary and non-primary users, and foreground unequal access and conflicting interests <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[33,</ref><ref type="bibr">136]</ref>. In the context of smart speakers and home voice assistants, Lau et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[80]</ref> discuss privacy tensions between users and incidental users of smart devices placed in common communal areas such as the living room. Pierce's design inquiry unpacks similar tensions in smart home cameras, highlighting "hole-and-corner" applications in which users' data and interactions are downplayed to them <ref type="bibr" target="#b95">[101]</ref>. This can lead to harmful and controversial uses, as Pierce describes in a speculative scenario with emotion tracking regulation for nannies, and is aligned with other work that addresses how abusers can exploit digital technologies in intimate partner violence contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">81]</ref>. Additionally, recent work highlights a need to study privacy and security practices and experiences of diverse and vulnerable users, including children <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">[89]</ref>, Airbnb guests <ref type="bibr" target="#b80">[87]</ref>, older adults <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b46">48]</ref>, and subjects of cyber harassment, domestic violence, and hate speech <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">20,</ref><ref type="bibr">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b81">88]</ref>. While work in privacy and security has begun to address the privacy needs of different populations (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[44,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">66,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b98">105,</ref><ref type="bibr">109,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b117">128]</ref>), such understandings are still nascent, incomplete and, in many cases, have not been translated into adequate solutions and recommendations.</p><p>More generally, a broader discourse concerning the ethics of IoT, AI, and surveillance has emerged within HCI and sciencetechnology-society (STS), among other adjacent fields. With regards to privacy and security, scholars have theorized ways of understanding threats and harms of digital data in terms of contextual integrity <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">[94]</ref>, surveillance capitalism <ref type="bibr" target="#b126">[138]</ref>, racialized surveillance <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[22]</ref>, and the effects of digitizing video surveillance <ref type="bibr">[60]</ref>. Sociotechnical scholars discuss notions of governmentality, accountability, and ethics with algorithmic [8, <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">54,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b73">79]</ref> , smart sensing <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">58]</ref> and cloud-based systems <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">70]</ref>. Furthermore, the data-driven and pervasive modes of computing that are central to IoT can obscure legibility to its users. Recent efforts for open and fair IoT data literacy <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[38,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b47">49]</ref> raise concern about the pervasive connectivity of IoT devices, and how IoT can amplify challenges related to privacy and ethics <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b103">111]</ref>. A prominent line of STS and cultural studies scholarship has challenged scientific and engineering understandings of data as objective or neutral, describing instead how it may be uncertain <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr">43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">62]</ref>, heterogenous <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr">42]</ref>, and local [84].</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Studies Involving Home Security Cameras</head><p>Various research on home surveillance and internet-connected cameras have prefigured many frontiers for today's complex smart camera interactions. For example, prior work with internet-connected home security cameras and smart locks suggests ways to alleviate potential privacy concerns from teens and parents through outsourcing the auditing of home entry data logs to companies or through technology-assisted facial recognition features <ref type="bibr">[123]</ref>. Early research directions also explore the concept of sharing camera data between neighbors <ref type="bibr">[24]</ref>. Furthermore, studies with home surveillance cameras reveal how initial anxieties and concerns regarding privacy gradually wane over time as users become accustomed to their presence <ref type="bibr" target="#b89">[96]</ref>. As the smart camera has since evolved with robust tracking, sensing, and data sharing capabilities, these features further complicate past findings about the potential ways that surveillance cameras can affirm or realign power relations within households and communities.</p><p>However, despite the vast empirical research on IoT, surveillance technologies, and domestic sensing and security devices, our literature review found few examples of qualitative empirical studies primarily focused on smart home cameras. Ahmad et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> examine tangible privacy perceptions with non-owners of the Nest security camera and the Amazon Echo Show, a smart voice assistant with video sensing capabilities. Their interviews demonstrated a general uncertainty regarding devices' on and off states, which can be further complicated with possible tensions of navigating interpersonal solutions for preserving bystander privacy without tangible feedback that the device may still be recording them. A self-use study of smart cameras by Pierce et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b94">[100]</ref> identified several prominent trust and controls issues for both primary and non-primary users, including "not trusting it's OFF," "forgetting it's ON," and "lack of control options"-such as unreliable indicator lights, lack of physical controls, and lack of granular controls. We extend findings about bystanders' perceptions of video and audio recording sensing devices through specifically analyzing primary users' motivations and uses across various smart security cameras, in addition to their perceptions about the social dynamics of operating such devices.</p><p>Other empirical investigations with the smart camera examine its risks alongside other IoT or internet-connected devices <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">55,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">87,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b110">118]</ref>. These studies describe the smart camera with respect to the different power relations that it enables amongst other smart home devices in the context of families, multi-user home settings, and in temporary homes between Airbnb hosts and renters. For example, Chalhoub et al.'s longitudinal analysis of smart systems highlights how repurposing such technology for other purposes can lead to potential misuse by exacerbating power imbalances within households <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[29]</ref>. Mentioning two households who have repurposed their smart cameras for entertainment, parenting, and streaming uses, they discuss how a loss of control and debates over ownership of video footage can arise between different family members.</p><p>Likewise, researchers have described different methods for confronting or diffusing these power dynamics through how such technologies novel interpretations and feminist orientations <ref type="bibr">[68,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b110">118]</ref>. At the company level, researchers find that one goal of smart device designers is to ensure that the technologies like smart cameras are not perceived as "creepy" or "intrusive" <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[28]</ref>. Some of these emerging design potentials, including dystopian provocations of surveillance in smart cameras, have been explored through design research approaches such as design inquiry <ref type="bibr" target="#b95">[101]</ref> and research through design (RtD) <ref type="bibr" target="#b96">[102,</ref><ref type="bibr">120,</ref><ref type="bibr">127]</ref>.</p><p>As a result, our study calls attention to the standalone smart camera as a unique form of IoT that requires dedicated analysis. Specifically, our contributions of different surveillance categories and power asymmetries complement related work with understanding complex social dynamics surrounding IoT devices, from intrahousehold relationships to smart home companies. Furthermore, although privacy and security represent a focus of our study, it is not the sole focus. We seek to more broadly understand the various uses and experiences of these increasingly popular, pervasive, and potentially invasive devices. And while our work is informed by and directed towards HCI design research and RtD, our research adopts a qualitative empirical approach to investigate user experiences and practices, along with social tensions and power dynamics, connected to the consumer smart home camera.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHODS</head><p>We conducted semi-structured interviews over Zoom (with 1 inperson interview) with 14 geographically and experientially diverse smart home camera users in the United States. This study was approved by our university's Institutional Review Board, and participants gave formal consent to participating in our study before engaging in the interview. Interviews were 60-90 minutes each, and participants were compensated $50. In these semi-structured interviews, we asked participants about their experiences, thoughts, and current practices with smart cameras. We discussed their use cases, mental models, household dynamics, and other factors they consider when interacting with cameras. With each participant, we conducted a device tour-either virtually or, in one case, inperson-where participants walked us through the different smart cameras in their home, discussing the reasons why they obtained the cameras, where they placed them, and how they used them. Beforehand, we asked participants to send us photographs of their devices in context (in lieu of any potential technical difficulties with conducting the device tour over Zoom). After, we probed further about participants' data practices, assumptions, and privacy practices. Examples of interview questions include: "What kinds of information do you collect through or with this device?", "Have you ever shared videos or information from your camera with others? If so, what did you share and why?", "What do you do when guests or others come over?", and "Have you ever had an argument over the device? With neighbors, family members, or others?".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Study Participants</head><p>We recruited participants from across the United States through social media posts, online forums, and email lists such as posts on smart home camera subreddits and Craigslist. We selected participants based on criteria from our screener survey. We generally sought participants with more than one camera, and with variance across several categories including age, race, number of cameras, living situation, location (rural versus urban), level of engagement (casual users, new users, sustained users, power users), and variety and regularity of reported uses. Our investigation also included two non-primary users-users who interacted with SHCs, but who did not directly install the cameras themselves. We provide an overview of our participants in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Analysis</head><p>Data analysis was an ongoing, iterative process throughout the course of the study. Field notes were reviewed immediately following an interview and tentative insights and themes noted in reflective field logs and memos <ref type="bibr">[57]</ref>. The team met periodically to debrief, share notes, and generate and record tentative themes. We transcribed all our interviews using the transcription service Temi. Following transcription, we conducted analysis according to a modified grounded theory coding scheme, overall employing an iterative process of searching for emergent patterns and themes <ref type="bibr">[92]</ref>. Once we had completed all interviews, we began by initially coding data according to emergent themes and guided by our memos. We then refined and organized these codes according to larger thematic categories. More specifically, we first focused on clustering participant descriptions of their SHCS uses and later, by emergent overarching categories (e.g., "gaining a better view", "spotting animals", "keeping an eye on kids", "watching over loved ones"). After solidifying these initial categories, we iteratively coded transcript data to eventually arrive at high-level themes, including categories of use, surveillance, trust, and concern for others. Writing and sharing the themes within our research team constituted a final stage in our analysis.</p><p>During the course of this study, we also reviewed hundreds of product instructional and promotional images (see Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>), monitored our local Ring Neighbors and Nextdoor social media apps (where users frequently share and request video footage pertaining to incidents such as minor trespassing, stalking, burglaries, and package thieves, also known as "porch pirates"). We also purchased, used, and familiarized ourselves with several smart cameras, including the Nest Indoor, Nest IQ Indoor, Wyze Indoor, Yi Indoor, Amazon Ring doorbell, and Blink smart home cameras.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">STUDY BACKGROUND AND OVERVIEW</head><p>Here, we present an overview of smart cameras and our study findings. To aid the reader in contextualizing our findings, we offer a short primer on the form, function, and operation of the SHC products used by our participants. While these features represent the "state of the art" at the time of this study, it is important to note that the functional offerings of these and related devices will continue to expand significantly-particularly with regards to object recognition capabilities (e.g., "animal seen" and "package removed" alerts). Following this guide, we then outline a high-level summary of the various key concepts from our findings, including various categories of SHC use and everyday surveillance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Product Onboarding: A Short Guide to Smart Home Cameras</head><p>Smart home cameras offer users a variety of novel features, the most common of which include cloud recording, cloud-based video histories and timelines, smart alerts with motion detection, real-time video and audio feeds, and two-way voice intercom communication. Some SHCs offer motion detection, object detection, person detection, and facial recognition features that identify familiar and unfamiliar faces. Additionally, some SHCs allow users to set activity zones to focus these filters on specific areas, while ignoring others.</p><p>In contrast to older video security surveillance technologies, SHCs are supported by cloud-based applications that enable live video feeds, automated monitoring, and simplified review and storage capabilities. A paid subscription upgrade is often required to unlock some of these features. The unique cloud components and intelligent detection features of SHCs increase the functionality of home security cameras by providing the ability for users to monitor different facets of their environment through a smartphone app and receive automated notifications when events like motion or unfamiliar faces are detected. One major advertised value of SHCs are relevant activity notifications, such as a person making a loud noise, thus relieving users of a need to constantly monitor or painstakingly review hours of video footage.</p><p>SHCs exist in a variety of form factors, including indoor, outdoor, and doorbell cameras. Others include Pan-Tilt-Zoom (PTZ) features that integrate with motion detection (e.g., the Wyze Cam Pan), and anthropomorphic, decorative, or camouflaged camera housings (See Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">2</ref>, lower right, for an example of a camera decorated with a hat). Most are distinguished by their small and sleek design, often blending into the environment (Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Findings Overview</head><p>We organize our findings into three sections. First, we describe how and why participants use smart home cameras, with an emphasis on the range of uses and motivations. We then extend these findings to characterize them as surveillant uses. See Table <ref type="table">2</ref> for a summary table of the various key categories of use and surveillance we identify. Finally, we refine our analysis of surveillance by reporting on types of asymmetric user relations we uncovered with significant implications for privacy, security, trust, and power: frontend versus backend uses, and primary versus non-primary users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">MORE THAN CAMERAS, MORE THAN HOME SECURITY DEVICES: HOW PRIMARY USERS ARE USING SMART HOME CAMERAS</head><p>In this section, we describe the range of smart home camera uses reported by participants. We find that while many users were initially attracted to smart home security cameras for a specific use-often through specific home safety or security applications-all participants reported using these devices in multiple ways to support a wide range of everyday activities. Commonly described conventional home security and safety applications included catching and deterring intruders, thieves, vandals, and negligent caretakers, as well as providing general "peace of mind" (P4), "just in case anything suspicious happens" (P9). While most participants cited these types of conventional home security and safety applications as an initial, and often primary, motivations for adopting SHCs, all participants mentioned engaging in many additional activities with their SHCs such as checking in on pets, greeting and receiving guests, confirming and managing deliveries, keeping an eye on kids, casually spying on neighbors, and reviewing footage of oneself, others, their home, and their neighborhood out of curiosity or without a clear, singular aim.</p><p>To better understand this range of uses, we identify several general smart camera capabilities that surfaced across participants, and Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref>: Example SHC products, features, and marketing depictions. Top row: Several popular brands of smart cameras used by participants in our study, including the Eufy outdoor camera, Wyze indoor camera, Google Nest and Amazon Ring doorbell cameras, and the Wyze Cam Pan, which can be rotated remotely from the app. Middle row: Several popular and innovative SHC features, like the timeline history view, activity zones, live feed, and smart alerts-all accessed via the manufacturer's smartphone app. Bottom row: Several official promotional images portraying various marketed use cases indoors, with kids, pets, babies, package deliverers, guests, funny moments (a child attempting to steal a piece of cake), and outdoors.</p><p>which enable HCI researchers and designers to better understand the full extent to which individuals use these systems. First, we identify cameras as extended sensory perception devices, based on the basic capabilities participants described using. We then report four additional, action-oriented categories of use enabled by this extended sensory perception: behavioral deterring, communicating, documenting, and device actuating. We conclude by describing some of the latent perceptual, actional, and affective effects of smart home cameras, namely avoiding SHC sensor fields, feeling pressure from SHC surveillance, and acclimating to SHC surveillance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Smart Home Cameras as Extended Sensory Perception Devices</head><p>Below, we present several examples depicting how participants commonly use smart home cameras to extend their 'naked' sensory perception [71] of their surroundings. In these sections, we first discuss several directed modes of extended sensory perception, wherein individuals monitor camera data with a relatively clear intention or expected outcome. We report on three sets of directed engagement: anticipatory monitoring, focal monitoring, and retrospective review. In contrast to these directed forms of engaging with SHCs, we also discuss several examples of undirected monitoring and reviewing, in which participants engage with camera data without a clear or singular purpose. Then, we discuss how participants describe what we refer to as the mere-potential for Anticipatory monitoring (Watching over and watching out for)</p><p>Using smart home camera systems to remotely monitor the environment to watch out for specific events (e.g., keeping an eye on children elsewhere, being aware if a loved one falls, or monitoring package deliveries).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Focal monitoring (Looking into and getting perspective)</head><p>Attentively observing live video or audio to actively monitor events (as opposed to peripherally viewing or momentarily checking footage).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Retrospective review (Knowing and evidencing what happened)</head><p>Using the smart camera to review past events to know or evidence what happened. Examples include traffic accidents, thefts, and trespassing; spotting animals; catching negligence or abuse; and settling disputes. Undirected monitoring (Casually checking, peeking, and spying) Monitoring without a clear or singular instrumental purpose, such as monitoring driven by curiosity or a desire to connect with others, such as checking on pets and animals or spying on neighbors.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Types of interpersonal and cross-device actuation uses (see Section 5.2)</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SHCs as Behavioral Deterrents</head><p>Using the smart camera to deter harmful, improper, annoying, or illegal behavior. SHCs as Interpersonal Communication Communicating with visitors and workers, co-dwellers, or pets with the smart camera.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SHCs as Documentation Devices</head><p>Documenting smart camera footage for reminiscence, sharing moments, or video requests (e.g., investigating a hit and run).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>SHCs as Device Actuation Systems</head><p>Configuring the smart home camera to deliver text or email notifications, or to automatically capture certain video/audio.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Types of surveillance in smart home cameras (see Section 6)</head><p>Deterrent and Regulating Surveillance Surveillance to deter or regulate behaviors (typically of others).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Managerial Surveillance</head><p>Surveillance to manage and oversee paid workers, e.g., tradespeople or domestic workers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Care-based Surveillance</head><p>Surveilling loved ones to better care for them, or as an outward expression of care. Diagnostic and Evidentiary Surveillance Surveillance to diagnose the cause or effect of an event, or as evidence (often in conjunction with deterrent, managerial, or care-based uses).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cuing Surveillance</head><p>Surveillance to anticipatorily notify users of events that may require specific action, such as receiving a package or greeting a guest.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Aesthetic and Atelic Surveillance</head><p>Surveillance because it is intriguing, beautiful, shocking (aesthetic surveillance); and/or without a clear instrumental purpose (atelic surveillance) monitoring, and mere-potential reviewing to achieve desirable outcomes (e.g., having "peace of mind" or feeling in control of their home).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.1">Anticipatory Monitoring: Watching Over and Watching Out</head><p>For. Overall, participants described using their SHC systems to watch over loved ones, pets, workers, and areas of their homes while they were occupied with other activities elsewhere. Participants also described using SHC systems to watch out for specific events, such as a loved one falling (P1, P4) or a package arriving (P1, P2, P3, P7, P8, P11, P13). These and other examples of anticipatory monitoring involve the use of SHCs to monitor the environment for specific events. Typically, participants used automated smartphone alerts, such as motion or person detection, to aid in anticipatory monitoring, thus removing the need to focally monitor the live video or audio feeds.</p><p>Most cases of anticipatory monitoring we uncovered involved doorbell cameras or cameras directed at outside entryways. Beyond mere awareness, anticipatory monitoring was frequently described as valuable for prompting or cuing users to take specific action or inaction. For example, P8 described regularly using an entryway SHC to receive an indication when a guest is parking or walking up to her doorway so that she can put her dog away before he starts barking. For her, these few additional moments make a big difference as they allow her to prevent her dog from causing a scene and more pleasantly greet a guest. (Note, however, that other participants found that a lag-time of several seconds between event and notification prevented them from responding to certain events; for example, by the time they received an alert someone had already left.)</p><p>Another common use of anticipatory monitoring we observed is parents using smart cameras to keep an eye on their children. P10 described how she places an indoor camera near her three kids while working elsewhere around the home because she "doesn't have extra eyes or ears." In such cases, a few participants devised display configurations that allowed them to continuously peripherally watch over their children through the live camera feed while performing other tasks. P8 described and demonstrated how she positioned a Facebook Portal display screen next to her home office work computer to monitor her child playing outside (See Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">3</ref>) -thus creating a glanceable display akin to a virtual window (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[51,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">52]</ref>).</p><p>One participant, P4, uses smart cameras to anticipatorily monitor her husband who has Parkinson's disease. She described how SHCs enable her to keep an eye for any potential falls from a distance, allowing her husband to maintain his autonomy ("without making him think that I'm hovering over him" physically). P4 explained the labor involved with monitoring her spouse before she had cameras: "I'd be running drinks to him every 30 minutes. . . Now with cameras, she says, "I'm [still] micro-managing but it's at ease." Reflecting on the overall value of cameras, P4 expresses, "All I know is that smart home cameras provide something that I can't-I can't be a watchman 24 hours a day." Thus, anticipatory monitoring mediates a variety of temporal expectations: tracking certain future events (e.g. package deliveries), and managing care and concern around events that may happen (e.g. falls or harm).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.2">Focal</head><p>Monitoring: Looking into and Getting Perspective. A second mode of engagement with SHCs we observed is focal monitoring, wherein a user attentively observes live video or audio to focally monitor what is happening, rather than peripherally viewing or momentarily checking. Instances of focal monitoring were often described as short duration events, typically just long enough to assess what is happening. For example, participants described scenarios where anticipatory monitoring transitioned to short-duration focal monitoring, such as watching the doorbell camera video long enough to assess who is at the door and determine whether to answer or ignore them. Longer duration viewing was, in general, less mentioned by participants and typically constrained to retrospective review of past data, which we discuss later.</p><p>Two participants described exceptional or infrequent acts of focal monitoring that involved longer duration viewing. P8 described how at night she will sometimes hear a noise and then watch the live feeds from their multiple indoor and outdoor cameras to monitor what is happening, even though she "know[s] it's probably nothing" and "it never is [anything of alarm]" P3 demonstrated how she remotely repositions and angles the camera to eavesdrop on conversations outside. Both examples illustrate how SHCs may enable users to gain a better perspective on nearby activities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.3">Retrospective Review: Knowing and Evidencing</head><p>What Happened. Participants described many instances where they engaged in retrospective review of video and audio recordings, along with metadata such as timestamps and filtered events (e.g., motion, a person, a loud sound). Later we discuss retrospective reviewing related to reminiscence, managing workers, and curiosity-driven engagement. Below we present several other examples, ranging from serious to playful.</p><p>Neighborhood traffic accidents, thefts, and trespassing. Some participants used smart cameras to document, evidence, or solve unexplained crimes. For example, P5 reviewed their SHC video when someone trespassed and tried to break into his house and learned that it was his neighbor's son. He subsequently used this evidence to confront his neighbor.</p><p>Spotting animals. Many participants reported spotting animal activity with their smart cameras. Several participants discussed rare and awe-inspiring recordings, including spotting a wolf and coyote on their patio (P11), a bald eagle eating their chickens (P11), and a bear walking through their residential neighborhood (P8). These and other participants typically indicated that animal spotting was a valued and sometimes regular use of their smart cameras.</p><p>Catching negligence and abuse. One participant (unnamed for privacy purposes) discussed how she uses the cameras to check up on her daughter and daughter's caregiver. She explained a complicated situation wherein she used her SHCs to identify an act of abuse by the caregiver, which we refrain from detailing for privacy reasons. This participant described how SHCs were especially valuable for monitoring caregivers, to help prevent or identify possible future cases of abuse or negligence.</p><p>Settling disputes. In at least three cases, participants reported using smart camera recordings to settle interpersonal disputes with neighbors or family. P11 relayed an initial event where he told his nephew, whom he suspected was lying to him, that they would "check the cameras" to confirm if his side of the story was true. Over time, this became a pattern in which P11 would occasionally threaten his nephew by saying, "let's check the cameras", when, for example, he suspected the nephew was lying about finishing a household chore. P11 later began using this warning with his own children, although he eventually stopped doing so due to conflicted feelings about this emergent SHC use to threaten and settle family disputes: "I didn't want to use [the smart camera] as a weapon. " 5.1.4 Undirected Monitoring and Review: Casually Checking, Peeking, and Spying. Participants also described several use cases involving partially or predominantly undirected monitoring and review, which seemed to lack a clear instrumental purpose or outcome. Often participants suggested these were driven by curiosity, a desire to connect with family or pets, or possibly anxiety or habituation. Later we elaborate on these and related uses as aesthetic and atelic surveillance. Below we note two commonly reported areas of undirected monitoring.</p><p>Checking on pets and animals. Several participants used SHCs to check on pets (P2, P3, P4, P8, P10), especially when they were away from their homes. A few participants specifically set up additional cameras for this purpose-for example, checking on their puppy while away from work (P2) and monitoring their chicken coop and horses (P11).</p><p>Casually spying on neighbors. Participants also described undirected monitoring to casually spy (our term) on neighbors, often described as an accidental or opportunistic activity, rather than premeditated. For example, two participants, P3 and P13, expressed how they semi-regularly liked to listen in on conversations between neighbors, even though they both do not usually talk to their neighbors. P13 referred to this as "people watching" through the smart camera.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1.5">Mere-Potential Monitoring and Review: I can-but I haven't.</head><p>In the uses reported above, participants described actual, immediate engagement with SHC sensor data and visual, auditory, and textual representations thereof. Distinct from, yet intimately related to this actual monitoring and reviewing, participants sometimes described a value of SHCs in terms of a mere-potential for monitoring or reviewing events that had not actually occurred, had not been captured, or which they had not yet viewed. Participants described the value of these mere-potential sensory-perceptual capabilities when frequently discussing events that might happen: "I could use this to check on [if my older dad falls]" (P1); "I saved a lot of footage of [the neighborhood children] coming near my property, just to have it, to show ongoing harassment [to police]" (P10) (emphases added). Some participants also referenced capturing a single event that validated their installation of the smart camera and their continued use of the device. For instance, P11 explained that he initially installed SHCs for security purposes and, while friends called him "crazy" at first, his cameras transitioned from the mere-potential to actual review of video footage when someone had broken into his home.</p><p>A common framework used in qualitative analysis when describing examples of uses and behaviors is to identify mismatches between what participants say they do and what they actually do. We agree, but offer an additional interpretation to this duality: SHC users meaningfully and consciously use the mere-potential for monitoring and reviewing to achieve senses of safety, security, control, and power. Which is to say, potential uses appear to be a very real and valuable use of smart cameras, and surveillance apparatuses in general.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">From Personal Extension of Sensory Perception to Interpersonal and Cross-Device Interaction</head><p>Our previous examples demonstrated how cameras are used to enhance people's sensation and perception of their environment.</p><p>In this section, we highlight four additional general capabilities of smart cameras that build upon extended sensory perception in ways that effect specific types of responses in other people or devices: behavioral deterrence, interpersonal communication, documentation, and device actuation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1">Smart Home</head><p>Cameras as Behavioral Deterrents. Unsurprisingly, given the design and marketing of these devices as smart home security cameras, one of the most cited uses of smart home cameras among our participants was to deter harmful, improper, annoying, or illegal behavior. Throughout the paper, we report many examples in which participants describe or allude to behavioral deterrence as a primary use and value of their SHCs. The most reported target of behavioral deterrents was to inhibit trespassing, intrusion, theft, vandalism, and related forms of harmful activity from predominantly unknown and unexpected persons. Some participants also described using SHCs to deter negative behavior from specific neighbors, family members, guests, and domestic workers. Whereas a parent in our study described SHCs as "extra eyes and ears" (P10), another participant described the devices as a "friendlier" form of "bars on the window" (P9).</p><p>To function as an effective deterrent, participants often described the importance of installing cameras with sufficient visibility to deter potential intruders. At the same time, these participants often noted a counterbalancing need for inconspicuous placement that does not draw the alarm or disdain of neighbors who might vandalize or negatively judge the SHC owner. P14, for example, feared that if her cameras were too visible then her neighbors might vandalize it. P2, whose camera has a floodlight sensor that lights up at night based on motion, elaborated on how his camera's form factor needed to be conspicuous, not only to deter intruders, but also to visually communicate to others that he was not using it for stealth purposes: "The smaller the camera, the more [it's] like a spy or nanny cam. I don't want to be secretly recording anybody and I don't want it to be a surprise. I got the cameras for security. The more obvious that it is, the better security it provides. . . No one's going to walk in and think that there's no camera, it's like this giant light turns on. " -P2 These responses suggest a tacit camera placement principle: just conspicuous enough to deter, but not so conspicuous as to stand out in a way that might be negatively perceived. For some participants, this balance was more important than to others.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.2">Smart</head><p>Home Cameras as Interpersonal (and Interspecies) Communication Devices. Some participants used their smart home cameras to support two-way communication through the built-in voice intercom feature or, in a few cases, in conjunction with smartphone text or voice communication. We found three main groups that participants frequently reported communicating or attempting to communicate with.</p><p>Communicating with visitors and workers. Participants described using their SHCs to communicate with delivery workers. This enabled P4, for example, to interact with delivers while she's away from her home; "You can just say, 'Oh, I'm busy right now. I can't come to the door, leave the package on the side. "' The ability to communicate via the SHC helped P4 feel more at ease answering the door: "That's one aspect I like about the Ring doorbell. They don't know you're home [you could be communicating with them remotely from anywhere]. "</p><p>Communicating with co-dwellers. Participants described using the built-in voice intercom in conjunction with the camera to communicate with their kids or spouses, either when they were away from home or in separate rooms. P11 describes how communication with and visibility of his family were primary motivators for adopting indoor SHCs: "So the initial [reason I adopted SHCs] was just, I could hit a button and say 'hi' to my girls. I can hit a button and talk to my wife rather than have to call her. And I like my house. I like my family. It's nice to be able to hit a button and see them. " At times, P11 more specifically uses his SHCs to visually check when his kids were not responding to his text messages, and then getting their attention by using it as an intercom. Other participants reported using SHC communication features in playful ways, including using the intercom to scare family members (P9, P10) or pets (P3).</p><p>Communicating with pets. Many participants used SHCs to monitor pets, and a few described specific instances of using SHCs to communicate, or attempt to communicate, with pets. P4 communicates with her dog when she is away from home through setting her Echo Show on a chair to check on him: "I can drop in and see my dog, and my dog can see me." Likewise, P3 explained that she uses her Nest Cam "when her cats accidentally leave the house [to] call them in." P3 also described one notable case when she used her SHC to find a lost cat through its audio features, deducing that her cat was in her neighbor's yard through hearing it meow on the camera feed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.3">Smart Home Cameras as Documentation Devices.</head><p>Participants further indicated the value of SHCs as documentation tools that enabled them to archive and share recorded events with others. Later, we elaborate on two types of surveillant uses related to documentation: surveillant memory-making and evidentiary surveillance. We illustrate three specific documentary applications below.</p><p>Reminiscence. Several participants described instances where they either deliberately or serendipitously reviewed documented audio and video of their lives in way that facilitated reminiscencethe enjoyable recollection of past events. P11 saved one sentimental video of his kids and mother-in-law walking together, and P14 reminiscing on videos captured by her SHC of and her children on family outings and at neighborhood festivals. These examples recall novel HCI design prototypes for enhancing and supporting reminiscence (e.g., <ref type="bibr">[99,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b123">135]</ref>).</p><p>moments. Several participants describing sharing morous, awe-inspiring, or otherwise memorable moments with friends or neighbors. For example, P2 described accessing the live feed of his backyard to show his garden jalapeño plants to his P8 recounted how she uploaded footage where her smart captured a bear in her neighborhood to YouTube, and also a humorous "highlights reel" of her son sleepwalking with other family members (which they later submitted to America's Funniest Home Videos). In other cases, participants described sharing videos with more serious evidentiary or disciplinary aims, as when P11 captured his friend's daughter getting into a fight on his smart camera, and shared it with his friend, the daughter's parent.</p><p>Video requests. In a few cases participants received requests from neighbors to review their camera data and send them any recordings. P8's neighbors requested her SHC footage of a bear rummaging through the trash, which "helped debug what was happening. " P8 further explained that her neighbors will rely on her and her smart camera as the neighborhood "point person": text me, 'Hey, can you see if this got caught on there?' . . [and I respond], 'Maybe you should get these cameras. "' 5.2.4 Smart Home Cameras as Device Actuation Systems. and actuation of other devices or systems is the final basic SHC capabilities we report. The most common example is configuring SHCs to deliver text or email notifications, or to automatically record video/audio. In common instances where users configured their cameras to send smartphone alerts that notify them when mosound, people, or familiar or unfamiliar faces are detected (P2, P3, P7, P8), SHC interfaces typically refer to these notifications as "events" or "moments, " and enable users to configure their devices automatically save events or moments to the cloud for retrospecreview and documentation. However, these capabilities often upgrading to paid subscriptions. The only other example device actuation that we identified from our interviews was the use of SHCs to control external lights to deter potential thieves or intruders (P2). No participants reported availing themselves of that enable control of built-in sirens or add-on smart power</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Clear Limitations and Subtle Effects of Current Smart Home Camera Products</head><p>Participants also noted several prominent limitations to their uses the SHCs and the types of extended sensory perception discussed above. Commonly cited pragmatic limitations include:</p><p>• Lack of robust recording or storage access. upgraded subscriptions typically expunge video recordings after 30 days, thus requiring that the user manually downloads relevant video clips within this period. Without a paid subscription, recording capabilities are even more limited. Irrelevant, inaccurate, and excessive smart alert notifiparticipants described motion, person, object, sound, and face alerts that were inaccurate or irrelevant. In some cases, participants consequently disabled notifications or became desensitized to them. • Practical obstacles to physically mounting, positioning, powering, and connecting the device. described difficulties positioning, repositioning, and indevices because of the effort and skill required to mount the devices to walls or ceilings and physically connect to a power source (currently, very few SHC products battery powered). Participants also described limited Wi-Fi coverage as a major obstacle at times, especially when installing outdoor SHCs away from home routers. Significant lag times when viewing live video/audio and receiving smart alert notifications, which at times prevented users from monitoring or recording pertinent events. For example, alerts typically lag events by at least seconds.</p><p>• achieving the right balance and targeting of device visibility/invisibility to others, especially with minimizing visibility of the devices for neighbors and passersby while maximizing visibility to potential intruders.</p><p>Later in the discussion section, we observe that these limitations clear opportunities to improve the user experience of for primary users. Meanwhile, we however observe more subtly that some of these limitations enhance privacy and security for non-primary users and thus also represent latent privacy controls and safeguards.</p><p>We conclude this section by noting several seemingly unintended side-effects of the extended sensory perception enabled by smart home cameras. (1) Avoiding camera fields. A few participants described how they consciously avoid the SHC's surveillant field of view. P3 walks to another block to say goodbye to friends or "people of the opposite gender, " as she is worried that her mother might watch or listen in on her with their SHC. P6, a food delivery driver, described parking away from cameras. (2) Subtle pressure/intrusion of surveillance. While this was reported in only a few cases (P6, P11), P11 memorably described feeling "subtle pressure" that caused him to be on his best behavior by, for example, not playing video games and staying productive at work. He explained that this pressure was partly based on knowledge that his mother-in-law-who lives with him and shares access to the SHC app-may be watching him. Interestingly, P11 describes reflecting on this "subtle pressure" only after he stopped using cameras during a move to another residence. Similar findings are reported by Pierce et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b96">[102]</ref>. (3) Acclimating to smart cameras. As participants cameras into their home, some reported becoming acto their use over time. P9 expressed that his "cameras are now like ornaments, " indicating that the novelty of playing around the smart camera's features wore off and that he now rarely directly engages his outdoor camera. Other participants, who lived with as many as one to ten indoor cameras, expressed no significant concerns about their privacy and security when asked. Our study suggests that some sizable portion of SHC users readily accept and rarely notice the near-constant surveillant gaze of cameras in their rooms, entryways, kitchens, yards, and even bedrooms.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>EVERYDAY SURVEILLANCE: FROM FORMAL OBSERVATION TO CASUAL</head><p>the previous section, we reported how participants used SHCs to sensory perception, deter undesirable behavior, communicate with others, document evidence, capture memories, and control smart devices to everyday activities. We now extend those findings by characterizing such uses as forms of surveillance. We loosely define surveillance in the more general sense of "the collection and storage of information, presumed to be useful, about or objects" <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[37]</ref>. Yet we also intend the term surveillance to read, at times, with the power-laden and potentially negative connotations associated with mass surveillance, carceral surveillance, spying, stalking, and so on. As our participants and scholars alike observe, surveillance-like any technology-is neither inherently good nor bad, but neither is it neutral <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[78]</ref>. As Rule states, "ranges from the benign to the repressive-from the personal information systems supporting intensive care in hospitals to those mobilized to track and curtail terrorists" [106].</p><p>This section examines how smart cameras mediate multiple modes of surveillance, a term we use in reference to any broadly surveillant use enabled by commonplace and accessible products and services within everyday contexts. We further find that these various surveillant uses occur along a spectrum from formal to casual surveillance, such as formally monitoring the home to deter intruders, to casually emergent forms of opportunistic, accidental, curiosity-driven, or one-off acts of surveillance. This spectrum is defined by three dimensions: premeditation, focus, and regularity. Formal surveillance is premeditated, it is focused with a specific aim or outcome, and it is often practiced on a regular basis. Casual surveillance, on the other hand, is some combination of unplanned, unfocused, or irregular, such as overhearing a neighbor's conversation.</p><p>Adding to insights from surveillance studies, our research-albeit based on a small sample of committed SHC users-contributes further empirical evidence to the idea is becoming more accepted and even normative mode of everyday one supports a much wider variety of activities than deterring, identifying, and punishing illegal or improper behavior. This includes surveillance as a mode of caring for others <ref type="bibr">[72,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b109">117]</ref>, managing labor <ref type="bibr" target="#b109">[117]</ref>, feeding obsession and paranoia <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[70]</ref>, maximizing monetary and social capital <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b126">138]</ref>, and tracking and regulating one's self <ref type="bibr">[56,</ref><ref type="bibr">83]</ref>.</p><p>organize our findings into six prominent types of surveillant uses of SHCs we identify: deterrent and regulating surveillance, managerial surveillance, care-based surveillance, diagnostic surveillance, cuing surveillance, and aesthetic and atelic surveillance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Deterrent and Regulating Surveillance</head><p>surveillance refers to instances where the threat of surveillance is used-often, we find, in a formal, premeditated manner-to deter behavior, particularly harmful, destructive, or invasive behavior such as theft, trespassing, and violence. More general than deterrent surveillance, regulating surveillance refers to uses that prompt or encourage the surveilled subject to self-regulate own behavior. For example, P11 described an emergent use of constant SHC surveillance to regulate his nephew and children's wherein he developed a habit of saying "let's check the cameras" when he suspected they may be lying. Both concepts of deterrent and regulatory surveillance are common concepts in surveillance literature (e.g., Foucault's disciplinary surveillance [46], Deleuze's control society <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[39]</ref>).</p><p>All participants indicated that deterrent surveillance was an important, if not sole motivation for installing SHCs and many suggested that their camera's core function was to provide security or Yet, over time, some participants also discovered emergent and more casual forms of deterrent surveillance. Many such cases deterred relatively minor or petty offenses, rather than egregious or deleterious behavior such as burglary or home invasion. For ex-P3 relayed that her mother noticed that neighbors stopped letting their "dogs poop in our yard" after installing the Nest camera, presumably because the dog owners noticed the camera. The example is a rare occurrence in which a participant referenced material evidence to confirm the effectiveness of deterrent As a basic observation, there is an inherent difficulty in verifying, on a case-by-case basis, to what extent SHCs deter rare or uncommon behaviors such as burglaries.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.2">Managerial Surveillance</head><p>Participants described various surveillant uses of SHC aimed at managing and overseeing paid workers, particularly tradespeople such as carpenters, delivery workers, and domestic workers includnannies, babysitter, caregivers, and housekeepers. Our naming this term informed by Stark and Levy's notion of the "consumer as manager" <ref type="bibr" target="#b109">[117]</ref>. Through analysis of contemporary smartphone applications, Stark and Levy argue that the "managerial logics of surveillance are proliferating across digitally mediated service enlisting customers as both managers and cheerleaders for themselves pressured systematic and metricized expectations also out of their control." Our findings appear to support broader cultural trend. However, our study focuses on how and why primary users engage in managerial surveillance-mediated through SHC extended sensory perception-and in some instances, offers a counter-perspective that highlights the value of managerial surveillance to the "consumer as manager. "</p><p>For example, one participant (P4) explains how she uses her cameras to monitor her daughter's caretakers in case she is misas well as if "anything goes missing. " For her, SHCs provide extra layer of protection. " This suggests how the consumer as manager may surveil workers casually, and via the mode of merepotential monitoring and review that we articulated previously. P12 going beyond mere-potential monitoring and review to engage in anticipatory, focal, and retrospective monitoring and her housekeeper and nanny to "check" to see if the nanny is "getting along" with her children: "If there are no cameras, you know what kind of behavior [they are] having around my kids. " Interestingly, while P12 does bring up disputes to the nanny about situations she saw on camera, she does so indirectly without that she was monitoring or reviewing the video footage her SHC. She explains that doing so would be "detrimental" to their working relationship.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.3">Care-based Surveillance</head><p>Participants described other instances where they surveilled loved ones to better care for them, or as an expression of their care. Stark and Levy refer to this more generally as the "conas observer," through which surveillant products are used to supervise "intimate relations as component of a normalized of care" <ref type="bibr" target="#b109">[117]</ref>. Our notion of care-based surveillance aligns even closer with Alan Jacobs' observation that "[digitally mediated] has become the normative form of care" within our <ref type="bibr">[72]</ref>.</p><p>surveillance of loved ones usually occurred while the participant was away from their home at work or traveling of town. Two commonly cited examples were checking on kids pets. For example, we previously discussed how P8 created a peripheral virtual window display to watch over her child playing outside in the cul-de-sac while she worked from her home office upstairs. In another example, P2 installed an indoor SHC to check on his puppy while away at work. While participants at times suggested that checking on pets was a form of anticipatory monitoring keep an eye on the dog, " in P2's case), they also described such monitoring as motivated by a desire to emotionally connect with pets when they are physically separated.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.4">Diagnostic and Evidentiary Surveillance</head><p>Diagnostic surveillance refers to the use of surveillant technologies to diagnose the cause or effect of an event. Evidentiary surveillance was often suggested in conjunction with deterrent, managerial, and care-based uses-such as helping identify an unsuccessfully deterred intruder or confronting a negligent caretaker. Here we present three brief sets of examples, which range from formal and to casual and playful. Evidencing crimes. Participants described a few instances where they provided local police with smart camera footage as evidence. P11 recounted a traumatic break in experience in which SHC footage helped them discover how the intruder had entered their home. P10 also discussed various instances where she used her smart camera footage to identify and provide evidence the police, such as a hit-and-run of a parked car, stolen bikes, an assault, and issues in the neighborhood.</p><p>Settling disputes. In several cases, participants used SHC data to help settle family or neighborhood disputes. Participants described reviewing their smart camera footage to discover evidence when kids fought with the family pet (P8) or with each other (P11), settling crime disputes related to theft and harassment from (P10). Reviewing remarkable, entertaining, or unexplained events. In contrast to the relatively high stakes disputes above, participants contrastingly presented many examples of fun, amusing, and sometimes sensational diagnostics and evidentiary video. Examples include retrospectively reviewing their video to find footage of a bear eating from their trash cans (P8), a video of an approaching tornado (P4), and a video of a family member being followed by their chickens (P11).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Cuing Surveillance</head><p>surveillance refers to when people use surveillance to anticinotify them of events that may require specific action. This type of surveillance involves the mode of anticipatory monitoring we discussed previously and is often enabled by smart alerts to detect motion, people, or familiar or unfamiliar faces. The doorway was the most common site in which participants described formally and regularly using cuing surveillance. Examples of cuing surveilinclude (1) knowing when an expected guest has arrived, as a cue to answer the door and sometimes to finish readying the home for example, kenneling dogs or putting kids to sleep (e.g., P3, P7, P14); (2) knowing when someone is at the door, as a cue to see there and decide whether and how to answer (e.g., P3, P4, and (3) knowing when a package has arrived, as a cue to take it in or sometimes to thank or confirm to the deliverer that it was (e.g., P4, P7, P8, P13). Some participants also mentioned surveilling disabled or older family members and kids, as a cue to help them if they fall or need assistance (e.g., P1, P4).</p><p>A few participants described comparatively unique types of cusurveillance that they regularly engaged in. For example, P4 a doorbell camera to know precisely when her daughter's spemedicine arrives, to ensure she refrigerates it before it spoils. These examples suggest how future smart cameras and sensing systems might enable even more personalized, ad-hoc, idiosyncratic modes of everyday surveillance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6.6">Aesthetic and Atelic Surveillance</head><p>surveillant use categories described thus far are usually directed a relatively clear aim or outcome. Yet we also uncovered inwhere SHC surveillance was discussed as predominantly or partially motivated by more emergent and less instrumental drives associated with curiosity, excitement, entertainment, reminiscence, and other experiences. We characterize such uses as a combination of aesthetic and atelic surveillance. Aesthetic surveillance occurs when users are inspired to sensuously engage with surveillant information because it is pleasing, intriguing, beautiful, shocking, so on. Atelic surveillance occurs when users apply surveillance technologies without a clear instrumental purpose or outcome, but rather a sense of emergent, momentary, or open-ended engagement.</p><p>describe several more specific variations below. Surveillant noticing. At a basic sensory level, aesthetic and surveillance sometimes appear to begin as merely a modified of everyday noticing akin to looking out the window or overhearing a conversation. For example, P13 recalls a time her SHC enabled her to watch various events or commotion on her street, citing small neighborhood parades to celebrate essential workers during the COVID-19 pandemic, "couples having arguments," or a bike being stolen. She explains, "If you catch it at interesting it's New York City, you'll always see something kind of like " However, in many other cases, such acts of noticing would been difficult if not impossible without the extended sensory of the SHC, such as remote viewing, recorded timeline histories, and smart alerts. Furthermore, the capabilities and affordances of the SHC system often shield the viewer from being observed by a surveilled subject.</p><p>surveillance. Several participants described casually observing behaviors and overhearing conversations of neighbors, passersby, friends, or even themselves. P3 describes occasional situations where the SHC prompts her to casually watch neighbors and passersby: "Sometimes if I stay up super late, I'll get notifications on my phone about motion detection, and I'll go, 'What the hell are people doing at or 12AM at night?' People are And if I'm up and want to see what's going on, I'll in on neighbors' conversations." P13 talked about hearing her neighbors' arguments, slamming doors, seeing might be storming out of the building "not to be nosy, but I guess also to be nosy. "</p><p>Reflexive surveillance. Surveillant noticing also led to deeper on the interplay between one's surveillant smart camera and environment. P8, for example, described how the smart recognition capability of her doorbell camera regularly mistook her friend's husband for her own husband because they dress similarly. P8 later shared this information with her friends in a humorous and her husband at one point even attempted at one point dress up as their friend to "spoof" the camera. This example how a surveillant noticing led to insight both about her own life and the inner workings of the camera.</p><p>Surveillant memory-making. Some participants described premeditated use of their smart home cameras in ways that closely approximated the typical usage of smartphone cameras or action cameras (such as a GoPro) to capture meaningful moments in their For example, P10 owns a Wyze camera that she moves to different places to monitor her kids throughout the house. P10 further on an instance in which she set up this camera specifically to document a Christmas scavenger hunt she had designed for her children. Participants also suggested a more novel form of video photography in which meaningful moments are inadvertently or unexpectedly caught on camera. In addition to examples of natural disasters and animal spotting previously reported, other examples include saving funny or memorable moments of P11's cat getting scared on camera, performing Brazilian jiu jitsu, and videos of his daughters calling each other funny names. These uses parallel use cases depicted in SHC marketing materials, such as Nest advertisewhich suggest cameras can be used to record a baby's first steps, for instance.</p><p>Self-reflective and self-conscious surveillance. In a few inparticipants described retrospectively reviewing video and audio of themselves and their interactions with others. P3 described when she reviews video of herself with friends to "just to see happened, " "to see how the interaction went, " and "to see how I look and stuff like that. "</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">TWO AXES OF ASYMMETRY FOR ANALYZING PRIVACY, SECURITY, TRUST, POWER</head><p>this final section of findings, we dig deeper into perceptual and power asymmetries with the smart camera, and their connection data privacy, security, and trust. We divide our reporting and analysis into two sections, each representing an axis of asymmetry: frontend users and backend users, and primary users and nonusers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1">Frontend and Backend Users</head><p>Studies of user privacy and security often focus on how companies malicious actors might use people's personal data. Here, we refine this notion by distinguishing between frontend users who own, install, and operate SHCs, versus companies, platforms, service providers, and other backend actors, notably malicious actors like hackers and cyberstalkers. A backend user is one who accesses a system and its data such that the frontend user is oblivious to or only peripherally aware of the backend user and their uses. Typically the backend user interfaces with this data via network connection, rather than, say, physical theft of a device. A prime example is a device company that accesses, shares, and utilizes frontend users' SHC data for reasons other than or in addition to directly providing feedback or value those frontend users. Reciprocally, a frontend user any user oblivious or only tangentially aware of backend users and uses of the data. While a backend user not necessarily nefarious or malicious, backend uses do often dovetail with Zuboff's concept of "surveillance capitalism" <ref type="bibr" target="#b126">[138]</ref>, and the related concept of "hole-and-corner applications" <ref type="bibr" target="#b95">[101]</ref> that are hidden from and potentially harmful to frontend users.</p><p>Below we describe our participants' awareness, attitudes, and practical orientations toward their own privacy, and toward backusers, specifically three main groups that repeatedly surface during our interviews: (1) companies, manufacturers, platforms, service providers, and "third parties", (2) hackers, cybercriminals, and other malicious actors, and (3) state and foreign authorities, including perceptions of interference by international governments and local police.</p><p>Steps Taken to Increase Privacy, Security, Trust, and Control. While most primary users did not express much concern about their data privacy and security regarding their SHCs, there were some exceptions. Some brought up concerns that "China" might have access to their data (P2, P11, P9). Others indicated differences in trust among brands to safeguard their personal data. P2, for mentioned how he did not trust Wyze because they are a Chinese company, and was wary of how cheap Wyze devices were: "It almost seems too good to be true. . someone's gotta be subsidizing the data or something." 1 To P2, "if it's free or cheap, are the product." P8, in contrast, mentioned that she and her husband are early Wyze Cam adopters, and wanted to support the because they are headquartered locally. Two participants expressed suspicion with Amazon and were wary of them using their SHC data for marketing purposes (P9, P11). P13 reflected that she "probably should" be more concerned about her data on the camera. Some participants did, however, take sophisticated technical steps to protect their privacy and security. One salient example was P11, who customized his camera system (which connects to his 25 smart home cameras) to operate only locally through a combination local SD card device storage and use of a custom app for managing their SHC data. Others decided to stop using devices. Out of concern Wyze's ability to record and save 24/7 footage inside his home (coupled with concerns already listed), P2 uninstalled the camera after spending more time it while working from home. The placement and installation of their cameras was the one notable area in which all participants expressed some level of distrust and concern for their privacy and and many participants highlighted areas where they disallowed SHCs. example, P7 and P9 were adamant that they would be uncomfortable with any indoor cameras. On the other hand, P4 and P8-who each live with multiple indoor smart cameras that are virtually always monitoringexpressed that their bathrooms and bedrooms were "off limits" areas for SHCs, but that anywhere else is fine. Similar to variance in how users manage boundaries with online privacy (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>), these findings suggest there also variance with how primary users conceptualize and manage boundaries respect to SHCs and IoT sensing devices more This finding is echoed in et al.'s longitudinal study of smart home where participants expressed varied and changing perspectives about their comfort level with microphone and camera devices in areas such as bathrooms and bedrooms <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[29]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.1.2">High Trust and Low Concern with Backend Users and Personal</head><p>Privacy and Security. had much to say about the various (frontend) uses of their SHCs but had comparatively less to say about backend users/uses and their personal data privacy and Only towards the later portion of our interview did we explicitly ask participants about privacy, security, and trust with respect to companies, hackers, and other backend users and uses of their data. Participants mostly expressed little concern for their own personal data privacy and security, though we discuss some notable exceptions further below. While participants noted various technical shortcomings of the cameras-including connectivity issues, video lag of seconds or minutes, and inaccurate or irrelevant notifications-participants rarely expressed distrust in the device manufacturers and service providers.</p><p>When asked about potential privacy or security concerns, our analysis of participant responses surfaced 6 types of reactions that may explain why they expressed little concern with privacy and security. We encapsulate each general reaction in first-person terms, and briefly exemplify each. (1) I have little to hide. When asked data privacy, P8 and her husband indicated they were "pretty boring" people and had "nothing to hide from" one another.</p><p>risk is very low. P1 described his chances of getting "hacked" as low, "because I'm not a high-profile person." The benefits outweigh any risks. P1, continuing from above, went on to say that he sees SHCs "as more helpful than the chance of getting hacked for something." P4 responded to our questions about privacy by "if I have to worry about [privacy], then I shouldn't have a camera", and described the importance of monitoring her caregivers ensure they were properly caring for her family. P3 explained her SHC use was motivated by a lack of trust in the police to protect her security and safety, stating that her Nest camera was more effective and trustworthy than local police. (4) I have sufficient control. P8 responded to our questions about privacy by emphasizing that none of her indoor cameras-even the active camera in her bedroom-are pointed at the bed to avoid capturing anything "intimate": "As long as they're not pointed at the bed, we're not concerned." (5) I hadn't thought of that. When asked about privacy regarding their data (P13) and consideration for their neighbors' privacy (P7), both responded that maybe they should be more conscious of this. (6) I only see what's in front of me. While no participants directly stated that they did not consider or concern themselves with backend privacy and security threats because these threats remained out of sight, this explanation is suggested in the preceding examples-namely that participants had much say about their firsthand of their SHCs but had little to say about actual or potential backend uses by companies, criminals, or governments. Furthermore, many participants insufficient or inaccurate technical knowledge about their SHCs and potential privacy and security implications, which we discuss below.</p><p>Limited Knowledge of Backend Uses and Implications for Privacy and Security. Consistent with Zheng et al.'s findings <ref type="bibr" target="#b125">[137]</ref>, participants in our study sometimes demonstrated incomplete or incorrect knowledge of backend and future system capabilities.</p><p>we present one instance that exemplifies how imprecise menmodels may be formed from interface features directly available to the user (frontend capabilities), without considering how a company may independently access, store, analyze, and share user data (backend capabilities). P2 notes that Amazon Ring requires an uppaid subscription to record videos and save them to the cloud, and uses this to infer how Amazon is handling his data: "[Knowing that Amazon requires a paid subscription] is good for me because it means that it's not being recorded somewhere else. . . I mean, if they had the being saved, I assumed that they would just give to you for free as, like, a service. But if you're not them, they're probably just not recording any-" -P2</p><p>Here, P2 reasons that what he sees on his smartphone interface any backend processing that might be "recorded somewhere else": While we cannot know with certainty to what extent P2's SHC data (and metadata) are in fact being stored and analyzed by Amazon, this example illustrates the temptation to infer that backend capabilities are limited to the frontend interfaces one can see and use-even though this technically is often not the case. Following Kahneman's concept of the WYSIATI bias (What You Is All There Is) [74], we refocus this idea to hypothesize a specific bias about digital user interfaces, especially with cloud comapplications: WYSOYIATI-What You See On Your Interface Is There Is. The correct mental model, however, is See Is Just Your Interface. Which is to say, your user interface application is just your interface (but there are also interfaces and applications).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2">Primary Users, Non-Primary Users, and</head><p>Interpersonal Power Asymmetries we focus on the second prominent power differential: the relationship between primary users and non-primary users. In the context of our study, primary users are those own, install, and operate consumer SHC products. Non-primary users are those who, at some level, interact with SHCs but do so with comparatively limited access, control, feedback, consent, awareness, or benefit, and often with increased associated risk or harm. This notion of a non-primary is more general than a bystander, in that it captures situations where someone with partial consent awareness of device's presence interacts with it (e.g. a delivering a package, or a visiting and noticing a camera is present). The concept of a non-primary user addresses where a subject is not an innocent or accidental bystander, but rather an intended of surveillance. In some scenarios, SHCs sense or surveil completely unaware and non-consenting subjects, which we follow Baumer <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref> and may qualify such subjects as rather than users. For simplicity, in this we often refer to non-primary users and usees collectively as non-primary users. (Note that the primary and non-primary we reference are both frontend users with respect to the backend actors we discussed previously-companies, cybercriminals, and government actors.) our participant sample gives us a limited vantage point onto many important non-primary user perspectives-including those of nannies, housekeepers, guests, and passersby-our study does, by design, provide three routes to understanding non-primary and uses. First, we present findings related to how primary users do and do not consider non-primary users. Second, nearly all our primary user participants also describe events where they a role as a non-primary user, either with respect to their own SHCs or those managed by others. Third, two participants in study worked in prominent non-primary user roles affected by SHCs: a delivery driver and census worker.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.1">Limited Concern for Privacy and Security of Non-Primary</head><p>Most primary users we talked to had limited concern for users' privacy. Here, we present several typified and example responses to our questions concerning non-primary users' privacy and security.</p><p>(1) It's my home and my safety. P1 rationalizes that recording others is acceptable and that he does not have to explain to guests that they have a home camera. "I'm not using it for commercial it's for my personal security and I would be getting some sort of consent just in case I needed to publish it publicly . . It's my house. " P3 echoes this sentiment, further adding that her neighbors and passersby know she has a camera-presumably because they see it-but "it's whatever . . can't just tell someone to take their stuff down so people don't say anything. " It's legal. Several referenced laws around recording and consent. P9 exthat she does not have privacy if police want to investigate a crime using her Ring camera. P9 also explains that while in "public" does not have privacy because she lives in a one-party recording (i.e., other parties do not have to have consent for recording in public). (3) It's expected. Several participants expressed that people expect to be recorded in public these days. P2 stated: "It's 2021 . . . so I'm not going to immediately jump to be like, 'Oh, let me the camera up. ' If we're all just sitting on the porch, hanging I don't think any of my friends would mind." They don't mind. When asked about their family's, neighbors', and domestic workers' orientations to their SHCs, many primary users explained that specific non-primary users, like their kids or parents, found the devices acceptable or useful, or hardly noticed them. P9 said that her kids are of a generation where they grow up with cameras everywhere and are used to being recorded. P1 explained that his older parents do not how the camera works because it is "techy, " but they trust that the camera is useful. (5) I can relate. some instances, including several described above, participants general role as a non-primary user (e.g., "It's 2021" and referencing one-party consent state laws) to explain they do not mind, or why they do not expect personal privacy. (6) They're protected / I'm using it responsibly. contrast to the above explanations, in some cases participants described they did not dwell on non-primary users' privacy because the they configured or used the devices tacitly protected them. For P3 explains that being able to see her neighbor's house and sometimes overhearing their conversations through her Nest is okay because the SHC is not recording-"as soon as they [the neighbors and their conversations] leave, it's gone in my head because I'm not recording anything. "</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.2">Positive Considerations for Privacy and Security of Non-</head><p>Users. In contrast to the above responses, some participants expressed forward-looking concern for non-primary users took concrete steps to protect their privacy. For example, P9 uses activity zones in his Ring camera to avoid recording areas pertaining to his neighbor's yard and to avoid getting motion alerts for those areas. P2's neighbor's privacy was also a consideration for regarding his camera placement, as P2 had removed his Ring from his front door when he realized that it also captured a view of his neighbor's door across from him. P10 alerted her neighbors that she had a camera when she installed it, and P9 asked his neighbors if they were okay with him setting up a SHC.</p><p>Regarding indoor SHCs, P11 explained that he was very conwhen a guest was staying over. To protect their guest's privacy and communicate that his devices were deactivated, he unplugged his SHC and positioned it facing down. P11 further that he took this secure and subtly visible action preemptively, without asking guests if they mind the cameras, to avoid imparting any pressure for them to consent.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7.2.3">Perspectives as and on</head><p>Non-Primary Users. study included two participants who worked in occupations in which they regularly interacted with SHCs as non-primary users. Within this sample we nonetheless see differing perspectives. P7, a census taker, had little to say about her interaction with SHCs other than that they were common, but that the Ring doorbell communication features were often technically faulty. P7 implied this was a that prevented devices from helping her do her job.</p><p>P6, a young woman who works as a delivery driver and is within presumed sight of her neighbors' smart cameras, had much more say these perspectives. To her, smart cameras take away "last shred of privacy" and create a "breach of privacy to people because it's not selective on who it's filming. " At a more level, P6 says, "I don't like being on someone's camera that don't even know. You never know what they're doing with the " and is concerned people are using cameras for "voyeuristic" P6 also describes steps she takes to avoid being recorded on SHCs in her work as a delivery driver: "If I notice that the house has a Ring camera, I will purposely drive past the view of the Ring camera before I get out and drop the food off. Or, if I notice that they have a camera in their driveway pointing a different direction, I will park behind wherever it's to stay out of the frame. I do kind of avoid it a little bit and again, [but] it's not like I'm doing anything that I'm afraid to be It's just, I guess it's to maintain [my anonymity], you know?" -P6 P6 also acknowledged the need and right for people to their privacy, and that the police should be able to access if they are "doing bad stuff." Several primary users also experiences where they found themselves in the position non-primary as a guest or visitor. For example, P9 expressed criticism of how some of his family used SHCs. P9, who only has outdoor SHCs, disapproved of his sister's use of indoor cameras.</p><p>described several specific incidents where he visited his sister and felt uncomfortable with use of the cameras to surveil both his and her own family, and suggested his sister did not need this degree of surveillance in her "gated community. " P10 talked about how she tends to stay away from the Ring Neighbors app and other platforms such as Nextdoor or certain groups where people regularly post and request smart camera videos of incidents. She avoids these platforms because finds their content racially targeted: "it seemed like everybody you caught on video and posted was Black or a person of She reflected on her identity as a Mexican woman and it to her that people would just post any suspicious activity, unsubstantiated activity of a Black person-such as simply walking someone's yard. These experiences are best summed in P10's statement: "Either the people that utilize them are racist and they don't know it, or racist and they won't admit it. "</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DISCUSSION</head><p>Based on our findings, we elaborate upon four key insights that emerge from our analysis and reporting.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1.">People use smart home cameras as multi-functional</head><p>The narrow product marketing nomenclature of "smart home security camera, " which implies a straightforward extension of older home security cameras, belies the diverse range SHC uses we uncovered. Our work suggests that researchers and designers should understand smart home security cameras as more than image-capturing cameras, and more than conventional home security devices for deterring and protecting against intruders or thieves. Our empirical findings, in conversation with critical writing <ref type="bibr" target="#b95">[101]</ref>, lead us to conceptualize these devices as extended sensory perception technologies. In turn, we found these sensory-perceptual capabilities supported behavioral deterrence, communication, documentation, and the control and actuation of systems. Beyond conventional home security and safety applications, we found participants used SHCs as multi-functional technologies to support a variety of everyday activities-from managing guests and packages, to checking on pets and kids, to casually spying on neighbors out of curiosity. In some cases, participant uses of SHCs align with various "third-wave HCI" <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[19]</ref> concerns including aesthetic engagement, reminiscence <ref type="bibr" target="#b88">[95]</ref>, reflection <ref type="bibr">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b102">110]</ref>, creativity <ref type="bibr">[126]</ref>, and social connection. We thus extend and specify related work with IoT systems (including the smart camera) on how users reappropriate such devices for pleasure <ref type="bibr" target="#b110">[118]</ref> or entertainment <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[29]</ref> identifying these categories of adoption through multiple forms monitoring.</p><p>2. Smart home cameras are spatially sensitive and perceptually powerful devices. The landscape of interactive, networkedconnected, sensor-enabled, and data-driven devices is vast and expanding. Through identifying many forms of monitoring in smart home cameras, our study highlights the need to distinguish an important subset of smart devices that hold unique and significant implications for user privacy, security, trust, and power:</p><p>and perceptually powerful smart devices. In contrast to personal devices and applications such as laptop webbrowsers or smartwatch heart rate monitoring, SHCs are spatially sensitive devices in that their capacity to digitally detect data physically extends within large areas of the private home, and across long distances of space. But whereas an isolated heartrate sensor or temperature sensor offers only a narrow range of sensorypower, smart home cameras enable a much broader and deeper array of information and insight. Underpinned by cloud and edge computing-and enhanced by computer vision, far-field voice recognition, and other machine learning techniques-current SHC systems are capable of motion detection, noise detection, person detection, object detection, facial recognition, and "unusual activity"</p><p>In the future, new and emergent inference and prediction capabilities will likely become more robust, accessible, and mainstream-such as more advanced emotion or facial recognition Smart home cameras invariably involve non-primary A key insight of our study, confirmed and nuanced by our findings, is that in practice SHCs invariably affect non-primary users' experiences and practices, and their privacy and security. We find the non-primary users often interact with smart home at least from the perspective of primary users. This nonprimary user and usee interaction with SHCs typically involves very little awareness, consent, access, control, feedback, and benefitqualities that typically define a user experience. We found that non-primary users/usee interactions with SHCs was extremely and ranged from surveilling kids and family with implied or tacit consent and awareness (secondary users), delivery drivers and guests (indirect or incidental users <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[80,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b125">137]</ref>), domestic workers borderline consent and awareness (partially-consenting users), and neighbors and passersby with little or no apparent awareness or consent (non-consenting usees <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref>). More work is needed to further characterize the various valences here, including bystander incidental user <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[80,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b125">137]</ref>, usee <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref>, and non-user <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b100">108]</ref> with respect to spatially sensitive and perceptually smart devices. Understanding these actors as users, rather than mere subjects or stakeholders, underscores our finding that in many cases nonprimary users appear to have some significant degree of awareness of the presence, capabilities, and effects of interaction with the SHC, well as some minimal degree of consent, albeit tacit or coerced. illustrative example is the case of delivery driver or guest who typically notices a smart camera in the doorway or entryway, understands at least some of its capabilities, and then drops off a package or decides whether to ring the doorbell with awareness that are interacting with a smart sensing technology that may well be alerting and displaying their activity to the resident. study surfaces mundane yet illuminating examples of such interactions, ranging from neighbors who wait patiently without knocking to greeted at the door (P8) to delivery drivers who seek to avoid the surveillant gaze of smart cameras by parking further down the street (P6). We further saw concretely how the spatial sensitivity of smart home cameras (and built-in microphones) enables users to surveil neighbors and passersby through windows, across streets, and over property lines. Another benefit of conceptualizing these subjects as users, rather than merely surveilled is encourage us to attend to them with the usual considerations give to users-such as maximizing benefit, reducing harm, and creating a usable, useful, and enjoyable experience.</p><p>4. Smart home cameras support, enable, and invite formal, casual, and emergent surveillant uses. According to various of technological mediation theory (e.g., [45, 124, 125]), we shape technologies, and in turn, technologies shape us. Analyzing findings through this theoretical lens, we argue that SHCs support and subsequently invite and encourage emergent surveillant uses. This happens in many ways, including pushing surveillant notifications in front of users' attention, and bringing surveillant access to their fingertips at the press of a smartphone button. Our findings demonstrate a multitude of ways that primary users engage in SHC-mediated surveillance of non-primary users and other subjects for a variety of purposes-including behavioral deterrence, managing workers, caring for loved ones, cuing specific actions, and comparatively aimless, open-ended aesthetic and atelic engagements. This paper further has connections between these findings and concepts from surveillance studies, including Stark and Levy's surveillant consumer <ref type="bibr" target="#b109">[117]</ref>, Zuboff's surveillance capi- <ref type="bibr" target="#b126">[138]</ref> and foundational concepts from surveillance studies, such as regulatory or disciplinary surveillance <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[39,</ref><ref type="bibr">46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">50]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9">DESIGN INSIGHTS AND OPPORTUNITIES FOR ADDRESSING PRIVACY, SECURITY, POWER</head><p>We conclude by outlining design insights and opportunities for improving smart home cameras, particularly addressing privacy, security, and trust regarding both primary and non-primary users, frontend and backend users. From the perspective of primary SHC users, we found that while these devices were often highly valued, they nonetheless possess some significant technical and practical limitations. From the perspective of non-primary users and we have identified an overall power imbalance with SHCs, along with specific security threats and privacy harms. Together these two findings leave us, as technology designers and researchers, in a difficult position-a position we hope our work clarifies, and upon the reader. toward solutions and responses to improve this situation, we find ourselves in a generalized design dilemma: how to the needs and desires of primary users (and paying customer) in ways that are not invasive and harmful to non-primary users. While we argue that it is critical that designers better understand and address the effects of primary users' surveillance uses of non-primary users and usees, at the same time our research also identifies clear opportunities to improve and expand the capabilities and user experience of SHCs for (surveillant) primary users. Considering both sides of the primary/non-primary differential, we is necessary to develop more effective and equitable systems, which in some cases may best be handled contextually <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">[94]</ref> and locally <ref type="bibr">[84]</ref>. We examine each side of the primary/non-primary user divide in turn, and then merge our two sets of insights to outline paths toward more effective and equitable designs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.1">Improving, Expanding, and Limiting Smart</head><p>Cameras to Increase Privacy, Security, and Equity</p><p>While surveillance often appropriately carries a pejorative connotation, our findings also foreground surveillance applications that real benefits to our participants. These ranged from convenience in managing mundane practical affairs (e.g., kenneling the dog before answering the door), to connecting and sharing with others (e.g., checking on pets, capturing memories), caring for other family members, to deterring and documenting incidents of abuse and negligence from caretakers. Beyond the clear-cut areas for improvement noted in Section 5.3, participants at times demonstrated creative appropriations and workarounds that suggest opportunities for further enhancing and expanding the design SHCs.</p><p>Mobile, ad-hoc cameras, and remotely repositionable the design and marketing materials of SHCs suggest these devices are intended to be left in a relatively stationary position, several participants described regularly moving a SHC their home to aid in various tasks such as keeping an eye kids or pets. Two participants devised household names to refer cameras dedicated for mobile and ad hoc uses-"the spare camera" (P8) and "the nanny camera" (to imply P10's mobile use of the camera for care-based surveillance over her children) (P10). This suggests an opportunity to better support mobile smart home camera applications, perhaps through more adjustable fixtures, battery devices with inductive base chargers, or improved remote lens repositioning features offered by some SHC products.</p><p>Circumventing the cloud and backend uses. One participant, P11, described taking his smart home camera completely "off the cloud" because he did not trust presumed backend users (the manufacturer and "the Chinese government"). This and other uses suggest a need and opportunity to better enable SHC users to or switch between cloud and local storage, while also clarify performance limitations of doing so.</p><p>Ambient and peripheral displays. We reported one noteworthy instance where a participant created a peripheral display to monitor her kids playing outside (P8). This and other uses suggest need and opportunity to better support focal and peripheral monitoring, such as combing a more mobile SHC device with a similarly more mobile and adjustable dedicated display screen.</p><p>Targeted visibility/invisibility. Participants described challenges with achieving the desired outcome of conspicuously showcasing SHCs to potential intruders, while concealing or minimizing the visibility of the devices so as not to annoy or offend their neighbors. This presents a few opportunities for enhanced filtering capabilities, though we note that such filtering may also enable more invasive and discriminatory targeting behaviors. For one, capabilities may allow primary users to automatically filter different subjects-whether someone is distant, nearby, trespassing, or lingering-which would then allow users to adjust visibility parameters (i.e. the various intensities of lights and alarms). These filters could also control physical mechanisms, such as the type of mechanical "privacy shutter" devised by Cheng et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[31]</ref>. Future work may also consider how filters support non-primary users' privacy preferences. However, it is that some of the analytics required to identify the presence of non-primary users may be interpreted as privacy-invasive or overly surveillant. Secondary sensors, rather than image and video analytics, could also be used to implement these filters. To protect the privacy of neighbors and passersby, a SHC might remain visclosed most of the time. However, if motion is detected on one's property at night, the camera "awakens" and the physical shutter detracts and lens opening illuminates. Such a technique is also sometimes employed in science fiction films to dramatically personify surveillance systems. More simply, a SHC system enable a user to manually switch between different levels of visibility/invisibility.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.2">Personal Controls for Personal Privacy</head><p>users generally expressed high degrees of trust and control their SHCs. None directly expressed desires for new or improved privacy or security controls, and few took significant steps to protect their privacy with SHCs outside of determining its location and position, and who should have access to the app interface. Many participants describe leaving cameras on most of the time, even private settings like the living room or child's bedroom. One exception was P11 who undertook several steps to visually communicate to a guest that his SHCs were deactivated, by unplugging and his SHC face down on the ground. This suggests a need and opportunity for more easily and visibly "closed" devices, to assure guests and visitors that the devices are indeed disabled (c.f., <ref type="bibr" target="#b96">[102]</ref>).</p><p>our research would seem to confirm Zheng et al. 's find- <ref type="bibr" target="#b125">[137]</ref> that users generally trust smart devices (and backend users/uses), yet at the same time, these users often possess limknowledge about the types and extent of insight that machine learning can infer about their lives. They propose that users might express greater concern about their privacy with greater awareness. assuming this motivates users to protect their privacy, it seems unlikely that some SHC companies would be incentivized to reveal their backend uses of SHC data. Thus, this suggests that tools to motivate or educate primary users about backend uses must continue to come from relatively independent designers, artists, activist groups, or governments-ranging from awareness campaigns, to op-eds, to art and design exhibitions <ref type="bibr" target="#b111">[119]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.3">Controls for Non-Primary User Privacy and Security</head><p>Primary User Side Controls. Perhaps the most obvious design approach for improving privacy for non-primary users/usees is to empower and nudge them to configure and operate their devices in ways that better protect non-primary users. Several participants took steps specifically to safeguard the privacy and security of nonusers. For example, P9 used the "activity zone" feature to the application of motion and person alerts to his own yard, and to exclude his neighbor's P3 described how using her camera without a subscription (so it only saves short snippets of videos) protects her neighbors' privacy, though she still listens in on small portions of their conversations.</p><p>On one hand, these examples suggest that new or foregrounded interface features could support and encourage primary users to help protect non-primary users' privacy and security by limiting sensing capabilities (e.g., not saving recordings) or discrimisensing (e.g., specifying areas to exclude from recordings or notifications). On the other hand, these examples illustrate an inherent and serious limitation of primary user side controls: they remain invisible and unverifiable to any non-primary without access to the interface. Thus, while simple steps such as configuring exclusion zones and allowing recordings to be automatically deleted may in fact achieve suitable privacy for non-primary users, a neighbor or passersby has no way of knowing or verifying these settings just by looking at the smart camera. Even the indicator light and opening of the camera lens may be misleading, as many cameras possess wide-angle visual fields, and some allow users to dim the indicator while it is actively sensing. Non-Primary User Side Protections and Interventions.</p><p>route is to empower non-primary users with tools to protect their own privacy. This approach is illustrated by techniques such Truong et al. 's infrared LED camera sensor blocking device <ref type="bibr" target="#b113">[122]</ref> and Chen et al.'s wearable ultrasonic microphone jamming tech- <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[30]</ref>. It is also explored in Harvey's counter-facial-recognition <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[65]</ref>, Shepard's CCD-Me-Not Umbrella [112], and Pierce's CCD-Me-Not Curtains <ref type="bibr" target="#b95">[101]</ref>-an open riff on Shepard's speculative design concept. More generally, we might design technologies help the homeowner circumvent, say, a surveillant neighbor as much as an activist might circumvent surveillant states <ref type="bibr" target="#b99">[107]</ref>.</p><p>such tools have significant technical, practical, and legal limitations. For example, surveilled individuals rarely have practical legal ways of accessing and controlling someone else's digital surveillance system. Hence, each of the counter-surveillance tools above is a standalone hardware or non-computational tool.</p><p>Shared or Negotiated Controls. A third design direction is develop better shared and negotiated controls. Many devices already support access for trusted secondary users like spouses, children, or housemates. There are also examples of specialized portals for mediating the sharing of sensitive personal data, notably Ring's video request portal for formally requesting footage of serious incidents such as car accidents or abductions. However, neither of these features do much to address the effects of perceptually powerful and surveillant SHCs on neighbors, domestic workers, houseguests, and passersby. Despite significant legal, technical, and usability hurdles, one might imagine a portal-like Ring's video request portal, but instead functioning as a mechanism for formally requesting that someone limit or disable a pointed at their property or window. We might also imagine provisions that require SHC service providers to add ways people to "opt out" of video feeds through dynamic masking to block their faces and bodies, or to notify individuals of devices their properties or bodies. These implications extend cooperative mechanisms for managing bystander privacy in other technologies, such as information and footage deletion request features for drone bystanders [134].</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.4">Latent and Embedded Controls and</head><p>Common approaches to privacy and security typically rely upon notice and consent <ref type="bibr" target="#b106">[114,</ref><ref type="bibr">115]</ref>, and individual user interface controls (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>). A different approach we propose is to design latent and embedded controls and safeguards. Our study uncovered many instances where technical or practical limitations of the SHCs appeared to inadvertently create privacy protections. For example, many users described not paying for cloud subscription upgrades, which limited their ability to collect surveillant histories. Even when participants did upgrade, the systems do store user accessible video or other data for longer than 30 days. This suggests a latent privacy safeguard that inhibits users from acquiring detailed, searchable databases. While it is technically possible to download all SHC camera data, in practice this is prohibitively cumbersome and is not readily supported by the app or platform. These findings parallel design directions from prior work analyzing the implications of ubiquitous digital trails for victims of state surveillance, in which researchers argue for enhancing plausible deniability in technologies-indicating a need to design systems for ephemerality, rather than permanence <ref type="bibr" target="#b99">[107]</ref>.</p><p>In addition to the disincentive of paying for cloud subscription as one latent privacy safeguard, our participants also discussed the mediating effects of the size and visibility of the camera's housing and form-factor, often desiring that it was visible enough to deter intruders but not so visible as to draw the ire or alarm of neighbors.</p><p>need to maintain balance (between being just visible enough, but not too visible), may inadvertently help protect the privacy of neighbors by alerting them to the presence of the devices. Further, while SHCs are lighter, cheaper, and easier to setup than older video surveillance cameras, participants still described cost and practical barriers to achieving more complete coverage of their property. These examples and other limitations suggest design opportunities to deliberately embed controls and safeguards that inhibit and discourage primary users from overly invasive (though often inadvertent) surveillance of non-primary users-though may fall short of outright preventing them from doing so.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="9.5">Informing the Design of Laws, Regulations, and Policy</head><p>we would be remiss to neglect the relevance of policy and law to these issues-perspectives that are increasingly discussed within HCI (e.g., <ref type="bibr">[116,</ref><ref type="bibr">131]</ref>). Such policy interventions are necessary address the complex array of privacy, security, trust, and power issues at play. Our above discussion underscores the responsibility of HCI and design researchers to identify potential limits to our own expertise and interventions. This may also entail imagining ways to encourage users to limit or relinquish use of surveillant <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[12]</ref>, and adopting an "undesign" <ref type="bibr" target="#b94">[100,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b118">129]</ref> perspective that pushes back against the assumption that SHCs are a necessary or facet of daily life. We conducted our study in the United States, where regulations on recording vary by state; international laws vary even further. With such considerations and limitations mind, we provide three specific regulatory implications from our work:</p><p>Policy must consider privacy and data collection in contextual ways. findings depict a diversity of uses of smart cameras. This evolving multi-functionality suggests that general regulations for devices (policies affecting all smart cameras) be overly broad and can neglect to consider the contextual norms that correspond to different types of social interactions and (e.g., physical security surveillance is different from carebased surveillance, and so forth). As such, Nissenbaum's contextual integrity approach is pertinent to consider how, and which data flows are appropriate for these varied use cases <ref type="bibr" target="#b87">[94]</ref>.</p><p>More regulations are necessary to stop deceptive design in smart cameras. In findings about frontend and backend users, participants derived inferences about backend processes with their SHC data based on company subscription plans, creating "What you see on your interface is all there is" model, when in the correct mental model is "What you see is just your interface" (the company can see so much more). This asymmetry has the potential to mislead users, conveying incorrect mental models backend elements (such as what data is being collected or stored). At times, this practice may constitute what legal scholar Hartzog refers to as "deceptive design" [64]. However, the mismatch between what a user sees on their interface and what a company is doing behind the scenes is not necessarily deceptive a "dark design pattern" [61], and it is common for designers to deliberately shield users from unnecessary or confusing information.</p><p>in instances where such practices are deemed deceptive, one might turn to US consumer protection laws, in which the Federal Trade Commission may formally label these design choices as "deceptive" to create regulatory enforcement against companies these practices. Law and policy need to recognize new mechanisms for legally collecting or using data beyond current individually focused privacy notice and consent models. illumithe various interhousehold dynamics associated with monitoring and surveillance uses of smart home cameras, we assert that privacy legislation needs to consider group and non-primary user issues differently. As SHCs enable non-primary users' data to be and shared by others, we must reconsider the prevailing individual consent models for privacy. This is aligned with Levy and Baroca's concept of privacy dependencies, which illustrates how other's actions may violate one's privacy (and vice versa) <ref type="bibr">[9]</ref>. They impart, "privacy dependencies should thus not only call into question notice and choice as a model for privacy regulation; they should force us to abandon the naïve hope that solidarity can help rescue informed consent by clarifying the degree to which our privacy choices implicate others" (p. 615). Therefore, as our work details the myriad interdependencies, relational uses, and power asymmetries of SHCs, we understate the need to establish privacy paradigms beyond individual approaches for notice and consent-indicating the consequential and dynamic implications for monitoring and surveillance as perpetuated by smart home cameras.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="10">CONCLUSION</head><p>Our provides an empirical investigation into the various surveillance use cases of the consumer smart home camera an increasingly popular new category of smart home Through interviews with 14 SHC users, we unravel privacy tensions and power imbalances related to the household dynamics of living with these perceptually powerful and sensitive devices. We observed how users employed the range of sensing capabilities in smart cameras to extend perception, and to engage in various forms of monitoring and surveillance that includes but goes beyond conventional security uses cases such as deterring or catching intruders.</p><p>Our findings impart several concepts for classifying these uses of SHCs, as we categorize the different types of everyday monitoring and surveillance activities participants engaged in. We also discuss asymmetrical and power-laden implications of these uses and the tensions created between primary and non-primary users. From these insights, we conclude with design considerations for balancprimary and non-primary users' privacy, and implications for law policy regulations with smart camera technology. Overall, we hope our investigation paves new directions for HCI, privacy, and IoT, as we stress the need to continue to examine and critique new forms of surveillance afforded by emerging ubiquitous technologies such as the smart home camera.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure 2: Examples of participants' indoor, outdoor, and doorbell smart cameras. The top row of images depicts various indoor camera placements, and the bottom row depicts outdoor camera placements. Notable images include a camera mounted upside down on the indoor ceiling, a camera placed among other domestic objects on a bookshelf, and an outdoor camera adorned with a small, decorative cowboy hat.Table 2: Summary of Key Categories of Surveillance and Monitoring</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="8,87.82,83.68,436.36,186.87" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Figure 3: Examples of P8's anticipatory monitoring of her child (left) and doorway (right).</figDesc><graphic url="image-4.png" coords="9,90.31,83.68,431.39,283.09" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>I'd say, 'Stay where I can see you!'. . . Or I'd ask my daughter, 'Did Dad come in yet?' It was like, I'd have to search for him. It got kind of nerve wracking, cause I was like, micro-managing his life. " -P4</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="7,127.17,83.68,357.66,368.77" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Overview of participants, cameras, and their households</figDesc><table><row><cell>ID</cell><cell>Cameras</cell><cell># of</cell><cell>Other Household</cell><cell>Location</cell><cell>Ethnicity</cell><cell>Age</cell><cell>Gender</cell><cell>Individual</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>owned</cell><cell>SHCs</cell><cell>Members</cell><cell>(self-described)</cell><cell>(self-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Income Level</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>described)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P1</cell><cell>Wyze Cam,</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2 (Parents, ages 80</cell><cell>Small city, middle</cell><cell>Asian</cell><cell>37</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>$50-$100k</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Google Nest</cell><cell></cell><cell>&amp; 70)</cell><cell>of urban and</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Cam</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>suburban</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P2</cell><cell>Wyze Cam;</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>1 (Spouse)</cell><cell>Densely populated</cell><cell>White</cell><cell>30</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>$100-$150k</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ring floodlight</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>suburb</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Cam</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P3</cell><cell>Nest outdoor</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>1 (Mother, age 43)</cell><cell>Suburban</cell><cell>Black</cell><cell>19</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>$50-100k</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>security Cam</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P4</cell><cell>4 Wyze Cams,</cell><cell>6</cell><cell>2 (Husband, age 62;</cell><cell>Suburban</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>59</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>N/A</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Ring doorbell,</cell><cell></cell><cell>Daughter, age 36)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Wisenet</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>security Cam</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P5</cell><cell>Google Nest</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>3</cell><cell>Big city</cell><cell>Black/African</cell><cell>33</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>$100-150k</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Cams</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>American</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P6 a</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>1 (age 31)</cell><cell cols="2">Big city/ Suburban White</cell><cell>25</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>$50-100k</cell></row><row><cell>P7</cell><cell>Nest Cam</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>1 (age 29)</cell><cell>Suburban</cell><cell>White</cell><cell>64</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Prefer not to</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>share</cell></row><row><cell>P8</cell><cell>Wyze Cams</cell><cell>8</cell><cell>2 (1 adult, mid-30s;</cell><cell>Suburban</cell><cell>N/A</cell><cell>35</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Prefer not to</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>∼8, Nest</cell><cell></cell><cell>1, age 8)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>share</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Doorbell Cam</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P9</cell><cell>2 Ring Cams</cell><cell>2</cell><cell>2 (age 35; age 3)</cell><cell>Suburban</cell><cell>Hispanic</cell><cell>36</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>$50-100k</cell></row><row><cell>P10</cell><cell>2 Ring</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>5 (ages 71, 45, 12,</cell><cell>Midsize to larger</cell><cell cols="2">Hispanic white 46</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>$50-100k</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Doorbell Cams,</cell><cell></cell><cell>12, 12)</cell><cell>city</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>3 Ring Stick</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Up Cams</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P11</cell><cell>2 Amcrest, 17</cell><cell>5</cell><cell>4</cell><cell>Rural</cell><cell>White</cell><cell>41</cell><cell>Male</cell><cell>$100-150k</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Eufy, 16 Lorex,</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P12</cell><cell>Google Nest</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>3 (Husband, aged</cell><cell>Big city</cell><cell>African</cell><cell>27</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>$50-100k</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Cam IQ Indoor</cell><cell></cell><cell>30; Caregiver, age</cell><cell></cell><cell>American</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>25; Child, age 3)</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P13</cell><cell>Carson</cell><cell>1 b</cell><cell>n/a (lives alone)</cell><cell>Urban</cell><cell>Black</cell><cell>31</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>$10-50k</cell></row><row><cell>P14</cell><cell>Samsung</cell><cell>1</cell><cell>3 (ages 16, 13, 54)</cell><cell>Urban</cell><cell>Black</cell><cell>36</cell><cell>Female</cell><cell>Below $10k</cell></row><row><cell cols="9">a This participant does not own smart cameras but is surveilled by them at work, as a delivery driver, and at home by her neighbors.</cell></row><row><cell cols="5">b This smart home camera was installed in her apartment building.</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">that, according to the Wyze website they are a US company based in a major US We recognize that these claims may fall into potentially harmful and incorrect political, and xenophobic political assumptions or stereotypes, though we include this finding to represent participants' experiences of mistrust. While participants' suggest that this mistrust may be influenced by a variety of factors (such as reporting, exposure to online information, political beliefs, or other experiences), do not have enough data to analyze the root causes of these statements and beliefs in this paper.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>We express our sincere gratitude to our participants for generously sharing their time and perspectives, and to our anonymous reviewers for providing helpful comments and suggestions. This study was funded by a Mozilla Research Grant 2018H2, the National Science Foundation under awards IIS-1947696, IIS-155367, and IIS-2142795, and the National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship under No. DGE-1762114.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Smart Home Reports. Strategy Analytics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Ablondi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.strategyanalytics.com/access-services/devices/connected-" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Nudges for privacy and security: Understanding and assisting users&apos; choices online</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alessandro</forename><surname>Acquisti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Idris</forename><surname>Adjerid</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Balebako</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Brandimarte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lorrie</forename><surname>Cranor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Saranga</forename><surname>Komanduri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pedro</forename><forename type="middle">Giovanni</forename><surname>Leon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Norman</forename><surname>Sadeh</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Comput. Surv. CSUR</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="41" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Over-exposed? Privacy patterns and considerations in online mobile photo sharing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shane</forename><surname>Ahern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dean</forename><surname>Eckles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nathaniel</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Good</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Simon</forename><surname>King</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI conference on Human in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="357" to="366" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Mor Naaman, and Rahul Nair</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Tangible Towards user-centric sensor designs for bystander privacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rosta</forename><surname>Ahmad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Apu</forename><surname>Farzan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam J</forename><surname>Kapadia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Interact</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The heterogehome</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Aipperspach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Allison</forename><surname>Hooker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Woodruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 10th international conference on Ubiquitous</title>
				<meeting>the 10th international conference on Ubiquitous</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="222" to="231" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Music, and IoT: How People (Really) Use Voice Assistants</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jofish</forename><surname>Ammari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janice</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Kaye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Tsai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bentley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. Comput.-Hum. Interact</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="28" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-06">2019. June 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Seeing without knowing: Limitations of the transparency ideal and its application to algorithmic accountability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amoore</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New Media Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="973" to="989" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2020. 2018. 2018</date>
			<publisher>Duke University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Mike Ananny and Kate Crawford</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy Dependencies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Barocas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wash. Law Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">95</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">555</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-06">2020. June 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reflective informatics: conceptual dimensions for detechnologies of reflection</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Eric</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Baumer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="594" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Usees</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Baumer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Seoul Republic of Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Limiting, leaving, (re) lapsing: an exploration of facebook non-use practices and experiences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Phil</forename><surname>Ps Baumer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Adams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Vera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tony</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Khovanskaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Madeline</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Victoria Schwanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kaiton</forename><surname>Sosik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on human factors in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI conference on human factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mapping the Margins: Navigating the Ecologies of Domestic Violence Service Provision</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rosanna</forename><surname>Bellini</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Angelika</forename><surname>Strohmayer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Olivier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Clara</forename><surname>Crivellaro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Glasgow Scotland Uk</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Assumptions Checked: How Families Learn About and Use the Echo Dot</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erin</forename><surname>Beneteau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yini</forename><surname>Guan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Olivia</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Richards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mingrui</forename><forename type="middle">Ray</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kientz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Yip</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexis</forename><surname>Hiniker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Interact. Mob. Ubiquitous Technol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="23" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-03">2020. March 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Machine Learning Uncertainty as a Design Material: A Post-Phenomenological Inquiry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Josua</forename><surname>Benjamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arne</forename><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Merrill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pierce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proc. 2021 CHI Conf</title>
				<meeting>2021 CHI Conf</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-05">2021. May 2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the Long-Term Use of Smart Assistants</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Bentley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Max</forename><surname>Luvogt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rushani</forename><surname>Silverman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brooke</forename><surname>Wirasinghe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danielle</forename><surname>White</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lottridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Interact. Mob. Wearable Ubiquitous Technol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2018-09">2018. September 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social and ethical the internet of things</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Francine</forename><surname>Berman Vinton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Cerf</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Commun. ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6" to="7" />
			<date type="published" when="2017-01">2017. January 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cameras on beds: The ethics of surveillance in nursing home rooms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Clara</forename><surname>Berridge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jodi</forename><surname>Halpern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">AJOB Empir. Bioeth</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-01">2019. January 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When second wave HCI meets third wave challenges</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bødker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th Nordic conference on Human-computer interaction: roles</title>
				<meeting>the 4th Nordic conference on Human-computer interaction: roles</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Thermostats, Locks and Lights: Digital Tools of Domestic The New York Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nellie</forename><surname>Bowles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.nytimes.com/2018/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Smart home tech is being turned into a tool for abuse</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Braithwaite</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.wired.co.uk/article/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dark Matters: On the Surveillance of Blackness</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Simone</forename><surname>Browne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<publisher>Duke Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Focusing on shared moving beyond the camera in video communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Brubaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gina</forename><surname>Venolia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the Designing Interactive Systems Conference on -DIS &apos;12</title>
				<meeting>the Designing Interactive Systems Conference on -DIS &apos;12<address><addrLine>Newcastle Upon Tyne, United Kingdom</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">96</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaeyeon</forename><surname>Aj Bernheim Brush</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ratul</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frank</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Martinez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Digital neighborhood watch: Investigating the sharing of camera data amongst In Proceedings of the 2013 conference on Computer supported cooperative work</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="693" to="700" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Home automation in the wild: challenges and</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Bernheim Brush</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bongshin</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ratul</forename><surname>Mahajan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sharad</forename><surname>Agarwal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Saroiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Dixon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Vancouver BC Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2115" to="2124" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bucher</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Want to be on the top? Algorithmic power and the threat of invisibility on Facebook</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1164" to="1180" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From Nest Is A Content Idea Firing On All Cylinders</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.forbes.com/sites/willburns/2018/03/02/the-nestie-awards-from-nest-is-a-content-idea-firing-on-all" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Burns</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The &quot;Nestie Awards</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2020. inaction or in action? the role of user experience in the security and privacy design of smart home cameras</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Chalhoub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Flechais</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Norbert</forename><surname>Nthala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ruba</forename><surname>Abu-Salma</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sixteenth Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2020</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="185" to="204" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2021. did not give me an option to decline&quot;: A Longitudinal Analysis of the User of Security and Privacy in Smart Home Products</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Chalhoub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Norbert</forename><surname>Kraemer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ivan</forename><surname>Nthala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Flechais</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, ACM, Japan</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, ACM, Japan</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wearable microphone jamming</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huiying</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shan-Yuan</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Teng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhijing</forename><surname>Nagels</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pedro</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lopes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Ben</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Haitao</forename><surname>Zhao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2020 chi conference on human factors in computing systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Peekaboo Cam: Designing an Observational Camera for Home Ecologies Concerning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yu-Ting</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mathias</forename><surname>Funk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wenn-Chieh</forename><surname>Tsai</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lin-Lin</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 on Designing Interactive Systems Conference</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 on Designing Interactive Systems Conference<address><addrLine>San Diego CA USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="823" to="836" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Smart Homes Learn: The Evolution of the Networked Home and Household</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marshini</forename><surname>Chetty</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ja-Young</forename><surname>Sung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Grinter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Ubi-2007: Ubiquitous Computing</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Krumm</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Abowd</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aruna</forename></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Strang</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Heidelberg; Berlin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="127" to="144" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Living in a glass house: a survey of private moments in the home</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kyoung</forename><surname>Choe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sunny</forename><surname>Consolvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaeyeon</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Beverly</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th international conference on Ubiquitous computing -UbiComp &apos;11</title>
				<meeting>the 13th international conference on Ubiquitous computing -UbiComp &apos;11<address><addrLine>Beijing, China; Harvard University</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">41</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Keats Citron. 2014. Hate crimes in cyberspace</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Repacking &apos;Privacy&apos; for a World</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Crabtree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Will</forename><surname>Tolmie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Knight</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Support. Coop. Work CSCW</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2017-12">2017. December 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Atlas of AI: Power, Politics, and the Planetary Costs of Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Crawford</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<publisher>Yale University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surveillance and Military Transformation: Organi-Trends in Twenty First Century Armed Services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Dandeker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New Polit. Surveill. Visibility</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="225" to="249" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2012. I would DiYSE for it! A manifesto for dointernet-of-things creation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">De</forename><surname>Roeck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karin</forename><surname>Slegers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Johan</forename><surname>Criel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Godon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laurence</forename><surname>Claeys</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kilpi</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">An</forename><surname>Jacobs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">NordiCHI &apos;12 Proceedings of the 7th</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction: Making Sense Through AMC</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="170" to="179" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Postscript on the Societies of Control</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gilles</forename><surname>Deleuze</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992-10-59">1992. October 59. 1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">residents&apos; perceived need of and preferences for &quot;smart home&quot; sensor technologies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Demiris</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Brian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marjorie</forename><surname>Hensel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marilyn</forename><surname>Skubic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rantz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Technol. Assess. Health Care</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="124" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">In situ with of augmented reality glasses: perspectives on recording and privacytechnologies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tamara</forename><surname>Denning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zakariya</forename><surname>Dehlawi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tadayoshi</forename><surname>Kohno</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Desjardins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeremy</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Viny</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cayla</forename><surname>Key</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nouela</forename><surname>Johnston</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Toronto Ontario Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2377" to="2386" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alternative Avenues for IoT: Designing with Non-Stereotypical Homes</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems -CHI &apos;19</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems -CHI &apos;19<address><addrLine>Glasgow, Scotland Uk</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Divining a digital future: Mess and in ubiquitous computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Dourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Genevieve</forename><surname>Bell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<publisher>Mit Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Myth of the Average User: Improving Privacy and Security Systems through Individualization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eyal</forename><surname>Egelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Peer</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2015 New Security Paradigms Workshop, ACM, Twente Netherlands</title>
				<meeting>the 2015 New Security Paradigms Workshop, ACM, Twente Netherlands</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="28" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The new good: exploring the potential of philosophy of technology to contribute to human-computer interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fallman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on human factors in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI conference on human factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1051" to="1060" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discipline and punish: The birth of the prison</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Foucault</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<pubPlace>Vintage</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Stalker&apos;s Paradise&quot;: How Partner Abusers Exploit Technology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Palmer</forename><surname>Freed</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Minchala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Ristenpart</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Dell</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy and security threat models and mitigation strategies of older adults</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alisa</forename><surname>Frik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leysan</forename><surname>Nurgalieva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Bernd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joyce</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Schaub</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Serge</forename><surname>Egelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Fifteenth Symposium on Usable Privacy and Security</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="40" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>SOUPS 2019</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Calling for a Revolution: An IoT Manifestos</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ester</forename><forename type="middle">Irina</forename><surname>Shklovski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rachel Douglas-Jones</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How Can Surveillance Be Defined? Remarks on Theoretical Foundations of Surveillance Studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fuchs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010. 2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">24</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">The Internet</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Hole-In-Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sherrie</forename><surname>Galloway</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rabinowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.ecafe.com/getty/HIS/index.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980">1980</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The video window: my life with a ludic system</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Pers. Ubiquitous Comput</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="60" to="65" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Indoor weather stations: investigating a ludic approach to environmental HCI through prototyping</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Gaver</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Bowers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kirsten</forename><surname>Boehner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andy</forename><surname>Boucher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nadine</forename><surname>Mark Hauenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Jarvis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Pennington</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Paris France</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3451" to="3460" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timnit</forename><surname>Gebru</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jamie</forename><surname>Morgenstern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Briana</forename><surname>Vecchione</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><forename type="middle">Wortman</forename><surname>Vaughan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hanna</forename><surname>Wallach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hal</forename><surname>Daumé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Iii</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kate</forename><surname>Crawford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">180309010</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Datasheets datasets. ArXiv Prepr</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gilliard and David Golumbia. 2021. Luxury Surveillance. Real Life</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Geeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Franziska</forename><surname>Roesner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://reallifemag.com/luxury-surveillance/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>ACM, Glasgow Scotland Uk</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Who&apos;s In Control?: Interactions Multi-User Smart Homes</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Discovery of grounded theory: for qualitative research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Glaser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anselm</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Through the Handoff Lens: Competing Visions of Autonomous Futures</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jake</forename><surname>Goldenfein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deirdre</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mulligan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Nissenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><surname>Ju</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Berkeley Tech LJ</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">35</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">835</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Urbanism under Google: Lessons from Sidewalk Toronto</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Goodman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Powles</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Fordham Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">88</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">457</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digitizing Surveillance: Categorization, Space</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Graham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inequality. Crit. Soc. Policy</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="248" />
			<date type="published" when="2003-05">2003. May 2003</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dark patterns and the legal requirements of consent banners: An criticism perspective</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Colin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cristiana</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nataliia</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Bielova</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Damian</forename><surname>Toth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Clifford</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Jenny Hansson. Fearless feline chases coyote in Portland neighborhood</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Byung-Chul</forename><surname>Han</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.koin.com/news/animals/fearless-feline-chases-coyote-in-portland-neighborhood/Hartzog.2018.Privacy&apos;sblueprint" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>In the swarm: Digital prospects</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">CV Dazzle: Computer Vision Dazzle Camouflage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Harvey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://cvdazzle.com/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Challenges in universally usable privacy and security</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harry</forename><surname>Hochheiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jinjuan</forename><surname>Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Lazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Symposium On Usable Privacy and Security</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">New York University Press. Heather A Horst, Cherry Baylosis, and Sheba Mohammid. 2021. Looking pro-How women decide what to wear with and through automated tech-Convergence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-10">2020. October 2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1250" to="1263" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Technologies of Speculation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Privacy Behaviors of Lifeloggers using Wearable Cameras</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert</forename><surname>Hoyle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steven</forename><surname>Templeman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Denise</forename><surname>Armes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Anthony</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">All Apu</forename><surname>Cr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kapadia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="571" to="582" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Technology and the lifeworld: From garden to earth</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tung-Hui</forename><surname>Hu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990">2015. 1990. 1990</date>
			<publisher>MIT press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A Prehistory of the Cloud</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Attending to Technology: Theses for Disputation. The New Atlantis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Jacobs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.thenewatlantis.com/publications/attending-" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Can You See Now?: How Field of View Affects Collaboration in Robotic Telepresence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Irene</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bilge</forename><surname>Rae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leila</forename><surname>Mutlu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Takayama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Systems<address><addrLine>Seoul Republic of Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2397" to="2406" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Thinking, Fast and Slow</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Kahneman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<publisher>Macmillan</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Evangelos</forename><surname>Karapanos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rúben</forename><surname>Gouveia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marc</forename><surname>Hassenzahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jodi</forename><surname>Forlizzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">the making: peoples&apos; experiences with wearable activity trackers</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychol. Well-Being</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The ethics of aesthetics: Stigma, information, and the of electronic ankle monitor design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lauren</forename><surname>Kilgour</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inf. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="131" to="146" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-05">2020. May 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">We Just Use What They Give Us&quot;: Understanding Passenger User Perspecin Smart Homes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vinay</forename><surname>Koshy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joon Sung Sung</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ti-Chung</forename><surname>Cheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karrie</forename><surname>Karahalios</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Yokohama Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Spaces and Traces: Implications of Smart Technology in</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sandjar</forename><surname>Kozubaev</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fernando</forename><surname>Rochaix</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carl</forename><surname>Disalvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><forename type="middle">A Le</forename><surname>Dantec</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Public In Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Glasgow Scotland Uk</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accountable Algorithms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Kroll</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joanna</forename><surname>Huey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Solon</forename><surname>Barocas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Edward W Felten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Reidenberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harlan</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Univ. Pa. Law Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">165</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">74</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Alexa, Are You Listening?: Privacy Perceptions, Concerns and Privacy-seeking Behaviors with Speakers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Josephine</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><surname>Zimmerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Florian</forename><surname>Schaub</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018-11">2018. November 2018</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Digital Technologies and their Role in Intimate Partner Violence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roxanne</forename><surname>Leitão</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Extended Abstracts of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Watch the Viral Video of a Small Boy Filling an Trick-or-Treat Bowl With His Halloween Candy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melissa</forename><surname>Lemieux</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.newsweek.com/watch-viral-video-small-boy-filling-empty-trick-treat-bowl-his-halloween-candy-1469331" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">All data are local: Thinking critically in a data-driven society</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E C</forename><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ida. Law Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014. 2019</date>
			<publisher>MIT Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Yanni Alexander Loukissas</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">protect their privacy if they can: Determinants of webcam covering</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dominique</forename><surname>Machuletz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Henrik</forename><surname>Sendt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Laube</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rainer</forename><surname>Böhme</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the European Workshop on Usable Security at the Privacy Enhaning Technologies Symposium (EuroSEC&apos;16)(EuroUSEC&apos;16)</title>
				<meeting>the European Workshop on Usable Security at the Privacy Enhaning Technologies Symposium (EuroSEC&apos;16)(EuroUSEC&apos;16)<address><addrLine>Reston, VA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy Attitudes of Smart Speaker Users</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nathan</forename><surname>Malkin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joe</forename><surname>Deatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Allen</forename><surname>Tong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Primal</forename><surname>Wijesekera</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Serge</forename><surname>Egelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Priv. Enhancing Technol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2019</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="250" to="271" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-10">2019. October 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smart Devices in Airbnbs: Considering Privacy and Security for both Guests and Hosts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tadayoshi</forename><surname>Shrirang Franziska Roesner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kohno</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. Priv. Enhancing Technol</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2020</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="436" to="458" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-04">2020. April 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stories from Survivors: Privacy &amp; Security Practices when Coping with Intimate Partner Abuse</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kathleen</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Matthews</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Leary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Manya</forename><surname>Turner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jill</forename><forename type="middle">Palzkill</forename><surname>Sleeper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Woelfer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cori</forename><surname>Shelton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><forename type="middle">F</forename><surname>Manthorne</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sunny</forename><surname>Churchill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Consolvo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Colorado USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">2201</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toys that Listen: A Study of Parents, Children, and Internet-Connected Toys</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Mcreynolds</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Hubbard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><surname>Lau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aditya</forename><surname>Saraf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maya</forename><surname>Cakmak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Franziska</forename><surname>Roesner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Denver Colorado USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5197" to="5207" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hacking the natural habitat: an in-the-wild study of smart homes, their development, and the people who live in them</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Mennicken</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elaine</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">International conference on pervasive computing</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="143" to="160" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring Longitudinal Use of Activity Trackers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jochen</forename><surname>Meyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jochen</forename><surname>Schnauber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wilko</forename><surname>Heuten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harm</forename><surname>Wienbergen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rainer</forename><surname>Hambrecht</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hans-Jürgen</forename><surname>Appelrath</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susanne</forename><surname>Boll</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">IEEE International Healthcare IEEE</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="198" to="206" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Qualitative data analysis: An sage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Matthew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Miles</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Huberman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Health empowerment through activity trackers: An empirical smart wristband study</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tibert</forename><surname>Elizabeth C Nelson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthijs L</forename><surname>Verhagen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Noordzij</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Hum. Behav</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="364" to="374" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016. 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy as contextual integrity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Nissenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wash Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">79</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding Long-Term Interactions with a Slow Techan Investigation of Experiences with FutureMe</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Odom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Seoul Republic of Korea</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="575" to="584" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b89">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Long-term of ubiquitous surveillance in the home</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Antti</forename><surname>Oulasvirta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aurora</forename><surname>Pihlajamaa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jukka</forename><surname>Perkiö</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Debarshi</forename><surname>Ray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Taneli</forename><surname>Vähäkangas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tero</forename><surname>Hasu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Niklas</forename><surname>Vainio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Petri</forename><surname>Myllymäki</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2012 ACM Conference on Ubiquitous Computing</title>
				<meeting>the 2012 ACM Conference on Ubiquitous Computing</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="41" to="50" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b90">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">You Gotta Watch You Say&quot;: Surveillance of Communication with Incarcerated People</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Camille</forename><surname>Owens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lorrie</forename><surname>Cobb</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cranor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing ACM</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing ACM<address><addrLine>Yokohama Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b91">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Daeyoun D Won</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Brian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Diego</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andre</forename><surname>Escobedo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Esteva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jessie</forename><surname>Aalipour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jung</forename><forename type="middle">Ha</forename><surname>Ge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susie</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Suh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Elliot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Choi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b92">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A mountable toilet system for personalized health monitoring via the analysis of excreta</title>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nat. Biomed. Eng</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="624" to="635" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b93">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pensieve: supporting everyday reminiscence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>S Tejaswi Peesapati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Johnathon</forename><surname>Schwanda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lepage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>So-Jeong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cosley</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2027" to="2036" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b94">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Undesigning technology: considering the negation of design design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pierce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="957" to="966" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b95">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Smart Home Security Cameras and Shifting Lines of Creepi-A Design-Led Inquiry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Pierce</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;19)</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;19)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b96">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sensor Illumination: Exploring Design Qualities and Ethical Implications of Smart Image/Video Analytics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><surname>Pierce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richmond</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Merrill</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Honolulu HI USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="19" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b97">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Framework for Understanding and Designing Telepresence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Irene</forename><surname>Rae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gina</forename><surname>Venolia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Molnar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">;</forename><surname>Melvin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Webber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 18th Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; ACM</title>
				<meeting>the 18th Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work &amp; ACM<address><addrLine>Vancouver BC Canada</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1974">2015. 1974. 1974</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="272" to="280" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Wicked Problems</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b98">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy in peril: How we are sacrificing a fundamental right exchange for security and convenience</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gilad</forename><surname>Rosner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erin</forename><surname>Kenneally</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Clearly Opaque: Privacy Risks of the Internet of Things</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Erin</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2018. May 1. 2018. 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Clearly opaque: Privacy risks of the internet of things</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b99">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Surveillance: Technology Practices of those Monitored by the State</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vasiliki</forename><surname>Sanches</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Asreen</forename><surname>Tsaknaki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barry</forename><surname>Rostami</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Brown</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing ACM</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing ACM<address><addrLine>Honolulu HI USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b100">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond the user: use and non-use in</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Satchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Dourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 21st annual conference of the Australian computerhuman interaction special interest group: Design: Open 24</title>
				<meeting>the 21st annual conference of the Australian computerhuman interaction special interest group: Design: Open 24</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="9" to="16" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b101">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Personality traits, usage patterns and information disclosure in online communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Johann</forename><surname>Schrammel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Köffel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Manfred</forename><surname>Tscheligi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">HCI &apos;09: Proceedings of the 2009 British Computer Society Conference on Human-Computer Interaction</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="169" to="174" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b102">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kirsten</forename><surname>Sengers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shay</forename><surname>Boehner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joseph'jofish'</forename><surname>David</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kaye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 4th decennial conference on Critical between sense and sensibility</title>
				<meeting>the 4th decennial conference on Critical between sense and sensibility</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="49" to="58" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b103">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strangers in the Room: Unpacking Perceptions of &quot;Smartness&quot; and Related Concerns in the Home</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Reuben</forename><surname>Seymour</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Petr</forename><surname>Binns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Max</forename><surname>Slovak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nigel</forename><surname>Van Kleek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shadbolt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2020 ACM Designing Interactive Systems Conference</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 ACM Designing Interactive Systems Conference<address><addrLine>Eindhoven Netherlands</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="841" to="854" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b104">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shepard</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Sentient City Survival Kit</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page">2022</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2009-03">March 9</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b105">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">You are Being Watched: Bystanders&apos; Perspective the Use of Camera Devices in Public Spaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Samarth</forename><surname>Singhal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carman</forename><surname>Neustaedter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thecla</forename><surname>Schiphorst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Tang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Ab-Patra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Pan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 CHI Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2016 CHI Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>San Jose California USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3197" to="3203" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b106">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond notice and choice: Privacy, and consent</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Sloan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>Warner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J High Tech L</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">370</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b107">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction: Privacy self-management and the consent</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Daniel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Solove</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Harv Rev</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">126</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1880</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b108">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding Boundaries between Policymaking and HCI</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>Spaa</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abigail</forename><surname>Durrant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Elsden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Vines</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b109">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The surveillant consumer</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karen</forename><surname>Stark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Levy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Media Cult. Soc</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1202" to="1220" />
			<date type="published" when="2018-11">2018. November 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b110">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Protection, Productivity and Pleasure in the Smart Home: Emerging and Gendered Insights from Australian Early Adopters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yolande</forename><surname>Strengers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><surname>Kennedy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paula</forename><surname>Arcari</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Larissa</forename><surname>Nicholls</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melissa</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Glasgow Scotland Uk</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b111">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Eyecam: Revealing Relations between Humans and Sensing Dethrough an Anthropomorphic Webcam</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Tech ; Marion Koelle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Strohmeier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jürgen</forename><surname>Fruchard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.theglassroom.org/en/home/Teyssier," />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Yokohama Japan</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Glass Room -Looking into your online life</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b112">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Accountabilities of reframing location-based systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emily</forename><surname>Troshynski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charlotte</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Dourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Droit Cult. Rev. Int. Interdiscip</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="171" to="193" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b113">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Preventing Recording by Designing a Capture-Resistant Environment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shwetak</forename><surname>Truong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jay</forename><surname>Patel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><surname>Summet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Abowd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b114">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intruders versus intruteens&apos; and parents&apos; perspectives on home-entryway surveillance</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaeyeon</forename><surname>Ur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Jung</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Schechter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2014 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Seattle Washington</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="129" to="139" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b115">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Things We Could Design: For More Than Human-Centered</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Verbeek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">What Things Do: Philosophical Reflections on Technology, Agency, and Design</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2021. 2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="163" to="172" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Proceedings of the 6th ACM SIGCHI conference on Creativity &amp; Cognition &apos;07)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b116">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The SelfReflector: Design, IoT and the High Street</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jayne</forename><surname>Wallace</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Shorter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pete</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martin</forename><surname>Skelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cook</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing ACM</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing ACM</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b117">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Proceedof the 2017 New Security Paradigms Workshop</title>
				<meeting>eedof the 2017 New Security Paradigms Workshop<address><addrLine>Santa Cruz CA USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The Third Wave?: Inclusive Privacy and Security</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b118">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Undesigning the Internet: An Exploratory Study of Reducing Internet Connectivity</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kelly</forename><surname>Widdicks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tina</forename><surname>Ringenson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Pargman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vishnupriya</forename><surname>Kuppusamy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patricia</forename><surname>Lago</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">EPiC Series in Computing, EasyChair</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="384" to="397" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b119">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bringing Design to the Privacy Table: Broadening &quot;Design&quot; in &quot;Privacy by Design&quot; Through the Lens of HCI</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">; -Y</forename><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deirdre</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mulligan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.huffingtonpost.co.uk/entry/nestie-awards-2017-hilarious" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing (CHI &apos;19)</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing (CHI &apos;19)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017. 2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Hilarious Moments Caught On Home Security Cameras</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b120">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sabbath Day Home &quot;It&apos;s Like Mixing Technology and Religion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sally</forename><surname>Woodruff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brooke</forename><surname>Augustin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Foucault</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2007 Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2007 Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. CHI 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b121">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy Perceptions and Designs of Bystanders in Smart Homes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yaxing</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Justin</forename><forename type="middle">Reed</forename><surname>Basdeo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Oriana</forename><forename type="middle">Rosata</forename><surname>Mcdonough</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yang</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-11">2019. November 2019</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b122">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy Mechanisms for Drones: Perceptions of Drone Controllers and Bystanders</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huichuan</forename><surname>Yao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yun</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Denver Colorado USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="6777" to="6788" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b123">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding Everyday Experiences of Reminiscence for People with Blindness: Practices, Tensions and New Design Possibilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">William</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arne</forename><surname>Odom</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Berger</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;21)</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;21)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b124">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">End User Security &amp; Privacy Concerns with Smart Homes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shrirang</forename><surname>Zeng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Franziska</forename><surname>Mare</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Roesner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b125">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">User Perceptions of Smart Home IoT Privacy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Serena</forename><surname>Zheng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Noah</forename><surname>Apthorpe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marshini</forename><surname>Chetty</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">20</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018-11">2018. November 2018</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b126">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Age of Surveillance Capitalism: The Fight for a Human Future at the New of Power</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shoshana</forename><surname>Zuboff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b127">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">61% Of Smart-Home Revenue Came From Security Cameras In Last Year. TWICE</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.twice.com/news/61-smart-home-revenue-came-security-cameras-last-year-62631" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
