<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">&apos;It Is Not Always Discovery Time&apos;: Four Pragmatic Approaches in Designing AI Systems</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Maximiliane</forename><surname>Windl</surname></persName>
							<email>maximiliane.windl@if.lmu.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sebastian</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Feger</surname></persName>
							<email>sebastian.feger@if.lmu.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Lara</forename><surname>Zijlstra</surname></persName>
							<email>l.e.zijlstra@uu.nl</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Albrecht</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
							<email>lbrecht.schmidt@if.lmu.de</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Paweł</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Woźniak</surname></persName>
							<email>pawel.wozniak@chalmers.se</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">LMU Munich Munich</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">LMU Munich Munich</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">Utrecht University Utrecht</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="NL">Netherlands</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">LMU Munich Munich</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="DE">Germany</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">Chalmers University of Technology Gothenburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="SE">Sweden</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">&apos;It Is Not Always Discovery Time&apos;: Four Pragmatic Approaches in Designing AI Systems</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3501943</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>artifcial intelligence</term>
					<term>design</term>
					<term>process</term>
					<term>data work</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>While systems that use Artifcial Intelligence (AI) are increasingly becoming part of everyday technology use, we do not fully understand how AI changes design processes. A structured understanding of how designers work with AI is needed to improve the design process and educate future designers. To that end, we conducted interviews with designers who participated in projects which used AI. While past work focused on AI systems created by experienced designers, we focus on the perspectives of a diverse sample of interaction designers. Our results show that the design process of an interactive system is afected when AI is integrated and that design teams adapt their processes to accommodate AI. Based on our data, we contribute four approaches adopted by interaction designers working with AI: a priori, post-hoc, model-centric, and competence-centric. Our work contributes a pragmatic account of how design processes for AI systems are enacted.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Human-centered computing → Human computer interaction (HCI).</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Artifcial intelligence (AI) is transforming the way we apply and design digital solutions in everyday tasks. In the public discourse there is an increased focus on mitigating the possibly negative aspects of AI. Ensuring control, including human values in the AI system, or designing AI products <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24]</ref> are highly desired qualities. However, building a user-centred AI future is only possible with the engagement of responsible interaction designers who can efectively work with AI. As a consequence, it is a task for Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) research to study existing and future design processes of AI-based systems to ensure that such solutions are designed with the user in mind.</p><p>Recent work in HCI has suggested that AI can be interpreted as a design material in interaction design <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">31]</ref>. This implies that designers need to efectively leverage AI's specifc properties and capitalise on the opportunities it provides. Holmquist <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> compared this need to graphic designers who need to be aware of the properties of the paper, printing press, color blends, and much more to design signifcant products. There is consensus in the community that we need to build a better understanding of design processes which involve AI and the ways in which designers harness the opportunities provided by AI.</p><p>Past research investigated the properties of AI which make it particularly complex in a design process. Such challenges include understanding the functionality <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b4">5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">30]</ref> and capabilities of AI <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">32]</ref>, prototyping and testing <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>, creating user value <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref>, and collaborating with developers and data scientists <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">30]</ref>. Given the multitude of factors which designers need to control, there is a need to empirically study design processes with AI in their current form to identify how they can be improved and how we can train future interaction designers. This paper aims to juxtapose the aspects of designing in AI reported in the literature with front-line experiences of design practitioners.</p><p>Current research investigating the infuence of AI on the design process is limited to a relatively small and specifc sample. Yang et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[30]</ref> interviewed 13 designers who all had extensive experience designing AI-enhanced products, mostly worked at very large companies, and designed products with a vast user base. In this work, we study a diferent group of designers. We portray the diverse landscape of designers by interviewing 20 designers from companies of various sizes. These designers have diferent levels of AI competence. In this work, we relate existing frameworks for AI-driven innovation <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">31]</ref> to the experiences reported by our participants. Our analysis resulted in four pragmatic approaches which design teams adopt when designing for AI: a priori, post-hoc, model-centric and competence-centric.</p><p>This paper is structured as follows. We frst report on related work to motivate our research questions. We then explain our methodology and sample and report on our fndings. Based on these fndings, we propose four approaches for how designers work with AI. Finally, in our discussion, we relate these processes to the fve human interventions in data science by Muller et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>.</p><p>Our work makes three key contributions: <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref> we provide empirical insights into how designers across a diverse sample help to create AI products; <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">(2)</ref> we contribute four approaches adopted by interaction designers working with AI: a priori, post-hoc, modelcentric and competence-centric; and (3) we relate the approaches in the development of AI products to the fve human interventions in AI <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>: discovery, capture, curation, design, and creation to show diferences in how design for AI systems is enacted in diverse environments.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED WORK</head><p>In this section, we refect on related work through three lenses:</p><p>(1) challenges and opportunities in designing Human-Centered AI (HCAI); (2) the growing body of work around the challenges of designing for AI; and (3) models and procedures for understanding AI and data-centric work practices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Human-Centered AI</head><p>HCAI is gaining importance to counteract concerns about biased data sets, discrimination of minorities, or privacy threats. Li and Etchemendy <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref> suggested that HCAI's goal is to serve "the collective needs of humanity." Therefore, in contrast to technical AI, HCAI does not only focus on algorithmic performance but also evaluates human performance and satisfaction, values user needs, and ensures control <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24]</ref>. Shneiderman <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref> argues that AI processes must be complemented with traditional HCI methods, such as user requirements analysis, design iterations, and usability testing, to create valuable products and services. They propose 15 recommendations to enable this shift towards HCAI and increase the reliability, safety, and trustworthiness of AI systems on three levels: (1) team, responsible for reliable software, (2) organization, ensuring a safety culture, and (3) industry, taking care of trustworthy certifcations from outside the organization. In this context, Shneiderman <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref> especially highlights the importance of designers who are responsible for explainable user interfaces. Our work provides an answer to Shneidermann's call for focusing on the designers. We study the difculties and opportunities experienced by interaction designers working with AI to better understand and improve design processes for HCAI.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Challenges Designing for AI</head><p>Recent work has investigated the difculties that make the design of AI products uniquely diferent and challenging. Xu <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref> states that current HCI methods are inherently insufcient for designing for AI, because they were created for non-intelligent systems. Instead, they suggest enhanced HCI methods, tailored explicitly for AI solutions. Prioritizing the use of machine intelligence functions over the usual focus on visual and interactive design has, for example, already shown to lead to more intuitive UIs and thus better UX <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>.</p><p>To investigate the practice and challenges of experienced UX designers working on AI products, Yang et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[30]</ref> conducted an interview study with 13 designers. They found that these designers did not think that extensive AI knowledge was necessary to design valuable products; much more critical was the focus on collaboration and a data-centric culture. Moreover, they found that the designers employed a "divide-and-conquer" approach when designing AI products, focusing on the design while barely engaging in technical aspects such as model construction or data collection. As a result, they did not have to adapt their design processes or acquire extensive AI knowledge. However, this strategy also led to protracted and iterative design processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref>. While these fndings accurately describe the experiences of those 13 designers, nine of whom worked at very large companies with more than 10,000 employees, they are only representative of a specifc group of designers. In Yang et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref>'s study, nine interviewees designed products used by more than one billion users and they were experienced in AI. Our work aims to extend these fndings by recruiting a more diverse set of designers from all company sizes and with diferent AI experience levels to portray the wider landscape of designers.</p><p>The challenges surrounding the design of AI products are diverse and can be subdivided into several distinct problem spaces. One such challenge is the designers' knowledge of the capabilities of AI. Designers are often unaware of what AI can and cannot do, which makes it challenging to come up with innovative ideas <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">33]</ref>. Close cooperation or co-designing with developers and data scientists can resolve this issue <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22]</ref>. However, such collaboration is often difcult, because developers and data scientists can be a limited resource in the company <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[30]</ref>, or communication is inherently difcult because both parties lack a common language and a shared workfow <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b30">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">30]</ref>.</p><p>Designers often struggle to create AI products that add value for users while also considering ethical aspects such as who is responsible for potential mistakes by the system <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8]</ref>. Prototyping AI products is another critical challenge because the prototypes have to resemble the complexity and uncertainty of AI models, while often requiring a large amount of data <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>. This makes the prototyping process slower and more difcult <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. As a result, designers often resort to Wizard of Oz methods for prototyping and testing <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b9">10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b15">16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20]</ref>. Another possible remedy is model-informed prototyping as proposed by Subramonyam et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>, which enables designers to directly work with AI features during prototyping.</p><p>Refecting on these challenges, Yang <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref> constructs an AI complexity framework that attributes these hurdles to two root causes: "evolving capabilities whose limits are difcult for designers to grasp, and complex, adaptive interactions that resist simulation." They argue that systems that share these characteristics arrive at the limits of conventional HCI methods and thus call for new methods and tools. Our work studies how these challenges and, possibly, solutions, are used in design practice in a diverse sample of interaction designers working in diferent domains.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Models and Perspectives around AI and Data-Centric Work</head><p>AI is rapidly changing the development and interaction of systems across all domains. In order to describe these changes, understand the complex activities involved in the design process, and provide frameworks for research and practice, the HCI feld has developed models and procedures involved in AI systems design. Olsson and Väänänen <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref> proposed to look at AI design practice through four perspectives: product, people, principles, and process. The product perspective concerns designing collaborative and proactive agents.</p><p>People asks to take into account for whom systems are designed and who is impacted by them, i.e. secondary and tertiary users.</p><p>Principles links to a set of fundamental ethical considerations, including explainability, autonomy, and fairness. Finally, the process perspective closely relates to our goal of better understanding design processes for AI systems. While Olsson and Väänänen argued that AI design should follow the basic stages of human-centered design, they stressed that this process was impacted by new challenges, including the need to recognize risks earlier and to develop an evolving understanding around the defnition of 'done'. In our work, we investigate how these perspective translate to the lived experience of interaction designers working with AI on an everyday basis.</p><p>Yang et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref> constructed a framework showing how the two main challenges of designing for AI, namely uncertainty and output complexity, afect the design process. They mapped these two challenges on the translation process between the technological capabilities and the user experience. Muller et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref> explored how data science workers work with data through an interview study with 21 professionals from IBM. Based on their fndings, they mapped fve human interventions that help to understand and formalize complex activities around data practices: Discovery, Capture, Curation, Design, and Creation. Discovery relates to data as given, for example in the form of client-provided or public datasets. Capture is referred to tasks around data integration, and data selection and substitution. Curation relates to activities involving data-cleaning, converting meta-data, and data-alignment. Design covers a wide range of activities, including imputing missing data, validating data, engineering features, and appropriation of external tools or data. Finally, the ffth intervention, Creation, concerns the crafting of data. Our research revealed that approaches employed by designers involved in the development of AI systems closely align to those fve human interventions. Therefore, we adapted this model and demonstrated its applicability in the context of designers working with data and models for AI systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">Summary and Research Questions</head><p>As AI increasingly raises concerns related to biased data sets, discrimination, or privacy, HCAI becomes more important <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>. Designers assume a unique role of ensuring the embedding of human aspects in AI systems. Designing AI products raises new challenges over those already discussed in the literature. Research has also found that designers barely engage in the technical aspects of AI projects, which leads to lengthy and repetitive processes. It is, however, unknown how these fndings expand to the diverse landscape of designers from diferent organizational sizes and with diverse experience levels. To this end, this paper applies existing models of designing AI systems in a new context. We provide an understanding of how designers adjust their processes to accommodate AI. We also reveal possibilities for the optimization of the AI design process. Our research was guided by the following two research questions:</p><p>RQ1: How does AI change interaction design processes? Research suggests that how and if the design process changes depends on the model's complexity level. While for low-level systems with static output the standard HCI methods sufce, completely new tools and techniques are needed for level four systems that constantly change and deliver unpredictable output <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref>. We investigated whether this holds for the everyday practice of a diverse sample of designers by examining what tools and methods they leverage and which specifc activities they perform in the context of AI projects.</p><p>RQ2: How do interaction designers engage in the development of AI systems? Research found that designers often do not engage in the technical aspects of AI projects <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[30]</ref>. This may lead to lengthy and repetitive processes and difculties in using the capabilities and output complexities of AI systems to their full extent <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref>. We investigated whether this assumption holds for a diverse sample of designers and studied how they engaged in the development of AI systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHOD</head><p>To achieve a comprehensive overview of designers' practices, we conducted semi-structured interviews with 20 designers. We used a retrospective research method to allow the participants to discuss completed projects from beginning to end, covering the entire design process. Previous studies on the practice of designers working with AI have used surveys and interviews <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b33">32]</ref>, which allowed for retrospective data gathering. Since design practice is difcult to capture in numbers or short textual descriptions, the type of data commonly gathered from a survey, we decided to conduct an in-depth interview study. Interviews are often used to characterize practice and acquire deeper insights associated with the matter <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. In addition to the interviews, we used a pre-interview survey to gather background information on the projects in which the designers were involved and demographic data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Interview protocol</head><p>Before we started an interview, we provided our interviewees with a short introduction and explanation of the study, followed by practical interview information, such as time and confdentiality. After they had signed the consent form, we began the actual interview. We centered the narrative of the interviews around an example AI project selected by the interviewee before the interview. We frst asked them to briefy describe their selected project. Then we asked how the project was initiated including at which point they got involved, the process they followed and specifc activities they performed, and any further challenges encountered during the project. We prepared nine additional topics, which we discussed either when participants mentioned them or later as specifc questions we initiated. The topics included data collection, AI knowledge, familiarization to AI as design material, design methods, prototyping, mental models, system changes over time, personalization, and the black-box nature of AI. We provide the complete interview guide as supplementary material.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Participants</head><p>We recruited the participants through four channels: the AI x Design Slack community, LinkedIn, our network, and snowball sampling. We identifed potential participants on LinkedIn by mentions of AI and design on their profles. To be included in our sample, participants had to match our inclusion criteria which were: 1) must self-identify as a designer, 2) must have experience working on products that contain or are powered by AI technologies, and 3) must have at least one (nearly) completed project or design case in the feld of AI.</p><p>Our sample illustrates the diverse landscape of designers involved in designing for AI. We interviewed 20 participants between 23 and 50 years old (M = 31.7, SD = 7.45). The experience levels of our participants in designing AI-enhanced products difered, see Table <ref type="table">1</ref>. Most (13) of the participants had a design background, three held a degree in computer science, one in law, two in engineering, and one did not hold a formal degree. The participants worked at companies of various sizes, with six coming from companies with fewer than 100 employees, three with 100-1,000 employees, three with 1,000-10,000 employees, and eight from large corporations with more than 10,000 employees.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Data Analysis</head><p>We recorded and transcribed 22.36 hours of audio during the 20 interviews (M = 70.6min, SD = 10.2min). We used thematic analysis and Atlas.ti to analyze our qualitative data <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Thereby, three researchers frst independently open-coded two randomly selected interviews. Afterwards, we met to discuss and compare these initial codes, and following this initial discussion the remaining interviews were divided among the three researchers for coding. In the third iteration, we formed categories of related codes and constructed themes. These themes were repeatedly reviewed by comparing and reviewing the coded extracts and comparing them to extracts from other themes. The full Atlas.ti code group report is available as supplementary material. In the end, this process led to the following four themes: Models and Data, Process, Team, and Translation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">FINDINGS</head><p>We present fndings from our study using the four themes Data and Models, Process, Team, and Translation. Data and Models are unique to AI-powered products and describe the properties of the models and data used in the design process and designers' responsibility and involvement in the data collection and model construction. The theme Process describes how the design process changes when AI products are designed, how these products are tested, and at what stage designers are involved. An interdisciplinary Team is of special importance in the context of AI projects. Designers frequently need to consult AI experts for the technical feasibility of their ideas or ask how a specifc algorithm or model works to be able to design an interface for it. On the other hand, the AI experts often need the designers' perspective to identify new opportunities for the applications of AI and not lose focus on the real-world value of the product. Designers often take a unique role in the team: they advocate for the users. This might take the form of Translation-translating the technical aspects for the users so that they can understand and use the product. Often, translation becomes mediation, where the designers need to negotiate between the user needs and the needs of the engineers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Data and Models</head><p>Our participants extensively discussed the challenges around data collection and preparation, the diferent roles they adopted in these processes, and the impact of data quality and fdelity on AI models. We present fndings related to four key aspects that informed this major theme: data collection; exploration; fdelity; and model and AI interaction.</p><p>Several designers stressed that they were for the frst time confronted with tasks and issues around data collection when they got involved in an AI project. Some designers were involved directly with in-situ data collection. P6 was involved in the development of an inventory organization app and took pictures of objects that the application was supposed to classify. Here, the designer needed to have an understanding of the approximate number of photos needed, as well as requirements around sample diversity (e.g. perspective and illumination). In contrast, P1 described a project for which the designers were themselves creating the data as part of the data collection process. They were tasked with creating a service that digitized sketched user interface wireframes and making them interactive. The designers frst sketched various prototypes themselves before taking pictures of their designs. Here again, the designers had to develop an understanding of model training requirements, in particular related to sketch and picture diversity. Other participants advised that for some of their projects their "data was given", either as part of public data sets or data provided by the client. In this context, P5 described the challenge of "narrowing the data" rather than creating or capturing it: I participated in narrowing the data that is about to add to the model.-P5 Finally, we observed that designers who were not taking an active part in any of those data collection strategies might be involved in the coordination, as another interviewee expressed: I do not manage the data myself, but I am in constant alignment with the people who do it.-P19 Designers often help in diferent ways to explore or interpret the collected data. To ensure good data quality and to report on quality assessments, some designers assume responsibilities associated with roles of data engineers or data scientist: One of the roles I see for myself often, when making data visualizations, is I try to sort of expose things like noise in the data, or outlying data points that maybe are indicative of some kind of error in the data sets. [...] Is the data that we are looking at actually correct?-P8 Our participants discussed practices and challenges around data fdelity. Several designers highlighted that they created and used fake data at some stage in the product development cycle. They did this instead of relying on data collection when the cost for collecting real data was too great or when they wanted to quickly test the feasibility of ideas: Sometimes you do not need real data to work on. You could totally fake up the data and start working and testing your model.-P11</p><p>In this context, several designers emphasized that the experience of building systems using fake data was similar to using real data:</p><p>There was no real data. This was all just design. But I kinda set up the prototype so it felt like you were adding data, you were adding things, and moving through the steps.-P12</p><p>The participants further discussed trade-ofs and usefulness of fake and real data extensively. In particular, the interview with P11 demonstrates this well. While emphasizing the value in using fake data to test models early on, the designer further demonstrated, related to a concrete project, that using mock data was not always feasible.</p><p>Another project that I am working on right now, for that one you cannot work on fake data at all because the whole concept is from real data. It's impossible.-P11 Our participants described the direct link between data and model fdelity, as well as the resulting implications. Some designers emphasized the importance of creating mock AI without underlying models to build an interaction-based communication channel with other team members. The time at which the model is introduced into the development cycle, as well as its fdelity, further impacts both visual and interaction design. In this context, P10 described an experience of a strongly evolving model, stressing:</p><p>It would be almost irresponsible to lock a certain design in as the one that must be followed.-P10 This notion of locking in a design is interesting, as it relates to a design process that is driven by the interface and user experience insights. In contrast, an example from P16 provides a contrasting perspective around data and model driven design processes:</p><p>Then engineering also brings up quite often some edge cases. We are like, well, we are gonna forecast ten metrics, and then how are we going to display our charts? And, you know, so that is where I think we came up with various layouts.-P16</p><p>In general, we see that the designers' workfows around core interaction tasks and data-centric responsibilities is becoming more diverse in AI projects. P4 stressed this in the context of discovery and delivery:</p><p>One quarter we are doing more discovery and in the next part we are more dedicated to deliver something. And this cadence happens all the time. So you have to understand this to work well. It is not always discovery time, it is not always delivery time. You have to balance.-P4 Table <ref type="table">1</ref>: Demographic and background data about the participants in our study including educational degree, their role in the project, their experience designing AI-enhanced products, the size of the organization, and the example project they chose to discuss. Our goal was to recruit a diverse sample of designers. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Process</head><p>This theme describes how the designers experienced the changes in their roles, responsibilities and work routines when using AI.</p><p>Most of the participants expressed clear opinions about how AI changed design processes. Few designers like P7 expressed that just because they machine learning, principal challenges and responsibilities around interaction design remained similar. Another interviewee argued that designing AI products was just like designing every other product: Now, why can't we look at that and go, there is nothing diferent here. It's still software, it's just a lot of advanced mathematics, or whatever you want from that.-P13 Yet most interviewees described substantial changes in the design process of AI applications. Some participants reported on preconceptualized or existing systems where AI was later integrated in order to transform the user experience through advanced features or to solve very specifc problems. P12 stressed that such an integration of limited AI features might have been the result of attempts to automate actions that users previously had to complete manually.</p><p>Our participants discussed when they were involved in the projects. The timing of designer involvement often determined the format of the design process. If an AI model serves the starting point, designers tend to get involved too late, after a product or feature has already been developed to a certain degree. That means they can no longer bring in their specifc expertise to guarantee that users will accept the feature. P12 echoed this: (I) was introduced too late to the process. That is a huge thing I know UX designers face. And there was one project where I was introduced to fx things after the engineering team had already implemented a big of the product-P12</p><p>Most participants, instead, emphasized the need to involve designers early on, even in projects with a pre-existing AI system. In this context, P10 highlighted that designers should be consulted about the design of application programming interfaces (APIs):</p><p>In a perfect world, design comes before engineering so we can guide the APIs and the other builds, what to build right.-P10 Further, we found that the time at which designers get involved impacts the range of activities that they can guide or impact during the design and development process. In projects built on existing AI, for example, their work focuses on the interaction design. In processes where AI is to be added to existing applications, designers participate in various activities around data collection and preparation, as outlined in the theme Data Models. Here, they also adapt and apply common design processes to support the developprocess at various stages. For example, P4 reported adopting common card sorting techniques to metadata. P9 further described applying wizard of oz methods to compensate for models that were not yet ready:</p><p>We want to quickly get some signal to the feld, [...] even if it's these days not yet possible by a machine. We try to still make our interventions in a way that we expect later on the algorithms will be available or the development team will just be able to develop such a system.-P9</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Team</head><p>Our participants stressed that team diversity and interdisciplinary eforts represent key pillars for many successful AI projects. For example, when developers create new models and features, they ask designers for input and visualizations. P16 talked about concrete experiences:</p><p>They want to bounce their ideas around with me and say, oh, you know, we have this technical piece that we are working on in an algorithm. And we think that it can be used here. So can you maybe spend half a day and put together some quick wireframes to capture the fow?-P16 In this context, P18 went even further and addressed the intricate interdependence:</p><p>I always say that it's teamwork. I cannot get my work without my other two colleagues. [...] My work is normally always dependent on theirs and theirs dependent on mine.-P18 The study participants extensively discussed the challenges communication between developers and designers. Most participants stressed designers needed a basic understanding of AI and its abilities and limitations in order for this relationship to work. In this context, P12 emphasized that AI knowledge had helped them in communicating with team members and taking part in the decision making process. P15 noted that the designer at the very least wants to be able to have an idea of the kind of technology that is suitable to address a real-world problem best. At the same time, most participants indicated that they had little to no knowledge about AI when starting on their current projects. Most participants reported learning the basics either through online courses or by learning on the fy, i.e. by continuously consulting the AI experts on the team for clarifcations or feasibility checks, as P11 stated:</p><p>I was having a lot of meetings internally with our product team, with our dev people to learn about limitations that we might have. Things we could do, things we could not do.</p><p>-P11 Yet, we also note that several designers stressed that they could not proft from in-depth knowledge around AI development. Few designers reported challenges in demonstrating their value and establishing their expertise within more technical project teams:</p><p>I am thinking about, more about how people accept the designer working on machine learning projects. It's not always easy. Some people still see the designers as UI designers. The designers have nothing to do with machine learning.-P15</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Translation</head><p>This theme relates to the designers' tasks and responsibilities around communication and translation of diferent perspectives, grounds, and expectations within the project teams. While designers traditionally play an important role at the interface between users and developers, role is changed when designing with AI.</p><p>The interviewees described how it was often the job of the designers to mediate between AI experts and non-AI experts in the team. Even though this translation within the team was essential, was perceived challenging and required work: I stayed over at work, and I have asked them to explain to me. Sometimes I have to admit I did not understand. They were also sometimes using neural networks and stuf that they sometimes explained to me like a black hole was complex, even for them.-P1 The need to explain constraints involved in the AI and its models was discussed as a novel and challenging task, possibly unrelated to traditional tasks of interaction designers. P14 provided an example that depicts the confict between user expectations model limitations:</p><p>We had to fnd a way to try to simplify what (the product) does in a way that was easily understandable. And they don't have a great mental model of all the machine learning going on when it takes ffteen minutes to get an output. But they're used to doing a Google search and getting immediate results. That was something that people didn't like. They didn't understand why it would take so long.-P14 The buzz around AI that has been pushed by media reports and fctional material has resulted in many people overestimating capabilities, necessitating additional translation eforts between developers both customer and end users. P11 talked about their frustration dealing with unrealistic expectations, stressing that users had "absurd and unrealistic wishes". Finally, turning those unfeasible expectations into features that add value, represents a major efort in translation It's very hard to fnd this match between users and AI. AI is powerful, in some cases, it's over-marketed The biggest factor here is to fnd the right use case for making AI work in a meaningful way and a valuable way.-P5</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">Design Approaches in Interaction Design for AI systems</head><p>Based on fndings from the interviews, we classifed the design decisions and processes in which the design teams engaged into four approaches. We used the term approaches to encapsulate both intentional actions, similar to strategies, as well as actions that are at least partly driven by the socio-technical frameworks of the designers. These approaches represent archetypes of how design teams deal with the challenge of including a data model as part of a user-centered design process of interactive technologies. Figure <ref type="figure">1</ref> shows the four approaches: a priori, post-hoc, model-centric and competence-centric. While the frst two approaches focus more on aspects, the second two are more process-orientated. We describe the approaches in terms of how the system's interface interrelates with the underlying AI model. This enables us to discuss the infuence of including AI in the design process and showcases the diferences between how system design is understood within teams. In the following, we describe the approaches in detail.</p><p>A Priori. As we saw in Data Models, many designers were confronted with data and models for the frst time when AI was introduced the project. This led to entirely new challenges, uncertainties and processes. Further, as seen in team, some designers struggled with understanding the capabilities of AI or even felt that deeper AI knowledge would distract them from their core tasks. As a consequence, some design teams opted for not engaging with AI whatsoever treated the AI functionality as a priori correct and functioning according to plan. The model could have been sidered ready both when it was implemented and tested or when no further engineering work was possible due to company policy. An alternative scenario was assuming that the specifcation of an unimplemented model was fully correct and perfect functionality was assumed through an intermediate artifact-a model which was considered to be ready. An advantage of this approach was that the design team felt independent of the AI specialists could focus on enacting their usual, unchanged design process. However, adopting this approach also introduced vulnerability as most models are imperfect and change over time. A design process where the model is assumed to be static may introduce problems where the model does not produce ideal results. Another risk is that the fnalised product lacks real user value and thus real-world applicability because the designers were involved too late (cf. process).</p><p>Example Project. Designers working with this approach repeatedly reported being involved too late to sufciently infuence the project's success or even to fx an unsuccessful product already on the market. P14 was employed to evaluate and redesign a topic model generator that had already been released was not being very well received the users. The problematic aspects were mainly the result of the developers neglecting the non-technical perspective, as we observed in teams. One issue was, for example, its long execution time. The designer reported being overwhelmed the complexities of the project and spending weeks coming to understand the project and constraints of the model. Model-wise, the designer was mainly focused on the in-and outputs because the model was already implemented, making any further impact impossible.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5.2">Post-hoc.</head><p>The post-hoc approach is, fguratively, a mirror image of the a priori approach. Like the former, this approach is primarily adopted by teams who desire a clear separation between model and interface development. The teams adopting this approach usually limited their translation activities to the minimum. Instead, a clear separation between the design team and the data team was in place, as we observed in teams. Providing the data team with a detailed specifcation of what the AI in the system should do was the ultimate goal of the design team. Design iterations were conducted until an accurate enough specifcation of the required model was developed. the interface was fnalised, the design team defned the inputs of the model and specifed what kind of inference was required the system to ofer a user-friendly experience. This approach has the advantage of giving the design team a high degree of independence. On the other hand, it ignores possible design constraints posed by the technical implementation of a model.</p><p>Example Project. P3 reports about a project where they were tasked with creating a fan experience for visually impaired people.</p><p>The designers frst developed the design using traditional techniques. They hardly deviated from their usual process by employing regular and known strategies for requirements analysis and ideation such as brainstorming sessions or participatory design. After the design was fnished, designers tasked the AI experts with the realization of the The designers were not involved in any of the technical aspects of the project, such as data collection or model construction. In fact, the participant was unsure whether the fnal product included the designed functionality.</p><p>1: Four approaches for designing for and with AI. The approaches describe how the design teams in our study included models in their design process and how they adapted their methods to include (or avoid) designing a data model.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5.3">Model-Centric.</head><p>Our results show that teams that adopted this approach used the data model not only as a key element of the systems but also as a vehicle for driving the design process forward.</p><p>contrast to the previous two approaches where the data and model were treated separate from the design, the designers were now directly involved in technical aspects. Thus, this approach required where the AI experts were to share their expertise with the interface designers. In process, we observed how the integrated team developed model together, considering its limitations and possible training sets. To allow for iterative interface development, the teams built intermediate models with limited functionality. This enabled early prototyping and synchronisation (models and Further, as the design team developed understanding of what was possible given the AI solutions available in the project, they could develop fake AI tools for prototyping in anticiof trained models later in the process. This approach allows for coherent coordination between the design and data teams and facilitates developing the model and the interface in parallel. It does, however, come at a cost. In the translation theme, we observed that adopting this approach spent extra efort and resources on coordination and translation. Further, this approach is highly dependent on the team members' skills in sharing knowledge.</p><p>Example Project. P13 reported on a project where the modelcentric approach was applied. They developed an intelligent assistant for optimizing chemical processes and operations. The design and model were constructed together a steady and clear focus on teamwork. There was consensus that the combination of diverse expertise would to a successful outcome. Thus, the designers were involved in almost every step of the data collection model construction. In the data collection, they could bring in their extensive knowledge about human decision-making, as described in models and data. The designers were even responsible for the decision of what model to use. They decided to use an optimizer instead of a concrete prediction to keep the decision-making power with the users. The designers were so involved in the technical aspects of the project that they even participated in testing and executing the model. Artifacts used in the design process, such as paper prototypes, were developed and evaluated together to guide the model development.</p><p>Competence-Centric. The fnal approach was used by teams where the design and data teams featured members with diverse competence. In models and data, we observed how understanding the diferent roles of the team members led to helping each other defne tasks. Thus, users would collectively decide when to train and build models or when to use simulated input. This resulted in a divergent design process where multiple intermediate artifacts were developed at the same The multitude of ideas and prototypes contributed to an exploratory approach to developing model and interface. Further, on more atomic artifacts contributed to more translation and team members understanding the priorities of their colleagues. Adopting this approach emphasises the individual skills and creativity of the team members. However, divergent nature of the process may make it difcult to control the temporal aspect of the process, especially as divergent design iterations are often not synchronised. This approach appears to be most suitable for exploratory projects where the exact nature of the AI system is to be defned.</p><p>Example Project. P10 employed a competence-centric approach to develop an enterprise search for a large corporation. Even though the design and model were developed in parallel, the process was not as interwoven in the model-centric approach. Instead, the designers and AI specialists focused on their specifc expertise and repeatedly synced to ensure the individual developments matched, which could be time-consuming. The designer was once again responsible for bringing in human expertise. This was, however, not achieved by developing the model together with the AI specialist but rather by testing the fnished model (or selected parts of it) and reporting problems. Since the teams were disconnected, artifacts used in the process were divergent and required translation. The design team, for example, constructed their own test data set to be able to evaluate whether the model matched their user interface. 4.5.5 Summary. Depending on the capabilities of the team and constraints of the project, designers employ diferent approaches when designing AI products. The a-priori approach assumes the model to be fnished before the start of the UI development, so the challenge for designers is fulflling the requirements the model. In contrast, in the post-hoc approach, the UI design is completed before the model, implying that the model is built to ft the requirements the design. In both approaches, the design team is not required deeply engage in the data aspects of the project. In in the model-centric approach, the model is at the core of the project and the designers are strongly involved in nearly all technical aspects. The competence-centric approach is similar in the that it also requires designers to engage with the data, albeit never in a leading. The competence-centric approach leverages a clear focus on the heterogeneous expertise within the team. Finally, we note that there is an apparent conceptual divide between the four approaches. The frst two approaches, a-priori and post-hoc are focused on temporal aspects, are impacted by techno-economical constraints. This implies that these approaches are primarily motivated by the infrastructure already in place within an organization and, possibly, how technical processes are organized. In contrast, model-centric and competence-centric approaches are process-oriented. Thus, they are primarily determined by the social dynamics within the development team and the particular combination of skills present when developing a system.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">DISCUSSION</head><p>The fndings of our interviews show that the designers adopted pragmatic solutions to efectively include AI development in their design processes. Contrary to past work, our results paint a picture of designing AI which is more diverse and requires more makeshift solutions. Our approaches provide, on the useful through which the design processes can be analyzed in retrospect. On the other, they can serve as a guideline to decide for a certain approach or an adaptation of organizational frameworks tailored to desired outcomes or constraints of a project.</p><p>In order to contextualise our fndings within past work, we relate the four approaches which we observed to the fve human interventions in data science practice as postulated by Mueller et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>, as shown in Figure <ref type="figure">2</ref>. As predicted by Mueller et al., we identifed elements of all fve interventions in our fndings. In the a priori and post-hoc approaches, some of the human interventions are decoupled from the interaction design process and designers do not take part in them. Thus, discovery, capture and curation are delegated to a diferent team. In our results, teams using those approaches did not report participating in those interventions. In the model-centric stategy, we observed that there was intensive lation work at the boundary between and design. Here, design teams used artifacts which helped them communicate what the model could (potentially) deliver and how it could be improved.</p><p>took the form of developing fake AI or partially functional models. These intermediate artifacts allowed the entire team to be part of all fve interventions. Finally, in the competence-centric approach, the teams developed numerous divergent artifacts. This implied that multiple interventions happened simultaneously. This way, diferent members of the design teams could participate in diferent interventions at diferent times.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">From Perfect Processes to Pragmatic Approaches</head><p>In contrast to previous work that found that AI design processes are characterized by a clear separation of technology and design <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[31]</ref>, our fndings suggest diverging levels of designer involvement in the data collection and model construction. Our four approaches show these diferent levels. When either the a priori or post-hoc approach is applied, the model and design are independent, which is in line with insights from previous studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[30]</ref>. Our results show that a low involvement in the model can be result of specifc company culture, strategic decision or a result of the designers being uncomfortable in dealing with the technicalities of AI. However, contrast to previous research, our interviewees reported occasions of great involvement the technical aspects, where the designers even took part in the data collection and model testing. As seen in the competence-centric or model-centric approaches, the designers are consciously involved in the technical aspects. In contrast to previous work that stated that designers did not feel a need for extensive AI knowledge to be able to efectively collaborate with the technical team <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[30]</ref>, our interviewees reported that greater knowledge was an important building block for efective collaboration. In the model-centric approach, designers and AI specialists develop the model and product together. This approach results in the biggest involvement of designers in the technical process as they are asked to bring in their expertise to every stage of the model development. When the competence-centric approach is employed, designers and AI specialists develop the product in parallel while each team is focused on their specifc expertise. the involvement of the designers takes a diferent form.</p><p>Looking at the approaches from a designer involvement point of view, it can be observed adapting one of the approaches can result in a certain level of involvement. Alternatively, the approach could be a pragmatic product of the level of involvement which is comfortable for the interaction designers. In the design processes studied in this paper, a common requirement all approaches was that designers needed to develop an understanding of the data quality and diversity needed to train models. This was achieved with difering levels of success. Our work suggests that there is a need to further study the organisational processes which lead to determining the approaches in order to understand why particular design scenarios are enacted. Further, our results show that while past models of AI-based design processes are useful in understanding how the intellectual value is built through AI, further work needed to see how design teams can reach a stage where these processes are in place in an optimal form.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Towards Improved Processes for Designing AI systems</head><p>The approaches presented in work can serve as archetypes for understanding the pros and cons of diferent process choices when designing for AI. For example, the competence-centric approach is especially useful for exploratory projects where time is not an important factor since its divergent nature fosters creativity, which may come at a time cost. The a-priori and post-hoc approaches might be a direct response to the project's constraints when the design team is included in the project to develop a product after a viable model is built. Some teams may not have the capacity to foster the close cooperation needed in the model-centric or competence-centric approaches. While future design processes most likely use a blend of the approaches identifed in this paper, our insights can help understand the pros and cons of the approaches and tailor particular processes to a particular task and design team. We note that the approaches identifed in our work are purely empirical-many of the design cases described in this paper describe often emergent practices rather than elaborate processes with extensive Thus, our account can be used by future researchers to chart if and how the nature of designing with AI will change in the future. Further, while future design activities can choose to explicitly adopt one of the approaches, we anticipate that it might be efective to use diferent approaches at diferent stages of the design. While we did observe such shifts, we anticipate that this should be possible with the development of designing with AI. For instance, design processes could initially a competence-centric to foster and then shift to a model-centric approach as the technical product matures. These approach choices could mimic how using diferent tools in the design process allows 2: The four approaches for designing with AI identifed in our study related to the fve human interventions in science by Mueller et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. As our approaches identify continual processes, they need to be visually presented in a certain order, yet the intervention can happen in any order and their timing is primarily determined by the needs of the design process.</p><p>for diferent levels of convergent thinking <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> and thus allows better control of the design process.</p><p>Finally, a key fnding of our work is the fact that most of the processes we studied were grassroots determined by particular team and organizational cultures. This indicates that there is future research needed in how we can explicitly organize such processes. More importantly, we need to understand how we can meaningfully include AI in interaction design education so that processes such as the ones described in this paper require efort. The approaches presented in this paper contribute to the discussion on how we can create efective design teams for AI that support interdisciplinary collaboration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Limitations</head><p>We recognise that inquiry is prone certain limitations. While we did aim to recruit a diverse sample of designers, there certainly is more diversity in AI design teams. Future studies should investigate approaches AI design teams across diferent organisational cultures and geographical locations. Moreover, our analytical lens treated design teams as single entities which traversed design processes. Further insights can be achieved by studying diferent roles of designers between and investigating individual accounts multiple designers from a single team. Finally, we note that we classifed the design processes reported in our data into a fnite set of four approaches. While these approaches present analytical archetypes of the stories contained in the interviews, they also present an inherently holistic view of the approaches. Thus, the approaches do not fully represent the temporally unstable nature of the design processes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">CONCLUSION</head><p>In this paper, we studied accounts of designing with AI by 20 interaction designers. In contrast to past work, we studied a diverse group with diferent levels of AI competence, working in organisations of diferent sizes. Through thematic analysis, we identifed four themes which described the designers' experience of designing AI systems: Data Models, Process, Team, and Translation. Based on the themes, we identifed four design approaches (a priori, post-hoc, model-centric and competence-centric), which teams adopted to adjust their design process to include AI. We then related the approaches to Mueller et al. 's fve human interventions in data science to show how the design processes can vary in levels of designer involvement. We hope that our work inspires further research on how AI design is enacted by practitioners.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc></figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="10,104.24,83.68,403.53,455.46" type="bitmap" /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>This work has been funded by the German Federal Ministry of Education and Research (BMBF) under Grant No. 01IS18036A. The authors of this work take full responsibilities for its content.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trends and Trajectories for Explainable, Accountable and Systems: An HCI Research Agenda</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ashraf</forename><surname>Abdul</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jo</forename><surname>Vermeulen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danding</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brian</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Lim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mohan</forename><surname>Kankanhalli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3174156</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3174156" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guidelines for Human-AI Interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Saleema</forename><surname>Amershi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Weld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Mihaela</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Besmira</forename><surname>Fourney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Penny</forename><surname>Nushi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jina</forename><surname>Collisson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shamsi</forename><surname>Suh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Iqbal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kori</forename><surname>Bennett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>Inkpen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ruth</forename><surname>Teevan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eric</forename><surname>Kikin-Gil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290605.3300233</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3290605.3300233" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Qualitative HCI Research: Going Behind the Scenes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Blandford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dominic</forename><surname>Furniss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephann</forename><surname>Makri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.2200/S00706ED1V01Y201602HCI034</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.2200/S00706ED1V01Y201602HCI034" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>Morgan &amp; Claypool Publishers</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="51" to="60" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Help: Designing a Workfow-Based Scheduling Agent with Humans in the Loop</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Cranshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Emad</forename><surname>Elwany</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Todd</forename><surname>Newman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rafal</forename><surname>Kocielnik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bowen</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sandeep</forename><surname>Soni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>Teevan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrés</forename><surname>Monroy-Hernández</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3025453.3025780</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3025453.3025780" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2382" to="2393" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note type="report_type">Calendar</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">UX Design Innovation: Challenges for Working with Machine Learning as a Design Material</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Graham</forename><surname>Kim Halskov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jodi</forename><surname>Forlizzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Zimmerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3025453.3025739</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3025453.3025739" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="278" to="288" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Digital Tools Impact Convergent and Divergent Thinking in Design Ideation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonas</forename><surname>Frich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Midas</forename><surname>Nouwens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kim</forename><surname>Halskov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Dalsgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3411764.3445062</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445062" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA, Article</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">431</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">When User Experience Designers Partner with Data Scientists</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fabien</forename><surname>Girardin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Neal</forename><surname>Lathia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.aaai.org/ocs/index.php/SSS/SSS17/paper/view/15364" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lars</forename><forename type="middle">Erik</forename><surname>Holmquist</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3085571</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3085571" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Intelligence on Tap: Artifcial Intelligence as a New Design Material. Interactions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="28" to="33" />
			<date type="published" when="2017-06">2017. June 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Identifying the Intersections: User Experience + Research Scientist Collaboration in a Generative Machine Learning Interface</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Claire</forename><surname>Kayacik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sherol</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Signe</forename><surname>Noerly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jess</forename><surname>Holbrook</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Roberts</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Eck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290607.3299059</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3290607.3299059" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Extended Abstracts of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Glasgow, Uk; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI EA &apos;19)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Suede: A Wizard of Oz Prototyping Tool for Speech User Interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anoop</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Klemmer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jack</forename><surname>Sinha</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nadeem</forename><surname>Landay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Annie</forename><surname>Aboobaker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/354401.354406</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/354401.354406" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 13th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology</title>
				<meeting>the 13th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology<address><addrLine>San Diego, California, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="10" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>UIST &apos;00)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jef</forename><surname>Larson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julia</forename><surname>Angwin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Surya</forename><surname>Mattu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lauren</forename><surname>Kirchner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.propublica.org/article/machine-bias-risk-assessments-in-criminal-sentencing" />
		<title level="m">Machine bias</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Lazar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jinjuan</forename><surname>Heidi Feng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harry</forename><surname>Hochheiser</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.safaribooksonline.com/library/view/research-methods-in/" />
		<title level="m">Research Methods in Human-Computer Interaction</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Cambridge, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Morgan Kaufmann</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>2 ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Welcome to the Stanford Institute for Human-Centered Artifcial Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fei-Fei</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Etchemendy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://hai.stanford.edu/about/welcome" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">How Data Science Workers Work with Data: Discovery, Capture, Curation, Design, Creation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ingrid</forename><surname>Lange</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dakuo</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Piorkowski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jason</forename><surname>Tsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Q</forename><forename type="middle">Vera</forename><surname>Liao</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Casey</forename><surname>Dugan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Erickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290605.3300356</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3290605.3300356" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How Does AI Challenge Design Practice?</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Olsson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kaisa</forename><surname>Väänänen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3467479</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3467479" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-06">2021. June 2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="62" to="64" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Wizard of Oz Studies in HRI: A Systematic Review and New Reporting Guidelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laurel</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Riek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.5898/JHRI.1.1.Riek</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.5898/JHRI.1.1.Riek" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Hum.-Robot Interact</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="119" to="136" />
			<date type="published" when="2012-07">2012. July 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Meaningful Human Control over Autonomous Systems: A Philosophical Account</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Filippo</forename><surname>Santoni De Sio</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeroen</forename><surname>Van Den Hoven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3389/frobt.2018.00015</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3389/frobt.2018.00015" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Frontiers in Robotics and AI</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">15</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bridging the Gap Between Ethics and Practice: Guidelines for Reliable, Safe, and Trustworthy Human-Centered AI Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ben</forename><surname>Shneiderman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3419764</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3419764" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. Interact. Intell. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">31</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-10">2020. Oct. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design Lessons From AI&apos;s Two Grand Goals: Human Emulation and Useful Applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Shneiderman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Transactions on Technology and Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="82" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing Natural Speech Interactions for the Living Room</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lisa</forename><surname>Stifelman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Elman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><surname>Sullivan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2468356.2468574</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2468356.2468574" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CHI &apos;13 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Paris, France; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1215" to="1220" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CHI EA &apos;13)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">ProtoAI: Model-Informed Prototyping for AI-Powered Interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hariharan</forename><surname>Subramonyam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Colleen</forename><surname>Seifert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eytan</forename><surname>Adar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3397481.3450640</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3397481.3450640" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">26th International Conference on Intelligent User Interfaces</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>College Station, TX, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="48" to="58" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>IUI &apos;21)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2021. Towards A Process Model for Co-Creating AI Experiences</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Colleen</forename><surname>Hariharan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eytan</forename><surname>Seifert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Adar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3461778.3462012</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3461778.3462012" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Designing Interactive Systems Conference 2021</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1529" to="1543" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Prototyping Ways of Prototyping AI</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Van Allen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3274566</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3274566" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interactions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="51" />
			<date type="published" when="2018-10">2018. Oct. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Afrmative and silent cyber coverage in traditional insurance policies: Qualitative content analysis of selected insurance products German insurance market. The Geneva Papers on Risk and Insurance -Issues and Practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dirk</forename><surname>Wrede</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Johann-Matthias</forename><surname>Stegen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Graf Von Der Schulenburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1057/s41288-020-00183-6</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1057/s41288-020-00183-6" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-10-01">2020. 01 Oct 2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">45</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="657" to="689" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward Human-Centered AI: A Perspective from Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3328485</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3328485" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Interactions</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="42" to="46" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-06">2019. June 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Applications of an interaction, process, integration and intelligence (IPII) design approach for ergonomics solutions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wei</forename><surname>Xu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dov</forename><surname>Furie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Manjunath</forename><surname>Mahabhaleshwar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bala</forename><surname>Suresh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hardev</forename><surname>Chouhan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/00140139.2019.1588996</idno>
		<idno type="PMID">30836051</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/00140139.2019.1588996" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ergonomics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">62</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="954" to="980" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Profling Artifcial Intelligence a Material for User Experience Design. dissertation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qian</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mapping Machine Advances from HCI Research to Reveal Starting Places for Design Innovation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qian</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nikola</forename><surname>Banovic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Zimmerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="11" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maximiliane</forename><surname>Windl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3173704</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173704" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sketching NLP: A Case Study of Exploring the Right Things To Design with Language Intelligence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qian</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Cranshaw</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Saleema</forename><surname>Amershi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Shamsi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jaime</forename><surname>Iqbal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Teevan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290605.3300415</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3290605.3300415" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Investigating How Experienced UX Designers Efectively Work with Machine Learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qian</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alex</forename><surname>Scuito</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Zimmerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jodi</forename><surname>Forlizzi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Steinfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3196709.3196730</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3196709.3196730" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 Designing Interactive Systems Conference</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 Designing Interactive Systems Conference<address><addrLine>Hong Kong, China; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="585" to="596" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>DIS &apos;18)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Re-Examining Whether, Why, and How Human-AI Interaction Is Uniquely Difcult to Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qian</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><forename type="middle">Carolyn</forename><surname>Rosé</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Zimmerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3313831.3376301</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3313831.3376301" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Grounding Interactive Machine Learning Tool Design in How Non-Experts Actually Build Models</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qian</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jina</forename><surname>Suh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nan-Chen</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gonzalo</forename><surname>Ramos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3196709.3196729</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3196709.3196729" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2018 Designing Interactive Systems Conference</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 Designing Interactive Systems Conference<address><addrLine>Hong Kong, China; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="573" to="584" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>DIS &apos;18)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Planning Adaptive Mobile Experiences When Wireframing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Qian</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Zimmerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aaron</forename><surname>Steinfeld</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anthony</forename><surname>Tomasic</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2901790.2901858</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2901790.2901858" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2016 ACM Conference on Designing Interactive Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2016 ACM Conference on Designing Interactive Systems<address><addrLine>Brisbane, QLD, Australia; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="565" to="576" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>DIS &apos;16)</note>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
