<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Unpacking Practitioners&apos; Atitudes Towards Codifications of Design Knowledge for Voice User Interfaces</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Krishika</forename><forename type="middle">Haresh</forename><surname>Khemani</surname></persName>
							<email>krishika.khemani@nottingham.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Horizon Digital Economy Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nottingham</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Reeves</surname></persName>
							<email>stuart.reeves@nottingham.ac.uk</email>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">School of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="laboratory">Mixed Reality Lab</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Nottingham</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Unpacking Practitioners&apos; Atitudes Towards Codifications of Design Knowledge for Voice User Interfaces</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3517623</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Design guidelines</term>
					<term>voice user interfaces</term>
					<term>industry practitioners</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Recent HCI research has sought to develop guidelines-'heuristics', 'best practices', 'principles' and so on-for voice user interfaces (VUI) to aid both practitioners and researchers in improving the quality of VUI-based design. However, limited research is available on how such design knowledge is conceptualised and used by industry practitioners. We present a small interview-based study conducted with 9 experienced VUI industry practitioners. Their concerns range from terminological challenges associated with VUI design knowledge, the role of codifcations of such knowledge like design guidelines alongside their practical design work, through to their views on the value of 'harmonisation' of VUI design knowledge. Given the complex-albeit preliminary-picture that emerges, we argue for HCI's deeper consideration of how design knowledge meshes with the contingencies of practice, so that VUI design knowledge-such as design guidelines developed in HCI-delivers the most potential value for industry practice.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>A key part of HCI's programme has been in the development of tools to generalise and codify (i.e., document or formalise) design knowledge and provide reliable resources to support design work <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[36]</ref>. This includes-variously-heuristics, guidelines, frameworks, best practices, principles, and so on (see <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[36]</ref>). Recent research interest in conversational user interfaces has (perhaps somewhat naturally) also led to the development of design tools like guidelines for voice user interfaces (VUI) <ref type="bibr">[9, 13-15, 37, 41, 42]</ref>. And like more general HCI design knowledge that is presented as guidelines etc., codifed VUI design knowledge also tend to be presented as application-oriented and framed for audiences of both practitioners (e.g., VUI designers in industry) and researchers.</p><p>At the same time, industry UX and design practice in VUIstrongly oriented to specifc platforms like Alexa, Siri or Google Assistant which tend to defne and delimit what is meant by 'VUI'is expanding, and maturing. Like academic HCI, it too is seeking ways to preserve, codify, and share generalised design knowledge in the form of practitioner-originated guidelines, best practices, principles and so on (e.g., see Deibel and Evanhoe's recent book <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>). This move refects practitioners' prior familiarity with codifed design knowledge and experience of their value within design work for more traditional interfaces-desktop, web, mobile-for which signifcant eforts have been made in, e.g., infuential style guides <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">24]</ref>.</p><p>However, it is unclear how these various emerging forms of codifed design knowledge for voice user interfaces, particularly from research, will meet the needs of practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref> given that we do not know much about how VUI practitioners conceptualise them or indeed actually use them in the frst place. To begin sketching out the dimensions of this problem space, we conducted a survey and interviewed a number of VUI design practitioners to discuss their work with respect to what they consider to be relevant 'design guidelines', and uncover some initial concerns with which to orient future HCI research on VUI practitioners' design practices. We focussed on 'design guidelines' as a way into conversations with them rather than a more abstract notion like 'codifed design knowledge', which we use in this paper to refer to such resources.</p><p>In this paper, at frst, we very briefy examine how codifed design knowledge has been discussed within relevant research communities (e.g., HCI, conversational user interface (CUI) research, etc.). We also look at the role of this in GUI, interactive voice response (IVR) and VUI design and its impact on UX. Then we discuss platformspecifc VUI 'design guidelines' published by industry practitioners, alongside contributions made by academic research. Turning to our empirical studies, we describe the approach we used to explore how practitioners treat such codifed design knowledge, then present our fndings structured around the following: variation in use of terminology, integration of guidelines and considerations in practitioners' design process, and lastly harmonisation of design guidelines. By 'harmonisation' we mean the notion that various codifcations may be brought together somehow for varied potential purposes: e.g., increasing consistency, establishing standards, or generating community agreement on design. We conclude with a discussion on the salient issues arising from our fndings with respect to HCI research and implications of this for potential areas of further exploration.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">DESIGN PRINCIPLES, GUIDELINES, HEURISTICS AND BEST PRACTICES</head><p>We frst need to lay some groundwork for our interview study's fndings, frstly by scoping the domains of conversational UI, voice UI, and so on. Then we examine the language of codifcations of design knowledge, their expression within prior HCI and interaction design, and review emerging discussions on the development of design knowledge codifcations for VUI design research and practice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Scoping conversational user interfaces (CUI) and voice interfaces</head><p>Here we want to provide some context for our interest in voice user interfaces specifcally, and very briefy tease out the complexities of this space, particularly given that some of our interviewees had experience in, say, IVRs or chatbots (which were not the topic of our investigation but nevertheless related). The notion of interfaces that engage in 'dialogue' or 'conversation' has of course had a long history and goes by various names-conversational interfaces, speech user interfaces, IVRs, voice assistants, smart speakers, etc. Ultimately, however, the interactional modes of such interfaces tend to either be text-based ('chatbots') or voice-based. CUIs can be defned as interfaces where the "user interaction is conducted primarily through words: typed or spoken. " <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[41]</ref>. As implied by the name, voice user interfaces use 'voice' as a mode of interaction <ref type="bibr">[32]</ref>. Interactive voice response (IVR) systems and voice assistants (e.g., Siri, Alexa, etc.) are the two main types of voice user interfaces. IVRs-developed since the 1970s-are mainly integrated with telephone systems and use a menu-based approach to carry out a limited number of tasks for the user, often integrating speech recognition since the 1990s. Voice assistants on the other hand have been designed with speech recognition as a given, and ofer a much wider range of tasks. Ultimately, however, text-based and voice-based conversational interfaces have a similar architecture for handling input and output. The main diference is that voice-based interfaces employ Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR) and Speech-to-Text (STT) components <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[39]</ref>, but both interfaces are often implemented using similar natural language processing engines and back-end dialogue management systems to process data. Our paper therefore, while focusing on modern, voice assistant platforms that are popular with UX practitioners, may have some implications for conversational UI in general.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Codifcations of design knowledge: Design guidelines and afliated concepts</head><p>Prior work has sought to clarify and defne what is meant by (e.g.) design principles, design guidelines and heuristics [29, <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">33,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">35]</ref>. HCI researchers and practitioners suggest that guidelines and other forms of HCI knowledge like principles or heuristics are derived from empirical research and practical experiences [29, <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">35]</ref>. One view distinguishes design principles as "laws" that drive the design process forward to produce efective solutions and design guidelines as "context-dependent directives" <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[35]</ref> or recommendations on how design principles should be applied <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">33]</ref>. The term heuristics is also often used, with some arguing that although they are similar in nature to design guidelines as contextdependent rules, they are usually less prescriptive in nature than design guidelines and can also be descriptive <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[35]</ref>. In this view, heuristics are based on "intuition, tacit knowledge, or experiential understanding" <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[35]</ref>. Others argue that heuristics may be thought instead as "rules of thumb" or (circularly) "principles" <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[30,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">33]</ref> because they are thought to be not as specifc as design guidelines. Another term in use is best practices. Suhm argues that best practices are simply design guidelines which produce a "positive impact" <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref> which can be evaluated using an appropriate metric.</p><p>As may be clear at this point, the discourse of HCI 'guidelines' and afliated concepts-as codifed design knowledge-is sometimes contradictory and ambiguous. We will see later how this in some senses mirrors the picture painted by VUI design practitioners.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">From classic HCI guidelines to VUI guidelines</head><p>HCI research has often suggested (e.g., within standard textbooks <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[45]</ref>) that the various codifcations of design knowledge as described above are crucial to successful implementation of a design solution.</p><p>Designers and developers reportedly use them as tools to guide implementation of various interfaces. Therefore, we refer to literature on human-centered and UX design to ground our understanding of how they are embedded into GUI, IVR and VUI design. Further, we also must look to burgeoning communities dedicated to conversational user interface research specifcally (as represented by the CUI series of conferences <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2]</ref>).</p><p>In HCI, it is well-known that guidelines, principles, heuristics, etc. are intended to ensure critical factors-usability, cognitive load, usefulness, desirability and accessibility which signifcantly infuence user experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[31]</ref>. Implementation of guidelines or heuristics e.g., Jakob Nielsen's 10 Usability Heuristics for user interface design, account for these factors. First documented in 1990 by Nielsen and Molich, such classic guidelines have perhaps naturally found themselves repurposed for VUI design <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>. However, questions have been raised about the suitability of applying these to voice <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[40]</ref>.</p><p>IVR systems in the past have also had their own tradition of design guidelines <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11]</ref>. Killam and Autry <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> note that despite IVRs increased popularity at the time, designers struggled with the design and evaluation of IVRs due to lack of publicly available standardised design guidelines <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>. The design guidelines which were available were proprietary and companies would not disclose them <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>. Consequently, human factors practitioners started developing their own design guidelines to support designers who wanted to perform evaluation of IVRs <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b10">11]</ref>. Some of these IVR design guidelines have laid the foundation for codifcations of VUI design knowledge developed by academic researchers <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[46]</ref>.</p><p>Wei and Landay <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[46]</ref> developed what they call "usability heuristics" for VUI design after reviewing design guidelines for GUI and telephony systems, and design guides by Amazon and Google <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr">23]</ref>. Some of the heuristics they developed revolve around conversation design, error handling guidance for users (e.g., discoverability and what a voice assistant can help the user accomplish), and length of prompts or speech. Murad et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref> used a diferent approach to compile what they term as "design guidelines" for voice interfaces. They frst reviewed literature to identify VUI usability issues, and mapped them to existing codifcations of GUI design knowledge associated with privacy and social context. Next, they developed a mapping system between GUI design knowledge and a combination of work by aforementioned Wei and Landay <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[46]</ref> and Suhm <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref>. This mapping system helped reveal the overlapping notions between codifcations of GUI and VUI design knowledge which, it is argued, would support the shift from GUI to VUI, for designers <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3.1">Industry and practitioner initiatives for VUI design guidelines.</head><p>As a result of increasing popularity of voice interfaces, voice industry has generated its own approaches to codifying design knowledge in terms of principles, guidelines and heuristics that tend to be developed in parallel to more academic approaches outlined above. For instance, practitioners have published books <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12,</ref><ref type="bibr">38]</ref> and blogposts <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">25]</ref> which reveal the VUI design process and provide 'formal' articulations of VUI design knowledge. For instance, Pearl shares what she calls "VUI design principles" centered around topics like conversation design, user expectations, confrmations, error handling, etc., in <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>. Additionally, instead of listing dos and don'ts, she shares examples of human-agent interactions to demonstrate how to apply these principles and to distinguish between good design and bad design. Similarly, Cohen et al. <ref type="bibr">[38]</ref> present 6 "core VUI design principles" derived from analysis of lab and feld studies. These principles refect an understanding of human factors, linguistics, speech technologies and voice interface design e.g., "minimize the cognitive load", "accommodate conversational expectations", "gracefully recover from errors" and "ensure high accuracy" <ref type="bibr">[38]</ref>. Unlike Pearl, the Cohen et al. speak of VUIs in a broad sense-they make no distinction between IVR's and voice assistants; hence, the principles are more generic than those provided by Pearl <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>.</p><p>Therefore, it can be argued that multiple eforts are being made by companies, practitioners, and academic researchers to develop what they variously term as design principles, guidelines or heuristics-i.e., practitioner-oriented codifcations of design knowledge-for voice interfaces. Some of these codifcations overlap or are conceptually similar. Indeed, there are initiatives which attempt to bring together a common, shared set of guidelines for VUIs. For example, the Multi-Agent Design Guide <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref> published by Amazon to facilitate support for multiple voice services ofered by diferent companies (e.g., Accenture, BBC, etc.) on the same device. We take this as a key example of what we mean by 'harmonisation'a concern addressed during our interviews with practitioners.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHODOLOGY</head><p>We were interested in learning how VUI experts implemented codifcations of design knowledge, such as design guidelines, while creating VUIs. Our conversations tended to centre on currently popular voice assistant platforms like Amazon Echo, Siri, or Google Home-platforms our participants were experienced with. Furthermore, we were intrigued by what practitioners' opinions were on harmonising design guidelines given that this impulse seems to have been a driving force for prior UI codifcations. So, we did a preliminary survey to recruit participants and gather background information for our main research-an interview study.</p><p>Prior to the study, we submitted an ethics application to the Computer Science Research Ethics Committee at University of Nottingham. We also ensured data collection and storage of survey and interview data was GDPR compliant. Personal information such as names and email address were only collected in our data if participants expressed their interest to interview, otherwise respondents could share information anonymously within the survey. Given we were talking to industry practitioners, we emphasised the need to avoid disclosing any confdential information or information bound by non-disclosure agreements.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Participant recruitment through preliminary survey</head><p>We decided it was essential to recruit participants who had professional experience with building voice-based conversational interfaces, although this necessarily meant that many of them had broader 'conversational design' experience too (e.g., chatbots). To this end, we initially created a survey in part to better understand practitioners' experiences designing and building voice assistants, but also to recruit interview participants for developing a more in-depth appreciation of this. We shared our survey on social media platforms such as Twitter and LinkedIn. With the help of VUI practitioner networks and members of the CUI research community on Twitter and other social media we were able to advertise our survey and obtained a total of 64 respondents. The survey had 13 questions designed to elicit detail about practitioners' experiences. Firstly, we asked participants if they had any professional experience working with VUIs. By asking about their 'professional' experience, we wanted to make a distinction between work that is conducted in a more 'professional' capacity (whether in academia or industry) versus work done as a part of passion projects or coursework. The survey terminated for those who responded with 'no' to this question. Secondly, we wanted to know how many years of experience the participant had. These questions were important to help funnel participants who had signifcant experience working with voice interfaces towards the interview stage. Next, we asked participants if they had used codifcations of design knowledge like design guidelines, heuristics, and so on in the course of this work, such as those published by Amazon, Fjord, Google <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22,</ref><ref type="bibr">23]</ref>, etc. We also asked about technologies they worked with (e.g., Alexa, Google Assistant). For these two questions, we enabled multi-selection to allow participants to choose more than one option for the answer and also added 'Other' as an option to encourage them to tell us more about any other design guidelines or platforms they may have built voice applications with. Additionally, we added open-ended questions to the survey to learn about their perceptions on design guidelines for VUIs. We collected the contact information of those who were interested to schedule an interview. Although we had 64 respondents who attempted the survey, only 42 (i.e., 66%) of those respondents reported signifcant professional experience-i.e., 'real world' familiarity with designing VUIs for actual deployment. As a result, only those 42 survey respondents could answer all the questions to complete the survey. Initially, 16 out of 42 survey respondents (i.e., 38% of our sample) expressed their interest to interview, while 9 respondents actually agreed to interview. Filtering respondents who had signifcant experience largely played a role in the small sample size for our interview study. In addition, the duration of the study i.e., 3 months, and voice design as a feld being seen as quite new (in spite of historic developments in, say, IVR) may have been other contributing factors.</p><p>Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> below summarises our interviewees' experience with VUIs and their background. It shows all interviewees had at least 2 years of experience in the voice industry. The 2 interviewees with over 10 years of experience also had experience with IVR systems.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Interview study</head><p>We frst describe how we used the fndings from the survey to shape the interview study and formulate the questions we asked our interviewees. We then briefy describe the inductive and deductive approach used to perform thematic analysis on our interview data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Interview study:</head><p>Using preliminary survey responses to inform our interview questions. As stated previously, the preliminary survey was useful to gather background information needed for the interview study. Through the survey responses we learned about the platforms practitioners often worked with, their perceptions on codifcations of design knowledge for VUIs, and limitations of existing VUI design knowledge.</p><p>From our survey responses, we discovered Alexa (90.5%) and Google Assistant (59.5%) platforms were more popular amongst the respondents. Similarly, our respondents were more familiar with codifcations of design knowledge for these two platforms compared to other options listed in the survey: Alexa Design Guide, 83.3%, and Actions on Google Design Guide, 64.2% (percentages are calculated by considering the 42 respondents with 'professional' experience; as respondents were allowed to select multiple platforms and design guides, the percentages do not sum up to 100%). Upon learning this, we closely examined these design guides prior to the interviews to expand our understanding of VUI design for these platforms. Some of our respondents also reported they worked with 'other' platforms such as Nuance VoCon 1 , IVRs, Amazon Lex 2 , and Amelia IPSoft 3 . Several respondents have also created or worked with proprietary VUI design guidelines. Few of them indicated they had referred to Grice's Maxim <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[27]</ref> or Pearl's book <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref>.</p><p>The survey further helped us scope how practitioners respond to the notion of codifying design knowledge and thus informed how we conducted interviews. Most of the survey responses conveyed that design knowledge for voice interfaces are "necessary" or "critical". Moreover, respondents deemed useful to "standardise" or create "consistent experiences". Additionally, they suggested design guides "played an important role" in their learning process and are in everyday work". Some of our respondents reported problems with existing voice design guides. One shared that design guides are "lacking examples", and there is "a lot of need" to design guides "really applicable". Another respondent complained design guides "overthe process" and are "aimed at beginners". Some criticised existing design guides as "mostly surface level", "quite linear" and lacking "deep psycholinguistic foundations". Other respondents were more conciliatory about this, expressing their sense that since VUI systems are "emerging tech", so design knowledge for them is in "early stages" but is "evolving rapidly". Making note of this while analysing our survey responses, we realised it might be important to explore these limitations of voice design guides further during the interviews.</p><p>Despite the current challenges with codifcations of VUI design knowledge, of our respondents seemed to feel positively about it. One of the respondents said "creation of design guidelines facilitates much-needed discussion within the VUI community". Another respondent emphasised that "VUI design guidelines need to be established" and "continually updated [. . .] as voice assistants improve". Therefore, our survey responses supported the notion that practitioner communities could beneft from HCI research that builds further codifcations of voice design knowledge in some way (although we would suggest this is predicated upon HCI and CUI research developing deeper understandings of practitioners' actual practices so as to coherently ground and situate design knowledge).</p><p>The survey identifed for us specifc areas to explore in more detail during the interviews. We organised our interview questions around the following key topics for discussion with participants: their professional experience; descriptions of their VUI design process, and how design guidelines ftted into that; how they performed evaluation of VUI designs; their views on design guidelines; their views on ideas about 'unifed' or 'standardised' guidelines; descriptions of instances where design guidelines were limiting or problematic; and, areas of VUI design they thought design guidelines might address.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>3.2.2</head><p>Interview study: Approach and analysis. We followed a semistructured interview format mainly to delve deeper better understand our interviewees' perspectives on codifcations of VUI design knowledge. We wanted to follow-up on what interviewees mentioned in the survey. And, if during the interviews they shared something that was unusual yet relevant, inquiring further to better understand the context.</p><p>We tried to be sensitive towards the terminology practitioners used to speak of design guidelines. Of course, a key part of our interviews revolved around understanding what 'design guidelines' meant for participants. In some cases, practitioners seemed to adopt a deliberate use of language, whereas if we noticed them using varying terminology, we asked them to explain what they meant by this (e.g., if they saw any diference in terms and therefore distinguished between codifcations of design knowledge). This enabled us to unpack assumptions and support a shared understanding of the topic being discussed.</p><p>Once all interviews were completed, we cleaned up the transcripts by revisiting the interview recordings and rectifying errors observed. helped us familiarise ourselves with the data collected and prepare it for thematic analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">44]</ref>. Our deductive approach involved developing an initial set of codes based on questions asked during the interviews. The initial list of codes included 'design process', 'VUI design evaluation', 'views on design guidelines', 'design guidelines limitations', and 'unifcation of design guidelines'. As we conducted semi-structured interviews, there was a possibility that several other themes would emerge. So, our inductive approach involved re-reading the interview data, and looking beyond initial codes we developed. So, returning to our discussion of terminology above, instance, where a few participants spoke about, say, 'best practices' and in addition to 'design guidelines' while others used 'best practices' and 'design guidelines' interchangeably, this led us to develop a new theme around 'inconsistent terminology'.</p><p>After following an iterative process of re-reading and coding, we eventually combined the codes under three main themes: terminology, VUI design processes and considerations, and harmonisation of design guidelines. These themes of course sit in a relationship to the kind of questions we asked, it is that there is an interaction between the way interviews were framed and the kinds of themes that emerged from the data-in that sense our analysis is by this fact. Further, our themes should be read as preliminary, as befts the limited scope of this initial study into industry practitioners' orientations to VUI design.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">UNDERSTANDING VUI PRACTITIONERS' ORIENTATIONS TO CODIFICATIONS OF DESIGN KNOWLEDGE</head><p>Our analysis of the interviews led us focus on three core issues impacting practitioners' relationship with codifed design knowledge. Firstly, our interviews reveal a wide range of terminological issues, and what concepts language design practitioners use to talk about VUI design. Secondly, we explore practitioners' accounts of how design guidelines feature in VUI design processes. Finally, we discuss practitioners' responses to familiar questions of 'harmonisation' of design guidelines as coherent, codifed bodies of knowledge.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Trouble terminology</head><p>One might perhaps naively think that VUI design practitioners have some kind of common language that enables them to talk about VUI design. To this end we asked practitioners to discuss with us the ways they talked about design guidelines (a term we introduced reference to e.g., platform 'guidelines' but used as way of initiating discussion of codifed design knowledge for VUIs in general). We found that practitioners frstly produced many diferent related terms beyond simply 'guidelines', including 'heuristics' and 'best practices', and secondly some made defnite distinctions between such terms while others did not do so, using them seemingly interchangeably.</p><p>For those that made distinctions, some interviewees ofered different defnitions of best practices, design guidelines and heuristics. In one view, our interviewees explained that 'best practice' held connotations of there being only one way to go about somethingthat a 'best practice' tells you what interaction with VUIs should 'look' like to end users and the specifcs of it make it restrictive in nature (P8). This is thus introducing a 'moral' favour to notions of 'best practice' (e.g., as P8 describes below). On the other hand, interviewees suggested terms like 'design guidelines' could in contrast to 'best practices' be considered more like general attributes or characteristics one should try to accomplish in one's VUI design, i.e., that 'design guidelines' express how a VUI should 'act' and 'feel' like: "You'll see things that are labelled on your best practices like um, 'don't give anybody more than three choices at its time. ' Whereas, guidelines are 'make it clear by structuring information in a logical order and not presenting it too quickly"' (P8).</p><p>Another participant, P1, made a diferent distinction between heuristics and design guidelines. They described design guidelines are a "checklist of dos and don'ts" and heuristics as "a set of values": "Heuristics side is [. . .] these high-level things like 'this system should be able to handle context' which includes everything from pronoun context to, situational context" (P1).</p><p>Regardless of the terms, then, we can see a general point being made here by interviewees in terms of a tension between guidelines-as-prescriptions and guidelines-as-values. As we will see, there was a general reaction that prescription for VUI design is perhaps diferently problematic than for its existing GUI equivalents due to the nature of the design material, i.e., language. Some interviewees not seem to diferentiate as much between these terms. For example, we observed P7 using the terms 'design guidelines' and 'design practice' interchangeably and so we clarifed if they were making a distinction. They replied "I don't know that I'm using it super precisely there, so I don't know that I'm using it diferently".</p><p>Finally, some interviewees within some 'middle ground' between the two extremes described previously. For instance, P3 positioned VUI design guidelines as related to best practices in a more complex way: "The earliest GUI design guidelines there were things like you know, for dropdown menus, 'make sure your menus are between 5 and 7 items on it', no more, no because here's what the research leads us to believe why that would be good. think our design guidelines for voice these days are much the same.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>[. . .]</head><p>Based on what we know, here are some good guidelines. [. . .] So, I like the fact that our current guidelines are more a set of best practices than hard bricks that we're laying down to follow" (P3).</p><p>In this P3 frstly sets up GUI design guidelines as an analogy to then suggest that guidelines for VUI may be more or less 'strict'. Overall, we can conclude that the understanding of the terms 'design principles', 'guidelines', 'heuristics' and 'best practices' varies quite strongly between practitioners and is little to suggest the presence of a set of agreements (tacit or not) over how such language is to be deployed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Doing VUI design with guidelines</head><p>We talked to interviewees about their VUI design process experiences and the role of design guidelines in them. In this section we report on their accounts of this process, then we turn to examining how interviewees described guidelines meshing with this process (if they could). Then we describe various 'considerations' which were not explicitly described as 'guidelines' but nevertheless acted as a vernacular set of stable concerns for design across instances.</p><p>Interviewees described beginning by determining the scope of project by collaborating with stakeholders and clients, identifying user needs to develop user personas, establishing if voice is the appropriate medium, and defning use cases and a persona for the VUI.</p><p>Next, in response to identifed needs, interviewees described typically starting prototyping work by writing a 'script' or a dialogue to depict the interaction between the user and their agent <ref type="bibr">[20]</ref>. Interviewees transposed the concept of the 'happy path'-the 'optimal' or 'best' interactional route through the design that satisfes various stakeholder and user requirements-to of the VUI, however introducing the notion of a 'script' into this process, i.e., the simplest conversational path the user might take to accomplish their goal <ref type="bibr">[26]</ref>. This 'script' was then subject to further elaboration via prototyping processes, eventually working towards an object more compatible with the requirements VUI development e.g., a "bulky fow chart" or dialogue in a tree form <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[43]</ref> as P7 outlines nicely here: "So, we do the sample scripts, if I have time, I annotate them with kind of references to design guidelines. Once we approve scripts or start it, usually I'm also recording kinda talking through the dialogue. I have a mic; you know right here and I'll sometimes I'll record myself with Alexa having that dialogue for me. [. . .] Once we had a point where we feel good, client feels good, they've heard a few recordings, they have a good sense for how at least the happy path is going to sound, that's when I go in and start to do really bulky fow chart. And I started to say, OK, these prompts that we're providing give rise to these conversational pathways" (P7).</p><p>Finally, practitioners would evaluate VUI designs, but the approaches varied: having "users read through [. . .] scripts" (P1), employing "expert reviews" (P9) or a "friendly user test" with 'good' users (P4), testing on "mockups" and "Wizard of Oz testing" (P9), log fle evaluation (P4).</p><p>Accounts from our interviewees a collective coherence in that they all described a surprisingly similar design process for their VUI work. We observed interviewees tended to articulate process in line with structures of design thinking to explain the VUI design process they followed. accounts also followed the form of 'standard' narratives about user-centred design projects (e.g., see ISO 9241-210). We thus noticed that designers tended to articulate their process in ways similar to GUI design process discover, defne, ideate, design and evaluate. This does not tell us that VUI design is 'similar' to classical UI design, merely that the approach taken is consonant with it-whether this is the 'right' approach is a diferent question, as this could indicate simply applying old context to new questioning if the approach needs fundamentally reengineering.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.1">How did VUI guidelines feature in accounts of design process?</head><p>Given interviewees' accounts of their design processes, perhaps surprisingly we found that of our interviewees struggled to articulate the how design guidelines featured in their design process at all. Instead, they tended to talk about such guidelines in terms of broad design resources that may or may not be called upon as 'tools to hand' at a given moment in their practice.</p><p>Building upon this, we noted a correlation between how the VUI designers we interviewed reported using (for instance) platformspecifc VUI guidelines, and how much experience they stated having in the feld. Those newer to VUI design tended to describe using guidelines as an authoritative resource, arguing, for instance, that various platform guidelines from or Amazon ofered a frm "foundation" (P7) for establishing their design practice. Yet, the development of design competence <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17]</ref> played an important role in VUI design practice. One more experienced expressed it this way: "In those early days, I like read a lot of those design guides and kind of treated them as like a set of rules. And those things about like how to word a prompt in a way that's easy for people to listen to or what are certain types of error messages that you should always include things like that. Now I would say that I have a much deeper understanding of design and how it's like a user experience process. I actually don't like the concept of design guides anymore because I fnd them very limiting and I think there is no best way to do anything at all. [. . .] It's about weighing those pros and cons, forming hypothesis and testing it. " (P1).</p><p>Further, as competency with VUI design developed, we found that interviewees reported developing their own design guidelines and curated 'collections' from more formal guidelines. This was especially the case when dealing with cross-platform where specifc platform guides may no longer serve this higherlevel purpose. These home-grown guidelines would be rooted in practitioners' experiences within VUI design practice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Design considerations.</head><p>We found interviewees revealed there are several factors which infuence the design choices they make that act in a somewhat similar way to 'design guidelines' but nevertheless were not referred to as such. We've called these 'considerations' to indicate their relevance across instances of VUI design practice (since it would be presumptive for us to label them 'guidelines' given our interviewees not do so themselves) and their quality more as 'questions' to pose.</p><p>Interviewees shared that before they would begin designing for voice, it was important to consider if voice was the appropriate modality for the application. This is important as not every application required voice and instead other forms of conversation design could be applied (e.g., chatbot). P7 describes having to make this decision, sometimes having to say "'hey, that's terrible idea, let's not do that voice, not a great voice experience', vice versa, you know, like 'hey, that would be a fantastic voice experience"'. designers interviewed also reported weighing if voice is to be the only mode or multimodal integration is required. the latter, there are other aspects to consider, including "people mixing modes, switching between modes, signaling which mode they prefer versus just using a mode that's faster" (P3).</p><p>Additionally, we found interviewees described several considerations to weigh as they scripted interactions, including how the language of the VUI is 'built' i.e., its 'components', how content is delivered, and how temporality (e.g., length of speech) shapes design (P8). Interviewees argued that the components of language such as syntax, grammatical rules, semantics and lexical morphology dramatically infuence the user experience of voice interfaces (P6) and therefore provided a go-to set of refective in the course of VUI design. For example, P3 mentioned plurals: "you have one item in your cart or you have two items in your cart" and also gave an example of lists, comparing "your choices are bananas, oranges, tomatoes" with "or tomatoes". P3 here wanted to avoid the impression of a "bulleted list" and instead ofer interaction that was more "natural". Interviewees also raised considerations of avoiding long speech, which they felt often results in users missing out on key information and leads to poor experience.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Harmonisation of codifed VUI design knowledge</head><p>As we have noted earlier, many existing codifcations of VUI design knowledge seem to overlap conceptually. Further, it is argued that there are benefts from cohering around common or shared set of (e.g.) in practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>-practices such as interface consistency have been important in enhancing efective use. But our interviewees presented various responses this idea of 'harmonisation' for VUI design. While interviewees did acknowledge guidelines are broadly similar, they felt there were other considerations at play. Some suggested in spite of the potential benefts of having a consolidated set of guidelines, it might be too early to do so due to design immaturity. It was sometimes argued by our interviewees harmonisation, associated with the development of shared approaches or more formal standards will likely grow in potential with greater understanding of the feld of VUI design and VUI technologies.</p><p>However, some interviewees seemed more doubtful about the notion of harmonisation. They noted it would be challenging because the impetus towards a shared set of common guidelines potentially worked against what they saw as the constantly evolving nature of language: "Standards really have come out of our software and before equipment. So, you know standards <ref type="bibr">[are]</ref> really important because otherwise we build infrastructure systems that don't work with each other. [. . .] But language is not a infrastructure system, and it isn't a technical system; it wasn't invented in the same way. [. . .] Language continues to be very emergent and fexible, and we interact with voice today, diferently than we did 25 years ago and that was diferent than 25 years before that. " [P8] Instead, interviewees saw harmonised design knowledge for VUIs being potentially relevant more for narrow, particular technical of VUI design, such as audio, volume, clarity and comprehension, while drawing parallels with standards associated with visual features (e.g., colour, etc.).</p><p>There are also platform-related challenges to harmonisation. P2, for instance, argued that domain specifc diferences for different voice assistants constrained design along line; P2 suggested that Amazon would potentially ofer better shopping experience than Google, so Amazon's guidelines be tailored to serve that domain, whereas Google's would be better suited to respond queries. Lastly, some interviewees reminded that modality-based guidelines are also platform-specifc. So, guidelines around switching between modes, displaying data on multimodal interfaces would difer based on the platform being used.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">DISCUSSION &amp; CONCLUSIONS</head><p>Voice user interface design practitioners shared insights into the present state and role of codifcations of VUI design knowledge in practice which we believe are not currently represented in HCI research. Here we bring together some of the key points our study raises, and the implications it surfaces for further research.</p><p>A key question has been about how practitioners consider and potentially use existing codifed design knowledge. Our study shows somewhat mixed picture. For starters, there is considerable lack of common shared language or terminology for consistently describing and distinguishing principles, guidelines, heuristics and so on. Thus, a source of terminological trouble might be caused by a) reliance on platform design guidelines and b) vendor-introduced distinctions. So, we found some participants (e.g., P1, P2)-in attempting to describe what they thought of the diference between e.g., "design guidelines" and "heuristics"-recalled Amazon's (platform) language describing these as "tenets". The author of a blogpost published on Amazon's website refers to these design patterns as "tenets" too <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. In contrast, in the Alexa design guidelines, what the participant recalled as "tenets", are listed as "design patterns" <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. Furthermore, uses 'design guidelines' and 'principles' to refer to the design guidance they published <ref type="bibr">[28]</ref>. Thus, we can build a case about this confusion over varying terminology being driven by platform and vendor. HCI research should refect on the role of platform and vendor when producing design knowledge for VUI practitioners-presently we think the importance of these practical issues tend to be underplayed. Some participants argued that present codifcations like guidelines basically do not ft their work practices, which is why they reject them (or pay less attention to them). For instance, they pointed out that guidelines listed as "dos and don'ts" "simplifes the work" but is "harmful to the user experience" The reasoning here is that participants argued this encourages a tendency (especially new to VUI design) to follow them as rules, rather than trying and testing if the design guidelines actually apply to a given use case and is a success with the users. It is less a case of 'missing' guidelines and more that practitioners have to work out how to ft guidelines into their practical work. Further, their own accounts, practitioners described various diferent 'modes' of practice with respect to applying VUI guidelines, from considering guidelines a kind of knowledge-bootstrapping process or pedagogical tool, through to a 'pick and mix' approach, as well as a 'roll your own' approach. Practitioner attitudes towards guidelines also mesh the development of their own particular journey towards VUI design competence, consonant with UX competence development more broadly <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b16">17]</ref>. Practitioners may well start their journey in voice design by adopting design guidelines but over time become more agile and adaptive, can better judge what actually works, and subsequently rely more on the needs of a given design process than guidelines themselves.</p><p>Thus, we argue that appreciating the texture of these various different modes and their relationship to competence development is likely critically important if CHI is going to continue its investment in conversational user interface research, and in seeking the development of design guidelines, heuristics, and so on, which aspire to industry adoption and use. If we create such VUI design knowledge, practitioner career point are they aimed at? Further, what style or way of working might they be tailored towards? So, on one hand, our research encourages industry practitioners, especially those new to VUI design, to think more critically about existing platform-oriented design knowledge and not treat it as a 'one-stop shop' for designing voice interfaces. On the other it calls for further investigation by HCI researchers into VUI designers' actual practices, so that better descriptions of these diferent 'modes' may be established.</p><p>The second point we return to is matters of harmonising design guidelines, i.e., ways in which guidelines etc. as codifcations of design knowledge-often initially tied to specifc platforms-may be brought together in some way, whether as a formal standard or something looser. Maybe surprisingly, practitioners had mixed about the potential value of this concept in spite of industry initiatives to do so <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4]</ref>. This is further complexifed by the nature of how they reported use of existing guidelines in practice and how VUI design processes unfold, as we described above. Specifically, we suggest that the VUI design process itself along with various informal design 'considerations' jointly shape how and in what ways design guidelines are 'used' (if at all). For instance, platform-relevant matters seemed consistently to loom large across the design processes engaged in and any harmonisation of design knowledge needs to navigate this. This means that there are potential bumps along the road for HCI research into VUIs if it is to develop guidelines that knit together multiple approaches in an attempt to produce 'unifed' design techniques for voice user interfaces. The tendency in academic research is towards generalisation and abstraction, which seems resonant with the idea of 'harmonisation' of codifed design knowledge-this approach is valued due to the emphasis on knowledge accumulation and progress. But this urge might run counter to the needs of actual practitioners, so we are left questioning who attempts at harmonisation might ultimately be serving? When is it appropriate and when may harmonisations between codifed design knowledges be counter-productive for practice?</p><p>We also need to discuss the language codifed design knowledge for VUIs: of guidelines, heuristics, best practices, principles, and the like. It is an open question as to whether the fuidity of this language really 'matters'. We saw, for instance, some practitioners switching between them seamlessly, while others had strong distinctions to make. Instead, we suggest HCI research into VUI design moves beyond language to consider motivations that drive terminological troubles-for instance, as we pointed out, there was a distinction to be made between more 'prescriptive' and those inculcating certain 'values'. This a question regarding the style and type of guidelines being generated in HCI research and in which part of the spectrum from 'prescription' to 'values' they sit. Are we making specifc must-follow rules or suggesting particular values to be embodied?</p><p>Finally, there are implications for further research here too. Based on our survey fndings, it appears there is a need for codifcation of voice design guidance and as a growing feld there is much rapid movement in this area. Our interview study has been limited to a relatively small number of experienced VUI designers in industry and drawn out some initial themes. Whilst we have not looked directly at VUI designers' practices, we have seen accounts of those practices in interview and note the prominent gaps that further research should examine, such as further details on the objects of collaboration and how VUI designers work with developers and other designers. As part of this, there are likely many aspects of how codifed design knowledge is considered by designers and enacted in practice that we have missed. As Murad et al. state "For VUI-specifc or heuristics to be efective, they must be by designers" (our emphasis) <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>. HCI and CUI research conversational user interfaces in general thus needs to understand VUI design processes 'in the wild' to adequately determine what type of object we are or should be building, and whether, say, 'design guidelines' are even an appropriate vehicle for those aims. Further work should seek to investigate practitioners' work practices with the design of VUIs to help calibrate 'adoptability'. From our interviewees' to pinpoint in detail how codifcations like design guidelines were embedded in their practice, we suggest that study of an ethnographic nature examining work practice may have a greater potential to unpack how guidelines are worked with / into practices, that moves beyond more 'scenic' accounts of their process</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary of interviewees' professional experience with VUIs</figDesc><table><row><cell>Participant</cell><cell>Years of</cell><cell>Education</cell><cell>Role</cell><cell>Area of expertise</cell><cell>Platforms</cell></row><row><cell>ID</cell><cell>Experi-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>ence</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P1</cell><cell>5-10</cell><cell>Postgraduate degree in</cell><cell>Conversation</cell><cell>Conversation design, UX and UX</cell><cell>Alexa, Google Assistant</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Creative Writing</cell><cell>Designer</cell><cell>writing</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P2</cell><cell>2-3</cell><cell>Undergraduate degree in</cell><cell>UX Writer</cell><cell>Design VUI documentation,</cell><cell>Alexa</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Creative Writing</cell><cell></cell><cell>content strategy</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P3</cell><cell>3-5</cell><cell>Undergraduate degree in</cell><cell>Developer</cell><cell>Conversational interface design</cell><cell>Google Assistant,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Computer Science</cell><cell></cell><cell>and development</cell><cell>Google Glass, Alexa</cell></row><row><cell>P4</cell><cell>10+</cell><cell>Undergraduate degree in</cell><cell>Managing</cell><cell>VUI design, development and</cell><cell>Nuance</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Economics</cell><cell>Director</cell><cell>testing, IVR systems</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P5</cell><cell>3-5</cell><cell>Undergraduate degree in</cell><cell>Director</cell><cell>Product design (created</cell><cell>Alexa, Siri, Google</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Marketing</cell><cell></cell><cell>prototyping tools for voice</cell><cell>Assistant</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>interfaces)</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P6</cell><cell>1-2</cell><cell>Postgraduate degree in</cell><cell>Conversation</cell><cell>Conversation design, Linguistics</cell><cell>Alexa, Jovo Framework,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Cognitive Linguistics</cell><cell>Designer</cell><cell></cell><cell>Google Assitant</cell></row><row><cell>P7</cell><cell>2-3</cell><cell>Undergraduate degree in</cell><cell>Conversation</cell><cell>VUI design, Language</cell><cell>Alexa, Google Assistant</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>English Literature</cell><cell>Designer</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>P8</cell><cell>10+</cell><cell>Undergraduate degree in</cell><cell>Entrepreneur</cell><cell>VUI and conversation design, IVR</cell><cell>IVR platforms, Alexa,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>English Language</cell><cell></cell><cell>systems</cell><cell>Google Assistant,</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Cortana</cell></row><row><cell>P9</cell><cell>2-3</cell><cell>Postgraduate degree in</cell><cell>VUI Architect</cell><cell>VUI architecture, conversation</cell><cell>Hello Magenta, Google</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Speech Communication</cell><cell></cell><cell>design, IVR</cell><cell>Assistant, Alexa</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">Nuance VoCon -https://www.nuance.com/content/dam/nuance/en_us/collateral/ mobile/automotive/data-sheet/ds-vocon-hybrid-speech-recognition-data-sheet-enus.pdf<ref type="bibr" target="#b1">2</ref> Amazon Lex -https://aws.amazon.com/lex/ 3 Amerlia IPSoft -https://amelia.ai/</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>thank the reviewers their valuable feedback and suggestions. This work was supported by the Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council [EP/T022493/1].</p><p>Data access statement: In line with consent restrictions in place for interviews performed for this paper including towards protecting identities and confdential information (e.g., non-disclosure agreements, commercially sensitive information), anonymised transcripts are available at the following resource: http://dx.doi.org/10.17639/nott.7174</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 1st International Conference on Conversational User Interfaces</title>
				<meeting>the 1st International Conference on Conversational User Interfaces<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2nd Conference on Conversational User Interfaces</title>
				<meeting>the 2nd Conference on Conversational User Interfaces<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Alexa Design Guide -Get Started with the Guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Amazon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/docs/alexa/alexa-design/get-started.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date>Retrieved February 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Multi-Agent Design Guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Amazon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://developer.amazon.com/en-US/alexa/voice-interoperability/design-" />
		<imprint>
			<date>February 25</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Prcis. In Doing Design Ethnography</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Crabtree</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Peter Tolmie</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-4471-2726-0_1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4471-2726-0_1" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="5" />
			<pubPlace>London, London, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">New Alexa Design Guide: Create Engaging Alexa Skills Using Situational Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Van Brookhoven</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://developer.amazon.com/blogs/alexa/post/ee0e00c9-37cd-46ac-8695-06552e0885b0/new-alexa-design-guide-create-engaging-alexa-skills-using-situational-design" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-05-09">2019. May 9. 2019. August 10</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Human Interface Guidelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Apple</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://developer.apple.com/design/human-interface-guidelines/" />
		<imprint>
			<date>Retrieved February 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Designing Voice Experience</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arun</forename><surname>George</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://uxdesign.cc/voice-user-experience-design-and-prototyping-for-mere-mortals-ef080c843640" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-09-28">2017. September 28. 2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards best practices for speech user interface design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Suhm</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Eighth European Conference on Speech Communication and Technology</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Geneva, Switzerland</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003-09-01">2003. September 1-4, 2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2217" to="2220" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ivr Usability Engineering Using Guidelines And Analyses Of End-to-End Calls</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bernhard</forename><surname>Suhm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-0-387-68439-0_1</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-0-387-68439-0_1" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Factors and Voice Interactive Systems. Signals and Communication Technology</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human Factors Guidelines for Interactive Voice Response Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bill</forename><surname>Killam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marguerite</forename><surname>Autry</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/154193120004400308</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting</title>
				<meeting>the Human Factors and Ergonomics Society Annual Meeting</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000-07">2000. July 2000</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="391" to="394" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Designing Voice User Interfaces: Principles of Conversational Experiences (1st</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cathy</forename><surname>Pearl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>Reilly Media, Inc</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Sebastopol, California, CA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">I don&apos;t know what you&apos;re talking about, HALexa&quot;: the case for voice user interface guidelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Murad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cosmin</forename><surname>Munteanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3342775.3342795</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3342775.3342795" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 1st International Conference on Conversational User Interfaces (CUI &apos;19)</title>
				<meeting>the 1st International Conference on Conversational User Interfaces (CUI &apos;19)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revolution or evolution? Speech interaction and HCI design guidelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Murad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cosmin</forename><surname>Munteanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Benjamin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leigh</forename><surname>Cowan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/MPRV.2019.2906991</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Pervasive Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="33" to="45" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design guidelines for hands-free speech interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christine</forename><surname>Murad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Cosmin</forename><surname>Munteanu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leigh</forename><surname>Clark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Benjamin</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Cowan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3236112.3236149</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3236112.3236149" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 20th International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction with Mobile Devices and Services Adjunct (MobileHCI &apos;18)</title>
				<meeting>the 20th International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction with Mobile Devices and Services Adjunct (MobileHCI &apos;18)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="276" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Flow of Competence in UX Design Practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Colin</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Austin</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Toombs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shad</forename><surname>Gross</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2702123.2702579</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2702123.2702579" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;15)</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;15)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3285" to="3294" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evolution of design competence in UX practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Colin</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2556288.2557264</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2556288.2557264" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;14)</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;14)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1645" to="1654" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guidelines for Speech-Enabled IVR Application Design. Human Factors and Voice Interactive Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daryle</forename><surname>Gardner-Bonneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-1-4757-2980-1_7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-4757-2980-1_7" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Springer International Series in Engineering and Computer Science</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Boston, MA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1999">1999</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">498</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How Nielsen&apos;s 10 usability heuristics apply to Voice UI</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deepika</forename><surname>Mittal</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://uxdesign.cc/10-usability-heuristics-for-voice-user-interface-design-69ad9ea4f166" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-02-11">2018. April 2. 2018. February 11</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Scriptwriting for Voice UI</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Designit</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://medium.designit.com/scriptwriting-for-voice-ui" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">City</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018-12-11">2018. December 11. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Conversations with Things: UX Design for Chat and Voice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Diana</forename><surname>Deibel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><surname>Evanhoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Rosenfeld Media</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Guide to Voice Interfaces: Six Principles for Designing for Voice UI</title>
		<ptr target="https://designguidelines.withgoogle.com/conversation/conversation-design/welcome.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date>December 25. Retrieved February 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="https://material.io/design/introduction" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Google. Design Introduction</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-02-08">February 8. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A Concrete Guide to Designing Voice User Interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Grace</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://medium.com/voice-tech-podcast/a-concrete-guide-to-designing-a-voice-ui-bd186777b704" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-02-11">2019. May 11. 2019. February 11</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fundamental Elements of VUI Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Guillaume</forename><surname>Privat</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://blog.prototypr.io/fundamental-elements-of-vui-design-8630077a7009" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-02-23">2018. December 10. 2018. February 23</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Logic and conversation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Herbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Grice</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Syntax and semantics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1975">1975</date>
			<publisher>Academic Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Talk meets technology: Conversation design guidelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ibm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/topics/design-principles" />
		<imprint>
			<date>February 8. Retrieved February 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Interaction Design Foundation. Design Principles</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How to Conduct a Heuristic Evaluation for Usability in HCI and Information Visualization</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/article/how-to-conduct-~:text=A%20heuristic%20is%20a%20simple" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="20" to="E22" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Interaction Design Foundation</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">-factors-that-infuence-user-experience Interaction Design Foundation. Voice User Interfaces</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.interaction-design.org/literature/topics/voice-user-" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-12-20">Retrieved February 8. December 20. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The 7 Factors that Infuence User Experience</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">10 Usability Heuristics for User Interface Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jakob</forename><surname>Nielsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.nngroup.com/articles/ten-usability-heuristics/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nielsen Norman Group, City</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994-02-08">1994. April 24. 1994. February 8, 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Hybrid Approach to Thematic Analysis in Qualitative Research: Using a Practical Example</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jon</forename><surname>Swain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4135/9781526435477</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.doi" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">SAGE Research Methods Cases</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design Principles: The Foundation of Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katherine</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Fu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maria</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Yang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristin</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1115/DETC2015-46157</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1115/DETC2015-46157" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the ASME 2015 International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference</title>
				<meeting>the ASME 2015 International Design Engineering Technical Conferences and Computers and Information in Engineering Conference<address><addrLine>Boston, Massachusetts, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015-08-02">2015. August 2-5, 2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>27th International Conference on Design Theory and Methodology</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Knowledge Production in Interaction Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kristina</forename><surname>Hk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Dalsgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stuart</forename><surname>Reeves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jefrey</forename><surname>Bardzell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonas</forename><surname>Lwgren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Erik</forename><surname>Stolterman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yvonne</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2702613.2702653</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2702613.2702653" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 33rd Annual ACM Conference Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>Seoul, Republic of Korea; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015-04">2015. April 2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2429" to="2432" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Usability guidelines and evaluation criteria for user interfaces: a heuristic and linguistic approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kyoko</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Bleiker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3404983.3405505</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3404983.3405505" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Krishika Haresh Khemani and Stuart Reeves Proceedings of the Conference on Mensch und Computer (MuC &apos;20)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="309" to="319" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Voice User Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Harris Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Balogh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<publisher>Addison-Wesley</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Boston</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Speech Input and Output. The Conversational Interface</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Mctear</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zoraida</forename><surname>Callejas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Griol</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/978-3-319-32967-3_5</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-32967-3_5" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Switzerland</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Designing SpeechActs: Issues in speech user interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicole</forename><surname>Yankelovich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gina-Anne</forename><surname>Levow</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Marx</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/223904.223952</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/223904.223952" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;95)</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI conference on Human factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;95)<address><addrLine>USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM Press/Addison-Wesley Publishing Co</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="369" to="376" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Conversational UX Design: A Practitioner&apos;s Guide to the Natural Conversation Framework. Association for Computing Machinery</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raphael</forename><surname>Moore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Arar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3304087</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3304087" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Designing efective speech interfaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susan</forename><surname>Weinschenk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dean</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Barker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc., USA</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Decision Trees Sociotechnical Objects in Chatbot Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Teresa</forename><surname>Castle-Green</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Reeves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Boriana</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Koleva</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3405755.3406133</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3405755.3406133" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2nd Conference on Conversational User Interfaces (CUI &apos;20)</title>
				<meeting>the 2nd Conference on Conversational User Interfaces (CUI &apos;20)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA, Article</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="3" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using thematic analysis in psychol-In Qualitative Research in Psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Virginia</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Victoria</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1191/1478088706qp063oa</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="101" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yvonne</forename><forename type="middle">Helen</forename><surname>Sharp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jenny</forename><surname>Preece</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Interaction Design: Beyond Human -Computer Interaction</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>John Wiley &amp; Sons</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>4th ed.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Evaluating speech-based devices using new usability heuristics</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zhuxiaona</forename><surname>Wei</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Landay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1109/MPRV.2018.022511249</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IEEE Pervasive Computing</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="84" to="96" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
