<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Tech Help Desk: Support for Local Entrepreneurs Addressing the Long Tail of Computing Challenges</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yasmine</forename><surname>Kotturi</surname></persName>
							<email>ykotturi@cs.cmu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Herman</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Johnson</surname><genName>Jr</genName></persName>
							<email>herman@forge.community</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Skirpan</surname></persName>
							<email>mskirpan@cs.cmu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Bigham</surname></persName>
							<email>jbigham@cs.cmu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Pavel</surname></persName>
							<email>apavel@cs.utexas.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
							<email>sarahf@andrew.cmu.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Human-Computer Interaction Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">Community Forge Wilkinsburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.A</postBox>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Institute of Software Research</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution">Community Forge Wilkinsburg</orgName>
								<address>
									<postBox>P.A</postBox>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Sarah E Fox Human-Computer Interaction Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff5">
								<orgName type="department">Human-Computer Interaction Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff6">
								<orgName type="department">Human-Computer Interaction Institute</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Carnegie Mellon University Pittsburgh</orgName>
								<address>
									<region>PA</region>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff7">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Computer Science Department</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">T.X</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Texas at Austin Austin</orgName>
								<address>
									<country key="US">United States</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Tech Help Desk: Support for Local Entrepreneurs Addressing the Long Tail of Computing Challenges</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3517708</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>entrepreneurship</term>
					<term>small business</term>
					<term>technical assistance</term>
					<term>action research</term>
					<term>community engagement This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution International 4.0 License</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Even entrepreneurs whose businesses are not technological (e.g., handmade goods) need to be able to use a wide range of computing technologies in order to achieve their business goals. In this paper, we follow a participatory action research approach and collaborate with various stakeholders at an entrepreneurial co-working space to design "Tech Help Desk", an on-going technical service for entrepreneurs. Our model for technical assistance is strategic, in how it is designed to fit the context of local entrepreneurs, and responsive, in how it prioritizes emergent needs. From our engagements with 19 entrepreneurs and support personnel, we reflect on the challenges with existing technology support for non-technological entrepreneurs. Our work highlights the importance of ensuring technological support services can adapt based on entrepreneurs' ever-evolving priorities, preferences and constraints. Furthermore, we find technological support services should maintain broad technical support for entrepreneurs' long tail of computing challenges.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Human-centered computing → Field studies.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Starting a local business can lead to individual and community benefits, including building long-term wealth, creating desirable nearby jobs, and addressing local needs <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b60">59</ref>]. Today's local entrepreneurs must navigate an increasing array of technological tools to achieve their business goals (e.g., creating a polished website, syncing files with an assistant, scanning receipts to track expenses) <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b49">49]</ref>. Ever-evolving technology requirements create particularly strong barriers for entrepreneurs in minoritized and resource-constrained communities <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[65]</ref> due to historical inequalities in financial, social, and more recently digital resources (i.e., the "digital divide" <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[63]</ref>). The COVID-19 pandemic accelerated technology expectations for local business owners <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">57]</ref>, magnifying the effects of existing technology barriers <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[12]</ref>.</p><p>While decades of research and design efforts aimed to make the technology used by entrepreneurs less expensive and easier to use (e.g., WSYWIG website builders, social media, and desktop printing), technology barriers remain persistent for people in resourceconstrained or "lean economies" 1 <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">40,</ref><ref type="bibr">62]</ref>. Recent work has explored technology support for workers from lean economies such as digital literacy classes for returning citizens seeking jobs [62], and social supports including workshops and meetings for entrepreneurs creating tours <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref>. Such programs provided support for people with similar businesses or technical experience, but they may be less useful for entrepreneurs who have heterogeneous businesses, backgrounds and technology goals.</p><p>To understand and address the computing challenges faced by local entrepreneurs in a lean economy, we followed a Participatory Action Research <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref> approach to design and run "Tech Help Desk", an on-going service 2 that provides technology help to local entrepreneurs. Tech Help Desk was co-designed with community stakeholders from Community Forge: a local entrepreneurial hub that provides resources for local entrepreneurs in a small Midwest city in the U.S., Wilkinsburg, P.A., including co-working space, accelerator programs, and community events. Tech Help Desk's strategic and responsive approach to technological support in the workplace uniquely provides need-driven technology support for immediate entrepreneur requests (e.g., uploading PDFs for business registration, or connecting to a printer or scanner for taxes). By extension, Tech Help Desk addresses a critical gap in the existing ecology-an ever-evolving collection of resources <ref type="bibr" target="#b77">[76]</ref>-of local entrepreneurial support. During the design, deployment and study of Tech Help Desk, we asked the following research questions: (RQ1) What are the technology challenges faced by local entrepreneurs?, (RQ2) What are the existing resources and workarounds that local entrepreneurs use to overcome their technology challenges?, and (RQ3) What are features of technology support that may be more effective than common workplace approaches for technology support?</p><p>Our engagements with 19 local entrepreneurs and support staff revealed how local entrepreneurs were resourcefully and discerningly addressing their computing challenges by curating an ecology of support: building networks of trustworthy friends and mentors, seeking out business coaches, enrolling in business accelerators and courses. Still, the deployment of Tech Help Desk revealed 61 unique computing challenges that entrepreneurs were not yet able to address, due to a mismatch between support-or lack thereof-and entrepreneurs' technology challenges. We refer to this collection of 61 challenges addressed with Tech Help Desk as the long tail of computing challenges, given the large number of distinct challenges that were surfaced and solved. For instance, a single local entrepreneur used Tech Help Desk services to address a range of technology challenges including: freeing storage space, editing a PDF document, posting to a listserv, navigating local files, learning keyboard shortcuts, removing malware, setting up cloud services, accessing necessary hardware, automating social media posts, and updating products on a website. In total, we worked with entrepreneurs to address 61 unique computing challenges across 35 distinct computing tools (e.g., website builders such as Wix, Squarespace, or WordPress, financial software such as QuickBooks, cloud services such as Google Drive, social media platforms such as TikTok and Instagram, payment tools such as Venmo, content editing tools such as Canva and Adobe, and so on). Tech Help Desk's strategic and responsive approach was critical to match the local entrepreneurs' resourceful and discerning approaches to growing their business in a digitized landscape.</p><p>This paper makes the following three practical and conceptual contributions. First, drawing on our participatory approach, we present a model of technical support that addresses key design tradeoffs for entrepreneurial support and, as a result, is strategic in how it is attuned to local entrepreneurial contexts, and responsive in how it dynamically prioritizes emergent needs (See Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>). Our work demonstrated that strategic and responsive support in the form of flexible and personalized one-on-one sessions was critical to matching entrepreneurs' discernment (e.g., balancing learning goals with the demands of running a small business), where we recognized the wealth of resourcefulness they already possessed. Second, we offer a detailed case of this model through Tech Help Desk, illustrating how this strategic and responsive form of support can help address the many day-to-day computing challenges entrepreneurs need to overcome (i.e., the long tail of computing challenges). Third, towards practicality, this paper also contributes a deep investigation of other entrepreneurial support approaches and programs within the region and how our strategic and responsive model of technical support, instantiated in Tech Help Desk, fits alongside. Together, we present a detailed illustration of how resourceful and discerning entrepreneurs often stitched together multiple programs, social networks, and other resources to address their technical needs (i.e., their ecology of support). This will inform researchers' and community partners' understanding of entrepreneurial computing challenges and, by extension, will help to design services and tools to enable local entrepreneurs to thrive in their local economy and beyond.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED WORK</head><p>Our work in technology support for local entrepreneurs draws on three main areas of research: resources for entrepreneurship, computing pedagogy (e.g., one-on-one instruction), technology support in the workplace.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Resources for Entrepreneurship</head><p>Entrepreneurship research suggests that a business is more likely to be successful if the entrepreneur possesses individual skills and characteristics relevant to starting their business (i.e. "human capital") <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[53]</ref>, and social support for networking, information gathering and emotional needs (i.e."social capital") <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b52">52]</ref>. Human capital for entrepreneurship includes a broad range of knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[47]</ref> gained through work experience, education, and entrepreneurial experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b53">[53]</ref> as well as personal and psychological factors such as self-efficacy, social skills, health and motivation <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27]</ref>. Social capital relevant to entrepreneurship includes personal networks and formal or informal groups to which the entrepreneur has access (e.g., government, bank, or community-driven organizations, and inter-community or extra-community ties <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>). For people in lean economies, access to both social and human capital (as well as financial capital) can be limited <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">20]</ref>. In such communities, many turn to entrepreneurship out of necessity to make a living, i.e. "necessity-driven entrepreneurship" <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[41]</ref> rather than "opportunitydriven entrepreneurship" <ref type="bibr" target="#b76">[75]</ref> -the notable difference between being whether people can opt in or opt out to entrepreneurship. Access to general resources for entrepreneurs remains a challenge for "lowwealth" entrepreneurs <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>. To better support entrepreneurs pursuing necessity-driven entrepreneurship, there exist calls for flexible funding opportunities <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[56]</ref>, entrepreneurship education <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[58,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b62">61]</ref>, and incubator opportunities to facilitate social capital growth <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[42]</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we explore how to build human capital to overcome barriers to entrepreneurship-specifically technological barrierswithin an environment dedicated to entrepreneurs' social capital growth.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Entrepreneurial Skill Building for Using Technology</head><p>Research suggests that digital literacy is a form of human capital that is unequally distributed <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[65]</ref>. Digital literacy -or, "the ability to use information and communication technologies to find, evaluate, create, and communicate information" [8] -requires not only lowlevel skills for operating a specific technology (i.e. "operational", or "medium-related" skills <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b72">71]</ref>), but also higher-level skills that relate to the selection and strategic application of technology to reach a goal (i.e. "content-related" skills <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[71]</ref>). Prior work aimed to understand the types of technology challenges faced by entrepreneurs in lean economies using technology for business goals <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">41,</ref><ref type="bibr">[62]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[63]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b65">[64]</ref>.</p><p>In particular, scholars engaged in participatory action research <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b38">38]</ref> explored non-technical approaches to facilitating digital engagement which rely heavily on structures of social support such as peer learning <ref type="bibr">[62,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b64">63]</ref>. Peer support approaches are particularly beneficial as, by definition, peers have shared experiences which can to provide more contextually-relevant information <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[37]</ref>. Ogbonnaya-Ogburu et al. established a digital literacy class for returning citizens seeking jobs [62], and Pei and Crooks established a class for introducing tablets into an English as a Second Language (ESL) class <ref type="bibr" target="#b64">[63]</ref>. In the context of entrepreneurship, Hui et al. introduced social supports (e.g., in person meetings, paper prototyping, tour practice) for entrepreneurs developing tour businesses <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref>. To showcase pride in one's local community, Dillahunt et al. facilitated opportunities for entrepreneurs to grow local tour businesses (e.g., by setting the platforms and technical requirements for the tours) <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27]</ref>. This work uncovers highly-detailed accounts of the technical barriers specific to certain domains such as tour businesses. However, classes and group activities may work better when business goals are homogeneous rather than diverse as these standardized formats of assistance leave less room for customization <ref type="bibr">[43]</ref>. To address and adapt to the needs of entrepreneurs who run heterogeneous businesses at differing levels of maturity, we design a model for strategic and responsive technical support for resourceful and discerning entrepreneurs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Technology Support in the Workplace</head><p>While support structures for local entrepreneurs is an emergent field of study, a range of approaches have been explored to assist employees in overcoming their technical woes including both formal (help desks, IT consultants) and informal methods (over the shoulder learning or water cooler troubleshooting among peers). For instance, Novick et al. conducted interviews and participant observation among knowledge workers to understand how employees resolve their technical issues <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[60]</ref>. They found half of the time people asked colleagues and the other half of the time people went to their organization's in-house help desk. These help desks provided full-time employees who were dedicated to resolving their organization's technical woes. Yet formal help desk providers were pressured to maintain an unwavering sense of technical expertise (e.g., to inspire confidence with prepared answers <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[33]</ref>, and achieve performance goals <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[15]</ref>). Moreover, organizational help desks often focus on repeat problems, and may not fit entrepreneurs' diverse technology needs. Moreover, as a result of organizational incentives and pressures, help desks may foster reliance on the service rather than resilience to future computing challenges (a critical skill when resources are ever-changing).</p><p>Several scholars have investigated the benefits and drawbacks of peer learning when addressing computing challenges in the workplace such as among teachers <ref type="bibr" target="#b73">[72]</ref> and knowledge workers <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">[70]</ref>. For example, Twidale focused specifically on informal learning-water cooler exchanges <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[73]</ref>-among knowledge workers resolving technical issues and found that peers provided a helpful organizational context when addressing their colleague's technical issues <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">[70]</ref>. When offering technical support in these informal exchanges, employees providing assistance assumed one of two roles: a "guru", where their deep technical understanding led them to the solve their colleagues' challenges quickly <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[31]</ref>, or, a "gardener" or "translator" role where their approach was more collaborative <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[51]</ref>. While understanding role playing behaviors among knowledge workers provides critical insight into informal technical assistance within formal workplaces, our setting of a co-working space for entrepreneurs has important differences which may affect informal technical support. For instance, entrepreneurs do not work for a shared organization, and they therefore often do not have colleagues, standard expected working times, nor a shared organizational goal. Given this isolation, it may be challenging for entrepreneurs to form a network of peers from which to seek technical assistance. If an entrepreneur does have access to a network of peers, entrepreneurs must weigh the benefits of receiving help alongside reputational concerns, as asking for help from peers can result in being perceived as less knowledgeable <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[46]</ref>.</p><p>In this paper, we explore an approach to providing entrepreneurs with technical assistance that does not rely on peers by default.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.4">One-to-One Instruction and Technology Support</head><p>Beyond the workplace, one-to-one instruction is one of the most effective approaches to education <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[16]</ref>. In formal educational settings, learning is curriculum-driven such that all learners first receive the class curriculum that covers necessary knowledge, then learners are provided increasingly targeted support for learning that curriculum through group or one-to-one instruction <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">39]</ref>. Unlike reading and math, technology skills (e.g., typing, spreadsheets, document processing) are not part of standard U.S. curriculum, so students are unlikely to receive one-to-one support. Instead, people often learn technology for their personal goals in-situ while working on a task, rather than through any set curriculum. To support learning expert software or how to code, prior work has explored ways to remotely connect people to experts or peers with relevant technical knowledge <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">44]</ref>. Joshi et al. connect users of specialized help with another person who uses the software for three minute one-to-one help sessions <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[44]</ref>, and Codementor matches students to long term mentors for feedback on writing code <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[7]</ref>. The side-by-side approach of a person screen-sharing while another person serves as a side-kick (rather than the expert fixing the problem directly), can benefit learning and the work itself <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">34]</ref>. Alternatively, tool-specific support forums (e.g., Photoshop Guru, reddit.com/r/photoshop, Adobe Support Community) offer Q&amp;A-based asynchronous peer support. As formulating a query <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref> or supplying relevant information <ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[67]</ref> is challenging without domain knowledge, some tools propose to help surface general-purpose answers to Q&amp;A in-context of tool use <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">55]</ref>. These tools provide powerful guidance for technology use, yet require downloading a browser extension <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref> or setting up additional software <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[55]</ref>. In lean economies where access to technology and technology literacy may be limited, recent work highlights the importance to consider non-technological solutions to facilitate technology use (rather than addressing technology challenges with more technology) <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref>. For instance, library staff members can provide in-person one-to-one support for people performing tasks on library computers including seeking jobs or accessing government services <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[14,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">68]</ref>. In addition, recent work in human-computer interaction research by Hui et al. provided in-person ("low-tech") technology support for entrepreneurs creating tour businesses <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40]</ref>.</p><p>Overall, the broad and goal-oriented technical needs of local entrepreneurs (e.g., "launch a website myself", "keep track of my customers") fall outside of the scope of the purpose, expertise, and time that existing structured services provide -either due to their focus on a specific technology tool or specific goals. In this paper, we explore: the long tail of technology challenges that are not yet addressed by technology-based or social supports, and (2) how to tailor one-on-one support to meet the business needs of entrepreneurs in lean economies.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHODS</head><p>Informed by the needs of a local hub for entrepreneurship, we hosted a two and a half year long (and on-going) service providing broad one-on-one help for local entrepreneurs, called "Tech Help Desk". The findings we report are based on the design of and observations during Tech Help Desk sessions along with interviews with local entrepreneurs and others who provided services for local entrepreneurs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Location and Site</head><p>We conducted our research within a co-working space and community hub for local entrepreneurs based in Wilkinsburg, P.A. called Community Forge (See Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>). Wilkinsburg, P.A. Wilkinsburg, P.A. is a borough of Allegheny County, P.A. The population of Wilkinsburg, P.A. is roughly 68% Black and 35% of people are living at or below the poverty line [5]. Wilkinsburg, P.A. immediately borders but is not part of Pittsburgh, P.A., and it is one of the many unincorporated municipalities that acutely struggle with resource deprivation and long-term disinvestment <ref type="bibr">[1]</ref>. In 2021, Pittsburgh, P.A. was considered to be one of the U.S. 's "Apartheid Cities" [4], as the structures of power within the city continue to perpetuate systemic racial inequality and injustice <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[54]</ref>, magnified by the post-industrial blight the region experiences.</p><p>Community Forge Community Forge is a former elementary school re-purposed into a space that hosts mixed programming geared towards developing a more equitable economy for Wilkinsburg, P.A. and the Greater Pittsburgh, P.A. region (Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>). Towards this goal, Community Forge provides financial resources, jobs, job training, business development, youth empowerment programs (e.g., courses, summer camps, hands-on-learning), and community outreach events (e.g., food and supply giveaways, music and movie nights, hosts a voting location). Community Forge's business development resources include: coaching and professional service referrals, technical assistance, networking opportunities, financial support, and affordable office rentals (re-purposed classrooms with co-working and individual office space, Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1B</ref>). Community Forge works with roughly 50 local businesses each year through a variety of programs where 95% of the businesses are Black-owned, approximately 90% of entrepreneurs do not have a college degree, and 80% are first-time entrepreneurs. To spread information about resources available within the space, Community Forge relies on word-of-mouth and social media, as well as working with existing organizations in Wilkinsburg, P.A. and Pittsburgh, P.A. which support entrepreneurs. Community Forge also hosts quarterly tenant mixers, where the entrepreneurs renting space at Community Forge can mingle, enjoy free food, share updates and hear any announcements with the space. </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Co-Designing Tech Help Desk</head><p>Initial collaboration between Community Forge and the researchers' university began when one member of the research team reached out to leaders at Community Forge to introduce himself and to gauge and establish interest in collaborating for a grant proposal 3 . In these initial discussions, community stakeholders emphasized that it was important that our presence within Community Forge brought immediate value for the community members. The directors were clear that starting with any form of data collection immediately upon entering the space would not be permitted, as such an action would extracting value from the space without providing anything in return. This concern echoes previous calls to prioritize rapport building <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[48]</ref> and to deliver immediate value to stakeholders by prioritizing their needs rather than optimizing for a research agenda when conducting community-based research <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[35,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">69]</ref>. Community Forge leaders also emphasized the tenuous historical relationship between the researchers' institution and the surrounding community that Community Forge served. For instance, the researchers' institution had a history of being complicit to the racial injustice in the surrounding area, such issues ranging from public relations [2] to police brutality <ref type="bibr">[3]</ref>. Therefore the resulting lack of institutional trust needed to be taken into account when considering next steps.</p><p>In June of 2019, we began our discussions with Community Forge members for how the researchers could address challenges the entrepreneurs in Community Forge were experiencing. Community Forge leaders and researchers suggested a few ideas for how the research team could structure their involvement with the space. One idea was to offer a series of courses on technical skills, but given the diversity of entrepreneur businesses within Community Forge, it was not yet clear what technical skills a curriculum should cover. A second idea (similar to the original grant proposal) was to provide a class on how to find jobs within online labor markets such as Fiverr or Freelancer to facilitate job mobility, but few entrepreneurs in the space were interested in pursuing online freelance work alongside running their small business. Another idea was to provide a tool to facilitate peer mentorship among entrepreneurs at Community Forge, but the director of the peer mentorship program did not consider it appropriate to conduct a research study on peer mentorship as they were just establishing peer cohorts within Community Forge. As conversations deepened, the Community Forge executive director shared their experience working on day-to-day computing challenges entrepreneurs would come to them with. As the director had a tight schedule, such requests for one-on-one technical assistance were leaving them exasperated. These reflections, coupled with recommendations from leaders of other entrepreneurial non-profits (e.g., a director for a leading technology non-profit in the U.S.), led to a consistent starting point: to offer "office hours" in which research team members could answer any technical questions while physically present at Community Forge. Regular office hours would allow the research team to provide immediate value for Community Forge and enable relationship building. Community Forge leaders and the researchers agreed that repetition and consistency would be important to build a reliable presence within the space. After three months of discussions and iteration, in September 2019, we opened weekly "office hours" for entrepreneurs in the space, called Tech Help Desk.</p><p>When determining how to advertise Tech Help Desk, we considered how to communicate the types of technical services we would offer. This was a non-trivial task not only because of the need to keep the call as broad as possible, but also because those who the call was targeting did not necessarily know the technical jargon used to articulate and indentify technical issues <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[45,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">74]</ref>. Therefore, we did not list a fixed set of technical tasks our providers would offer, but instead left this call open and welcomed all technical challenges. However, during the study, this open-ended call caused confusion as entrepreneurs did not know what type of services Tech Help Desk provided. In the end, we created a flyer describing all the services providers had offered (See Supplemental Materials).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2.1">Timing and location within the building.</head><p>To determine time and location of Tech Help Desk, we discussed with Community Forge's Operations Manager, who was a constant presence in the facility and had the most in-depth understanding of who was at Community Forge and at what time (including co-occurring programs). As entrepreneurs were most likely to be in the space midweek and midday, we selected Wednesdays 12:00PM-3:00PM for the winter months and 1:00PM-4:00PM for the summer to account for the change in daylight. For the physical location of Tech Help Desk, we initially set up in the atrium, a central area where all tenants pass through when entering or leaving the building. We also tried renting a desk in a co-working room (but it was difficult to share sound space with entrepreneurs who sought quite time at their desks) and a renting a full room (which provided privacy for support sessions). In the end, we returned to the atrium as it afforded the best discoverability of the service.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Tech Help Desk Structure and Activity</head><p>Entrepreneurs discovered Tech Help Desk through flyers we posted with the monthly schedule throughout the building (See Supplemental Materials), word-of-mouth from prior participants, Community Forge staff, Community Forge newsletters sent monthly, as well as through physical encounters within the space (i.e., walking by the desk). The Tech Help Desk providers traversed the space to introduce themselves to other members and inquire if they had any technical issues. Once initial contact was established, the provider worked with the entrepreneur to determine if an in-person or virtual session would best fit their needs, and if they preferred to schedule an appointment or walk-in (when COVID-19 restrictions were in place and all appointments were remote).</p><p>For the session, we asked entrepreneurs to bring a device and charger they could easily access these. If they did not have access to a WiFi or data-enabled device, the computer lab within Community Forge provided devices. Entrepreneurs were given the option to opt into the research study, and it was made clear that participation in the research study was not required to receive technical assistance. To help mitigate any pressure entrepreneurs felt to opt in to the study, it was mentioned as a secondary point and deproritized alongside the other intake information provided to the entrepreneur. In addition, we also encouraged any questions and provided transparency into the research questions and research goals. Tech Help Desk sessions were not recorded, but instead the provider took field notes during and after the session. While note taking, the participant could view the provider's screen (when the session was in-person) and see the notes and ask questions. After the session, the provider asked if the entrepreneur would like to schedule a follow-up meeting. The provider then sent a follow-up email describing the tasks accomplished in the completed session, "to do" items the entrepreneur should attempt to accomplish between sessions, and goals for the next session.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.1">Responding to COVID-19.</head><p>In response to the COVID-19 pandemic, we transitioned Tech Help Desk to remote assistance via Zoom or phone starting in March 2020. All participants of Tech Help Desk had Zoom installed on their devices and were comfortable with using Zoom, but two participants preferred a phone call for an initial consultation. In Zoom sessions, participants shared their screen via Zoom, but they were not able to see the provider's screen. We expanded the hours participants could request a help session to Monday -Friday 9:00a-6:00p, acknowledging the heightened stress and demand on entrepreneurs to have a strong digital presence for their small business as a result of the pandemic. When Community Forge reopened in July 2021, the research team returned to offering in-person Tech Help Desk sessions, but continued to offer remote Tech Help Desk sessions for those who preferred to meet online.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3.2">Leading up to and Following the Tech Help Desk session.</head><p>A presession survey asked participants to provide details about their technical questions, their business, their demographics, and whether their business was their main source of income. A post-session survey asked participants to describe the solution implemented with the provider, as well as to provide positive and constructive feedback on the session with the "I like... " and "I wish... " format <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[36]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Interviews with Entrepreneurs and Supporters</head><p>To gain a rich, qualitative understanding of how local entrepreneurs overcome everyday technology challenges, we conducted semistructured interviews with Community Forge entrepreneurs as well as people who have supported Community Forge entrepreneurs (e.g., program directors, business coaches). We conducted our interviews between February 2020 and summer of 2021. We began our outreach for interviews in February of 2020, but the COVID-19 pandemic removed all possibility of interviewing entrepreneurial support personnel. We resumed and completed interviews in the summer of 2021.</p><p>3.4.1 Participants. We recruited entrepreneur participants by emailing entrepreneurs who had used Tech Help Desk or participated in the Business Bloom Program . We also recruited Community Forge leaders and people who served in support roles for the Business Bloom Program program (e.g., business coaches, lawyers, accountants, web developers), as well as people who led or served in support roles at other incubator and accelerator programs for local entrepreneurs in Pittsburgh, P.A. In total, we recruited 9 entrepreneurs, and 10 support people (7 support people also owned their own small business) (See Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref>).</p><p>3.4.2 Semi-Structured Interviews. Our semi-structured interviews with supporters and entrepreneurs took one hour, and participants were compensated $20. We asked entrepreneurs background questions about their business, the types of technology they used as part of their business (e.g., websites, software, hardware, cloud services, and social media), and types of external help they used. We then asked about what types of technical challenges they encountered as a business owners and how they overcame them. We concluded with asking about what resources they would like in the future for solving technology problems. During interviews with people in supporting roles for entrepreneurs, we asked about their organization and the types of entrepreneurial support it provided (e.g., educational, financial, or technology resources). We then asked about their experience with entrepreneur technology challenges and solutions, and about any resources for learning technology they felt were missing. Please see the Supplemental Materials for both interview protocols.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Data Analysis</head><p>For the semi-structured interviews, the research team conducted audio and video recording and took detailed field notes. All audio recordings were transcribed (with Descript.com) and reviewed for errors by hand. The research team analyzed these data through process of open coding to identify initial themes across the interviews and the Tech Help Desk field notes. We later engaged in affinity diagramming <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref> over the course of two weeks, where the three out of six authors reviewed each transcript, marked sections that informed and extended this paper's motivations, and printed out the corresponding data. Clusters formed around themes: barriers to using computing tools for entrepreneurs whether these barriers were "content", "operational", or "access" challenges <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[71]</ref>), resourceful workarounds entrepreneurs deduced to overcome barriers, systems of support and entrepreneurs used to facilitate the use of computing tools in their business. All authors repeatedly met during this period to review key findings and iteratively refine a set of analytic memos which expanded on emergent across our data <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>. We followed participant quote editing conventions consistent with applied social science repractices <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[25]</ref>. Specifically, we removed filler words and false starts, in some cases re-punctuated and used ellipses to indicate omissions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.6">Positionality</head><p>We disclose the identities and positionality of the researchers and authors of this paper, as a concern for reflexive design research practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[50,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b67">66]</ref>. Tech Help Desk sessions were led by a research team comprising three white women, one from the Southwest U.S., one from the Southeast U.S., and one is a U.S. immigrant from Western two white men from the rural Midwest of the and an impoverished, post-industrial part of Eastern U.S.; and one Black man from Eastern U.S whose work focuses on business development, who is dedicated to providing economic opportunities for minority entrepreneurs, and who has experienced racism firsthand during his time in "Corporate America". The research team comprises three researchers who are upper management at field site, three researchers in a technical department at a pri-U.S. university (a graduate student and two faculty members, one tenured and one un-tenured), one un-tenured faculty member in a technical department at a public U.S. university, and one individual who ceased their pursuit of a technical career in academia in order to center their community-based efforts to fight the tangible caused by racism, poverty, and devaluing of human life the U.S. The five middle-aged, white researchers do not have certain lived that are relevant to this study such as the impact of forms of violence due to racism, ageism, or xenophobia (especially the context of technology education). Three researchers do not have lived experience of poverty or other aspects of background that employers (or those funding business grants) discriminate against. All five white researchers experience privileges from whiteness, access to formal technical education (e.g., engineering and computer science degrees) and grew up with access to computing devices.</p><p>Given the predominantly white research team, we took meato mitigate power imbalances and to cultivate a more equirelationship between the research team and Community Forge (as well as within the research team). For instance, all of the research team were firmly to the Community Forge mission statement, prioritized generating immediate for the community members rather than optimizing their Participants were able to opt-out of sharing any asof their identity. All but four entrepreneurs who leveraged Tech Help Desk were sole proprietors of their businesses, and the other businesses had less than five employresearch agenda, maintained transparency with research practices, depriorizted data collection, and routinely sought feedback from Forge members and staff for how to improve Tech Help Desk.</p><p>To build relationships with Community Forge entrepreneurs, the first and last authors attended the quarterly tenant mixers hosted by Community Forge. Research team members spent mixers introducing themselves to tenants and asking entrepreneurs what kinds of technology questions, goals, and challenges they were experiencing. Community Forge staff served as an intermediary for of these introductions, in order to provide context to tenants for the research team's presence within Community Forge and to trust building.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">FINDINGS 4.1 Entrepreneurs Resourcefully and Discerningly Stitch Together an Ecology of Technical Support</head><p>We share the ways that entrepreneurs resourcefully and discerningly sought technical support to demonstrate entrepreneurs' ability in solving technical challenges. In addition, we detail the entrepreneurs' ecology of support to make salient the on-going techchallenges that are not yet addressed, illustrating the need for strategic and responsive model of technical support to match the approach of the entrepreneurs. Overall, entrepreneurs identified and used a range of services to overcome computing challenges including: courses and workshops, social support including peers and mentors, as well as one-on-one support from business-related professionals (e.g., accountants, business coaches).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.1">Courses and Workshops. Several entrepreneurs</head><p>business courses which were offered at local universities, public libraries, private companies, non-profits, and online. P11, a entrepreneurial support personnel, reflected that offering workshops for larger reach for when providers need to "tell everyone the same thing". P14 who ran a food business participated in seminars run by a local non-profit covering foundational business questions and technology (e.g., What type of customer are trying to attract? Will you use cash app or Venmo to accept payments?) This enabled her to immediately improve her use of the technology she was already using (e.g., by using analytics on a social media app).</p><p>However, classes not always line up with entrepreneurs' goals (reported by P1, P5-6, P9, P11, P15). In practice, entrepreneurs' technology needs were time-sensitive and dependent on business stage, domain and their knowledge. Further, general-audience classes offered through public libraries and universities were less useful they were not tailored to the entrepreneurial context (e.g., P11 noted that a general Excel course library did cover how to use Excel for accountinge.g., templates or formulas for creating a profit and loss).</p><p>Even if in classes be eventually be useful to their entrepreneurs often opted to spend their time on their immediate business tasks instead, as: "[Entrepreneurs] might've for-[the class material] by the time they have that need, especially it's not required, [and then] they won't attend a session until the need is there. " (P1). Still, P4 who noted that 80-90% of course content to be redundant, strategically tuned in through less relevant content because "there's always in there you didn't know". To use courses to meet their business goals, entrepreneurs planned to take specific classes when they reached that business need (e.g., P7 planned to take a QuickBooks accounting software class once they outgrew paper filing) and wished for regular local technology classes with on-demand access (P14).</p><p>Social and Mentors. Entrepreneurs identified informal opportunities for technical support through their own networks, incubator or accelerator-style programs. Several enreported that they had a network of a few trusted peers or mentors with similar businesses tasks who they could contact to work through specific technology challenges. Peers or mentors with similar businesses could provide highly domain-specific technical help, as P4 described seeking on-demand technology for a last minute filming job from a peer who was on a commercial shoot: "I kept he went on FaceTime and he went through all the settings <ref type="bibr">[and]</ref> he told me what to punch in. " Peer support also provided one-on-one help to through well-known technical problems with a better approach. P7 described that he contacted his website's company after running into a problem connecting his domain name (a common issue, P1, P6), and the company emailed instructions for how to resolve the problem. However, P7 still ended up calling his friend to discuss the instructions due to their shared experience, mutual understanding and trust. While peer and mentor support was valuable for entrepreneurs addressing their computing challenges, existing networks did not always have the skill needed (e.g., P7 did not know anyone who used a specialized music platform), and busy entrepreneur peers limited time to provide support (e.g., P4 sent his peer a gift for providing last-minute tech support). As a result, entrepreneurs technical assistance which was available on-demand, as as ways to expand their peer networks. To do so, several entrepreneurs participated in incubator-style programs in which they could meet other entrepreneurs.</p><p>To create opportunities to build social support relationships among entrepreneurs which endured, program leaders emphasized the importance of in-person interactions such as in-person coworking, mixers, barbeques and pitch competitions (P1, P5-6, P8, P15). Building new relationships in-person provided entrepreneurs more information about potential support from peers or men-For example, P2 preferred to meet only in-person for technolsupport, as physical aspects like body language were important for him to find signals of trustworthiness. in-person events were also critical to combat the isolation entrepreneurs can ex-"We just really want to emphasize [getting] comfortable speaking about their business" (P8). However, when it came to constructing cohorts of peer entrepreneurs through incubator-style programming, program leaders emphasized difficulties that can arise. For example, curating peer cohorts was challenging (P5-6) as a single cohort member can impact the efficacy of the whole group if there were clashing personalities, competing business models, or issues.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.3">One-on-One Technology Support with Business Profession-</head><p>Entrepreneurs in our study also identified opportunities for technical support while completing other business tasks with pro-(e.g., business coaches, accountants, lawyers and web developers). They accessed such professionals either through an incubator-style program or through hiring them for a specific job to complete taxes, to file for incorporation). For the most part, business coaches did not provide support for low-level technical challenges (P6, P10, P12, and P15), but would provide higher level feedback on how to use technology to reach business goals (e.g., whether or not to build a website -P10).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Addressing the Long Tail of Computing Challenges with Tech Help Desk</head><p>While the ecology of support entrepreneurs resourcefully created addressed many of their technical challenges, there were still computing challenges that entrepreneurs were not able to readily address given a mismatch in the design of these support structures entrepreneurial needs. In this section, we describe the 61 computing challenges entrepreneurs addressed with Tech Help Desk to further illuminate the need for strategic and responsive technical</p><p>We refer to this collection of 61 challenges addressed with Tech Help Desk as the long tail of computing challenges, given the large number of unique challenges that were solved. We categorize challenges into: (1) operational (related to the specific tool at hand, similar to "medium-related" challenges in <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[71]</ref>), (2) strategic challenges (related to the strategic selection and application of tools to a specific goal, similar to information and strategy <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[71]</ref>), and (3) access challenges (related to balancing technology costs in time or money with other business expenses). To examine the importance of our side-by-side approach which informed the discoverability of challenges, we distinguish between challenges that were self-diagnosed (an entrepreneur-identified issue) versus collaboratively diagnosed (both entrepreneur and provider together to uncover Self-Diagnosed Challenges were Mostly Operational Challenges. Entrepreneurs sought support when they self-identified technical challenges that blocked progress towards a business goal. Of the 34 unique technology challenges that entrepreneurs preto providers (i.e., self-diagnosed), 19 were operational challenges, 12 were strategic challenges, and three were access challenges. Self-diagnosed operational challenges indicated that a tool did not clearly communicate how to execute desired tasks, suggesting opportunity for improvements to technology design. The operational challenges were related to: the entrepreneurs' websites (P1-2, P5, P7, P14-17), generating digital content (P1-2, P4-9, P11, P15-17), and other types of general hardware and software challenges (P1-3, P5, P6, P8-13, P15-19). For example, as all enin our study used a website service provider (e.g., Wix, Squarespace, Wordpress), many sought assistance with operational challenges related to these platforms in order to: upload video and photos to their website (P2, P14), navigate an online product dashboard (P2), update branding (P16-17), customize a blog post template (P2), add new product listings to online store (P2, P15-17), understand surprising web tool behavior (e.g., why a customer was a high price for shipping for an order placed in their website, P2), and to fix expired security certificates (P7, P11). Entrepreneurs generating digital content sought support to edit videos photos of merchandise (P2, P4, P7) and to create or edit an existing PDF (P5, P9). Beyond websites and digital content, entrepreneurs help for general software and hardware challenges includdownloading software (e.g., Microsoft 365 -P9, Quickbooks -P1, P5), improving device performance (P2, P9), locating software features to complete task at hand (P1-2, P5, P9), and forwarding calls to business phone (P18).</p><p>Self-diagnosed strategic represented times where entrepreneurs proactively sought out advice on how to effectively use technology towards their business goals. The 12 self-diagnosed strategic computing challenges included: understanding the norms of use for computing tools such as social media platforms (e.g., to post) (P9-10, P12), selecting between several for tools to use (e.g. which website provider or financial software (P13, P17), determining credibility and trustworthiness of computing tools (P2, P9, P16), and building the confidence to make technological decisions that could greatly impact their business (e.g., publishing a new version of their website (P16)).</p><p>challenges represented that resources should be easier to acquire including fast and flexible capital opportunities <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[56]</ref> and on-demand technology lending. The three challenges that entrepreneurs shared were: paying for maintenance costs of websites and other software programs (P1, P2, P16), having reliable access to equipment (vinyl, laser, etc) (P15), and having reliable access to data and wifi-enabled devices (P15).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Computing Challenges Entrepreneurs and Providers Collabo-</head><p>Identified. found that entrepreneurs' demanding schedules made spending time optimizing their use of technology to be in competition with time spent completing essential business management tasks. Thus, collaboratively identified challenges (27 of 61 challenges in our data) presented as moments of recognizing for improved technology use-or disuse. The 15 (out of 27) strategic challenges identified by entrepreneurs in collaboration with providers included: discovering helpful tools for the task at hand (P1, P5-6, P10-11, P13, P17), considering whether or not to prioritize use of computing tools alongside other business (where entrepreneurs often realized that they needed to demote the prioritization of computing tools in order to ensure strong business foundation (P1, P3, P5, P8, P10-13)), optimizing for a minimum viable website (rather than overextending their already limited resources to use more advanced technology (P3, P10, P12)), deciding how much time to spend acquiring computing skills for they already use to become more expert versus allocating time learning other tools (P1, P3, P10, P12), and planning their tool usage as their business grew. Beyond the strategic challenges, were 12 operational challenges which were collaboratively between entrepreneur and Tech Help Desk provider such as how file types impacted uploading ability to online platforms (P5), management of multiple devices and file sharing across devices efficiently (P2), and implementing effective website design principles (P2, P16-17). These collaboratively identified operational challenges indicated that a technology tool was likely inadequately to provide error messages and recognize opportunities for improved use.</p><p>By distinguishing the types of challenges entrepreneurs addressed alongside whether the entrepreneur identified them (selfor worked with a provider to identify them (collaboratively diagnosed) illuminated how a side-by-side approach can facilitate further discovery of an array of computing challenges through mutual observation during Tech Help Desk sessions. Operchallenges were more likely to be observed by entrepreneurs themselves, as opposed to strategic challenges which were more likely to be identified with the providers' assistance. In the reflect on why this may the case. In the next we detail three entrepreneurs' experiences using Tech Help to address their long tail of computing challenges.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Three Vignettes: Addressing Computing</head><p>Challenges with Tech Help Desk illustrate how Tech Help Desk sessions uncovered and addressed diverse set of computing challenges with entrepreneurs, below are three vignettes of Tech Help Desk sessions the first author conducted. While each entrepreneur had vastly different technical each vignette showcases how the strategic and responsive Tech Help Desk model uniquely addressed diverse challenges.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1">Non-profit Sets Up to Work from Home During a</head><p>Pandemic. P9 (65-74 year old man, 30+ years running his business), the founder of a local non-profit housing and development association, first heard about Tech Help Desk through the Forge monthly newsletter in April 2020. Initial Computing Challenge. P9 wanted to use TechSoup, a thirdparty platform that offers subsidized software for non-profits, to download Office 365. His prior Office license was soon to expire and he needed to complete tasks at home on his personal laptop to the lockdown. Addressing the Initial Computing The provider worked P9 over the course of three one-hour remote Tech Help Desk to install Office 365 via TechSoup on his laptop. P9 shared screen so that provider could provide direct guidance. During moments when P9 would enter sensitive information (username and passwords), the provider would close her laptop partially and communicate she was doing so to P9. The provider searched online all of the steps required to download the software through TechSoup-this was her first time using TechSoup-and shared the documents she found so they could follow along together. The helped P9 formulate a request to TechSoup's customer support to retrieve his license information (which he could not in his records). The provider and P9 scheduled a follow-up session depending on P9's preferences. Given the urgency of having this software installed, P9 opted for the follow-up sessions to be within the same week. At the end of the third session, using the version of Office 365, P9 successfully opened a new Word document on his laptop.</p><p>Addressing Additional and Collaboratively Diagnosed Computing P9 reached out to the provider at an additional time in 2020 to set up Constant Contact (to reach his customers during the lockdown). In these follow-up sessions, P9 and the provider time sharing how they and their loved ones were doing-at point, the two had spent several hours together and taking the time to deepen the relationship felt important to both. During these the provider observed how P9 navigated his file system, documents, and opened the browser and applications. She suggested ways to make P9's laptop run more efficiently, as well as how P9 could more quickly traverse his file system and find applications. It had not occurred to P9 to attempt to clear disk space, but instead he had accepted the wait time as applications loaded and closed. P9 set up a total of four additional one-on-one one-hour Tech Help Desk sessions to cover issues that arose during prior sessions based on the provider's observations and recommendations. Between P9's prior experience using to download software, and the provider's to effectively search for, interpret, and actualize online documentation, together the two were to address P9's technical requests. The collaborative nature of the sessions increased with each session, as the provider and P9's building deepened.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Returning Citizen Sprints to Finalize</head><p>Website in time for Mar-Event. P2 (35-44 year old man, less than one year running his business), the founder and sole proprietor of his lifestyle and motivation coaching business, scheduled his first Tech Help Desk session in August of 2021. While in the Community Forge kitchen, the provider ran into P2 and struck up a conversation explaining who she was and what technical services were available to him via Help Desk. Initial Computing Challenge. P2 shared that he was trying to his website (hosted on Wix) in order to have it ready for an marketing event. Similarly to P9, P2 felt out of the loop with the many computing tools; P2 shared that he had recently completed a decade-long jail sentence and during this time he was unable to stay abreast with the substantial technological advancements. P2 emphasized that he had leaned on the support of his "mentor slash business coach" as well as a close "tech savvy" friend order to decide which devices to purchase and how set up his website.</p><p>Addressing the Initial Computing Challenge. P2 wanted to his website's product page, add a video of a recent speech he had given, and finish his blog posts. Even though the P2 had already up his website with his friend, he could not remember how to navigate website's dashboard. The provider loaded his website on her laptop across different browsers and simulated different screen sizes to look for mobile compatibility which he noted in his notebook for future use. The two sat side-by-side viewing each others' screens and the provider created a pretend Wix website on her so that she could familiarize herself with available tools. initial meeting extended beyond the hours of the Tech Help Desk window, but such flexibility of the provider's schedule was P2 expressed needing to be far enough along on any given task where he could continue to work on the task without her Between the sessions, the provider summarized the tasks comin the previous session, the tasks they would collaboratively prioritize in the next session (based P2's preferences), and any action items for P2 to complete between sessions. P2 noted that this documentation was helpful for him to stay on task, as well as visuthe progress he has made. At the end of P2's series of sessions, his online store was up-to-date with all of his merchandise and color options), and his website included a motivational blog and embedded video of his first paid motivational speech. Addressing Additional and Collaboratively Diagnosed Computing Challenges. P2 to ask about more types of technical assistance provider could offer, as he observed how the provider used her to complete similar tasks to his while they sat side-by-side. example, P2 observed how the provider used keyboard shortand asked did you do that so fast?" explaining what shortcuts were, they reviewed this in the next session refreshed these shortcuts every session thereafter). P2 particiin almost 15 sessions as he returned for several weeks, using Tech Help Desk as a concentrated co-working time for technology improvements across his business.</p><p>discovered Tech Help Desk through a "water cooler" encounter in the Community Forge kitchen, as compared to the entrepreneurs in the prior and following vignette who were more introduced to the service. Over the course of several sessions, P2's resourceful and discerning approach to his business him to explore the range of possibilities for how Tech Help Desk could help him. Rather than restricting conversation solely technology, the provider and P2 allocated time for exchanging (similar to P9), and P2 often reflected on how his time in jail had impacted his entrepreneurial pursuits. Through these sto-P2 shared he wrote a book while being incarcerated which was stalled due to a few technical complications (which they addressed in follow-up sessions). For both P2 and P9, relationship alongside technical assistance was important as deepening the relationship helped to extend the technical assistance.</p><p>Party Planner Creates a Website in Time for a Bus Ad Launch. P16, the founder and sole proprietor of three-year-old gift and party planning business, had her first Tech Help Desk session in 2021. P16 was introduced to Tech Help Desk by a Community Forge director during open hours.</p><p>Computing Challenges. P16 wanted help with her website to ensure all was up-to-date in time for her business's ad campaign on public buses in Pittsburgh, P.A. Tracing information in her inas well as her notebook, she explained she had two websites currently registered and did not know how to combine them.</p><p>the Initial Computing Challenge. Together, the provider P16 discovered that the server P16 was using for one of her websites, donated to her by a friend, was no longer in commission.</p><p>noted how distressing this period of time was when her website was down: "I was held hostage at one point with my website. I was frustrated and it brought tears because that's how I sell my prod-And for probably close to three months, my website was down. " the next four sessions, the provider worked with P16 to curate, refine, and finalize the content to list on her functioning website, implement an intake form for potential customers interin her event services, as well as update her product listings to include up-to-date event services. Importantly, P16 often the operations required to execute these tasks, but preferred sit side-by-side with the provider as she felt more confident to experiment: "I can sit with provider] and click a button and not worry about my whole website crashing." (P16). By utilizing Tech Help Desk, P16 felt comfortable to engage in more experimentation her technical decisions, as she knew someone was next to her in case something went awry. Throughout all the sessions, P16 took detailed notes so could to them later if she forgot we made certain decisions or if she needed a refresher for completing similar tasks in the future.</p><p>A Reflection on Three Vignettes. All entrepreneurs relied on an ecology of support which they had resourcefully curated to fit their businesses needs across various types of resources (e.g., incubators and courses, friends, peers and informal social support, and hiring temporary assistance). But at some point, each of these of support had a tipping point where the support was no longer available or would no longer suffice (P2 did not want to strain relationships with repeated help requests, P16's updated budget disallowed hiring technical assistance, and P9's colleague away). Given the strategic and responsive model of technical provided through Tech Help Desk, the provider and entrepreneurs worked together in order to address an array of computing challenges identified entrepreneur. Moreover, Tech Help Desk's collaborative approach facilitated relationship building which ultimately led to identifying and solving further challenges.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Limitations</head><p>Together with our community partners at Community Forge, we co-designed Tech Help Desk within the particular setting of an entrepreneurial hub in Wilkinsburg, P.A. All entrepreneurs in our study were tenants of Community Forge or participants of the Business Bloom Program. This required at least a $100 per month desk fee or an application to the Bloom Program, thus enneeded to have some amount of preexisting capital. the future, we aim to make Tech Help Desk accessible to more P.A. community members beyond Community Forge though more work will be needed to facilitate discoverability and scale of the service. While the design of Tech Help Desk may not be fully transferable to new contexts, we encourage work to explore opportunities to repurpose features of our strategic and responsive model in community-driven projects for entrepreneur technical support. In addition, the research team was predominantly from a private university neighboring Wilkinsburg, P.A., and the entrepreneurs at Community Forge were predominantly from Wilkinsburg, P.A. As shared identity is an important of trust, Tech Help Desk can work to improve trust recruiting or hiring providers who have more overlapping dimensions of identity such as place of employment (or status as an entrepreneur), place of origin, or socioeconomic status.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>DISCUSSION</head><p>work uncovered how local entrepreneurs running businesses in a variety of non-technology domains leveraged technologyand non-technology centered support to address the technology challenges that they encountered. Through our close partnership with Community Forge leaders and community members, we co-designed a model of technical assistance that is strategic, that it is designed to fit the context of local entrepreneurs, and responsive, in that it prioritizes emergent needs (See Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>). The two-and-a-half-year (and on-going) deployment of Tech Help Desk demonstrated its support for entrepreneurs addressing computing challenges including troubleshooting support, support for planning executing a technology project, and support for uncovering opportunities to improve the efficiency of their technology tasks. approach enabled us to gain knowledge about the long tail of computing challenges local entrepreneurs with diverse business domains, backgrounds, and goals face (RQ1), the ecology of support resourceful and discerning local entrepreneurs from lean economies construct to overcome technology challenges (RQ2), and how a strategic and responsive model of technology assistance can address gaps that standard technical support struggles to remedy within the entrepreneurial context (RQ3). Our complementary interviews with individuals who support entrepreneurs accountants, accelerator managers, business coaches, and lawyers beyond Community Forge provided greater depth to our understanding the importance of Tech Help Desk's uniquely strategic and responsive approach.</p><p>In this section, we highlight three key design trade-offs we made to effectively instantiate our model in the context of local in a co-working space (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>): responsive rather than standardized support for solving the long tail of computing challenges, (2) long-term learning rather than shortterm problem solving for entrepreneurs balancing technical demands with other business needs, and (3) prioritizing active trust and relationship building.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Responsive rather than standardized support for the long tail of computing challenges</head><p>Initial conversations with Community Forge stakeholders highthe importance for the research team to provide immediate value for the community upon arrival, so we prioritized responsive technical support through Tech Help Desk's individual support sessions. We identified unique of providing responsive support within the context of an entrepreneur community. First, entrepreneurs who visited Tech Help Desk or participated in interdescribed that they used (or planned to use) a variety of other existing services for standardized support such as digital literacy classes or business accelerator programs. In contrast, prior work provided course or group support for entrepreneurs focused on those who do not have access to these standardized forms of sup- <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[40,</ref><ref type="bibr">62]</ref>. Still, entrepreneurs in our study used the responsive support provided by Tech Help Desk for distinct, time-sensitive computing challenges not clearly addressed elsewhere (e.g., clearing files off of a computer, transferring image files across devices, removing an image from a Wix website). In the future, responsive support that has access to the dynamically changing needs of local entrepreneurs can inform the curriculum for courses and</p><p>In interviews, participants noted that while existing technology support was offered in courses or incubators, it was primarily towards program goals or a curriculum (similar to tiered curriculum support in education <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b39">39]</ref>), and thus lacked to support the long tail of computing challenges (See Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">2</ref> for a comparison between curriculum-driven support and need-driven support for local entrepreneurs). Incubator leaders referred entrepreneurs to us for technology support outside of their incubator's scope, and entrepreneurs visited us when other courses ended. In the future, we could also refer entrepreneurs to courses services as needed. Finally, entrepreneurs leveraged Tech Help Desk's hybrid drop-in and appointment schedule to stop by for a single session (e.g., to clear off files to fix a slow device), or to schedule repeated follow-ups (P2 attended 15 sessions total) to work through a single or emergent set of computing this scheduling format accommodated varied experience levels.</p><p>uncovered unique challenges of providing responsive First, the novelty of Tech Help Desk's broad and responsive support demonstrated a challenge in communicating its purpose scope. Entrepreneurs initially approached Tech Help Desk with needs outside scope including making a website for them (providers did not complete tasks for entrepreneurs) or supporting trademark legal issues (providers did not have legal expertise required). As miscommunication can mean wasted time for busy entrepreneurs, we updated our flyer to describe the side-by-side style and list of help we provided (See flyer in Supplemental Material). Second, scaling responsive support to multiple entrepreneurs per provider at a time is challenging. In particular, entrepreneurs' and experience levels are diverse, and scaling necessitates less responsiveness these factors as entrepreneurs would spend less time directly working with the provider. To limit demand, we advertised only within Community Forge (rather than to the surarea of Wilkinsburg, P.A.). In practice, providers worked one entrepreneur at a time, or two if they arrived at similar times (in which case entrepreneurs occasionally used the opportuto meet each other). Future work could explore one-to-three higher) support by providing a co-working room where the can circulate and peers can work together with guidance. Finally, tracking the outcome of highly responsive support like Tech Help Desk is challenging compared to standardized support, where programs may conduct pre-and post-tests for courses or evaluate business success along program goals. Program organizers and P8) shared that when they facilitate referrals to external resources for technical issues, it is currently either challenging (for website development) or nearly infeasible (for coaching) to manually track and document whether or not the referral was successful. As tracking impact is important for non-profits <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[17]</ref>, future work explore how to deliver and document responsive support to both entrepreneurs and program goals.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Collaborative learning for resourceful and entrepreneurs</head><p>design of Tech Help Desk involved the resources of a few to provide an opportunity for support a few hours a (as opposed to an organization that can provide around-theclock support <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[60]</ref>). Given that entrepreneurs adapt to changing business needs between and after visits to Tech Help Desk (e.g., a product to a website), we opted to promote learning via a side-by-side approach that has been found to be successful for technology learning (e.g., paired programming <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[34]</ref>, over-the-shoulder learning <ref type="bibr" target="#b71">[70]</ref>).</p><p>The design and deployment of the side-by-side approach within Tech Help Desk revealed nuances about the implementation and benefits that differ from prior work. First, providers initially aimed to demystify technological problem solving by expressing when did not know how to solve the problem at hand and then collaboratively solving the problem along with the entrepreneur. In practice, we found it was also important to establish providers knowledgeable at the start (e.g., by sharing past experiences and education, knowledge about alternative technology <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b48">48]</ref>), as entrepreneurs looked for to discern that providers would not waste their time by leading them astray. In this way, providers as both a "guru" in terms of their knowledge, and a "garin terms of fostering a collaborative approach (rather than work where employees assumed one role or the other <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[31]</ref>). Second, given the diversity of tools and technology experiences entrepreneurs, the side-by-side shared screen approach offered chance to collaboratively discover ways for entrepreneurs to optimize their technology use across a wide range of tasks (e.g., from discovering alternative tools for their work to accessing adfiles in a list). In fact, 27 of 61 of the unique computing challenges in our data were collaboratively diagnosed. While independently diagnosed challenges prompted a visit to Tech Help Desk via a notable error or blocker towards business goals (e.g., computer to a halt, or not able to update website with new product), diagnosed represented non-blocking improvements for efficiency (e.g., scrolling through files vs. using a or alternative strategies to using technology (e.g., using a website builder to create a minimum viable web presence rather than building a new web application from scratch). Future researchers and program directors may consider side-by-side technical support as an approach to inform future standardized support or referrals for local entrepreneurs.</p><p>The side-by-side approach was not always best for entrepreneurs seeking technology support while proactively managing their time. Entrepreneurs juggling many roles within their company several times visited Tech Help Desk or scheduled an appointment, but selected to not attend or complete the session due to dynamically demands on their time (e.g., an important client phone call or an assistant in need of help during a session). While side-bystyle support allowed entrepreneurs to learn technical skills to maintain any changes made during the session, busy entrepreneurs may benefit from additional opportunities for delegated, rather than learning-centered, support for particularly rare or one-off tasks that are unlikely to require maintenance (e.g., initial device set-up setting up a printer). Entrepreneurs identified that they prefer to delegate a task (e.g., launching a website, logo) to use their time completing a core business product or service that would be more difficult to delegate. This judicious use of time was also encouraged by the business coaches that we interviewed. In this case, our model still can support entrepreneurs -for example, P17 leveraged Tech Help Desk to help identify and assess a professional to hire for her business's website development.</p><p>work may consider how to adapt Tech Help Desk's model for later stages of business where delegation may be more frequently necessary.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Prioritizing trust and building over provider flexibility</head><p>When a discerning entrepreneur considers working with a support person, establishing trust -or belief that engaging with a person is unlikely to cause harm <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[30]</ref> -is a necessary prerequisite <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27]</ref>. While help desk providers in traditional workplace settings benefit from institutional credibility when establishing trust <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[46]</ref>, our research team was from an institution that historically had a tenuous relationship with community members at our field site [2, 3]. In our study, entrepreneurs also noted they felt their lack of technological made them vulnerable to being disrespected, overcharged or otherwise scammed. To engage in support relationships with entrepreneurs despite prior institutional and technology-related harms, we prioritized actively building trust with Community Forge We identified several strategies for building trust to facilitate technical support in an existing community and space for entrepreneurs.</p><p>the design and deployment of Tech Help Desk benefited from a cascade of trust. That is, we initially established trust with community leaders by dramatically changing our research agenda in response to existing needs of the community space (such change often occurs when appropriately weighing community input above researcher input during community-based research <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[48]</ref>). Building trust with community leaders and providing a communitydriven service prompted to Community Forge leaders to then refer entrepreneurs to us; and, these referrals in turn facilitated between the entrepreneur Tech Help Desk provider. Second, entrepreneurs who used Tech Help Desk and Community Forge leaders reflecting on attributes of Tech Help Desk that facilitated trust cited the reliable and long-term nature of technical support. The reliable time and place enabled ease of referral and getting to know Community Forge members when lulls occurred. Finally, the reliability also encouraged entrepreneurs to use their own techniskills more. For example, P16 described how she felt she could change her website without fear of breaking it for a long time, she could always visit Tech Help Desk the next Wednesday if needed.</p><p>it is difficult to tell when Tech Help Desk did not succeed at building trust. When entrepreneurs did not approach Help Desk or return for a follow up (which happened on three occasions), it is unclear as to why that happened and whether a lack trust was at play. For example, entrepreneurs may have no longer technical help because they addressed the issue quickly, or a technical employee (as was the case with one entrepreneur worked with). However, it is also likely that in some ways failed to build trust. In the future, we will experiment with alternative approaches to understand the reasons entrepreneurs did not use or continue to use Tech Help Desk services (e.g., by asking collaborating community leaders to talk to entrepreneurs for potentially more frank responses). Finally, prioritizing consistency and relationship building made it challenging to introduce new providers to the project (a months-to years-long rather than dropin volunteer activity). Future work may explore new incentives for long-term technical support such as course credit.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>6</head><p>Today's local entrepreneurs must navigate an increasing array of technological tools to achieve their business goals. To understand and address the computing challenges faced by local enin a lean economy, we co-designed an on-going techservice, called Tech Help Desk, with a local entrepreneurial Forge-in Wilkinsburg, P.A. Our participatory aprevealed how entrepreneurs resourcefully and discerningly their day-to-day computing challenges by curating an of support, yet many challenges went unaddressed. To keep pace with local entrepreneurs and ever-changing technological ad-Tech Help Desk mirrored the strategic and responsive approach entrepreneurs took to building their businesses in order to address their long tail of computing challenges. Our work informs researchers' understanding of computing challenges and to create responsive technical support within an already execosystem for entrepreneurs.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Photos depicting (A) the front entrance to Community Forge, (B) one of the classrooms in Community Forge, and (C) the Tech Help Desk room.</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="5,54.04,83.69,239.75,157.67" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Figure2: A comparison of the traditional Multi-Tiered System of Support<ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[39]</ref> for formal curriculum-driven comto our for need-driven technology education for local entrepreneurs.</figDesc><graphic url="image-3.png" coords="13,153.00,83.68,305.99,136.59" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>A model for technology support that can be strategically attuned to entrepreneurial contexts and is responsive to the preferences and needs of local entrepreneurs (Design Tradeoff). In our implementation of this model, our participatory approach informed the design choices (Choice) and how Tech Help Desk embodied these choices (Instantiation) within Community Forge.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Model of Strategic and Responsive Support</cell><cell>Tech Help Desk</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Design Tradeoff</cell><cell>Choice</cell><cell>Instantiation</cell></row><row><cell>Should we provide responsive or standardized support?</cell><cell>Responsive</cell><cell>Individualized support</cell></row><row><cell>Should we prioritize learning or problem-solving?</cell><cell>Learning</cell><cell>Side-by-side format</cell></row><row><cell>Should we assume recipients' trust or build trust actively?</cell><cell>Build trust actively</cell><cell>Relationship building with consistent providers &amp; times</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Should we present as technical authority or knowledgeable collaborator? Knowledgeable collaborator Knowledgeable, but disclose bounds of expertise</cell></row><row><cell>Should we provide one-off or on-going assistance?</cell><cell>On-going</cell><cell>Drop-in, but encourage appointments</cell></row><row><cell>Should we prioritize visibility or privacy?</cell><cell>Visibility</cell><cell>In-person (when possible), in common area</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Tech Help Desk and interview participant demographics.</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Gender</cell><cell>Business Category(ies)</cell><cell>Participant Type</cell></row><row><cell>P1</cell><cell>Woman</cell><cell>Community Development</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell>P2</cell><cell>Man</cell><cell cols="2">Lifestyle and Youth Motivation Entrepreneur</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Man</cell><cell>Law</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell>P4</cell><cell>Man</cell><cell>Music and Entertainment</cell><cell>Entrepreneur</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Man</cell><cell>Community Development</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell>P6</cell><cell>Woman</cell><cell>Peer-to-Peer Support</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell>P7</cell><cell>Man</cell><cell>Music and Entertainment</cell><cell>Entrepreneur</cell></row><row><cell>P8</cell><cell>Man</cell><cell>Community Development</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell>P9</cell><cell>Man</cell><cell>Housing and Development</cell><cell>Entrepreneur</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P10 Man</cell><cell>Business Development</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Woman</cell><cell>Community Development</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P12 Man</cell><cell>Law</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P13 Woman</cell><cell>Finance</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P14 Woman</cell><cell>Bakery and Confections</cell><cell>Entrepreneur</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Woman</cell><cell>Community Development</cell><cell>Supporter</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Woman</cell><cell>Gifts and Party Planning</cell><cell>Entrepreneur</cell></row><row><cell cols="2">P17 Woman</cell><cell>Estate Settlement and Food</cell><cell>Entrepreneur</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">P18 Non-Binary Events and Entertainment</cell><cell>Entrepreneur</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Woman</cell><cell>Stationary and Homeware</cell><cell>Entrepreneur</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">For the remainder of the paper, we use "lean economies" as the preferred term which highlights the resiliency and innovation of residents located in communities with few resources as done in prior work<ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27]</ref>.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">Tech Help Desk is an on-going project, but this paper reports on two and a half years of progress.</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">The grant proposal focused on leveraging existing community structures to facilitate job mobility within underserved communities (urban and rural) by training unemployed individuals to become online workers.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>We thank all staff and community members of Community Forge their candid conversations and feedback. We also thank our participants for their thoughtful and frank reflections, and we thank our reviewers for their suggestions. This research was conducted under Carnegie Mellon University's IRB protocol #STUDY2020_00000104 and was funded by the National Science Foundation (#IIS-1928631).</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Equity and Inclusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Allegheny</forename><surname>County</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.alleghenycounty.us/equity-inclusion/index.aspx" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2021" to="2029" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">students to sign petition to confront local racism</title>
		<ptr target="https://actionnetwork.org/petitions/cmu-confront-racist-policing-in-Accessed" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2021" to="2029" />
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Carnegie Mellon University</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Report of Inequality Across Gender and Race</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Pittsburgh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2021" to="2029" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Wilkinsburg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Demographics</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wilkinsburg,_Pennsylvania" />
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2021" to="2029" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Mapping digital competence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kirsti</forename><surname>Ala-Mutka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2011</date>
			<publisher>Towards a conceptual</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Library Association</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.codementor.io" />
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>BY arc(</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>n.d.. n.d.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Digital Literacy</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Additional labors of the entrepreneurial self</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><surname>Avle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Silvia</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tawanna</forename><surname>Lindtner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Dillahunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Evaluation of Response to Intervention Practices for Elementary School Reading. NCEE 2016-4000</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pei</forename><surname>Balu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fred</forename><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ellen</forename><surname>Doolittle</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joseph</forename><surname>Schiller</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Russell</forename><surname>Jenkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gersten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fran</forename><surname>Baum</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Macdougall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danielle</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Participatory action Journal of epidemiology and community health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">854</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006. 2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">COVID-19 and digital inequalities: Reciprocal impacts and mitigation strategies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elisabeth</forename><surname>Beaunoyer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sophie</forename><surname>Dupéré</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthieu</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Guitton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">in human behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">111</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">106424</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pair programming: what&apos;s in it for me</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Begel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nachiappan</forename><surname>Nagappan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Second ACM-IEEE international symposium on Empirical software engineering and measurement</title>
				<meeting>the Second ACM-IEEE international symposium on Empirical software engineering and measurement</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="120" to="128" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Public library funding and technology access survey: Survey and results</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">Carlo</forename><surname>Bertot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abigail</forename><surname>Mcdermott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ruth</forename><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
			<publisher>Information Policy and Access Center</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Brian Real; College Park, MD</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding work, learning and the remaking of cultural practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Billett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Raymond</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michelle</forename><surname>Barker</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Studies in continuing education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="219" to="237" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The 2 sigma problem: The search for methods of group instruction as effective as one-to-one tutoring</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bloom</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Educational researcher</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="4" to="16" />
			<date type="published" when="1984">1984. 1984</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Disempowered by data: its, social enterprises, and the consequences of data-driven work</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Chris</forename><surname>Bopp</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ellie</forename><surname>Harmon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Voida</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2017 CHI conference on human factors in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 CHI conference on human factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3608" to="3619" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The value of human and social capital investments for the business performance of startups</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Niels</forename><surname>Bosma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mirjam</forename><surname>Van Praag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Thurik</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gerrit</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Wit</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Business Economics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="227" to="236" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Verizon</forename><surname>Buisiness</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>n.d.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Verizon Business Survey Finds 68 of Small Businesses Believe They Can Recoup COVID-19 Related Losses</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.globenewswire.com/news" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s">Small-Businesses-Believe-They-Can-Recoup-COVID-19-Related-Losses.html</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Critical connections: The importance of community-based and social capital to credit access for low-wealth entrepreneurs</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Colleen</forename><surname>Casey</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Urban Affairs Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">50</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="366" to="390" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Grounded theory. Blackwell encyclopedia of sociology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">Liska</forename><surname>Charmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Belgrave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supporting remote real-time expert help: Opportunities and challenges for novice 3d modelers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nathaniel</forename><surname>Parmit K Chilana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Srinjita</forename><surname>Hudson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Prashant</forename><surname>Bhaduri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kane</forename><surname>Shashikumar</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2018 IEEE Symposium on Visual Languages and Human-Centric Computing</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="157" to="166" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A field study of crowdsourced contextual help: usage and perspectives of end users and software teams</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Chilana</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Andrew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Ko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tovi</forename><surname>Wobbrock</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="226" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Assisting students struggling with reading: to intervention (RtI) and multi-tier intervention in the primary grades</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>What Works Clearinghouse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2009">2009</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Washington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">The Institute of Education Sciences (IES)</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Using verbatim quotations in reporting qualitative social research: researchers&apos; views</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roy</forename><surname>Corden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sainsbury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<pubPlace>University of York York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The role of entrepreneurship in US job creation and economic dynamism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Decker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Haltiwanger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ron</forename><surname>Jarmin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Javier</forename><surname>Miranda</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Economic Perspectives</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Entrepreneurship and the socio-technical chasm in a lean economy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vaishnav</forename><surname>Tawanna R Dillahunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Desiree</forename><surname>Kameswaran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Minnie</forename><surname>Mclain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lester</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Orr</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Toyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A model for implementing responsiveness intervention</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Lynn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Fuchs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fuchs</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Teaching exceptional children</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="14" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The vocabulary problem in human-system communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Furnas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Landauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Louis</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Gomez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susan</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Dumais</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="964" to="971" />
			<date type="published" when="1987">1987. 1987</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Trust: Making and breaking cooperative relations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gambetta</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1988">1988. 1988</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Gardeners and gurus: patterns of cooperation among CAD users</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michelle</forename><surname>Gantt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bonnie</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Nardi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on Human in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI conference on Human in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992">1992</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="107" to="117" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Morteza</forename><surname>Ghobakhloo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniel</forename><surname>Arias-Aranda</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jose</forename><surname>Benitez-Amado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Adopof e-commerce applications in SMEs. Industrial Management &amp; Data Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Behind the help desk: evolution of a knowledge management system in a large organization</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Christine</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Halverson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Erickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Ackerman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2004 ACM conference on Computer supported cooperative work</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="304" to="313" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Pair programming in education: A literature review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Hanks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sue</forename><surname>Fitzgerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Renée</forename><surname>Mccauley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laurie</forename><surname>Murphy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Carol</forename><surname>Zander</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Science Education</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">21</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="135" to="173" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Deconstructing community-based collaborative design: Towards more equitable participatory design engagements</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Harrington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sheena</forename><surname>Erete</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">Marie</forename><surname>Piper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction CSCW</title>
				<meeting>the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction CSCW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Engaging Low-Income African American Older Adults in Health Discussions through Community-based Design Workshops</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katya</forename><surname>Christina N Harrington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">Marie</forename><surname>Borgos-Rodriguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Piper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>ACM</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">593</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The power of feedback</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hattie</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Timperley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">77</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="112" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The relationship of action research to human-computer interaction</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Gillian</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hayes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Transactions on Computer-Human Interaction (TOCHI)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="20" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Too much too soon?: Early learning and the erosion of childhood</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Richard</forename><surname>House</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<publisher>Hawthorn Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community Low-tech social support for digitally-engaged entrepreneurship</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Nefer Ra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wendy</forename><surname>Barber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Suzanne</forename><surname>Casey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cleage</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Danny</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Frances</forename><forename type="middle">Kentaro</forename><surname>Dolley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tawanna</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Toyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Dillahunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making a living my way: Necessity-driven entrepreneurship in resource-constrained communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><surname>Hui</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Toyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction CSCW</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Joyojeet Pal, and Tawanna Dillahunt</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kenan</forename><surname>Institute</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://kenaninstitute.unc.edu/kenan-insight/business-incubators-if-you-build-it-will-entrepreneurs-succeed/" />
		<title level="m">incubators if you build will entrepreneurs succeed</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">From response to intervention to multi-tiered systems of support: Advances in the science and practice of assessment and intervention</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Jimerson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Matthew</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Burns</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Vanderheyden</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of response to intervention</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="6" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Micromentor: Peer-to-peer software help sessions in three minutes or less</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nikhita</forename><surname>Joshi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Justin</forename><surname>Matejka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fraser</forename><surname>Anderson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tovi</forename><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">George</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Six learning barriers in end-user programming systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Ko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Brad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Htet Htet</forename><surname>Myers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Aung</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">2004 IEEE Symposium on Visual Languages-Human Centric Computing</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="199" to="206" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">and the transformation of white-collar work</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Robert</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kraut</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1987">1987</date>
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Balanced skills and entrepreneurship</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Edward</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lazear</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American Economic Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">94</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="208" to="211" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Strangers at the gate: Gaining access, building rapport, and co-constructing community-based research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Le</forename><surname>Christopher</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><surname>Dantec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 18th ACM conference on computer supported cooperative work &amp; computing</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1348" to="1358" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Discriminant analysis of technology adoption behavior: a of internet technologies in small businesses</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jungwoo</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">of computer information systems</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="66" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Embracing Four Tensions in Human-Computer Interaction Research with Marginalized People</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Calvin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sean</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Liang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Munson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kientz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Transactions on Computer-Human Interaction (TOCHI)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="47" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Patterns of sharing customizable software</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Wendy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mackay</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 1990 ACM conference on Computer-supported cooperative work</title>
				<meeting>the 1990 ACM conference on Computer-supported cooperative work</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="221" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Person-entrepreneurship fit: why some people are more successful as entrepreneurs than others. resource management review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gideon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Robert A</forename><surname>Markman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Baron</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003. 2003</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="281" to="301" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Human capital and research: A critical review and future directions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Marvel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Justin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Curtis</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Davis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sproul</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ship Theory and Practice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">40</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="599" to="626" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016. 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">American apartheid: Segregation and the making of the underclass</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Douglas</forename><surname>Massey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nancy</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Denton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
			<publisher>Harvard university press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">IP-QAT: in-product questions, answers, &amp; tips</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tovi</forename><surname>Matejka</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Grossman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fitzmaurice</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 24th annual ACM symposium on User interface software and technology</title>
				<meeting>the 24th annual ACM symposium on User interface software and technology</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="184" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Stanford Social Innovation Review Matthew Guttentag</title>
		<ptr target="https://ssir.org/articles/entry/six_ways_to_support_small_and_growing_" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Six Ways to Support Small and Growing Businesses in Emerging Markets</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>n.d.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mckinsey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>n.d.</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How COVID-19 has pushed companies over the technology tipping point and transformed business forever. technology-tipping-point-and-transformed-business-forever</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">College affiliated small business development centers: A case study of the Southwestern Pennsylvania Business Development Center</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Meeder</forename><surname>Robert Alan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Pittsburgh</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Do small businesses create jobs? New evidence for the United States from the National Establishment Time Series</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Neumark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brandon</forename><surname>Wall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Junfu</forename><surname>Zhang</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Review of Economics and Statistics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">93</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="16" to="29" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Toward a more view of when and how people seek help with computer applications</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Novick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Edith</forename><surname>Elizalde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nathaniel</forename><surname>Bean</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 25th annual ACM international conference on Design</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="102" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>University</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Support</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.oecd.org/education/imhe/46588578.pdf" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ISSUES, GOOD PRACTICES AND RECOMMENDATIONS</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards an effective digital literacy intervention to assist returning citizens with job search</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kentaro</forename><surname>Ihudiya Finda Ogbonnaya-Ogburu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tawanna</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Toyama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Dillahunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI conference on Human factors in systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI conference on Human factors in systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Attenuated Access: Accounting for Startup, Maintenance, and Affective Costs in Resource-Constrained Communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pei</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roderic</forename><surname>Crooks</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Making a&quot; Pro&quot;:&apos;professionalism&apos;after platforms in beauty-work</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joyojeet</forename><surname>Raval</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Pal</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction CSCW</title>
				<meeting>the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction CSCW</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Robinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hiroshi</forename><surname>Shelia R Cotten</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anabel</forename><surname>Ono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gustavo</forename><surname>Quan-Haase</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wenhong</forename><surname>Mesch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeremy</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Timothy</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Schulz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael J</forename><surname>Hale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Stern</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Digital inequalities and why they matter. communication &amp; society</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="569" to="582" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intersectional Engaging identity through gender, race, and class</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Keith</forename><surname>Schlesinger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Grinter</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 conference on human factors in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 conference on human factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="5412" to="5427" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Open source technical support: A look at peer help-giving</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Singh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dinesh</forename><surname>Twidale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rathi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 39th Annual Hawaii Conference on System Sciences (HICSS&apos;06)</title>
				<meeting>the 39th Annual Hawaii Conference on System Sciences (HICSS&apos;06)</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="118" to="118" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Kim M Thompson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Natalie</forename><forename type="middle">Greene</forename><surname>Jaeger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mega</forename><surname>Taylor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><forename type="middle">Carlo</forename><surname>Subramaniam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Bertot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Digital literacy and digital inclusion: Information policy and the public library</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Rowman &amp; Littlefield</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">gets to future? Race, representation, and design methods in Africatown</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">O'</forename><surname>Tran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Leary</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jennifer</forename><surname>Zewde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Daniela</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Mankoff</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rosner</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Over the shoulder learning: supporting brief informal learning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Michael</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Twidale</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer supported cooperative work</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="505" to="547" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Internet skills and the digital divide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><surname>Van Deursen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jan</forename><surname>Van Dijk</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New media &amp; society</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="893" to="911" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011. 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Freedom to personalize my digital classroom: Understanding teachers&apos; practices and motivations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joanna</forename><surname>Vermette</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Colin</forename><surname>Mcgrenere</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Birge</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Parmit K</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Chilana</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The psychology of computer programming</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Gerald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Weinberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1971">1971</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Van Nostrand Reinhold New York</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The effects of domain knowledge on search tactic formulation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Barbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Wildemuth</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the american society for information science and technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="246" to="258" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004. 2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond necessity-driven versus opportunity-driven entrepreneurship: a study of informal entrepreneurs in England</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Colin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Williams</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Russia and International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Innovation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="157" to="165" />
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008. 2008</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Infrastructural Speculations: Tactics for Designing and ing Lifeworlds</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Richmond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vera</forename><surname>Wong</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sarah</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Khovanskaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Fox</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Phoebe</forename><surname>Merrill</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sengers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
