<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Six Facets of Facilitation: Participatory Design Facilitators&apos; Perspectives on Their Role and Its Realization</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Yngve</forename><surname>Dahl</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Norwegian University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kshitij</forename><surname>Sharma</surname></persName>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="department">Department of Computer Science</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Norwegian University of Science and Technology</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Six Facets of Facilitation: Participatory Design Facilitators&apos; Perspectives on Their Role and Its Realization</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3502013</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:04+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Participation</term>
					<term>facilitation</term>
					<term>reflection</term>
					<term>role</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Participatory design facilitators have a significant impact on participatory activities, processes, and outcomes. However, the facilitator role has not yet been thoroughly debated in existing design discourse, and support for role-related reflections is limited. As the first steps towards an enriched collective understanding of this specific role and its realization, we interviewed 14 respondents with an academic background in participatory design and extensive facilitation experience. Based on a content analysis of the interviews, we identified six facets of the role: (1) trust builder, (2) enabler, (3) inquirer, (4) direction setter, (5) value provider, and (6) users' advocate. Each facet is presented as consisting of the respondents' perceived associated responsibilities and corresponding strategies. Our results paint a complex picture of participatory design facilitation. We propose the multi-faceted understanding of the facilitator role emerging from this work as a basis for problematized reflection on the role and its realization.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Human-centered computing → Interaction design; Participatory design.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>of facilitated design activities. In PD literature (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b32">32,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">35]</ref>), the person leading such activities is typically referred to as the facilitator.</p><p>In the context of PD and its principal values of participation, inclusion, equality and sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[33]</ref>, the responsibilities of the facilitator arguably extend far beyond that of a moderator of a group discussion. The facilitator can also be considered as playing an important part in the realization of PD's egalitarian values through participatory activities <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24]</ref>. Despite such obligations, the role of the facilitator in turning PD principles into practice has so far only been sporadically addressed in interaction design literature, indicating that facilitation as a practice is yet to be recognized as a key methodological challenge in PD and HCI discourse. The tendency to trivialize PD facilitation by turning it into an analytic "black box" <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[34]</ref> can be considered a potential threat to the integrity of the method, as a failure to turn principles into practice, in the long-term risks diluting PD as a democratic and empowering design approach <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p><p>Based on the understanding that the facilitator is one of several influential "forces" in the shaping of PD results, this paper seeks to answer the following research question: How do experienced PD facilitators understand the facilitator role, and how are their role interpretations reflected in strategies guiding their practice?</p><p>The term role, in this context, refers to the function or responsibility assumed by the person acting as the facilitator in PD activities and processes. Strategy describes a coherent approach by which the facilitator attempts to fulfill the role and that guides their facilitation practice, including, for example, choice of methods and techniques.</p><p>Earlier work <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">34]</ref> has described PD facilitation as closely dependent on the facilitator's skills and pointed to the practitioner's experiences from practice as an important source for reflection and professional development. While existing studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[27,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b35">35]</ref> have argued that reflections on personal practice are central in the context of PD, we see a rich, and yet untapped, potential in drawing on the collective understandings and reflections of the existing community of facilitators when it comes to informing PD facilitation practice.</p><p>To provide an answer to the research question presented above, we therefore conducted a qualitative investigation based on semi-structured interviews with PD researchers with significant facilitation experience from PD projects. Analyzing the data collected from 14 interview respondents, our investigation draws particular attention to the multiple sub-roles, or facets, of the facilitator's role and the associated rationalized strategies that guide the respondents' facilitation practice.</p><p>Through this paper, we seek to provide an empirically based understanding of the facilitator role and thereby contribute to increasing the awareness of the multifaceted aspects of PD facilitation and strategies that may help fulfill associated responsibilities. We see the identified role facets as potentially valuable reflection points in facilitators' reflective activities.</p><p>The structure of the paper is as follows. We continue in Sect. 2 by providing a brief account of key principles that define PD and a review of relevant work, which in various ways has drawn attention to the challenges of turning principles into PD facilitation practice. We also explain the current paper's contribution to the existing body of related studies. Next, in Sect. 3, we describe the methods used to collect and analyze data for this study. Sect. 4 presents an in-depth account of the results from the analysis, before we discuss key implications of the findings in Sect 5. Following a brief description of key methodological considerations in Sect. 6, we end the paper by providing a summary of the presented work and some concluding remarks in Sect. 7.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED WORK 2.1 Principles of Participatory Design</head><p>Originating in the political struggle of labor movements in Scandinavia during the 1970s and 1980s, PD was based on a democratic commitment to ensure that workers would have a say in the design of new information technology in their workplaces <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b28">28]</ref>. Since its origin, the application areas of PD have expanded considerably, extending well beyond that of workplace democracy (e.g., <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b8">9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b11">12,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">21,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23]</ref>). Similarly, contemporary ideas of democracy in today's global world are also different from democratic thinking at the time when PD was formed <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>.</p><p>An elaborate account of what defines PD today is beyond the scope of this paper. Instead, we rely on the six enduring principles described by Kensing and Greenbaum <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref> to sum up key PD characteristics. The principle of democratic practices embodies PD's commitment to actively involve people who may be affected by a new design solution in the design process. Equalizing power relations reflects PD's obligation to find ways to give voice in design processes to those that may be disadvantaged due to, for example, organizational power structures, social status, or other asymmetries. Situation-based actions refer to working directly with people in the actual home or work setting, which is being design for, as opposed to working with abstract representations of the setting and actions carried out. The principle of mutual learning refers to co-creating knowledge and the learning that can take place between individual participants and between participants and technology developers. PD is also defined by tools and techniques that are aimed at supporting participants' active engagement in design activities and processes. Finally, alternative visions about technology are the new ideas and concepts that are produced through PD processes and that often challenge existing technological solutions and/or organizational practices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Related Work Problematizing the Role of the Participatory Design Facilitator</head><p>Given PD's commitment to democratic practices, the PD facilitator can be regarded as a practitioner who ideally is concerned with turning PD philosophy into practice <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b14">15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18]</ref>, that is, realizing the guiding principles described above. Such a perspective implicates that facilitation thinking and practice can have a large impact on participation and the participatory result. Despite its potential impact, the role of the facilitator in the realization of PD has to a large extent been neglected in PD-related literature, albeit with noteworthy exceptions. Below, we provide a brief review of what we consider to be the most relevant research literature when it comes to problematizing the role.</p><p>The motivation for the study presented in this paper can, in many ways, be traced back to Suchman's <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[31]</ref> critique of the "design from nowhere" stance in which the designer is seen as an objective, anonymous part in the design process, that is, one who converts collected knowledge about a domain and its users into design solutions that meet the requirements without affecting the process or the output. Offering an alternative stance-one in which designers are held accountable, such as to "design from somewhere"-Suchman argued that designers need to acknowledge how their visions, previous experiences, interpretations, the context in which design occurs, etc. influence the design process and how knowledge gathered throughout the process is always incomplete and situated.</p><p>More recent studies focusing on the role of the facilitator of participatory activities have often been motivated by the situated perspective on design practices similar to that of Suchman <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[31]</ref>. Discussing the situatedness often characterizing PD activities, Wakeford and Pimbert <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[34]</ref> used the French notion of bricolage to describe how facilitators, similar to handypersons, often rely on large elements of improvisations based on available resources as part of their practice. With reference to the capability to utilize (in addition to available materials) acquired skills and tacit knowledge to get tasks done, Wakeford and Pimbert (ibid.) aptly used the notion of an intellectual bricoleur to characterize the PD facilitator. Studying the relevance of practice-acquired facilitation skills, Luck <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref> found that experienced facilitators tended to provide more opportunities for user engagement though their spoken interactions compared with less experienced facilitators.</p><p>Studying the micro-dynamics of participation in facilitated activities, Light and Akama <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref> brought attention to the ways in which facilitation style, scoping, structure, and control can affect participation as well as how facilitation practice needs to be considered in terms of the context in which it takes place. Highlighting the agency of the facilitator, the authors (ibid.) regarded PD methods to be enacted (as opposed to implemented) by the facilitator. From a similar perspective the PD facilitator can be considered a role to be played rather than a function to be executed.</p><p>While the aforementioned studies such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">34]</ref>, have drawn attention to the situatedness often characterizing participatory activities and which facilitators are faced with, other relevant studies have brought attention to the quality of facilitatorparticipant relations and its effect on participation and the participatory result. In particular, studies such as <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b12">13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b22">23]</ref> have emphasized the benefit of developing close relations among those taking part in a participatory process in order to equalize power relations. Other studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b13">14]</ref> have called attention to design contexts where direct, active engagement of participants may be challenging due to, for example, severe disability or disorders, and where the facilitator needs to make certain compromises when it comes to methods of user involvement.</p><p>Recent studies have also emphasized the potential benefits associated with practice-based reflections in the context of PD facilitation. <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref> discussed the often subtle and unanticipated ways in which the actions of a facilitator (and sometimes the lack of action) can affect participatory activities and the values that are embedded in design solutions. Inspired by Schön's <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref> reflectionon-action theory, the authors suggested that introspective analyses of, and reflections on, critical moments in recordings from facilitated PD activities may improve the facilitator's attentiveness to actions that may inadvertently reduce disfavored participants' possibilities for influence vis-à-vis other more empowered partakers. Relevant research has also underlined the need for co-reflective activities among facilitators. For example, Zahlsen et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[35]</ref> investigated the role, practice, and process perspectives of three project affiliates working together to facilitate participatory activities as part of a large-scale health IT project. One central finding was that the three interviewees reflected perspectives on facilitation pertaining to different system development traditions. Based on the findings, the authors proposed co-reflective activities for facilitators centered on the concepts of role, practice, and participatory process, to foster a conscious awareness of one's facilitation thinking and practice.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Dahl and Svanaes</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Positioning the Current Study</head><p>While the studies described above put the facilitator at the center of PD and its realization, an extensive study of how experienced PD facilitators conceptualize their role has, to the best of the authors' knowledge, not yet been conducted. Although facilitators' role perceptions were also addressed in <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[35]</ref>, the respective study did not involve respondents with an academic background in PD. In contrast to the aforementioned study, the investigation described in this paper is generic in the sense that it does not focus on role perception in a specific project, but rather on perspectives on the facilitator role emerging over a longer time span and across several PD projects.</p><p>In particular, we consider our study to complement the more case-specific and observation-of-practice-based studies cited above (i.e., <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b23">24]</ref>). These studies have helped shed light on how the PD facilitator and their enactment PD methods significantly affect the form, degree, and result of user participation, indicating the benefits of a reflective attitude toward one's role and practice. By offering an enriched collective understanding of the facilitator role, we aim to contribute to further to the existing body of knowledge on PD facilitation. Such an understanding, we would argue, can provide concrete reference points supporting reflective activities among facilitators, and thus help to "scaffold" reflection [30], albeit with a focus on supporting the PD facilitator.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHODS</head><p>To develop an in-depth empirical understanding of the perceptions of the facilitator role and its realization, we conducted a qualitative study consisting of semi-structured interviews with experienced PD facilitators. While the practice of PD facilitation can be studied objectively by means of third-person observations, as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>, the main goal of the current study is to unpack facilitation thinking, that is, how facilitators conceptualize the facilitator role. Such aspects cannot be studied objectively and demand instead an approach that addresses relevant phenomena from the subjective first-person point of view.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Respondents and Recruitment</head><p>A sample of 14 respondents with a background as PD researchers and facilitators in PD projects was recruited for the study through purposive sampling <ref type="bibr">[26, p. 98]</ref>. Given the focus of the study and to increase the prospect of recruiting participants with a reflective attitude toward facilitation, we decided to include only individuals holding a relevant doctoral degree and with scientific publications describing results from personally facilitated PD activities. The recruitment strategy involved contacting and inviting PD researchers both from the authors' personal network as well as authors of PDrelated scientific publications describing facilitated activities and their outcomes.</p><p>The respondent population consisted of three professors, six associate professors, four assistant professors and one senior researcher, representing a total of nine European universities in six different countries. The age of the respondents ranged from 38 to 62 years old (M = 46.42; SD = 7.14). Nine respondents described themselves as male, while five described themselves as female. The respondent population's facilitation experiences were derived from PD projects involving a wide variety of user groups including, for example, employees in public services, children with special needs, youths in education, older adults living in care facilities, people with lifestyle-associated medical conditions, and persons with cognitive impairments. To maintain respondent anonymity, we have not given specific background information for each respondent. For similar reasons, references to the gender of the respondents have been removed and replaced with gender-neutral terms throughout the paper.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Interview Guide</head><p>To support the interview process, an interview guide containing thematic areas and related questions was developed (Appendix 1). The thematic areas and questions were inspired in part by the research question as well as topics discussed in relevant work, which we identified when going through the literature reviewed in Sect. 2.2. In addition to an introductory section, the final interview guide contained the following five thematic areas: <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref> The role of the facilitator, (2) Reflection on facilitation practice, (3) Ethics and values, (4) User involvement, and (5) Evaluation of the output from facilitated PD activities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Data Collection and Analysis</head><p>The interviews were conducted from November 2020 to May 2021. The main question asked was how the respondents understood the facilitator role. While all the thematic areas in the interview guide were addressed in each interview, the questions pertaining to the different areas were typically asked only in cases where the interviewer found it necessary to trigger further reflection on a given topic.</p><p>The authors conducted seven interviews each. Each interview lasted from 50 to 75 min (M = 60 min; SD = 10 min) and was conducted one-on-one using Zoom videotelephony. All interviews were digitally recorded. The audio recordings from the interviews were automatically transcribed using Microsoft Word 365 with subsequent manual quality checking and corrections.</p><p>The transcribed interviews were then content analyzed following a three-step process. First, the two authors repeatedly examined the transcriptions from the seven interviews they each had conducted in search of statements or quotes describing either respondents' perceptions of the facilitator role, associated responsibilities, or strategies employed to fulfill the role. Relevant quotes were then marked with one or more matching labels or codes (i.e., "Role," "Responsibility, " and "Strategy") and combined selected words from the quote that captured the meaning as interpreted by the analyst (e.g., "Role: Making participants feel comfortable").</p><p>The second step of the analysis involved a qualitative content analysis of the labeled quotes resulting from the (rough) categorization performed in the first step. This involved further coding the inferred meaning of the quotes, that is, adding fitting labels (codes) indicating, for example, the type of role (i.e., role facet), responsibility, and strategy talked about in a quote as well as expressed challenges a given respondent associated with either of the above (e.g., "Role facet: Trust builder"; "Responsibility: Ensure open exchange of ideas and perspectives"; "Strategy: Spend time with participants outside facilitated activities").</p><p>In the third and most comprehensive step of the analysis, the authors examined each other's coding before reviewing together all the coded interview transcripts for consistency. The consistency check was performed iteratively several times and focused on identifying and merging similar phenomena of interest (i.e., role, responsibility, and strategies) across the transcripts and finding suitable and coherent labels (codes) to describe these. Inter-rater reliability was not calculated because our coding of semi-structured interview data meant that the same code was sometimes applied to different parts of the transcripts. Based on the third and final step of the analysis, we identified a set of role facets with associated responsibilities and strategies further described in the next section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">RESULTS</head><p>All respondents considered the role of the PD facilitator to be strongly associated with the responsibility of ensuring that PD activities and processes are in accordance with the principal values of PD. For example, one of the respondents stated:</p><p>"One could say that one essential part of the role is precisely to ensure that one lives up to the values [of PD]. " (Quote 1, Respondent 11)</p><p>While the facilitator's overall role was primarily associated with the responsibility of turning PD philosophy into practice according to the respondents, the analysis revealed far more nuanced perspectives. A total of six role facets, which serve as metaphors that describe aspects of the facilitator role, were identified. The six identified facets were based on understandings of the facilitator as: (1) trust builder, (2) enabler (3), inquirer, (4) direction setter, (5) value provider, and (6) users' advocate. Each facet corresponded to a set of related responsibilities and strategies for fulfilling the respective responsibilities of that facet. Below, an elaboration of each facet, including associated responsibilities and strategies, as reported by the respondents, is provided. In doing so, we present key quotes from the transcribed interviews and our interpretation of these (reflecting our coding process). By conveying the voice of the respondents, in the form of quotes, we aim to reduce our own (the researcher's') voices as interpreters.</p><p>Each quote has been marked with a unique identifier to make the quote referable in the text (e.g., "Quote 1") and a reference to the respondent stating the quote (e.g., "Respondent 11"). We also present some of the respondents' reflections on perceived challenges associated with fulfilling the responsibilities of different facets.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">The Facilitator as Trust Builder</head><p>4.1.1 Building trust. Motivating the active engagement of participants in design activities was regarded a central facilitator concern among the respondents and considered to be fundamental for a successful PD process. As illustrated in several of the following quotes, encouraging the active participation often involves establishing a sense of trust between facilitator and the participants.</p><p>"The role of the facilitator is to make sure that you set the ambience first and make sure everybody feels welcome." (Quote 2, Respondent 5)</p><p>In particular, making participants feel comfortable about openly sharing and discussing perspectives with other partakers was seen as essential for the participatory process. According to respondents, an important aspect of encouraging active engagement is to help participants understand the motivation for why they are invited to take part in the design process, and to reassure the participants about the value their ideas and perspectives may add in such a regard: "[The] facilitator's role is to encourage people to get them over this first threshold where people are always telling me [the facilitator] 'I'm not creative' and 'I don't have the expertise,' but to reassure them that it is their expertise that matters, and it is their choice how to tell the story . . . " (Quote 3, Respondent 6)</p><p>In both the above quotes, the facilitator is regarded as someone who sets the stage for the open exchange of ideas and perspectives, that is, a trust builder, who reassures participants about the value of their participation. The following statement highlights the potential benefits of conducting this type of preparation work in the context of PD:</p><p>"I think the sense of creating a holding space, in which there is like a free and safe environment, where you can explore and dare to go further than you would do normally. I think that's a very important part of the whole process. " (Quote 4, Respondent 9)</p><p>The above statement suggests that the quality and richness of insights emerging from PD activities are closely dependent on the establishment of a safe "holding space, " in which open exchange of perspectives and discussions can occur. Establishing such a space, or "ambience" (Quote 2), is regarded as a precondition for the facilitator to thoroughly explore and understand ideas and perspectives emerging as part of discussions.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">Trust builder Strategies.</head><p>In respect to the respondents' reported strategies for preparing the participatory process, a recurring theme in the accounts was the time they often invested in interacting with participants outside of design activities in order to establish and develop facilitator-participant relations: ". . . but I think that one of the critical things is just building up an empathetic relationship with the people that you are working with. Like building up some sort of human relationship with them, and not just a professional relationship, is really important . . . like taking the time to sit down and drink a cup of tea with them and chat with them about how things are going in general. That makes a design session that follows work far simpler and in a more straightforward way; makes them more comfortable to correct you when you're wrong; makes it easier for you to ask them more challenging questions and to try to dig beneath the answers they make. " (Quote 5, <ref type="bibr">Respondent 7)</ref> Similar to what was expressed in Quote 4, Respondent 7 (Quote 5) also regards the quality of the facilitator-participant relationship as greatly affecting the quality and richness of the emerging insights. Specifically, Respondent 7 argues that the development of an empathic relationship is central for the participants to speak openly and for the facilitator to go into potentially sensitive areas ("ask them more challenging questions. . ."). Such relationships are also important for being able to form an understanding of the underlying motivation behind expressed viewpoints ("dig beneath the answers. . .") later in the design process (this aspect is further elaborated in Sect 4.3, Facilitator as Inquirer).</p><p>Establishing an empathic relationship with participants could, in some cases and particularly when dealing with marginalized user groups, mean investing a considerable amount of time together with possible participants in their home environment. Describing the trust builder strategies applied in an earlier PD project, one of the respondents stated:</p><p>"I spent three or four months doing field work in a care center, sitting there on a daily basis eating lunch with elderly [participants], talking to the staff, observing, being present, becoming familiar with them and confident with them. They became confident with me. I got an idea about who they were, and they got an idea about who I was. " (Quote 6, Respondent 2)</p><p>Through the interviews, we also learned how the lack of possibilities to build relations with participants and understandings of their situation prior to facilitated PD activities could create challenges. Referring to experiences from a workshop focusing on the design of lifestyle management technology for children with a specific medical condition, one respondent described the dilemma the facilitators were faced with not knowing the extent to which the children recruited as workshop participants were aware of their health situation:</p><p>"We didn't really know if the children were aware of their health situation . . . and that was a challenge. We hadn't recruited the children ourselves. We had some [healthcare] employees recruit them. And therefore, we didn't have the dialog with the parents. So, when we came [to the workshop], we had prepared a good plan, and thought that it was feasible. But that small factor, which was about us not knowing how reflective the children were of their own situation made it a little bit challenging for us because we had to weigh our questions: 'Can we talk about [their condition] directly or shouldn't we? How do we talk about [relevant issues]?"' (Quote 7, Respondent 1)</p><p>In addition to spending time developing empathic relations with participants, respondents also emphasized the need to be mindful about how participants may perceive the facilitator in the initial stages of the PD process. Describing how they, as facilitators, present themselves to participants, one respondent stated:</p><p>"The way we present ourselves and act is important. I don't show up in a shirt and suit if I'm facilitating a workshop. I dress informal and small talk [with participants] to make the situation safe. It is really about making people feel safe. " (Quote 8, Respondent 1)</p><p>Statements such as the above show a mindful caution against interacting with participants in ways that risk reinforcing potential asymmetries between the facilitator and the participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">The Facilitator as Enabler</head><p>4.2.1 Enabling Active Involvement. The second aspect that emerged as central in respondents' understanding of the facilitator role was the perceived responsibility to help participants in PD activities voice their ideas, needs and perspectives. The following quotes illustrate this point:</p><p>"I think my role would be to facilitate end users to express their needs and their values and their beliefs. " (Quote 9, Respondent 13) "[The role is about] getting the voice of the minority in the room to be heard and to be valued. " (Quote 10, Respondent 9)</p><p>Essentially, these statements offer an understanding of the facilitator as an enabler: a person who provides the concrete means and possibilities for participants to express their ideas, needs and perspectives (thus complementing the trust builder strategies, which primarily focus on setting the stage for open and honest exchange of ideas and perspectives).</p><p>As expressed in Quote 9, enabling potential disadvantaged parties to voice their viewpoints was considered especially important in the context of PD.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Enabler Strategies.</head><p>In terms of strategies for enabling active involvement, we identified three overall approaches: use of common language, sensitizing and discourse management. In the following, each of the three strategies will be explained.</p><p>The first enabler strategy involves the establishment and use of a "common language", or shared tool for expression, to help participants communicate across different life-worlds, various professional backgrounds, cultural and language barriers, etc. and thereby offer all participants the possibility to express themselves and to be understood. One respondent gave the following reflection on the significance of finding a common language when facilitating PD activities for children with special needs and their parents:</p><p>"You have to find that common language. First of all, you have to clarify and define all the terms which are not clear and ask them if they understand or not. I remember when we tried to define 'prototype' for the children [...] And also, we try to find images, <ref type="bibr">[and]</ref> some examples of prototypes to help them understand better what we are talking about. When we have a mixture of people, we try to use a kind of language which everyone can understand, so that we don't embarrass them. That's very important." (Quote 11, <ref type="bibr">Respondent 12)</ref> As we can see from the above statement, identifying a suitable common language generally means adapting to disfavored partakers, for example, by using illustrations or images instead of written text or domain specific jargon. Several respondents also reported taking measures to verify that a proposed common language was comprehensible for all participants before continuing an activity.</p><p>Another strategy variant aimed at ensuring that participants share the same language, and which respondents reported using, was to separate participants into language-sharing groups, for example, keeping clinicians in one groups and patients in another.</p><p>The following quote reflects one of the respondent's perspectives on the matter: "I would not run sessions with clinicians and patients in the session early on in the design process. I just think that there are certain gaps that are too great to cross [. . .] It's honestly a matter of being careful about who you bring in. Keeping them separate is really important. " (Quote 12, Respondent 7)</p><p>The second enabler strategy respondents reported using involves giving the participants time to understand the design challenge and make preparations prior to the facilitated activity taking place: ". . . you give them a workbook with some homework which has the purpose of sensitizing them to the topic but also loading them with things to bring to the table and thereby promoting them to take the role of expert rather than the role of submissive interviewee." (Quote 13, Respondent 6)</p><p>Sensitizing partakers can be consider a means to effectively "jump-start" exchange of ideas and viewpoints in a facilitated PD activity. However, the primary means for facilitating such an endeavor, as pointed out by the respondents, would be to engage participants in the PD activity ("promoting them to take the role of expert") by allowing them to share aspect of their "life-words" with other participants.</p><p>The third enabler strategy that emerged through the interviews was discursion management, such as ways of ensuring that all partakers are given the opportunity to speak their minds on central design issues, for example, by controlling turn-taking in discussions.</p><p>Several respondents described having developed preferences toward certain methods and techniques intended to help participants engage in design issues. The same respondents emphasized that there is no "one size fits all" when it comes to selecting methods and that a method's usefulness typically is relative to the specific participant. Therefore, the enabler role also implies being attentive towards the effectiveness of the methods being applied, potentially changing if the situation calls for it:</p><p>"You have to be flexible. You have to be able to let go of your plan and just say, 'OK, this doesn't work. I have to come up with something else. How can I facilitate this individual person?' . . . And it also has to do with listening, because you really have to be very sensitive to any signal you might get from your user that it's not working, or that they're not comfortable, or that you ask things from them that they cannot do or don't want to do. " (Quote 14, <ref type="bibr">Respondent 13)</ref> What we observe from this statement is the responsibility of the facilitator as an enabler to pay close attention to each individual partaker. Close monitoring becomes important when there is a need to intuitively alter the pre-defined methods to make sure that all the partakers can contribute. The situations calling for intuitive flexibility might not be known a priori, and therefore the facilitators' sensitivity to social cues also becomes a key factor for them fulfilling the role as an enabler.</p><p>While respondents emphasized the need to apply methods that could be effectively used by the participants in, others focused more on the product of the employed methods:</p><p>"I know there are a lot of techniques that rely on people building things with their hands and showing things to one another because they get more active engagement. And I do agree. They do work, but there that's a superficial level of engagement, whereas what you really want is people thinking about and listening to each other's concepts and ideas and back and forth thing . . . I don't want to disparage them [the techniques] . . . They're about the quality of the conversation that you're having, and a lot of the design material that you see in a lot of the research that you see kind of tries to dress up the fact that PD is about having very authentic discussions with people because that is hard to write in a paper." (Quote 15, <ref type="bibr">Respondent 7)</ref> We can see from Respondents 7's argument in favor of the outcome of the PD session ("quality of conversation") that it is not only engagement of partakers, in terms of putting across their ideas and viewpoints, that should be catered to. Part of facilitators' responsibility as an enabler is also about providing the partakers with a platform for a deeper discussion about the design ideas, values and needs. "For me, it [a PD activity] is a research activity to get to know the needs and wants of my end users even better . . . and it happens very often that the ideas that come forward in participatory design sessions, they usually do not end up in the final product one on one. It's just a way for us to understand even better what should be in the product and how we could serve the end user. " (Quote 16, Respondent 13)</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">The Facilitator as Inquirer</head><p>In the statement above, we can see that the respondent considers facilitated PD activities primarily as a means to develop knowledge about participants and their needs and desires, rather than events informing a design solution in a direct sense. Several respondents also highlighted the facilitator's role in uncovering value dilemmas and conflicts of interest among participants in PD activities:</p><p>"For me, these participatory design sessions are first and foremost a way to expose value dilemmas and conflicts of interest and then see how to navigate around them, or to solve them, or to work with that in the next stages of the design process, and then come back to the participants. " (Quote 17, Respondent 4)</p><p>Both the above quotes reflect, to some extent, an understanding of the facilitator as an inquirer, that is, one that is responsible for exposing user needs, values, and perspectives and then communicating the findings to others involved in the design project (see Sect. 4.6, The Facilitator as Users' Advocate), so that the insights might be taken into consideration in subsequent design iterations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Inquirer Strategies.</head><p>In terms of strategies, respondents emphasized the inquisitiveness of probing for user insights often required from the facilitator. One respondent explained: "I think part of your role is to push back and challenge participants. So, when they say things, I think the role of a PD facilitator to ask: 'Well, why do you think that would work?' or that 'We've told that that wouldn't work because of these reasons' or been told . . .', you know. It's not just uncritically listening what your participants are telling you, but we interrogate it a bit. And I think that active interrogation, as well, heavily shapes the information that you get from them. " (Quote 18, Respondent 7).</p><p>This statement suggests that the respondent has developed a conscious awareness about their role in gathering user insights from PD activities. Rather than playing the passive part of an information gatherer (i.e., one who simply records what participants are expressing or replying) the strategy described here suggests that by taking an active role probing for user insights, the facilitator is likely to gather more insights. Continuously challenging ideas and perspectives that are put forward by participants ("push back and challenge participants") and attempting to understand the underlying motivation behind their viewpoints ("active interrogation") are key aspects of such a strategy.</p><p>In their reflections regarding strategies for gaining deep insights, also underscored the need for the facilitator to allow potential tensions between participants to play out: can also say like: 'Hey, whatever happens on the outside the PD activity] happens on the inside', so apparently the fight to happen inside as well. And then it's much more about, so how can you make that a productive fight rather than a fight, right? So, I think that's a very important mind shift that really helps me to sleep better at night, but also makes more valuable for the people that you work with." (Quote 19, 9) Here we can see that Respondent 9 considers tensions in a PD activity as potentially valuable in terms of offering the facilitator and participants more comprehensive understandings of various perspectives on matters being discussed.</p><p>the respondents expressed mindfulness concerning their own role in generating rich user insights through PD activities, we also learned about the potential challenges associated with constantly being attentive towards, and following up on, what participants are expressing.</p><p>feel that I miss out on certain aspects almost every time: 'Why didn't I pick up on that thread? You [the participant] said something there, but I didn't follow up,' or 'What did they [the participants] really mean by that?"' (Quote 20, Respondent 3)</p><p>The above quote suggests that, despite a facilitator's intentions to explore emerging viewpoints and ideas, turning the intentions into practice, as the PD activity unfolds, is not trivial. In effect, there are often aspects and issues that may pass under the facilitator's 4.4 The Facilitator as Direction Setter 4.4.1 Setting Directions for the Design Process. The fourth role facet we identified relates to decision-making and the setting of directions in PD activities and throughout design processes. Simto how the respondents considered the development of an in-depth understanding of users and their perspectives a key facilitator responsibility (cf., the facilitator as inquirer), they also regarded the facilitator as having a particular obligation to guide PD process and its participatory activities towards an objective. Concerning the facilitator's role in guiding the PD processes, one of the respondents said:</p><p>"You have to guide them [the participants] through a process . .] you have to make sure that the conversation [in a PD is related to the topic about which you want to learn rather drifting off in far directions . . . It's not just we sit down with and collaborate. There's always a goal that we are working towards, and you will always learn things [from participants] which not in line with that goal, but we always also work towards that goal. That's an important thing, to make sure you don't end up on another planet . . . " (Quote 21, Respondent 6)</p><p>Central to Respondent 6's understanding of the facilitator role is the responsibility to align conversations with the goal of the project. Another respondent expressed a similar viewpoint, highlighting the role of the facilitator in forming the discussions taking place in a PD activity in a way that makes the participants' contributions useful for the associated project:</p><p>"In general, I think that the role is to try to start discussions a group and move them in a direction that your project can do something meaningful with the results. My perspective on this is as someone based within computer science where most of my projects around, you know ¬, there's a distinct angle of: 'We would like develop a piece of technology as part of this project,' so that development] is there as a thing we want to do . . . and so, a lot of the facilitation you do is shaping the discussion in ways that you can do something about, as opposed to discussions where can't do anything about the problems people are articulating. " (Quote 22, Respondent 7)</p><p>In particular, Quotes 21 and 22 highlight an agency that comes the facilitator role. A project has specified goals, but also limi-(time, budget, mandate, etc.). According to these expressed viewpoints, it is the facilitator's responsibility to frame PD activities in a manner that makes the results useful for the PD project ("make sure you don't end up on another planet") and thereby increases the likelihood that the project will effectively contribute to change them in a direction that your project can do something meaningful with the results").</p><p>The facilitator's implications for the design process, however, beyond explicitly setting a direction within participatory activities. Respondents also considered decisions regarding, for example, who to invite as participants, and at what point, to implicitly affect the outcome of activities and the project as a whole:</p><p>"As a facilitator one is often playing a part in deciding who participates in a workshop and who participates in the process . . . and that's an important decision. It's something about who is taking part, but there is also the question of who is taking part at what point, and that is something you should think carefully about. "</p><p>23, Respondent 11) This quote illustrates how facilitators, through their activities (both consciously and sometimes subconsciously), set directions for the PD process.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.2">Direction Setter Strategies.</head><p>Through the interviews, we learned that the strategies employed by the respondents when setting directions in PD activities included both subtle and more concrete measures. The following statement shows an example of the former:</p><p>"You do guide the participants. You actually maintain direction with them, but you do that in a soft ambiguous way so that their interpretations of your ambiguously given triggers and materials and instructions and answers will keep in the keep them towards the direction of why the session is there, also will give them control to be unpredictable for you. " (Quote 24, Respondent 6) Respondent 6 considers, for example, materials (which potentially can be used for enabling active participation) and instructions provided by the facilitator implicitly means that-if used consciously-they can direct PD activities in ways that better align with the agenda of the related project. Describing a concrete stratfor setting directions in the early stages of a PD process, Respondent 7 stated:</p><p>"I think that it's very common, like a mistake that's made in a of sessions, to go into the session [as facilitator] with an area to discuss rather than a question or a problem to address. And I think that while the area is the right approach for participatory design . . . for your participants, who are just coming into a project, I think it's very difficult for them to just take this here's-a-general-feel-for-anarea prompt and start to work within it. I think for them it's much better to start discussing problems and really concrete questions to start with. " (Quote 25, <ref type="bibr">Respondent 7)</ref> As described by this respondent, one strategy increasing the chances of generating PD outcomes of immediate relevance for the associated project, is to provide the participants with concrete questions or challenges related to the problem area the project is addressing, as opposed to opening up for general discussions about the area. Respondent 7 considers giving concrete questions to be discussed in a PD activity to also be a more constructive approach from the participants' point of view ("I think for them it's much better to start discussing problems and really concrete questions to start with.").</p><p>While the guiding conversations in PD activities were seen by the respondents as a central facilitator responsibility, we learned that such an obligation is also associated with challenges related to finding a balance between making sure that the activity is progressing, on the one hand, and that topics and viewpoints are thoroughly discussed, on the other: able to listen is in many ways most critical for a facilitator, also establishing some boundaries to prevent that does not go off topic . . . It's like balancing on a knife edge, where you listen and allow things to emerge and to be addressed. And then, on the other side, it's about taking decisions: 'Yes, but we are going in that We are going to do this!"' (Quote 26, Respondent 3) Respondent 3's reflection underlines the constant risk of losing "balance" as facilitator, that is, offering too much room for idea generation and exploration (at the potential cost of progression) or introducing too much control (at the potential cost of new ideas and deeper understanding of perspectives).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5">The Facilitator as Value Provider</head></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5.1">Offering Participants Value in Return.</head><p>The fifth facet the respondents called attention to in their appraisal of facilitator role, concerns a obligation ensure that PD activities, in addition to benefitting the associated project (the facilitator as guide), also offer to participants-in other words-that the time and efforts that the participants put into the PD project yield some type of return of their investment:</p><p>"I also feel that it is the role of the facilitator to capture what the participants want to get out of it so that it becomes meaningful for both parts . . . I don't want to give them the impression that they have wasted their time. " (Quote 27, Respondent 14) Some respondents argued that the facilitator, as a representative the PD project, has an ethical responsibility, to strive toward actual change by turning ideas, values, and needs expressed by participants into working solutions that the user group which the participants represent can benefit from. This ethical responsibility was especially seen as central when working with marginalized the most important aspect for me is to allow people only to come up with ideas, but to experience them. In PD, we say that it is about imagining the future, but do we give them possibility to experience that part or are we just left with the 'imagine' part? Especially, when working with marginalized and vulnerable groups, I think it is important not to mislead someone say that that in this case [project], we can make a difference, when one really knows that nothing is going to change. For me, that is a problematic situation. Commenting further on the facilitator's role in offering participants the opportunity to increase their knowledge about technology and its possibilities, the respondent noted: is a very demanding situation when you are supposed to both teach someone about technology and its possibilities and at the same time learn something from them. It is demanding and it takes time. " (Quote 30, Respondent 30)</p><p>This also shows the challenge facilitators may face in their efforts to offer value, such as new knowledge, to participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.5.2">Value Provider</head><p>Strategies. the interviews, we learned that the value offering strategies employed by respondents depended strongly on the respondents' perception of what value constitutes and what was feasible within the given project to offer in return to participants.</p><p>respondents explained having developed routines that involved explicitly checking with participants at the beginning of a activity, concerning what they hoped to achieve through their participation, thus reflecting Respondent 14's (Quote 27) perception of the facilitator as value provider (". . .it is the role of the facilitator to capture what the participants want to get out of it"). Similarly, some respondents also reported routinely checking with participants when concluding PD activities what they had gained from taking part.</p><p>In many cases, however, respondents reported having learned that, on the topic in focus, the PD activity itself can offer values to participants: "What really surprised us in some of the studies that we did is that you engage with people [participants] and they become aware of an aspect of their life and what matters to them, and have discussed this together with other people . . . [Talking to after the project] we were astonished how much they remembered from the session and several of them had come and said: 'I've understood even better than at the session how this part of life is important. ' "(Quote 31, Respondent 6)</p><p>"They [the participants] received practical help [with the techand learned that you could do it this way." (Quote 32, Respondent 3)</p><p>Both the above quotes describe incidents in which the particifrom the respective respondents' points of view, acquired new knowledge without such a value being explicitly planned for the projects. The analysis also revealed strategies in which the facilitator takes steps to offer value to participants: "I also think that if you're doing iterative work, the other part your role is to make sure that you go away and come back with stuff, with artifacts for the design process. That could be iterations your design, or it could be iterations of a concept. But being able to show people clear, meaningful change in something that you building over time, I think is. . . I don't think it's essential, but think it is really valuable if you can do it. And it's an important role for the facilitators of those sessions. It's the work outside of the session. " (Quote 33, Respondent 7)</p><p>Continuously presenting participants with concrete evidence of how their input has informed the emerging design solution as seen from the respondent's perspective (Quote 33), serve as an affirmation to participants that their participation matters. Presenting the intermediate results of the participants' contribution, example, in the form of functional prototypes, can serve to motivate further active engagement from participants.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4.6</head><p>The Facilitator as Users' Advocate 4.6.1 Forefronting the User Perspective. The sixth facet the respondents discussed was the facilitator's role in forefronting users' perand needs uncovered through PD activities. One respondent gave the following description of the facilitator's role in conresults from PD activities to other project members and stakeholders:</p><p>We are their [the participants] mouthpiece. We ensure that their voice is heard, to put it like that. (Quote 34, Respondent 1)</p><p>Reflecting on the facilitator role in the aftermath of PD activities, respondent stated: which is still part of the process, [my role is] to interpret that [outcome of PD activities] and to understand what the underlying motivation for that is, and to decide together with others we can implement that in a design. " (Quote 35, Respondent 13)</p><p>As both quotes illustrate, respondents also considered themselves as playing a central part in representing the users' voice in contexts where, for example, important design decisions-potentially affecting the users to a large degree-are taken. One central reason why acting as the users' advocate in project meetings with partners and others was considered by the respondents as important was the to ensure that the outcome of PD activities would be commuto project partners and reflected in the technical solution in that align with the original "user perspective" (emerging from PD activities). Reflecting on their experiences from "championing" user perspective in project meetings, one of the respondents exhow project partners could sometimes be reluctant towards taking results from PD activities into consideration:</p><p>that can be a struggle, 'cause, what we notice, is that a lot of project partners are not really into these design activities, and really see that as a kind of a soft and fuzzy type of research. " (Quote 36, <ref type="bibr">Respondent 13)</ref> In some cases, being the users' advocate also means going into (tough) negotiations with project partners, trying to convince them to accept the user perspective: happens a lot that we then say things: 'OK, this doesn't work. have to change this', and that they say: 'We cannot change that anymore. ' It's quite annoying and especially if in a later phase the project, we come up with really great ideas that the end users came up with during the sessions. It's also very often that someone 'Oh no, we cannot add that anymore. ' So, that's a real struggle usually. " (Quote 37, <ref type="bibr">Respondent 13)</ref> According to Respondent 13's experience, then, the outcome of PD activities is not necessarily accepted or given priority by project partners, thus requiring active promotion by the facilitator.</p><p>Users' Advocate Strategies. In addition to "taking the stage" negotiating the user perspective in project meetings with partners and other stakeholders, respondents also reported inviting of the project, without direct experience from the project's PD activities, "behind the curtain"-that is, asking them to take part: "When it comes to communicating to designers, developers, and who we have to throw the ball [hand over results] to in project, the solution I have the most experience with has been to involve them in the last concluding design activities of the PD It is possibly perceived a bit strange by those who have been us all the way [in the PD process] that new people suddenly in at the very end, and then their role has probably been more observers and to gather experience, but also to be able to ask and be involved in more like a reflection phase [. . .]. And seen that those who take part get much more out of it than who only receive documents [describing the results]. " (Quote 38, Respondent 2) the strategy described above, the facilitator advocates the user not directly as when negotiating with project partners, but more subtly by offering partner representatives a first-hand experience of participatory activities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.7">Summary of Main Findings</head><p>In summarizing the main results of the study, we found that the of the PD facilitator can be divided into six interrelated facets, where each facet is associated with specific responsibilities and, relations with participants, for example, by also spending time together them also outside of facilitated PD activities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Enabler</head><p>Offer means that can help participants their ideas, and perspectives and employ a "common language" that can be understood and used by (and be prepared to change in case of failure). Alternatively, participants different languages can be kept in separate groups. participant by providing them tasks to prepare prior to the PD activity. Ensure all participants are given the possibility to speak their minds on matters being discussed (manage discussions when required). Inquirer Develop a comprehensive of the participants, their needs, perspectives, and Challenge participants by asking follow-up questions on suggestions, ideas, and perspectives they express. potential tensions between participants as they may provide deeper insight into conflicting values they hold. Direction setter a direction to increase the likelihood that the outcome of PD activities can be utilized by the related project.</p><p>Use materials (artefacts, prototyping materials, etc.) and instructions to set boundaries for participatory activities.</p><p>participants concrete questions or challenges related to the project's problem area.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Value provider</head><p>Ensure that the PD activity offers value in return to participants for their effort and input.</p><p>Provide opportunities for participants to learn the possibilities and the limitations of on participation offering intrinsic values (e.g., self-insight). participants what they expect to gain through participating (and try to accordingly) and verify the extent to which their expectations have been met. Users' advocate Forefront the "user perspective" though PD activities.</p><p>on behalf of users in situations where important design decisions are to be taken.</p><p>project partners to PD activities to provide them with a first-hand experience.</p><p>forms a particular purpose within the PD process. In enacting role facets and fulfilling the associated responsibilities the rereported following a set of strategies they had learned developed through their practice. An overview of the identified associated responsibilities and strategies for fulfilment is presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> 5 DISCUSSION results presented in the previous section yields a multifaceted view of PD facilitation in which the facilitator has several responsibilities. In the following, we discuss what we see as the further implications of the findings. In doing so, we first present three overarching concerns that stand out as central in the emerging collective view on the role of the facilitator: maximizing the value of user participation, striving for facilitator continuity, and upholding situational awareness. We also account for how we see that the identified facets can benefit a reflective facilitation practice. facilitator concerns we want to look at more is the challenges involved in maximizing the value of user participation a PD project. On the one hand, the respondents expressed a deep obligation to give all participants a voice in the design-related questions (cf., the enabler facet) and to form a comprehensive unof their needs and perspectives (cf., the inquirer facet). On the other hand, the respondents also expressed being highly conscious about setting directions in participatory activities so that outcome serves to inform the design solution and, hence, benefits the project. As opposed to holding a "the user-is-always-right" attitude toward input from participants, the respondents' general attitude was that to maximize the value of user participation in a PD project, critical and reflective thinking from the facilitator is essential. Ensuring that participatory activities stay within the boundaries formed by the associated project's goal, mandate, available resources, and other structural elements [4], can therefore be seen as central. Staying within the boundaries implies that the fasometimes needs to make "cuts" by, for example, choosing to take into further consideration a specific need, desire, or proeither because it is not possible for the project to follow up outside of the project's scope (Quote 22). As such, setting direcas a facilitator can be seen as a necessity to achieve a "greater good" in the form of a working, usable, and value-oriented design solutions form which the participants, and the user group they represent, can benefit. With reference to PD's democratic practices and commitment to giving disadvantaged groups a voice in design processes, our findings indicate that the facilitator in many cases as a "filter, " allowing some input to pass through to be followed up, while blocking other input. This "filtering" underscores the PD facilitator's as potentially highly influential the shaping of the participatory 5.1.2 Striving for Facilitator Continuity. If we look more closely at the identified role facets, it is noteworthy how respondents tended to regard their facilitator responsibilities as extending beyond the immediate PD activity. For example, the reported trust builder strategies generally involved taking measures to and develop relations with potential participants in the early phases of a PD project and typically prior to any facilitated PD activities (Quote 6). Similarly, acting as a users' advocate involved taking actions after between) PD activities, for example, championing the user perspective in meetings with project partners (Quote 37). As reflected in Quote 23, decisions concerning which participants to invite and when were also considered indirectly affect PD activities and their outcomes. These examples illustrate how the respondents, as opposed to considering facilitation a sporadic responsibility managing isolated PD activities), tended hold more long-term process perspective on facilitation, seeing the role as comprising a series of interrelated responsibilities requiring the facilitator's dedication and commitment from the beginning of the design process until its conclusion. Factors that for various reasons could prevent such a continuous engagement were often to compromise the participatory process and its results 7). The respondents' process perspective on facilitation is some extent in correspondence with the prolonged perspective on participation claimed by <ref type="bibr">Halskov and Hansen [10]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Emerging Facilitator Concerns</head><p>While the respondents considered the facilitator's continuous engagement throughout a PD project to be highly beneficial, it is to note that they did not express seeing a criterion conducting "genuine" PD. Instead, continuous engagement viewed more as an ideal or a facilitator's "best case scenario. " terms of ensuring a democratic process that gives a voice to user groups, facilitator continuity can be seen as a contributing factor.</p><p>Other PD-related studies have also discussed the significance of continuity in participatory processes. For example, <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[36]</ref> highlighted the benefits of having relatively stable groups of user representatives in participatory processes to ensure constructive discussions and productive participatory activities. Our findings suggest that facilitator continuity throughout a PD process may be equally important in terms of achieving a participatory result.</p><p>Upholding Situational Awareness. Lastly, the findings also draw attention to the demands placed upon a facilitator when tendto the many responsibilities involved in an ongoing PD activity. In particular, the results emphasize the situational awareness required by the facilitator to take note of, and potentially act on, participants are expressing (cf., the inquirer facet), the level of participant's' individual engagement (cf., the enabler facet), the potential project value of ongoing discussions and proposals (cf., direction setter facet), etc. Several of the presented quotes (e.g., 14, 18 and 26) illustrate how the facilitator is required to constantly be mindful of and attend to several responsibilities within a short timeframe. Minding responsibilities, such as those mentioned above, thus implies that the facilitator playing an active part in participatory activities has to constantly responding to emerging issues through "micro-adjustments" that are aimed at keeping the ongoing PD activity in line with democratic values as well as within the boundaries of the project's possibilities and limitations. In many ways, these constant adjustments taken in response to the changing situation is in line with the conceptualization of the PD facilitator intellectual bricoleur <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[34]</ref>.</p><p>The capacity to notice and take rational, purposeful actions in response to rapidly changing situations is also characteristic of what <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref> characterized as reflection in action. Performing such in-action reflections concerning, for example, statements to further clarify and what design suggestions to prioritize means that there is also a risk for of missing out on possible new insights and fruitful design ideas (Quote 20). The demands for situational awareness and in-action reflection, implicitly draws attention to how such skills can be developed through reflective activities taking place in the aftermath of PD activities and processes. Below, describe how the facilitator facets identified in the current work to potentially support such activities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Possibilities for Reflective Practice</head><p>This work has contributed an enriched understanding of how PD facilitators conceptualize their role. Self-awareness and the awareof one's role can be essential in the development of reflective practitioners <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[29]</ref>. In supporting a reflective PD facilitation practice, believe, the six identified facets can be of particular value as they highlight central aspects of facilitation and offer a vocabulary discussing these aspects. Especially, we see a potential in using the facets as catalysts for reflection both in the preparation and in the aftermath of PD processes and activities. For example, by deliberately questioning, in the early phases of a PD project, how one plans to attend different aspect of facilitation and associated responsibilities, the list of facets may support problematized reflection, as opposed to having more generalized or abstract discussions facilitation. Similarly, the facets may be used to support postactivity and process reflections by providing concrete topics to discuss and assess as part of reflective activities, and thus act as potential drivers for change in facilitation practice. It is important to note that although the multi-faceted conceptualization of the role presented in this work reflects the collective understanding of 14 experienced PD researchers and facilitators, we do consider the list of role facets exhaustive. Nor do the reported strategies rule out other possibilities.</p><p>Given the limited focus on facilitation and the role of the facilitain existing PD and HCI research literature, we consider the role performed in the current work to be of potential value for both novice and more experienced PD facilitators. For novice facilitators who, due to limited practical facilitation experilack a basis for reflecting on their role, how to fulfill it, and potential challenges, the list of facets along with the associated strategies (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>) may potentially serve as a mentor-apprentice model-an experience-based reference that one can learn from, but does not prevent the apprentice from developing their own perspectives on the role and strategies for role realization.</p><p>The general lack of reflective tools tailored for PD facilitators can also make the collective understanding of the role emerging for analysis useful in the reflective activities of more experienced facilitators. In addition to working as a potential checklist of aspects to go through part of a reflective activity, also see a potential for the responsibilities and with the different role facets (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>) to act as points for and reflection for the individual facilitator and their own enactment of the role.</p><p>Further investigations are required to verify the possibilities suggested</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">METHODOLOGICAL CONSIDERATIONS</head><p>Before concluding, we believe it is appropriate to also consider findings in the light of the employed methodology. Below, we briefly discuss three methodological limitations of our work.</p><p>First, while we have focused primarily on the multi-faceted aspects the PD facilitator role entails, we do not consider our findings be exhaustive in terms of possible ways to conceptualize the role has this been our goal). The described role facets represent only a collective understanding of how the 14 respondents taking part in study regarded their role as PD facilitators and do not rule out the possibility of other interpretations. Hence, we regard the identified facets as instances in an even richer world of interpretations.</p><p>to how we consider the list of identified facets as not being the strategies the respondents reported following when attending to associated responsibilities should be considered no more than examples. While the respondents appeared put emphasis on different aspects when accounting for the facilitator role, the that similar aspects reoccurred across different interviews adds credibility to the findings. since the findings were derived from data collected interviews, we were not able to verify the extent to which the facilitator strategies the respondents described were actually in their facilitation practice. As stated earlier, we have relied exclusively on the respondents' verbal accounts of strategies they employed in former PD projects, making it impossible for us to confirm their statements by means of observations. The focus in this paper, however, has been on unpacking how facilitators conceptualize their role rather than how it is in Third, in interpretative studies such as the current one, there always the of misinterpretations due to such factors as the potential ambiguity in respondents' statements <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>. As described Sect. 3.3, we attempted to compensate for this in the coding process by reassessing interpretations of transcribed statements times.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">CONCLUSION</head><p>this work, we have investigated how experienced PD facilitators understand their role and how they contemplate role realization. Based on a content analysis of interviews with 14 respondents, six pertaining to the facilitator role, each associated with specific responsibilities and strategies, were identified. Combined, the six facets paint a complex picture of the facilitator role. The facilitator is seen as responsible both for offering value to the participants in PD activities and to ensure that the output of the activities can be utilized by the associated PD project and thereby increase project's prospects for turning "imagined futures" into working, value-based design solutions. Realizing PD's egalitarian values also requires long-term dedication and commitment from the facilitator a design process as well as a high level of situational awareness in ongoing PD activities. We regard these overarching facilitator concerns as being strongly supportive in gaining an of PD facilitation as a practice in which required skills are learned and enhanced through practice-based reflection.</p><p>the context of reflective activities, we consider the collective multi-faceted understanding of the facilitator role emerging from the current study to have potential for supporting problematized reflections among PD facilitators about their practice. would like to express our deepest gratitude to the respondents took part in this study for sharing their time, perspectives, and deep reflections with us. </p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>4. 3 . 1</head><label>31</label><figDesc>Probing for Insights. The third facilitator facet the analysis revealed concerned the respondents' perceived responsibility to develop a comprehensive understanding of the participants, their needs, and values. One of the respondents expressed this:</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>" (Quote 28, Respondent 2) Other respondents emphasized the possibility for learning about technology as a potential value that facilitated PD activities can participants: "As participant, you can learn a little more about technology and especially about its possibilities, but also its limitations, what's possible and what's not possible. I think learning is what's most important in my experience. " (Quote 29, Respondent 3)</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_2"><head>5. 1 . 1</head><label>11</label><figDesc>Maximizing the Value of User Participation. The first of the</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Summary of Main Findings</figDesc><table><row><cell></cell><cell>Perceived responsibility</cell><cell>Identified strategies</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>the setting for an</cell></row><row><cell>builder</cell><cell>exchange of ideas and</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>perspectives.</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>14. How do you deal with asymmetries between participants in a project and within PD activities, i.e., in, for example, social status, work hierarchy, professional knowledge? you provide some examples of how you have dealt with asymmetries in PD projects you have taken part in and PD that you have facilitated? Could you explain what type of measures you take to ensure active involvement of participants in a PD activity? Could you provide some examples from your own practice? do you go about to ensure that the participants are able to follow the topics being discussed and remain engaged throughout the activity? A.5 Evaluation of output from the facilitated How do you evaluate and take the output from a PD activity to the rest of the design/development? Routines? Use of tools? A.6 Conclusion 17. In what way would you say that your facilitation practice has affected your views on PD as a design method? A.7 Collaboration (optional) 18. To what extent do you work alone or in collaboration with other IT or design professionals planning, running, and evaluating PD activities? How do you feel about this way?</figDesc><table /></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>APPENDICES A INTERVIEW GUIDE A.1 Introduction</head><p>To what extent would you say that you have a "standardized" of running PD activities such as co-design workshops? Can you explain the rationale for the approach you take? How was the approach established?</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Reimagining Participatory Design-Emerging Voices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liam</forename><surname>Bannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeffrey</forename><surname>Bardzell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Susanne</forename><surname>Bødker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">User participation and democracy: a discussion of Scandinavian research on systems development</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gro</forename><surname>Bjerknes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tone</forename><surname>Bratteteig</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Inf. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="73" to="98" />
			<date type="published" when="1995">1995</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Next steps for value sensitive design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alan</forename><surname>Borning</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Muller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, for Computing Machinery</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems, for Computing Machinery</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Unpacking the Notion of Participation Participatory Design. Supported Coop</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tone</forename><surname>Bratteteig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ina</forename><surname>Wagner</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10606-016-9259-4</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10606-016-9259-4" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Work</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="425" to="475" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A Utopian Experience: On design of Powerful Computer-based tools for skilled graphic workers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Morten</forename><surname>Bødker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pelle</forename><surname>Kyng</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Ehn</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yngve</forename><surname>Kammersgaard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Sundblad</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Computers and democracy: A Scandinavian challenge</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Aldershot</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Avebury</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1987">1987</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michela</forename><surname>Cozza</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Augusto</forename><surname>Cusinato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andreas</forename><surname>Philippopoulos-Mihalopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/09505431.2019.1681952</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/09505431.2019.1681952" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Atmosphere in Participatory Design. as Culture</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="269" to="292" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Breaking the Sound Barrier: Designing Patient Participation in Audiological Consultations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yngve</forename><surname>Dahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geir</forename><surname>Kjetil Hanssen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2016 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2016 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Facilitating Democracy: Concerns from Participatory Design with Asymmetric Stakeholder Relations in Health Care</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yngve</forename><surname>Dahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dag</forename><surname>Svanaes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Participatory Design and Participatory Research An HCI Case Study Young Forced Migrants</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ana Maria Bustamante</forename><surname>Duarte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nina</forename><surname>Brendel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Auriol</forename><surname>Degbelo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christian</forename><surname>Kray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3145472</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3145472" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM Trans. Comput.-Hum. Interact</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The diversity of participatory research practice at PDC 2002-2012</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kim</forename><surname>Halskov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Nicolai Brodersen Hansen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ijhcs.2014.09.003</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijhcs.2014.09.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Hum.-Comput. Stud</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">74</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="92" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using Participatory Design with Proxies with Children with Limited Communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Foad</forename><surname>Hamidi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melanie</forename><surname>Baljko</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Isabel</forename><surname>Gómez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3132525.3132527</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3132525.3132527" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</title>
				<meeting>the 19th International ACM SIGACCESS Conference on Computers and Accessibility</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Engaging Low-Income African American Older Adults in Health Discussions through Community-based Design Workshops</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christina</forename><forename type="middle">N</forename><surname>Harrington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katya</forename><surname>Borgos-Rodriguez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anne</forename><forename type="middle">Marie</forename><surname>Piper</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empathy @ design research: phenomenological study on young people experiencing participatory design social inclusion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jin</forename><surname>Kwok-Leung Ho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yanki</forename><surname>Ma</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/15710882.2011.609893</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15710882.2011.609893" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CoDesign</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="95" to="106" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Three tensions in participatory design for</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Harald</forename><surname>Holone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jo</forename><surname>Herstad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2470654.2481401</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2470654.2481401" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing 2903-2906</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing 2903-2906</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ethical Leadership in Participatory design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hussain</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013. 2013</date>
			<publisher>Intl Congress of the Intl Association of Societies of Design Research</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Work of Democratized Design in Setting-up a Hosted Citizen-Designer Community</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Virve</forename><surname>Hyysalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Louna</forename><surname>Hyysalo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hakkarainen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ternational Journal of Design</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ergonomics of human-system interaction -210: Humancentred design for interactive systems</title>
		<idno>ISO 9241-210. 2019</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Organization for Standard</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards ethical principles for participatory design practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Janet</forename><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/15710882.2018.1502324</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15710882.2018.1502324" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">CoDesign</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="329" to="344" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Heritage: having a say</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Finn</forename><surname>Kensing</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joan</forename><surname>Greenbaum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Routledge International Handbook of Participatory Design</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Routledge, London, UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Ten standard objections to qualitative research interviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kvale</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1163/156916294X00016</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Phenomenological Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">25</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Show Must Go On: A Conceptual Model of Conducting Synchronous Participatory Design With Children Online</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kung Jin Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3411764.3445715</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445715" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">345</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The human touch: participatory practice and the role of facilitation in designing with communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ann</forename><surname>Light</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yoko</forename><surname>Akama</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2347635.2347645</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2347635.2347645" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the Participatory Design Conference</title>
				<meeting>the Participatory Design Conference</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="61" to="70" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Empathy, participatory design and people with</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Lindsay</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2207676.2207749</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2207676.2207749" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing 521-530</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing 521-530</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Learning to talk to users in participatory design situations. Design Studies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rachael</forename><surname>Luck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.destud.2007.02.002</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.destud.2007.02.002" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">28</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="217" to="242" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">User Centered System Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Donald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Norman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Draper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1986">1986</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">New Perspectives on Human-Computer Interaction. L. Erlbaum Associates Inc</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Researching Information Systems and Computing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Briony</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Oates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<publisher>Sage Publications Ltd</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reflexive engagement: enacting reflexivity in design and for &apos;participation in plural</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Suvi</forename><surname>Pihkala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helena</forename><surname>Karasti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2940299.2940302</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/2940299.2940302" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">14th Participatory Design Con</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="30" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Participatory Design: An introduction. International Handbook of Participatory Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Toni</forename><surname>Robertson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jesper</forename><surname>Simonsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<pubPlace>Routledge, London, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Reflective Practitioner: How Professionals Think</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Donald</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Schön</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1983">1983</date>
			<publisher>Basic Books</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Reflective Practicum: A Framework of Sensitising Concepts to Design for Transformative</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Petr</forename><surname>Slovák</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Frauenberger</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geraldine</forename><surname>Fitzpatrick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3025453.3025516</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3025453.3025516" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Com-Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Com-Systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2696" to="2707" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Located accountabilities in technology production</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lucy</forename><surname>Suchman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Inf. Syst</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="91" to="105" />
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Putting the users center stage: role playing and low-fi prototyping enable end users to design mobile systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dag</forename><surname>Svanaes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gry</forename><surname>Seland</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/985692.985753</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/985692.985753" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="479" to="486" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Participatory Design and Design for Values</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christina</forename><surname>Maja Van Der Velden</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Mörtberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Ethics, Values, and Technological Design: Sources, Theory, Values and Application Domains</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Netherlands, Dordrecht</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Opening participatory democracy&apos;s black box: Facilitation as creative bricolage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tom</forename><surname>Wakeford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michel</forename><surname>Pimbert</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">of participation: Reflections on authority, democracy and the struggle for common life</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>UK</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Facilitating User in a Large IT Project: A Comparison of Facilitators&apos; Perspectives on Process, Role and Personal Practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dag</forename><surname>Øivind Klungseth Zahlsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yngve</forename><surname>Svanaes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Dahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno>INTERACT 2021</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
			<pubPlace>Bari Italy</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Understanding the Impact of Boundary Conditions on Participatory Activities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dag</forename><surname>Øivind Klungseth Zahlsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Arild</forename><surname>Svanaes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yngve</forename><surname>Faxvaag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Dahl</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3419249.3420129</idno>
		<ptr target="http://dx.doi.org/10.1145/3419249.3420129" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 11th Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction: Shaping Shaping Society</title>
				<meeting>the 11th Nordic Conference on Human-Computer Interaction: Shaping Shaping Society</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">81</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
