<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Making Space for Cultural Infrastructure: The Breakdown and Maintenance Work of Independent Movie Theaters During Crisis</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Sam</forename><surname>Addison Ankenbauer</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author role="corresp">
							<persName><forename type="first">Alex</forename><forename type="middle">Jiahong</forename><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
							<email>alexjlu@umich.edu</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ann Arbor</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<address>
									<settlement>New York</settlement>
									<region>NY</region>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Michigan</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Ann Arbor</settlement>
									<country key="US">USA</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Making Space for Cultural Infrastructure: The Breakdown and Maintenance Work of Independent Movie Theaters During Crisis</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3501840</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:03+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Infrastructure</term>
					<term>cultural infrastructure</term>
					<term>cultural spaces</term>
					<term>COVID-19</term>
					<term>infrastructuring work</term>
					<term>materiality</term>
					<term>symbolic meaning</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>Independent movie theaters (IMTs) are a part of the cultural infrastructure that ofers shared spaces for patron communities to access, share, and engage with cultural artifacts. In light of the COVID-19 pandemic, IMTs were mandated to shut down, resulting in unanticipated infrastructural breakdown. Drawing insights from a preliminary survey and interviews with staf members from 18 IMTs in the U.S., this paper attends to how this breakdown disrupted art and community engagement within patron communities. We investigate the sociotechnical practices of maintaining cultural infrastructure through 1) collaborating with community partners and external stakeholders, 2) screening flms through online virtual cinema platforms, and 3) retaining community members through online platforms. Our work highlights the tensions and invisible human labor in this maintenance work. Together, this work intends to foreground cultural infrastructure and discuss how HCI can support and contribute to the design and oft-invisible maintenance of cultural infrastructure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Human-centered computing → Empirical studies in collaborative and social computing; • Applied computing → Arts and humanities.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>Independent movie theaters (IMTs) are part of cultural infrastructure, invested in the (re)production and dissemination of knowledge and culture through the medium of flm with a focus on communitydriven, art-forward messaging <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[14]</ref>. In the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic, all cinemas in the United States (U.S.)-including IMTswere mandated to temporarily shut down by mid-March, 2020. The National Association of Theatre Owners (NATO) released a statement on March 17, 2020 that discussed the ongoing pandemic's efect on the movie theater industry that said, "While movie theaters will sufer some fnancial harm in the near term, and many of their 150,000 employees will face personal hardship, when this crisis passes and people return to their hard-wired social nature, movie theaters will be there for them as they have always been, with a full slate of movies far into the future" <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[15]</ref>. With the landscape of in-person engagement altered signifcantly, IMTs were in the precarious position of retaining their roles in facilitating the distribution of art and community engagement while still sustaining their businesses.</p><p>Scholars in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI), Computer Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW), and neighboring felds have long investigated varied kinds of critical infrastructures and infrastructuring work. Infrastructural breakdown and collapse make visible the invisible inner-workings of infrastructures <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[7]</ref> and provide an opportunity to understand human labor and sociotechnical practices in managing and coping with these breakdowns <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[35]</ref>. This paper extends this line of inquiry regarding cultural infrastructure during a time of crisis. In this work, we defne cultural infrastructure as a sociotechnical assemblage of artifacts, activities, users, and spaces in operation that supports the generation, transmission, exchange, and engagement of cultural beliefs, practices, and objects.</p><p>Drawing from a preliminary survey with stafs from 42 U.S.based IMTs and semi-structured interviews with 18 of these staf members, this paper attends to how the breakdown of cultural infrastructure impacts patron communities and investigates the formal and informal maintenance work carried out by IMT stafs in hopes of repairing infrastructure and coping with uncertainties. Through a case study of IMTs, this work demonstrates how, when cultural infrastructures are broken, various sociotechnical practices are adopted to make up for infrastructural disruption. In particular, this work sought to investigate the following research questions: RQ1: What are the sociotechnical practices of maintaining broken cultural infrastructure during this crisis? RQ2: How do the maintenance practices shift the symbolic and material dimensions of the cultural infrastructure? And how does this shift afect the outcomes of the maintenance work?</p><p>In addressing these questions, this paper unpacks how the COVID-19 pandemic led to the mandated closure of ofine cultural spaces, efectively disrupting art and community engagement. Such closure led to unanticipated infrastructural breakdowns with respect to IMTs' business operations and engagement with patron communities. These disruptions have put already precarious public cultural infrastructure at risk. In this light, our work identifes three salient sociotechnical practices of IMT maintenance, including 1) collaborating with community partners and external stakeholders for funding and support, 2) screening flms through online virtual cinema platform and encouraging individuals to access culture from home, and 3) retaining community members through social media and other online platforms. Our work highlights the tensions and invisible human labor in these types of maintenance work.</p><p>Building on HCI's ongoing discussions of critical infrastructures, our work aims to foreground cultural infrastructure in this discourse. We contribute ways in which HCI can contribute to the design and oft-invisible maintenance of cultural infrastructure, and discuss how considerations for cultural spaces can help us rethink the future of cultural infrastructure in the wake of a global pandemic. Broadly, understanding the promises and limitations of technology solutions in maintaining cultural infrastructure ofers critical insights into the opportunities and risks for recovery and reinvention of cultural spaces post-pandemic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">RELATED WORK</head><p>We situate this work in HCI, critical infrastructure studies, and neighboring felds. In this section, we frst review past studies on infrastructure and infrastructuring work, highlighting the limited engagement with cultural infrastructure. We then attend to past research on the breakdown and maintenance of infrastructure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Infrastructure and Infrastructuring Work</head><p>The term "infrastructure" has been used in myriad ways and contexts and, as such, has been described as causing "immense confusion" <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[45]</ref>. In this work, we position infrastructure as "an assemblage of artifacts, activities, and users in operation as providing support and service to some social system" <ref type="bibr">[31, p.30]</ref>. In this defnition of infrastructure, relationality is thematic and investigation tends to focus on "what is supporting the work of another and who is sustaining those relationships?" <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[44]</ref>. Here, these relationships and interactions are varied, with human-to-human, humanto-artifact, and human-to-community-environment each needing to be sustained by IMT stafs.</p><p>Equally signifcant to this paper is the term infrastructuring. Here, infrastructuring refers to the "ongoing and continual processes of creating and enacting" infrastructures that often emerge from "the installed base" and network of dependencies <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[26,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b25">27]</ref>. Infrastructuring is thus the ongoing work that makes infrastructure work, afording its taken-for-grantedness until breakdown. Infrastructuring work is a continual process, one that can be undertaken at any time for a variety of reasons ("design and redesign, implementation and introduction, adaptation and adoption, combination and recombination") and often refects infrastructure's tendency towards breakdown and the need for organizational adaptability and maintenance as a response to these disruptions <ref type="bibr">[55, p.204]</ref>.</p><p>Previous HCI research has studied infrastructuring in diferent contexts and crises. For instance, research has investigated individual patients' and caregivers' infrastructuring work in navigating breakdown within United States healthcare infrastructure <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[23]</ref>. In this paper, we extend the discussion of infrastructuring work to the context of cultural infrastructure and independent movie theaters, contributing empirical data to the growing scholarship on infrastructuring work during the COVID-19. Here, infrastructuring work refers to the ongoing work that independent movie theater staf has engaged in to maintain the cultural value, revenue, and community engagement of their establishments during the pandemic.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Cultural Infrastructure</head><p>The term "culture" itself has had a varied meaning. Following the cultural theorist Kwame Appiah, we loosely consider culture as "the product of human activity, particularly those things that are socially transmitted, including beliefs, practices, objects, etc. " <ref type="bibr">[4]</ref>. This defnition of culture is in line with the on-going democratization of culture, a practice in which the defnition of culture has "expanded to include public parks alongside art museums, food and drink experiences alongside dramatic theater, and street art alongside classical dance" <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[12]</ref>. In urban planning, cultural infrasturcture often refers to cultural institutions and the GLAMAZONS sector that include physical galleries, libraries, archives, museums, aquariums, zoos, observatories, and nature spaces <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b26">28]</ref>. In our work, we expand this narrowly-defned cultural infrastructure to incorporate the human and non-human actors involved in the (re)production, transmission, and engagement of cultural beliefs, practices, and artifacts that predominantly take place in the aforementioned GLAMAZONS spaces but can be found elsewhere within the community.</p><p>Cultural infrastructure supports individual and community cultural needs, oftentimes in a local community space. These venues support routine cultural functions while they conserve, research, present, and contextualize. Like local network infrastructure supports community communication <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[5]</ref>, cultural infrastructure supports its community's education while simultaneously serving as community space and recreational location. Culture (as placed within the community via cultural infrastructure) cultivates a community's ability to fourish and grow, to be resilient, and to experience fulfllment, purpose, meaning, and happiness <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[19]</ref>. Similarly, it has been said that cultural infrastructure is an important component in a city's identity <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[8]</ref> and is an essential contribution to "city reputation, economic prosperity and quality of life" <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[53]</ref>. Indeed, 76% of U.S. leisure travelers participated in cultural activities such as visiting museums <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[34]</ref>, citizens in the U.S. visited public libraries 1.32 billion times in 2017 [41], and U.S. public parks saw a 63.4% increase in attendance during the COVID-19 pandemic <ref type="bibr" target="#b46">[50]</ref>.</p><p>Surprisingly, few studies in HCI and related felds have explicitly investigated the concept of cultural infrastructure. However, given HCI scholars' long interests in locality and human experiences in varied places, past work has explored certain aspects of cultural infrastructure, mainly focusing on the implementation of digital technologies in particular cultural institutions and places. For example, scholars have explored the augmentation of cultural spaces through digital technologies <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[37]</ref>, Cultural User eXperience (CUX) <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[29]</ref> and the creation of community-oriented libraries knowledge building and sharing <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[25,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b50">54]</ref>. In these works, sociotechnical systems modify physical space in diferent ways, from interventions in the physical place itself to creating community cultural space online. Elsewhere, Macchia's investigation into designing interactive systems in the museum context suggests how technologies can be used to reconfgure the interactions and relationships among people, between people and cultural artifacts, and between people and their surroundings <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[33]</ref>. Another line of research has also applied participatory and co-design methods to support experiences in cultural places. For exmaple, works by Fuks et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[20]</ref> and Ciolf et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11]</ref> investigated how co-design can be implemented in the museum space to support collaboration, social engagement, and new use of space.</p><p>With the closure of physical spaces during the COVID-19 pandemic, cultural venues had to seek digital and online solutions for cultural and community engagement, which we unpack next <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>. In this light, we continue the discussion of technologies entering into ofine cultural space. Doing so can further the discussion of cultural infrastructure in HCI and contribute knowledge regarding its signifcance to local communities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">Infrastructure Breakdown and Maintenance</head><p>The COVID-19 pandemic has been called the most severe public health and social crisis since the creation of the World Health Organization, one that has been "attacking societies at their core" <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[38]</ref>. All aspects of public life were afected, including cultural infrastructure. Our work is concerned with infrastructuring and maintenance in the post-breakdown wake of the COVID-19 pandemic and, as such, we draw upon infrastructural breakdown and crisis research.</p><p>In the words of Star and Ruhleder, "The normally invisible quality of working infrastructure becomes visible when it breaks: the server is down, the bridge washes out, there is a power blackout (...) This breakdown became the basis for a much more detailed understanding of the relational nature of infrastructure" <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[47]</ref>. Infrastructural breakdowns make visible the inner workings of the otherwise embedded and invisible infrastructures <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[7]</ref>. Attending to infrastructural breakdowns also allows us to investigate how actors step in and put efort in managing the broken infrastructure <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[35]</ref>.</p><p>With regards to IMTs, we investigate the attempted maintenance of various aspects of ofine cultural spaces during crisis and the labor involved.</p><p>Labor that concerns sustaining and maintaining is integral to infrastructure research. The act of "building everyday resilience" is considered routine <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[51]</ref>. Everyday maintenance is necessary in all forms of infrastructure. For instance, in an independent movie theater, such maintenance work would include: spooling and cutting prints, downloading Digital Cinema Package prints, ordering a sustaining amount of concessions and goods, and addressing customer complaints. During crisis, these everyday forms of infrastructural maintenance are disrupted and replaced with greater existential threats. For instance, IMTs had to contend with the shut-down of their physical space and greater negotiations of resources including time, money, and safety were required for maintenance eforts. This infrastructural maintenance often requires human infrastructure, that is, "the arrangements of organizations and actors that must be brought into alignment in order for work to be accomplished" <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[30]</ref>. In this work, human infrastructure often involves negotiation among IMT organizations, distributors, community partners, IMT stafs, and patron communities.</p><p>In this paper, we extend this line of research by investigating how cultural infrastructure broke down during the crisis and how IMTs pieced sociotechnical systems together to maintain the infrastructure, highlighting the promise and limitations of infrastructuring work and how future HCI systems can better prepare cultural infrastructures for potential crises and breakdowns. The tactics that IMTs and their stafs attempt do not seamlessly maintain original infrastructure and communities. These issues are discussed below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHODS</head><p>To understand the current sociotechnical practices of IMTs in engaging their patron communities and disseminating art during the COVID-19 pandemic, we conducted a two-part study. First, we conducted a preliminary survey to understand IMT's general use of technologies and state of business. Informed by our survey results, we then conducted a series of follow-up semi-structured interviews with 18 IMT stafs, including directors of operation and fnance, programming coordinators, managers, and more. Our study was marked as exempt by our university's Institutional Review Board.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Preliminary Survey</head><p>Our preliminary survey consisted of 15 questions. These questions aimed to provide a basic understanding of 1) how independent theaters operated and generated revenue during COVID-19; 2) how independent theaters engaged with their patron communities during COVID-19; and 3) whether (and if so, how) independent theaters utilized technologies to facilitate these processes. We also asked our We recruited respondents through emailing 210 independent theaters listed on the Art House Convergence (AHC) database. 1 In total, 42 individuals responded to our request and completed our survey. To ensure the representation of IMTs based in the U.S., we removed one respondent who represented a theater from Milan, Italy. As such, we had 41 robust responses from 21 states for analysis. Among these 41 theaters, 11 (27%) were in the Northeast, nine were in the South (22%), 13 were in the Midwest (32%), and eight were in the West (19%).</p><p>As noted, the goal of this survey was to generate a basic understanding of independent theaters' business operation, community engagement, and technology use during COVID-19. The survey results act as a backdrop for the semi-structured interviews which were informed by the themes and concerns voiced in the survey. We ran descriptive statistical analysis on our 41 responses. Based on the results, the research team discussed the questions to cover in the semi-structured interview protocol, which we describe next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Semi-structured Interviews</head><p>To get a deeper understanding of independent theaters' practices during the COVID-19 pandemic, we conducted follow-up interviews. To be eligible for our semi-structured interview study, participants needed to <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref> have completed the survey study and (2) be a current staf of an independent theater. Among the 41 respondents of our survey, 23 agreed to participate in the follow-up interview, and we were able to reach out to 18 of them. The frst author conducted the interviews by phone over a period of three months, from August to October 2020. Our interviews lasted from 37 minutes to 72 minutes (mean=47 minutes). Participants did not receive compensation for the interview. The detailed demographics of participants are presented in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Participants and the independent theaters they represented were in the Midwest (n=8), the Northeast (n=4), the South (n=3), and the West of the U.S. (n=3). Among all the participants, the majority were directors and managers of their respective theaters (n=14), three were programming and media coordinators of their theaters (n=3), and one was a volunteer at a theater run exclusively by volunteers (n=1).</p><p>We asked our participants to answer the questions both from their own perspectives as employees of their respective theaters and on behalf of their organizations as a collective center of action. We prompted our participants with questions about their theaters' practices during the past six to nine months in community engagement, virtual cinema platform use, cross-organizational relationships, and more. In addition, we allowed time for participants to discuss what they considered were important takeaways from their work during the COVID-19 pandemic. The semi-structured interview method allowed us to uncover participants' nuanced positions and experiences that were not available in the preliminary survey. At the same time, this method allowed participants to discuss topics that we did not at frst include in the interview protocol. We received oral consent from participants before each interview. All participant personal information has been anonymized, and their names have been replaced by pseudonyms throughout this paper.</p><p>All interviews were audio-recorded and transcribed. We analyzed the interview transcripts through inductive thematic analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[6]</ref>, which allowed us to identify patterns in the transcripts without utilizing existing framework. In particular, the frst author and the second author conducted the frst round of open coding by examining the transcripts line by line on the open source collaborative coding platform Taguette. 2 Both authors met and reconciled the generated codes until reaching consensus. In this round, we identifed salient themes related to relevancy and maintenance in an online space, the engagement value of social media platforms, and more. In a further round of data coding and analysis, the authors conducted focused coding and reviewed themes related to IMTs' infrastructural breakdowns on diferent levels, and the specifc forms of maintenance work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">FINDINGS</head><p>We start by providing context for IMTs as part of the cultural infrastructure of their local communities. We discuss how IMTs are utilized as places for art and community engagement prior to the COVID-19 and how the pandemic has broken down these engagements. Thereafter, we discuss the sociotechnical practices of maintaining broken cultural infrastructure, highlighting the labor, systems, and negotiations that went into the maintenance work.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">The Role of the Independent Movie Theater in Cultural Infrastructure</head><p>4.1.1 Facilitating Arts Engagement . IMTs exist to circulate art and cultural artifacts through flm screenings while facilitating discussion in the local community context. IMTs predominately showed flms that were outside the realm of the cineplex and would not be screened ofine otherwise within the community. Participants cited experimental flms, international works, documentaries, and flms by and for populations experiencing marginalization as essential to their businesses. For example, Clint, a manager at a Northeast IMT, told us that sharing these flms flled him with a sense of pride: "I feel proud of [our flms], and I think we're doing our part as a vessel for these flms to get into our communities." Similarly, Marlene summed up the value of her "very small [...] extremely curated" theater, And just like that, it completely opens your mind to something that you had no idea existed in the world -to these ideas and of this community or this culture. And that, to me, that's the pleasure of what I do, but I think that's also the pleasure for an audience member who is part of an art house.</p><p>As the above quotes suggest, staf at IMTs felt a responsibility and pride at facilitating arts engagement. Without these cultural spaces, local communities may not have the opportunity to engage with artworks that allow for such new considerations and experiences.</p><p>Additionally, the cultural setting of the theater allowed for further discussion and investigation, with arts engagement not ending with flm screenings. Through pre-and post-flm arts engagement, individuals from the local community could learn about and engage with cultures and ideas embodied within the flms. In the words of Marlon, patrons did not necessarily come to Abbas Kiarostami flms "because they already love Iranian cinema. They want to learn about it. They want to hear [the] introductions and discussions." These enriching moments created embodied experiences that were not available to the community otherwise, in the same way that a library provides the potential for local enrichment through literature-based cultural programs and a museum through engagement with sculpture and canvas. Each place afords local communities the opportunity to take in art in a dedicated environment, leading to a deeper understanding of the work and its surrounding context, history, and culture <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[33]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.2">Supporting Community Engagement.</head><p>Another form of infrastructural support IMTs enacted was through serving as a social place for community engagement. In our participants' words, IMTs were essential as "community gathering spaces" (Ingrid) that fostered "the experience of being together with other similarly-curious individuals to explore [an] art form" (Henry). While noting the bond between his IMT and its patrons, Humphrey discussed how patrons described the placeness of IMTs, People see it as sort of [a] church, their spiritual center [...] their weekly thing that kind-of gives them a meaningful experience. [...] It provides that connection, which I do think, culturally, there are fewer places like that -social gathering spots outside of just bars and whatnot. I think for people [the IMT is] kind of flling a void in that sense, in that it gives them a place to go. They'll see people that they know, they'll meet new people. They'll have a collective experience and we have a nice big lobby for people to hang out in [and discuss].</p><p>By highlighting the value of shared gathering places, Humphrey's quote illustrated IMTs' value beyond pure entertainment. IMTs were perceived as space for the community be in the presence of one another and connect through the cultural value of curated arts engagement (flm screenings, post-flm discussions, receptions, and question and answer sessions). As such, IMTs both support and inform the local community through engagement. IMTs can be regarded as part of the cultural infrastructure that facilitated individuals' needs of learning, belonging, and actualization. The bond that connected the community was "the theater more than the individual movies" (Cary). Its value was inherent in its materiality and physicality; as a physical space, it provided a point of relational connection and developed bonds based in individuals' cultural needs.</p><p>IMT's role in facilitating community engagement was also amplifed by the historical value of some IMTs. As IMT staf said, their establishments had been part of the community for decades with some theaters nearing their hundredth anniversary. For instance, Spencer told us, You're seeing 35 millimeter flm, you're seeing flm in a historic building, you're getting popcorn, you're doing this whole kind of thing. [...] They came here when they were kids in the 1950s and they're excited to bring their grandkids. That's something we hear a lot, a lot of people had their frst dates here and are still in the community, still coming, still seeing [movies].</p><p>The weight of history creates, in the words of Spencer, a "real emotional bond" among patrons and the theater. This emotional bond illustrated the symbolic meaning of IMTs-the IMT was not only a functional space but a space dedicated to community and community engagement. Participants took pride in being a part of their community, as when Henry discussed the importance of community to his IMT, [We're really trying to focus on the power of flm to act as an agent or a tool for change. And so, often [we would show] flms, whether they were documentary or narrative, that helped or somehow aligned with the mission of other organizations and community groups in the area. I would defnitely say that we were trying to be a pretty active participant in what was important [to our community] and changing the things that needed to be changed in our community.</p><p>Importantly, IMTs' physical presence and unique cultural importance suggested that they were relational-they were shaping and shaped by the interactions between theater and community, among community members, as well as between communities and the broader society. However, both the symbolic and material meanings of the cultural infrastructure have been broken by the COVID-19 pandemic, which we discuss next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Infrastructure Breakdowns During the COVID-19</head><p>4.2.1 Breakdown of the IMT as a Business. With mandatory and rapid shutdowns during the early months of the pandemic, IMTs that were central in communities as a place for arts engagement became inaccessible, leaving their roles as such unfulflled. For example, Marlon was a programming coordinator who worked at a Midwestern IMT. He discussed how the state's lockdown order left little room for the theater to fulfll its upcoming slate of screenings:</p><p>At the start of the pandemic when we closed our doors, [my feeling] was: we can't show movies right now.</p><p>There's no way we can do it. It's just closed. There's nothing we can do. sudden shutdown left Marlon about how the pandemic would impact his IMT's ability to facilitate even its most basic function as a space for screening flms. This feeling was especially dire for theaters with relatively short histories and less rigorous organizational structures. For example, Kirk had celebrated the second anniversary of his theater, one built in the same space as a defunct century-old movie palace, in February, 2020. He described how the pandemic hit his theater's operation:</p><p>[W]e were just kind of hitting our stride, just about making enough money so we wouldn't have to borrow money. We could just about pay our bills. And then of course, the pandemic cut it all out right from under us. A lack of business revenue from a dearth of screenings was a "kick in the teeth" to his IMT and the shaky ground gained over the previous years was lost. In addition, shrinking resources led to layofs at all levels (i.e., hospitality staf and back of house staf alike). In fact, our survey results show that over 70% of theaters (n=30) were faced with staf layofs by summer 2020. These individuals were critical to the function and maintenance of the theaters. Clint speculated on such organizational disruption and its long-term impact:</p><p>[We're entering into] a brain drain of people, losing committed and competent senior staf [...] people who were part of the public face [of the theater]. That is going to defnitely be a challenge in the coming years for everybody, institutional knowledge being just sort-of wiped away. And, additionally, coming back with a signifcantly altered landscape. So you're entering a new phase and you're not going to have some of the people who knew how to run it to begin with. With screening rooms empty, upcoming events "dropped to zero" (Clint), and minimal staf, some participants described IMTs as no longer the pillars of community that they had once been. The theaters were efectively "not open [and] didn't have any way of communicating with most patrons" (Ingrid). During the pandemic, the community response to IMTs altered as well, which we will discuss next.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2.2">Breakdown between IMTs and their Communities.</head><p>Our interviews also spoke to how the COVID-19 crisis led to the breakdown of community-based interactions, revealing the broken relational dynamics of cultural infrastructure. Our participants expressed that the closure of their physical locations during the pandemic had resulted in confusion and, sometimes, anger within the community. For example, Sophia shared her experience of getting a large number of patron calls and voicemails regarding her theater's shut-down:</p><p>We'd get voicemails [that said] "I didn't realize you were closed, when will you be reopen?" -well, I'd like to know that information myself. [...] It seemed like a personal inconvenience sometimes instead of a global emergency. And I understand, for some, [the theater] is a home away from home, but stay in your real home, please.</p><p>Depending on local policy, some participants' IMTs could temporarily reopen after mandatory lockdown orders were suspended. Kirk's theater could momentarily re-open by early July, which Kirk thought would stem the tide of disappearing revenue and engagement. The re-opening did not lead to business-as-normal and community members' actions compounded these issues. He described the tensions brought about by the local community and their resistance to mask-wearing mandates and related policies: I can't tell you the number of people that have screamed and yelled at us in our lobby because we want them to wear a mask. It's exhausting, I very much am tired of that. [...] I've had guys knock shit over in the lobby -I'm not going to force you to wear a mask, but you will leave. It's not a right to get to see a movie, tough guy.</p><p>This quote suggests a shift in the relationship between community members and IMTs. In this case, we see that community members' controversial attitudes towards safety mandates and the attempts by IMTs to follow those safety guidelines led to tensions that further broke down community engagement. Some community members were frustrated that they could no longer interact with their local cultural infrastructure in the way that they were used to. Such frustration could be displaced onto the theaters themselves and their employees, leading to greater disconnect between community members and their community establishments.</p><p>Moreover, some participants highlighted breakdowns that resulted from some individuals' concerns regarding their own personal health and safety. According to our participants surveyed, adults made up the largest demographic of patron communities. This population of older adults tended to be more vulnerable to serious COVID-19 infection, with CDC guidelines suggesting older adults avoid public locations and community gatherings <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[9]</ref>. These vulnerable community members' health concerns led to their reluctance to interact with public cultural infrastructure as they had before. For example, Cary was Director of Operations at an urban Southern theater with a predominately older audience and said as much: "When you have an older audience, they don't want to come in [again], they're the most cautious, they're the least likely to return to the cinemas."</p><p>As indicated, theaters had to contend with broken community relationships resulting from both health concerns and the resistance to those same health concerns. This resistance further disrupted attempts at re-opening as theaters had to calculate the benefts and risks of re-opening their establishments. Spencer articulated this process: Do you want to piss people of -[people like] big donors or people who are politicians in the town -or do you want to have an unsafe environment? [...] We don't want to bring in less money, but we don't want one of our [patrons] dying or one of the staf -a lot of the staf is at risk. [...] It's not worth it to make money for that.</p><p>The nature of IMTs role in the cultural infrastructure of local communities was disrupted and we see both the IMTs and the communities impacted by and contributing to this breakdown. While IMTs faced layofs to conserve money, attempts to re-open and recover monetarily were disrupted by patron concerns and a lack of available, knowledgeable staf. The community value of the physical place as a space to gather was broken down by both restrictive safety mandates and those community members that defed these mandates.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Sociotechnical of Maintaining Cultural Infrastructure</head><p>Participants shared a sense of uncertainty regarding what efective infrastructuring work and maintenance would be or what forms it should take. We unpack this sentiment in this section. In particular, we highlight the maintenance of cultural infrastructure upon its breakdown, be it technology or otherwise, and we discuss the opportunities and challenges associated with these practices.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.1">Collaborating with Community</head><p>Partners and External Stakeholders. In response to the aforementioned breakdowns, participants began to consider how to retain their arts engagement while their physical spaces were closed or open with limiting restrictions by mandate or caution. Initially, a common maintenance strategy was utilizing outdoor locations for flm screening while keeping distancing and other safety measures. To accomplish this, IMTs had to rely on community partners and external stakeholders to supply time, funding, or the physical outdoor space.</p><p>According to participants, these stakeholders and partners included city-specifc nonprofts, community banks, catering companies, artist collectives, and local universities. These stakeholders helped to create site-specifc, one-time events with IMTs. For example, Gene and Henry curated ofine screenings via donated drive-in spaces, Orson collaborated with artists to paint a screening room mural on their IMT's exterior for outdoor events, Rita screened movies for free on the sidewalk outside her cinema with the aid of nonprofts, and Greta worked with their university collaborators to screen a flm at the university's football stadium.</p><p>Yet, our analysis revealed challenges employees faced in coordinating with multiple stakeholders within their maintenance work. For example, Gene discussed the negotiation of space and execution as difcult, with multiple partners needing to come together for a single screening. For Gene, the original sponsor did not provide an outdoor location, leading him to negotiate with the local government for a municipal location. The execution of the event was further complicated as "most of our theater staf [was] furloughed and there just wasn't enough of a team on hand to handle" the event. Plans for a second screening were halted due to the municipal space being used for community hockey leagues while the local government suggested a beach-front event, a location that provided its own set of issues as the weather turned cold.</p><p>Besides the negotiation and coordination work with external stakeholders, IMT staf reported facing challenges resulting from limited profts needed to maintenance work. Participants admitted that they had to carefully calculate and navigate the tradeofs between generating business profts and serving the community. Such tension can be illustrated by a quote from Henry: "By the time we rent the equipment and get the rights to the flms, we're not making much, if any, actual money -but it's a really nice service to the community." In Henry's case, providing a service to the community is a trade-of for a lack Other participants, like Sophia and Humphrey, expressed being unwilling to continue with outdoor screenings after collecting little revenue, Sophia stating, "after our initial outdoor failure, we decided no more [...] We had to look for other ways to screen flms. " With physical maintenance work being difcult and costly, participants discussed fnding online forms of maintenance.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Screening</head><p>Films through Online Virtual Cinema Platforms. By April 2020, major independent flm distributors such as Kino Lorber, Music Box Films, Oscilloscope, and Film Movement had launched their own "virtual cinema" platforms that allowed IMTs to screen new flms online. 3 While participants were generally unsure about such unfamiliar and decentralized platforms, 90% of IMTs surveyed reported opting in to these virtual cinema platforms, in the hope of maintaining basic flm screenings and proft generation. Marlon, the programming coordinator at a historic IMT, described this decision making process:</p><p>It was funny, in a weekend these distributors came up with their platforms seemingly out of nowhere, all of a sudden. It was just bizarre to see things pop up that quick and to go from zero to a hundred in a week. That was kind of exhilarating and scary because we didn't really know what waters we were jumping into but we had to jump. IMTs attempted to use these distributor-created platforms as they would have used their physical space for screenings: patrons would be charged the same price, new flms would be promoted on the same channels and would be "released" on Fridays. In this way, Humphrey states, "I think everybody's sort of maintaining the illusion that you're going to the cinema again, even though you're not." It is worth highlighting the use of the phrase "maintaining the illusion" in this quote. Through turning to virtual cinema platforms, IMTs were trying to maintain cultural infrastructure's cohesive services to patrons. Yet, our analysis revealed infrastructuring work was required maintain this cohesive illusion and attempts sufered due to a lack of maintenance with regards to the symbolic dimensions of cultural infrastructure (as further elaborated in Discussion).</p><p>First, the additional labor involved the coordination of the decentralized virtual cinema platforms designed by diferent flm distributors. For patrons, they had to put efort into navigating diferent platforms with diferent usernames, passwords, necessary personal information, payment options, navigational tools, and data collection According to our participants' observations, this was especially difcult for older adult patrons with relatively lower digital dexterity. To this end, IMTs found themselves engaged in a new, unfamiliar, role as technical support to patron communities. This new role demanded IMT staf attend to both issues stemming from diferences in virtual cinema platforms and the situated technical issues experienced by patrons at distance (e.g., internet services, data retrieval, etc.). In Henry's words, it was "very difcult to provide technical support to our audiences when there were a dozen diferent ways that they could be watching these flms. " Marlon also mentioned the lack of unifying structure amongst the platforms as an issue that complicated maintenance, What desperately needs to happen is we need to fnd a consistent platform. [...] It's great that all these distributors had their own system set up, but it's frustrating when a customer watches this movie, it's [one kind of] experience and if they want to watch [that] movie, it can be a completely other experience. Everything is set up diferently. Some will work better than others. Some have better streaming quality than others. It'd be nice to have something consistent where we could a product in the way that we used to be able to. As Marlon and attested to, the quality of in-theater Digital Cinema Package (DCP) flm prints were uniform. This allowed the theaters to maintain a guarantee of quality of image, something that became inconsistent with virtual cinema systems. Not only would distributors now have variation in quality of image and display format but patrons themselves would have to contend with their own streaming quality and available equipment.</p><p>Problems also arose as the virtual cinema platforms did not maintain the IMT value of locality and placeness. After asking their local patrons for opinions on virtual cinema platforms, Cary reported, "the common response was, 'We want to go to a movie. We want to go to the movie theater'." In essence, the experience of community and community space was missing from the virtual cinema platforms. As Gene put it, the platforms did not "really give you that community feeling and if [patrons are] going to be watching stuf on their computer or TV, there are considerably easier and cheaper ways to do it." This lack of incentive to utilize the platforms and the lack of community-centered value on the virtual cinema platforms was a common complaint. Some participants speculated the virtual cinema flms would have been more successful in their IMT's physical space and with the community physically present to engage,</p><p>[Normally] what we have is a historic theater that people can come in and experience. But to just put a movie online and ask people to pay us -it doesn't make any sense to me. [...] I know if we had done [the flm] in person, it would have been a really deep and powerful experience and sold out and people would have been gushing about it. But [on virtual cinema] it just had 15 ticket sales. These issues coalesced and overall turnout to virtual cinema platforms was considered poor with 30% of respondents (n=13) feeling the virtual cinema platforms had "not worked well" or were "failures" while 50% (n=21) felt the platforms were "moderately successful". Participants like Kirk found the efort not worth the reward:</p><p>The only problem was it didn't amount to anything. Money-wise, like none of it, it was drops in the bucket. It was something to keep us busy and it looked nice. And I mean, we still have a virtual site on the page, up on our website with tons of movies. But I think last week, two people rented movie and that's like six bucks. We get a check for six bucks. [The platforms] send us one every once in a while, it's absolutely zero help fnancially. As in ofine maintenance (with outdoor screenings, the navigation of community partners, etc), online maintenance via virtual cinema platforms required and efort with often minimal attendance and revenue. with patron communities online also presented its own unique challenges, as discussed below.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.3">Retaining Community Members through Social Media Communication.</head><p>According to participants, social media were used by many IMTs pre-pandemic, but they became one of the only ways for IMTs to engage with their local communities during the pandemic. For instance, Errol described migrating to online engagement via social media out of "survival": "I wouldn't say we're pivoting because this is a new thing we want to do. It's a survival tactic, right? We're just trying to survive until we can reopen." Our preliminary survey results show that every theater actively used a social media platform for the purpose of community engagement at least one time per week. And 95% (n=40) of respondents admitted that their use of social media platforms had increased during the pandemic. During our interview, Marlon explained his use of social media platforms was a way to remain relevant to their local community, We've always used social media, but that has become more important than ever because that's really the only voice that we [have] today. main thing at the beginning of quarantine, our number one goal was to just stay relevant, no matter what, just do anything that we can to keep people entertained, to talk to the community, make sure the community knows we're still here.</p><p>Here, Marlon described his diverse attempts at communicating with patrons on social media as a way to sustain patrons in the present and retain their interest for the future when they can reopen in their original space. The issue of what to discuss was a prominent question early into the pandemic. Navigating this question required labor from IMT stafs as they attempted to adjust their strategies and messaging to engage their patrons efectively. As IMTs were closed and flms were not being released, messaging to the local community became "mostly ranting about how depressed I am or something, " as decribed by Cary. Another participant, Ingrid, similarly described the constant struggles and negotition in this form of maintenance work:</p><p>You have to keep that conversation going, right? You have to always be putting something out there for the other party to hear and see it and respond to you. And it's been really hard [...] fnding something that's worth saying versus, 'Hey, we're still closed. What a bummer.</p><p>It's going to be like this all year'. So I've defnitely struggled with [that]. [...] That's just kind of our ongoing struggle: how do we keep trying to reach out and have that open communication that we've been really good at [in the past] when we don't really have to say? During this time, participants' IMTs used their social media platforms to answer questions about their shutdowns, ask for donations and memberships in lieu of ticket sales, and conduct discussions about flm. IMT stafs put efort into navigating the trade-ofs among varied social media platforms' afordances to identify the one that best maintained the IMT environment or, as Bette said, tried to an environment for people to "socially interact" like they once did in the theater itself. While the majority of IMTs eventually turned to Facebook, several participants like Marlon and Sophia were quick to mention the older adults that made up their biggest demographic do not engage with them online. Ingrid also discussed this disconnect and told a story of an older community member and supporter who gave their stimulus check money to Ingrid's theater and "sends us physical mail all the time, but I don't think she's ever looked at our Facebook page. " This concern that the most vocal supporters and moneyed community members were not active on social platforms and thus lost to maintenance eforts was shared among participants.</p><p>Similar to aforementioned ofine maintenance eforts, retaining community members on social media was conditioned labor issues. Rita mentioned that her IMT was understafed and the labor of navigating social media engagement was too much for her alone to accomplish:</p><p>If we had an intern... But I think in many ways we are understafed-as is the case for many organizations. And that's probably why I do so many diferent things at the organization. But there hasn't really been the time, frankly, or the bandwidth to really focus on what it looks like to have our space be online. Here, Rita discusses the burden resulting from undertaking multiple forms of maintenance work simultaneously. In addition, some participants considered community engagement maintenance efforts challenging due to the change in materiality from ofine to online spaces. For instance, Henry said the crowded space made diferentiation difcult, especially during the pandemic,</p><p>[We] absolutely used Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram to share information about screenings, to activate peoto communicate about flm [...] Now I feel like it's easy to get lost in the deluge because everyone is using social media to a much higher degree -individuals and organizations alike -than they were prior to the start of the pandemic. Online interactions grew in scope and frequency during the pandemic, as ofine spaces broke down and individuals and organizations needed an outlet for engagement. Consequently, it is perhaps unsurprising that IMTs had difculty standing out. Besides, participants also shared concerns that the change in engagement medium had reconfgured the theater had to ofer. Marlene articulated, "How do you keep people engaged [online] when so much of what you actually do is to bring people together physically, right? [...] It's hard to engage people that way and say, Oh, this is special." To Marlene, the shift in the materiality of the space forced her to reconsider what engagement was and how to go about creating it.</p><p>More importantly, we found that IMT staf's maintenance work was an evolving process of negotiating and adjusting what, how, and when to maintain. And this process required emotional labor and situated judgment from stafs, which were often invisible. For example, Clint described his initial eforts with Zoom Q&amp;A sessions at the beginning of the pandemic as "demoralizing" because of the low attendance. After several failed trials on Zoom, Clint decided to switch to Facebook for Q&amp;A livestreaming, where the theater already had a built-in audience. The chats would be archived on Facebook, eventually leading to "really solid, healthy" post-live engagement. For other theaters, this exploratory phase of online community engagement ended after initial disappointments, as in the case of Cary, who said, "I hate Twitter. I hate that kind of social engagement work. [...] I don't see any relation between engagement with Facebook and attendance" after eforts to engage on social media did not return revenue.</p><p>of post-pandemic plans tended to gravitate towards taking the experiments implemented and lessons learned during the pandemic and integrating them into eventual ofine engagements, which are ultimately seen as essential. As such, participants thought of their experiments in virtual art and community engagement as maintenance that will continue into the future, albeit with their ofine presentations and engagements intact. It is then clear that the (re)confguration and (re)making of cultural infrastructure has been occurring and will continue to be in fux.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">DISCUSSION</head><p>To summarize, through a preliminary survey with staf members from 42 U.S.-based IMTs and in-depth interviews with staf from 18 IMTs, this paper has unpacked ways in which the health crisis has disrupted IMTs' role in facilitating art and cultural engagement and supporting community engagement as part of the cultural infrastructure. As a result of unanticipated closure in the wake of the COVID-19 pandemic, such infrastructural breakdowns happened at both the organizational and community levels. To maintain the broken cultural infrastructure, IMTs turned to networked technologies and platforms to encourage new forms of engagement with culture and communities. We have unpacked three salient sociotechnical practices of maintaining broken cultural infrastructure. These socio-technical maintenance practices include 1) coordinating with community partners and external stakeholders for support, using online virtual cinema platforms patrons to from home, and 3) retaining community members and community engagement through social media communication (RQ1). In this process, IMT stafs had to take on additional labor in coordination and negotiation in the maintenance work, which was often invisible and under-appreciated. While this maintenance work has shown promise to diferent extents, our work has shed light on the limitations of current techno-solutions in mediating these aforementioned interactions. The value of these human-to-human and human-to-artifact interactions lies in their locality, accessibility, and the environment in which these interactions happen, which is not fully supported by presently available techno-solutions.</p><p>In the sections that follow, we synthesize our work and address RQ2 by frst discussing the material and symbolic dimensions of infrastructuring as unpacked in our work. We then discuss the invisible work of maintaining cultural infrastructure carried out by human labor. We conclude by unpacking the importance of making space for cultural infrastructure in HCI scholarship. The meaning of making space is two-fold here. First, cultural infrastructure-an often overlooked but critical kind of infrastructure in our everyday life-should be foregrounded and deserve further understanding in HCI and neighboring felds. Second, cultural infrastructure often relies on cultural spaces. Our paper has shown how the concepts of space and place has been contested and shifted during the health crisis. In the light of re-emergence from infrastructural breakdown, this work urges us to rethink the future of cultural spaces and how technologies may reconfgure cultural infrastructure and our experiences interacting with it. Together, this work intends to make visible both the cultural infrastructure and the human labor involved in maintaining cultural infrastructure.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Maintaining the Symbolic and Material Dimensions of Cultural Infrastructure</head><p>Cultural infrastructure is built upon cultural institutions and spaces, be it library, theater, or museum. During the pandemic, the interactions that were taking place in the ofine IMT space had to be moved into online spaces, which changed both the materiality and symbolic meanings of IMTs and cultural infrastructure. In this section, we discuss these two distinct properties and their infrastructural value.</p><p>On the one hand, as we have shown in the fndings, the materiality of the IMT lies in its physical space where various social interactions are cultivated. Interactions embodied in the theater's space include human-to-human (e.g., patron-to-patron, patron-to-IMT-staf), human-to-artifact (e.g., patron-to-flm), and human-tocommunity-environment. The physical space is also tied to its specifc community and the people therein, informing the interactions and artifacts available to each locality <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. On the other hand, our fndings have also shed light into the symbolic meanings of IMTs and cultural infrastructure. These theaters symbolic spaces that serve to distribute and exchange art and culture through their given communities. The IMT is a lieu de mémoire, serving as cultural historical marker for a community's collective memory <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[52]</ref>. In thinking with Harrison and Dourish's seminal work of Re-Placing Space, IMTs in our case demonstrate the placeness that displays shared social meanings within the community <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[24]</ref>. As culture and cultural beliefs and artifacts are exchanged, the place in which these exchanges occur becomes part of the exchange itself. This becomes truer the longer the space remains, as theaters built in the 1920s and 1930s become anchors of their given community <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[48]</ref>. As noted by participants, patrons have specifc memories and shared identities tied to their community's theater and, as they age, they bring their children and grandchildren to cultivate those same experiences.</p><p>With the disruption of cultural infrastructure due to the COVID-19 crisis, both the material and symbolic dimensions of the cultural infrastructure were forced to undergo reconfguration. The IMT employees attempted to maintain art and community engagementthe interactions-during the pandemic through ongoing infrastructuring. But the physical space could not be maintained with any degree of certainty. Instead, many of the interactions that were taking place within the IMT space had to be moved into diferent spaces (that were often mediated through technologies). With the diferent materiality of medium and space through which the interactions were conducted, the symbolic meanings and orders unfolded through these interactions were also reshaped. Recall from Marlene that engaging community online was essentially diferent from bringing people together physically even though patrons technically "gathered" in one way or another, and recall from Cary that seeing a flm via virtual cinema was diferent going to the physical theater even though the flm was technically "watched" by the audience. While maintaining art and community engagement through technical means appears straightforward (movies still play, conversation still fows), these attempts were not always as fruitful as stafs had initially hoped, perhaps due to the mismatch between the expected/patron-desired symbolic properties of cultural infrastructure and the symbolic meanings unfolded through the replicated forms of interactions. It was perhaps this mismatch that made what Humphrey described as "maintaining the illusion" especially challenging.</p><p>We argue that attending to this material and symbolic gap is critical to future HCI research that looks into the breakdown, maintenance, and repair of infrastructure. We have shown that in the case of IMTs, leaving such gaps unattuned could lead to disruptions to the community's identity and bonding, refected in the decreased material attendance and revenue from outdoor and virtual screenings and other engagements. Future discourse in infrastructuring should contend with the maintenance of symbolicity-whether, and if so how, one maintain an ofine embodied feeling online?</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Invisible Work of Maintaining Cultural Infrastructure</head><p>In this work, we have discussed a specifc moment of breakdown and the attempts at maintenance. This breakdown has changed what ofine cultural infrastructure afords to their local communities.</p><p>While and CSCW research has discussed sociotechnical maintenance during COVID-19 from educational [43], health <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, and business [49] perspectives, pandemic's efects on recreational and cultural spaces has not been documented to the same degree. The implications of the infrastructural breakdown into this sector deserves more attention. The ramifcations of this breakdown are far-reaching and are often beyond the scope of both this paper and the stafs attempting maintenance at independent movie theaters. For instance, consider the material implications of Warner Bros. decision to debut all of its 2021 flms on the HBO Max streaming service the same day as the flms' releases into theaters <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[46]</ref>. We have documented breakdowns and maintenance during the COVID-19 pandemic as IMT stafs attempted to recaparts and community engagement. Here, the infrastructuring work of IMT stafs speaks to the vulnerability of cultural infrastructure and its stafs. Aligning with past HCI studies <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[23]</ref>, the infrastructuring work identifed in our case was often done invisibly and, occasionally, at odds with a divided public. As infrastructuring work is emergent, it leads to confrontation and negotiation <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[17]</ref>. Recall that stafs had to navigate a public that could be confrontational or, otherwise, precautious to re-enter the theater's space. Additionally, stafs and the public had to navigate multiple online spaces to the same experience that they would have had in one ofine space (i.e., information acquisition, art engagement, community engagement), leading to issues with divided attention, multiple pressure points for further breakdown, and attendance drop-of (i.e., fnd showtimes on IMT website, watch a flm via virtual cinema, share feelings after flm on Facebook, join Q&amp;A and discussion on Zoom). And as suggested in our results, this process was accompanied by irregular and responsive coordination and emotional labor and their accompanying struggles, which were rendered invisible <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[47]</ref>.</p><p>The taken-for-grantedness of stafs' eforts towards reopening the physical space with restrictions or attempting new online engagements was apparent. The public held pandemic restrictions in contempt while issues with online platforms hindered their potential, led to complaints, and added additional labor onto stafs. These issues speak to misalignments throughout maintenance efforts across diferent levels. IMT stafs and patrons were misaligned on how to reopen safely and which technological measures would best maintain the material and symbolic properties of infrastructure. IMT stafs and distributors were misaligned on how virtual cinema systems should be designed and implemented. Virtual cinema systems imposed design constraints that IMT stafs could not modify while IMT stafs invisibly attempted troubleshooting methods for interfacing with the public.</p><p>Additionally, each theater had its own localized value within its distinct community and needed to maintain its situated value within the community. As such, participants from diverse locations faced diferent challenges within their communities depending on the local sociopolitical and cultural constructs (e.g., apprehension restrictions and local business relations). Similarly, each theater had diferent demographics of participants which infuenced their digital profciency and the level of being comfortable with technology use. These complicating factors distinguished the various eforts of the IMT stafs and made the already invisible work more difcult for some locations. Future HCI work on cultural infrastructure should continue to document infrastructuring work, the stafs that navigate the changing world of cultural spaces, and the efectiveness and limitations of technology in cultural infrastructuring work. Future work should also investigate community engagement and the community's perspective the above issues, and ways in which local constructs shape how cultural infrastructure is emerged, maintained, and evolved. focus on maintenance and infrastructuring work allows for an exploration of the value of such work and provides us with an opportunity to question what we want out of these spaces, both ofine and online, what benefts technology can bring to the sector, and what additional labor is required a workforce.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Making Space for Cultural Infrastructure in HCI</head><p>To date, HCI research regarding cultural infrastructure has been scattered and infrequent. Cultural spaces like museums have been in a state of fux, with issues such as digital archives, technologically augmented spaces, and technology-supported or augmented experiences being discussed as major changes within the GLAMA-ZONS sector <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[28]</ref>. With this work, we call the expanding of HCI discourse on infrastructure and infrastructuring work, and making space for discussing culture and community engagement, the arts and cultural sharing, and cultural infrastructure. In contrast to well-studied essential social and human infrastructures, cultural infrastructure speaks to recreational and cultural needs that remain less tangible and embodied. Going forward, existing lines of research within HCI should be placed into fruitful dialogue with each other to craft the space of cultural infrastructure within our feld. First, despite not being explicitly framed as cultural infrastructure, prior work has looked into deploying digital technologies to support direct interactions and visiting experiences occurring in cultural institutions and physical spaces (mostly in museums and libraries) <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[20]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[21]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[22]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b31">33]</ref>. The infrastructural lens can push us to rethink the taken-for-granted settings of such research: How do the cultural institutions and spaces like IMTs and museums come into being? What invisible labor and human involvement is necessary to support such institutions and spaces? Who is doing infrastructuring work to support individuals' and communities' cultural and recreational needs and for whom? And importantly, whose culture is included and whose is excluded in the process of infrastructuring?</p><p>To this end, it is worth noting the existing unequal access and representation of local communities in cultural institutions and the sociotechnical solutions' potential role in perpetuating this inequality. For instance, digitization practices increase diversity in online museum collections while indigenous artists feel no beneft from their works being digitized <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[42]</ref>. How can technology-supported infrastructure be designed and supported in equitable and localized ways? How can participatory co-design infuence the implementation of efective sociotechnical solutions into cultural infrastructure? Building on the works of Fuks et al. and Ciolf et al., future research investigate new forms of community co-design and participatory design methods within other cultural infrastructures and with an emphasis on preserving space, local culture, and community values <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b18">20]</ref>. As discussed in our work, shifts in space and design can present signifcantly altered meanings to the community for which these shifts were thought to be benefcial. These ideas and more could promote a vibrant cultural infrastructure that presents new design opportunities and research potentials.</p><p>Second, aligned with existing research focusing on communitysituated institutions, we see in this case the locus of proft and control is shifted out of the hands of locally-controlled cultural infrastructure and into the hands of networked entities and platforms (such as virtual cinema and social media platforms) whose mission might not directly aligned with the interests, needs, and mission of local IMTs and community members. As shown in this work, the promise of these networked technologies and platforms demanded ongoing maintenance work from IMT stafs and communities members on the ground. The labor that was originally dedicated to community needs might have been misplaced to platform expansion and development, which can be naturalized as part of the necessary maintenance work. In this light, this work raises critical questions about how our social, cultural, and human networks are technologically supported (or not). particular, it urges us to continue questioning how the afordances of existing networked technologies and platforms shift power, control, and capacity into and/or out of local communities, especially in the form less tangible interests and needs. These observations raises important questions for design: How can we better support local cultural infrastructure that are uniquely tailored to and uniquely charged with local community building as they seek to foster refection, dialogue, and social connection within their community? Furthermore, we argue that making space for cultural infrastructure is concerned with the making and sustaining of cultural spaces. With regards to cultural infrastructure, we have investigated the changing nature of ofine and online spaces to consider the question, what is "space"? The cultural spaces being modifed aspire to be sites of memory that contain, create, and remake community and cultural identities <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[39]</ref>. They support cultural heritage and act as places for community members to gather, bringing together members of the local community that might not meet otherwise. As Löw puts it, "Space makes us realize that things can hardly be experienced in isolation" <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[32]</ref>. In other words, the materiality of physical space invites certain interactions. In this light, future work should investigate aspects of cultural infrastructure such as history, community, identity, and memory to see if and how technologies and their digital spaces can replicate maintain these subjects, and community aspirations and values.</p><p>In light of this question, we want to rethink the future of cultural infrastructure and spaces, their community value, and community participation within them. Our work provides initial insights into an aspect of cultural infrastructure, however, further studies regarding, for instance, community perspectives cultural infrastructure and community support and engagement are required. Klinenberg suggests urban resilience can be measured both on the condition of basic utilities and the condition of parks, libraries, and community organizations that provide "social support" <ref type="bibr" target="#b34">[36]</ref> for residents, while art projects like Philadelphia Assembled utilize community participation to excavate community history and provide space for knowledge gathering and wellness <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[40]</ref>. As has been shown in previous work, engagement with culture and cultural spaces has an efect on mental health and well-being <ref type="bibr">[10]</ref>. With the COVID-19 pandemic exacerbating mental health issues globally [16], the HCI community should refect on whether, and if so, how the renewal of cultural infrastructure and spaces can aid in our collective recovery from this historic (mental) health crisis.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">LIMITATIONS AND FUTURE WORK</head><p>Our study was limited to survey and interviews with IMT staf about their perspectives and experiences during the COVID-19 pandemic as in-person observation were not possible during the COVID-19. We note that actors outside of independent movie theaters also contribute to the maintenance of cultural infrastructure, such as patron community members. Future research can look into how patron community members contribute to infrastructuring work upon cultural infrastructure breakdown and their personal perspectives on the properties and value of cultural spaces. In addition, all interviews were conducted with independent movie theaters within the U.S. We believe the fndings within this paper can be generalized to other contexts, but future research on specifc aspects of cultural infrastructure should engage with particular contexts of local communities.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="7">CONCLUSION</head><p>Due to the COVID-19 health crisis, cultural infrastructure and public cultural spaces-including theaters, museums, libraries, galleriesclosed overnight. This unprecedented crisis has greatly disrupted the ways individuals and communities access and engage with cultural artifacts. Similarly, the ways in which people interact with one another through cultural spaces and artifacts has been reconfgured. This paper ofers empirical insights from this particular moment. We reported on the cultural infrastructure breakdowns on diferent levels and the infrastructuring work undertaken by IMT stafs that attempted to maintain the function of the cultural infrastructure. By highlighting the human labor involved in the maintenance work, our work intends to advocate for these eforts and make visible the role of culture and cultural infrastructure in our collective re-emergence from the global health crisis. Indeed, our empirical investigation shows the promises and limitations of technology use in maintaining and repairing broken infrastructure amid a crisis, which identifes ways in which future HCI work can support the recovery reinvention of cultural spaces and infrastructures post-pandemic and beyond.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>[</head><label></label><figDesc>Patrons] are not just showing up to see what's going to make the most money. You're going to see Parasite, which at the time [of its original release] was a somewhat obscure foreign flm. But the patrons trust you. So people come in and they're like, 'That was amazing. That totally makes me rethink my role in the world'.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Participant Summary respondents if they would be willing to participate in a follow-up interview. We deployed our survey on Qualtrics in August, 2020.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Name</cell><cell>Position</cell><cell cols="2">State Region</cell></row><row><cell>Cary</cell><cell>Director of Operations</cell><cell>AL</cell><cell>South</cell></row><row><cell cols="3">Humphrey Programming &amp; Media Coordinator TX</cell><cell>South</cell></row><row><cell>Rita</cell><cell>Director of Programming</cell><cell>NY</cell><cell>Northeast</cell></row><row><cell>Marlon</cell><cell cols="2">Programming &amp; Media Coordinator MI</cell><cell>Midwest</cell></row><row><cell>Ingrid</cell><cell cols="2">Director of Operations and Finance ID</cell><cell>Midwest</cell></row><row><cell>Bette</cell><cell>Director of Operations</cell><cell>KS</cell><cell>Midwest</cell></row><row><cell>Kirk</cell><cell>Theater Manager</cell><cell>OK</cell><cell>South</cell></row><row><cell>Gene</cell><cell>Director of Operations</cell><cell>NY</cell><cell>Northeast</cell></row><row><cell>Orson</cell><cell>Volunteer</cell><cell>MI</cell><cell>Midwest</cell></row><row><cell>Clint</cell><cell>Theater Manager</cell><cell>MA</cell><cell>Northeast</cell></row><row><cell>Henry</cell><cell>Executive Director</cell><cell>NY</cell><cell>Northeast</cell></row><row><cell>Greta</cell><cell>Associate Director</cell><cell>IN</cell><cell>Midwest</cell></row><row><cell>Spencer</cell><cell>Theater Manager</cell><cell>IN</cell><cell>Midwest</cell></row><row><cell>Clara</cell><cell>Executive Director</cell><cell>UT</cell><cell>West</cell></row><row><cell>Errol</cell><cell>Executive Director</cell><cell>OR</cell><cell>West</cell></row><row><cell>Marlene</cell><cell>Executive Director</cell><cell>MI</cell><cell>Midwest</cell></row><row><cell>Sophia</cell><cell>Theater Manager</cell><cell>MI</cell><cell>Midwest</cell></row><row><cell>James</cell><cell cols="2">Programming &amp; Media Coordinator CA</cell><cell>West</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">The Art House Convergence is a community-based international network of independent and art house cinemas, flm societies, university cinemas, micro-cinemas, and more. See https://www.arthouseconvergence.org/</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="2">Taguette is an open-source and free qualitative research tool that allows collaborative data coding and analysis. See https://www.taguette.org/</note>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="3">Virtual cinema platforms provide video-on-demand streaming services to viewers, specifc to each distributor. They allow independent flm distributors to release new and repertory flms through IMT websites, while viewers' admission payments are shared between flm distributors and the IMT of the viewer's choice<ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[18]</ref>.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>We would like to thank our participants for sharing their time, insights, and struggles with us. We hope and trust all independent movie theaters discussed in this work are doing well and continue to do well into the future. We also thank the front of house employees at our local independent movie theaters for their work. Finally, we very much appreciate our anonymous reviewers Yuchen Chen for their constructive input and feedback on our drafts.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Community gardens: Space for interactions and adaptations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Imas</forename><surname>Agustina</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ruth</forename><surname>Beilin</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Procedia-social Behavioral sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">36</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="439" to="448" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012. 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Engaging Ofine Communities COVID-19: A Case Study of Independent Theaters</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Sam</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alex</forename><forename type="middle">Jiahong</forename><surname>Ankenbauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3406865.3418323</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3406865.3418323" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference Companion Publication of the 2020 on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (Virtual Event, USA) (CSCW &apos;20 Companion)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="209" to="213" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Glimmer of Hope&quot;: Challenges and Resilience among U.S. Older Adults in Seeking COVID-19 Vaccination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alex Jiahong</forename><surname>Sam Addison Ankenbauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3462204.3481768</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Companion Publication of the 2021 Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work and Social Computing (Virtual Event, USA) (CSCW &apos;21)</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kwame</forename><surname>Anthony</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Appiah</forename></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Princeton University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1998">2021. 1998</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="10" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Navigating the. Race, culture, identity: Misunderstood connections</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Guif. net, a crowdsourced network infrastructure held in common</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roger</forename><surname>Baig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ramon</forename><surname>Roca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Felix</forename><surname>Freitag</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Leandro</forename><surname>Navarro</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Networks</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">90</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="150" to="165" />
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015. 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Analyzing qualitative data: Systematic approaches</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H Russell</forename><surname>Bernard</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amber</forename><surname>Wutich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gery W</forename><surname>Ryan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>SAGE publications</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Information acumen: The understanding and use of knowledge in modern business</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Geofrey</forename><surname>Bowker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994. 1994</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="247" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Information mythology: The world of/as information</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Arts, dance, cultural infrastructure, and city regeneration: Knowledge, audience development, networks, and conventions, and the relocation of a Royal Ballet company from London to Birmingham</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>John R Bryson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Norsk Geografsk Tidsskrift-Norwegian Journal of Geography</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="98" to="110" />
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Older Adults Take Steps to Protect Yourself</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Cdc</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.cdc.gov/coronavirus/2019-ncov/need-extra-precautions/older-adults.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Museums, health and well-being</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helen</forename><surname>Chatterjee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Guy</forename><surname>Noble</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Articulating Co-Design in Museums: Refections on Two Participatory Processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luigina</forename><surname>Ciolf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gabriela</forename><surname>Avram</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Maye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nick</forename><surname>Dulake</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Marshall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dick</forename><surname>Van Dijk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fiona</forename><surname>Mcdermott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2818048.2819967</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2818048.2819967" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing</title>
				<meeting>the 19th ACM Conference on Computer-Supported Cooperative Work &amp; Social Computing<address><addrLine>San Francisco, California, USA; New York, NY</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="13" to="25" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CSCW &apos;16)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Culture Track &apos;17</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laplaca</forename><surname>Cohen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://2017study.culturetrack.com/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Aea Consulting</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Cultural Infrastructure</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016. 2016. 2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page">3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">About Us, Art House Convergence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Art</forename><surname>House Convergence</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.arthouseconvergence.org/index.php/about/" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">2020. NATO Statement on Coronovirus and the Movie Theater Industry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Corcoran</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mental health in the COVID-19 pandemic</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Cullen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gulati</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Kelly</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">QJM: An International Journal of Medicine</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">113</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="311" to="312" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Un Grano de Arena: Infrastructural Care, Social Media Platforms, and the Venezuelan Humanitarian Crisis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michaelanne</forename><surname>Dye</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021. 2021</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">W3</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">During coronavirus closures, indie movie theaters turn to online &apos;screenings&apos;. Los Angeles Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ryan</forename><surname>Faughnder</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.latimes.com/entertainment-arts/business/story/2020-04-08/your-local-cinema-is-closed-because-of-coronavirus-heres-how-you-can-help-save-it" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-03-02">2020. 8 April 2020. March 2</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Positive afect and the complex dynamics of human fourishing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Barbara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Fredrickson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Losada</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American psychologist</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">678</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005. 2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Collaborative Museums: An Approach to Co-Design</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hugo</forename><surname>Fuks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Heloisa</forename><surname>Moura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Debora</forename><surname>Cardador</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Katia</forename><surname>Vega</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wallace</forename><surname>Ugulino</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marcos</forename><surname>Barbato</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2145204.2145307</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2145204.2145307" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the ACM 2012 Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW &apos;12)</title>
				<meeting>the ACM 2012 Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW &apos;12)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="681" to="684" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beyond Boundaries: Towards Symbiotic Relationship Between Ecological Arts and Computational for Sustainability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">'</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Snehalkumar 'neil</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Gaikwad</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3406865.3418336</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3406865.3418336" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Conference Companion Publication of the 2020 on Computer Cooperative Work and Social Computing (Virtual Event, USA) (CSCW Companion). Association for Machinery</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="257" to="262" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Revisiting the Visit: Understanding How Technology Can Shape the Museum Visit</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rebecca</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Grinter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Aoki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Margaret</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Szymanski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">James</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Thornton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Allison</forename><surname>Woodruf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Hurst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/587078.587100</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/587078.587100" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2002 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
				<meeting>the 2002 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work<address><addrLine>New Orleans, Louisiana, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2002">2002</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="155" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CSCW &apos;02)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Making Healthcare Infrastructure Work: Unpacking the Infrastructuring Work of Individuals</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gui</forename></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yunan</forename><surname>Chen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290605.3300688</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3290605.3300688" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="14" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Re-Place-Ing The Roles of Place and Space in Collaborative Systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Dourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/240080.240193</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/240080.240193" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 1996 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
				<meeting>the 1996 ACM Conference on Computer Supported Cooperative Work<address><addrLine>Boston, Massachusetts, USA; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="76" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>CSCW &apos;96)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Human Library: Understanding Experience Sharing for Community Knowledge Building (CSCW &apos;17)</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yun</forename><surname>Huang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Dobreski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Huichuan</forename><surname>Xia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2998181.2998312</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2998181.2998312" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1152" to="1165" />
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Studying Infrastructuring Ethnographically</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Helena</forename><surname>Karasti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jeanette</forename><surname>Blomberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1007/s10606-017-9296-7</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1007/s10606-017-9296-7" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">An Afterword to &apos;Infrastructuring and Collaborative Design&apos;. Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Karasti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Pipek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Bowker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="267" to="289" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Digital Future of Museums: Conversations and Provocations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Winesmith</forename><surname>Keir</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anderson</forename><surname>Suse</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4324/9780429491573</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.4324/9780429491573" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Adding Culture to UX: UX Research Methodologies and Applications in Cultural Heritage</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Markos</forename><surname>Konstantakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">George</forename><surname>Caridakis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3354002</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3354002" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Comput. Cult. Herit</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-02">2020. Feb. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Human Infrastructure of Cyberinfrastructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charlotte</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Dourish</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gloria</forename><surname>Mark</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<pubPlace>New York, NY, USA</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A bridge too far?: Critical remarks on the concept of &quot;infrastructure&quot; in computer-supported cooperative work and information systems</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Charlotte</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kjeld</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Socio-Informatics</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The sociology of space: Materiality, social structures, and action</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Martina</forename><surname>Low</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>Palgrave MacMillan</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>xiv pages</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mediating an Invisible Relation: Formalizing the Exhibition as the Linking Artifact between Curators and Visitors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Teresa</forename><surname>Macchia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2662155.2662242</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2662155.2662242" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the Participatory Design Conference: Short Papers, Industry Cases, Workshop Descriptions, Doctoral Consortium Papers, and Keynote Abstracts -Volume</title>
				<meeting>the Participatory Design Conference: Short Papers, Industry Cases, Workshop Descriptions, Doctoral Consortium Papers, and Keynote Abstracts -Volume<address><addrLine>Windhoek, Namibia; New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="229" to="232" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>PDC &apos;14)</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Role of the Arts and Culture in the Future of Travel and Tourism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Laura</forename><surname>Mandala</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">132</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding a new normal: the role of technology in life disruptions</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Massimi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jill</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Dimond</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher A Le</forename><surname>Dantec</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the acm 2012 conference on computer supported cooperative work</title>
				<meeting>the acm 2012 conference on computer supported cooperative work</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="719" to="728" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Library as infrastructure</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shannon</forename><surname>Mattern</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Places Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014. 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Innovative IoT-Aware Services for a Smart Museum</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Vincenzo</forename><surname>Mighali</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><forename type="middle">Del</forename><surname>Fiore</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luigi</forename><surname>Patrono</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Luca</forename><surname>Mainetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefano</forename><surname>Alletto</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Giuseppe</forename><surname>Serra</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rita</forename><surname>Cucchiara</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 24th International Conference on World Wide Web</title>
				<meeting>the 24th International Conference on World Wide Web<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="547" to="550" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Everyone Included: Social Impact of COVID-19</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.un.org/development/desa/dspd/everyone-included-covid-19.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>The United Nations</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Between Memory and History: Les Lieux de Mémoire</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pierre</forename><surname>Nora</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://www.jstor.org/stable/2928520" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Representations</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">26</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="24" />
			<date type="published" when="1989">1989. 1989</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">from http://phlassembled.net/ sovereignty/events/health_is_wealth_holistic_wellness/ The Institute of Museum and Library Services. 2020. Public Libraries in the United States: Fiscal year 2017</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-10-01">2017. 2017. Oct 1, 2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2020</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">6</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Health is Wealth Holistic Wellness, Philadelphia Assembled</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">France and the restitution of cultural goods: the Sarr-Savoy report and its reception</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jonathan</forename><surname>Paquette</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Cultural Trends</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="302" to="316" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The Use of Digital Educational Resources in the Process of Teaching and Learning in Pandemic by COVID-19</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ricardo</forename><surname>Pocinho</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pedro</forename><forename type="middle">Cristovão</forename><surname>Margarido</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rui</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sandrina</forename><surname>Milhano</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Bruno</forename><surname>Trindade</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gisela</forename><surname>Santos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3434780.3436589</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3434780.3436589" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Eighth International Conference on Technological Ecosystems for Enhancing Multiculturality</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="810" to="816" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Sociotechnical Studies of Cyberinfrastructure and e-Research: Current Themes and Future Trajectories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">David</forename><surname>Ribes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Charlotte</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Lee</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Computer Supported Cooperative Work</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="231" to="244" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010. 2010</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational artifacts: interactive and collaborative computing as an integral feature of work</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kjeld</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jørgen</forename><surname>Bansler</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">COOP 2016: Proceedings of the 12th International Conference on the Design of Cooperative Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Trento, Italy</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2016-05-27">2016. 23-27 May 2016</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="21" to="38" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Dune, Matrix 4, and Every 2021 Warner Bros. Film to on HBO Max and in Theaters at Same Time</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zack</forename><surname>Sharf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.indiewire.com/2020/12/dune-matrix-all-warner-bros-flms-hbo-max-1234602168/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020. 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Steps Toward an Ecology of Infrastructure: Design and Access for Large Information Spaces</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Star</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">K</forename><surname>Ruhleder</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Inf. Syst. Res</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="111" to="134" />
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996. 1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Senator Theatre on national list as endangered</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jamie</forename><surname>Stiehm</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.baltimoresun.com/news/bs-xpm-2001-06-26-0106260011-story.htmlHussainSyed" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Sascha Skudelny, Helena Karasti, and Volkmar Pipek. 2021. Infrastructuring for organizational resilience: Experiences and perspectives business continuity</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Sam Ankenbauer, Sohaib Hassan, Konrad Meisner, Martin Stein</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001. 2001</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Public parks and the pandemic: How park usage has been afected by COVID-19 policies</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Zoe</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joel</forename><forename type="middle">O</forename><surname>Volenec</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alexander</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Abraham</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andy</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Becker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Dobson</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">PloS one</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">5</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Everyday Resilience: Supporting Resilient Strategies among Low Socioeconomic Status Communities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dhaval</forename><surname>Vyas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tawanna</forename><surname>Dillahunt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Memory&apos;s Remains: Les lieux de mémoire</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nancy</forename><surname>Wood</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">History and memory</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="123" to="149" />
			<date type="published" when="1994">1994. 1994</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Making Space for Culture</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sophia</forename><surname>Woodley</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tim</forename><surname>Jones</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017. 2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Supporting Community-Building in Digital Libraries: A Pilot Study of Library Thing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Adam</forename><surname>Worrall</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings the 73rd ASIS&amp;T Annual Meeting on Navigating Streams in an Information Ecosystem</title>
				<meeting>the 73rd ASIS&amp;T Annual Meeting on Navigating Streams in an Information Ecosystem</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>American Society for Information Science</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">47</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>3 pages</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Volkmar</forename><surname>Volker Wulf</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Markus</forename><surname>Pipek</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Rohde</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Stevens</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Randall</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Socio Informatics-A Practice-based Perspective</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
