<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">How to get away with cyberatacks An argumentative approach to cyberatacks&apos; legitimization &lt;strike/&gt;by common users</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Spagnolli</surname></persName>
							<email>anna.spagnolli@unipd.it</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Zuf</forename><surname>Beatrice</surname></persName>
							<email>beatrice.zuf@unipd.it</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><roleName>Mariavittoria, Masotina</roleName><forename type="first">Anna</forename><surname>Lorena</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><surname>Scarcia</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><surname>Beatrice</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Luciano</forename><surname>Zuf</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Gamberini</forename><surname>Luciano</surname></persName>
							<email>luciano.gamberini@unipd.it</email>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Dept. of General Psychology and Mariavittoria</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Masotina Dept. of General Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep3">Scarcia Dept. of General Psychology</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">Human Inspired Technologies University of Padova University of Padova Research Centre</orgName>
								<address>
									<settlement>Anna Lorena</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="institution">University of Padova</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of Public, International and Community Law</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Padova</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="department">Dept. of General Psychology and Human Inspired Technologies Research Centre</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">University of Padova</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">How to get away with cyberatacks An argumentative approach to cyberatacks&apos; legitimization &lt;strike/&gt;by common users</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3517444</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T05:05+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>Cyber-attacks</term>
					<term>Argumentation</term>
					<term>Cybersecurity</term>
					<term>Human factors</term>
					<term>Persuasion</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>The possibility that common users are successfully recruited in cyberattacks represents a considerable vulnerability because it implies that citizens can legitimize cyberattacks instead of condemning them. We propose to adopt an argumentative approach to identify which premises allow such legitimization. To showcase this approach, we created four short narratives describing cyberattacks involving generic users and covering diferent motives for the attacks: proft, recreation, revenge, and ideology. A sample of 16 participants read the four narratives and was afterward interviewed to express their position on the attacks described. All interview transcripts were then analyzed with an argumentative approach, and 15 premises were found to account for the diferent positions taken. We describe the premises, their distribution across the four narratives, and discuss the implications of this approach for cybersecurity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Security and privacy → Human and societal aspects of security and privacy; Social aspects of security and privacy.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>The attacks on computerized systems, or cyberattacks, are intuitively attributed to skillful developers and criminal communities both in popular culture and in criminology <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[59]</ref>. However, some cyberattacks can result from the deliberate contribution of common users, who lack programming skills and are unfamiliar with cybercriminal communities. For instance, common citizens can be involved in cyberattacks executed via Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS), ransomware, and malware. The frst type of attack, DDoS, engenders an abnormal increase in the data trafc of the targeted server, to the point of depleting its computing power, memory, or bandwidth <ref type="bibr" target="#b59">[58]</ref>. Common users believing that the targeted server deserves some punishment can easily be instructed on how to contribute to the attack. The second type of attack, via ransomware, rests on software that seems like regular software by a trustworthy source; the users installing it on their computers, however, will no longer be able to access the computer system or data. To unlock their computers, they will need to pay a full ransom or spread the ransomware among their contacts <ref type="bibr" target="#b41">[42]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[52]</ref> and become attackers themselves. Finally, software designed with malicious intent can be written by a skilled expert but used for fun by common users; if these pranks create damages, the common users responsible for it become attackers <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[61]</ref>. In all the examples described above, the attacks involve users who do not necessarily have any history of cybercrime or high digital literacy or belong to rebellious communities.</p><p>What can make common users look at cyberattacks as an acceptable thing to do? Researchers have looked at the psychological bases for legitimizing cyberattacks. One starting assumption is that cyberattacks are a form of antisocial, aggressive behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10]</ref>, i.e., a type of behavior meant to reduce the wellbeing of the target. Attackers are then associated with antisocial traits, such as exploitativeness and manipulativeness <ref type="bibr" target="#b44">[44]</ref>, psychopathy <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[51]</ref>, lack of moral beliefs, <ref type="bibr" target="#b27">[28]</ref>, Machiavellianism, and thrill-seeking <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>. However, the categorization of attackers as deviants would not ft common users' cases: they cannot be assumed to have steady antisocial tendencies or identify with criminal communities.</p><p>A more suitable psychological explanation for common citizens' sporadic participation in cyberattacks refers to the cultural ambivalence of such behavior. The frst contribution in this direction is ofered by the social learning framework and the notion of self-regulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. When some legitimizing elements of a deviant culture spread in the mainstream culture <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref>, the morality of a given behavior, e.g., illegal downloading, becomes ambivalent. Such ambivalence, in turn, compromises the individual's ability to self-regulate and refrain from performing the illegal behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40]</ref>. Opposite moral norms become available to frame the same behavior, which then acquires the characteristics of a moral dilemma <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>.</p><p>In sociology, Sykes and Matza <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[53]</ref> proposed the notion of neutralization; according to them, criminals do not belong to a deviant subculture that inverts the values of the 'respectable' society <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[53]</ref>. Instead, criminals keep some commitments to the dominant values of society and use some techniques to conciliate them with their criminal acts. Sykes and Matza identifed fve such techniques: denying the responsibility, denying the negativity of the efects, turning the victim or the condemners into culprits, or appealing to higher values <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[53]</ref>. Their ideas have been extensively used in the study of criminal behavior, included within various theoretical frameworks <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>, and re-elaborated by Scott and Lyman's theory of accounts <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[49]</ref>. They have also been applied to the study of cybercrime, and evidence of recourse to all fve types of neutralization techniques has been found so far in research on hackers <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref>. When it comes to understanding lay citizens' participation in cyberattacks, which is the topic of this paper, Sykes and Mazda's theory suggests that the distinction between a community of criminals and the community of law-abiding citizens is culturally more blurred than one might assume. One does not need to give up all values of the dominant society to legitimize their illegal behaviors. Indeed, Chua et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9]</ref> as well as Morris et al <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref> surveyed college students and found such neutralization techniques. <ref type="bibr">Morris et al.</ref>, in particular, investigated common forms of computer hacking, such as accessing somebody else's device or guessing somebody else's password <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>.</p><p>We propose that legitimization of cyberattacks is made possible by the argumentative nature of position-taking. Assigning someone the status of the victim or the ofender is the result of an interpretive, interactional process <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b57">[56]</ref>. identifying the premises on which favorable argumentation rests would help to understand how lay citizens could legitimize (or condemn) cyberattacks. (We prefer to use the term legitimized over neutralized or justifed/excused because the former term assumes a cognitive model that is not necessary to our purpose; the terms justifed or excused only refer to a subset of neutralization techniques, and are then not adequate to refer to all techniques in general <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[49]</ref>.) To showcase this argumentative approach to legitimization, we study the position on cyberattacks of a small sample of university students, who represent a typical participant in the literature on cybercrime <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5]</ref>. The investigation uses a refexive thematic analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref> <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, which is open to the arguments spontaneously used by the participants. The purpose is not to map the entire argumentative space used by university students to make sense of cyberattacks, but to illustrate an argumentative approach and draw some cybersecurity implications from the results. We will start by briefy explaining what we mean by "argumentative".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">AN ARGUMENTATIVE APPROACH</head><p>Psychologists Mercier and Sperber <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref> proposed that human reasoning is an exquisitely argumentative process because it does not look for the truth but for the conclusions that are supported by convincing arguments. They maintain that argumentation suits human society, in which communication and persuasion are instrumental to obtaining cooperation. They also review empirical evidence in psychology and conclude that reasoning is at its best when people are provided with an argumentative context, compared with abstract reasoning.</p><p>The clearest theorization of attitudes as positions in an argumentative space is due to the discursive psychologist Michael Billig, according to whom culture ofers a set of shared and accepted commonplaces <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> both in favor and against a given controversial behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>. An example is provided by the debate on Facebook's policy on users' personal data: their policy was justifed in the name of the free, valuable service it provided but also criticized in the name of transparency <ref type="bibr" target="#b40">[41]</ref>. Far from being possessed in advance, positions emerge from the very process of trying diferent arguments and testing their suitability and implications; this process, as in dialectic philosophy <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>, generates the knowledge needed to come to terms with a given controversy. A controversy is an issue that can inspire opposite positions and can be framed within opposite categories <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[57]</ref>. In our case, the cyberattack represents the controversy, i.e., a behavior that can be framed either favorably or unfavorably.</p><p>Selecting from the ambivalent ofer of arguments that apply to a given controversy is a process that reminds of normative reasoning and legal reasoning: the former consists of fnding reasons for action, applying norms, defning rights and duties, while legal reasoning is doing so with respect to legal knowledge. Legal reasoning involves fnding facts, applying the appropriate category to a behavior, fnding analogies with other behaviors, and abiding by the authority of law <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[54]</ref>. In both domains, reasoning involves connecting some general abstract principles (norms or laws) to the information gathered on the behavior in question. The result is infuenced by the circumstances in which the behavior occurred, which can mobilize one set of arguments instead of another <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>. For example, the majority of physicians in a study considered gifts from drug companies as unacceptable. However, if the same question was asked after reminding them of the personal and fnancial sacrifces to become physicians, more respondents were inclined to consider gifts acceptable <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[47]</ref>. Like legal reasoning, position-taking is argumentative, in that it relies on a stepwise building of arguments as information is found, and defeasible <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[48]</ref> because new information can lead to a diferent inference even if the rest of the premises remain in place.</p><p>To convert this conceptual approach to position-taking into an investigation methodology means to capture the premises mobilized when taking a favorable about a controversial behavior. Consistently, in our study, the participants did not rate pre-formulated arguments (as in <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref> or <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>) but worked their way to a position during open answers to interviews. This allowed them to use the arguments that spontaneously occurred while answering and to take articulated and ambivalent positions as they were considering various sides of the attack. What we valued were the arguments that backed such positions, not the positions themselves. An argumentative method also needs to consider various scenarios in which a controversial behavior can appear. Our study used four diferent cyberattack scenarios inspired by common motives for cyberattacks reported in the literature and applicable to general users.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHOD</head><p>We carried out semi-structured interviews with the participants. Semi-structured interviews allow participants a spontaneous choice of terms <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref>, and the production of articulated answers that are not forced into pre-defned categories. The interviews gravitated around four cases of cyberattacks, to set the questions in a vivid and realistic context and allow participants to form an idea <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b28">[29]</ref>. The process through which we analyzed the participants' answers was a refexive thematic analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>, in which the premises supporting the interviewees' positions represented the themes. In the rest of this section, we will describe the method in more detail.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Narratives</head><p>The cyberattack scenarios we created varied in their motives. The early taxonomies published in the literature distinguish between four motives, i.e., curiosity, proft, notoriety, and revenge <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>, <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[45]</ref>. Curiosity is the pursuit of the excitement connected to intellectual challenges. Proft refers to actions driven by greed or personal fnancial gain" ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[45]</ref>, p.100). Notoriety, also called prestige, consists of pursuing "media attention, bragging, and the quest for fame" ( <ref type="bibr" target="#b45">[45]</ref>, p. 100). Revenge is the search for compensating a tort sufered by the attacker. We excluded notoriety and curiosity from this original set of four motives because they did not ft our purposes: we were interested in cases involving lay people in the attack and not in a single attacker wanting to gain popularity or test their talent. We then added recreation or fun <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17]</ref> and ideology, which refers to ideological and societal motives <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[50]</ref>. Our fnal set of motives then included: proft, revenge, recreation, and ideology.</p><p>In writing the narratives, we took inspiration from real attacks but avoided references to places and names in the original event to prevent participants from contributing pre-formed opinions. In all narratives, a lay citizen with average computer skills had the option of participating in the attack. The attack modality was, respectively, via ransomware (N1), malware (N2), and DDoS (N3,4). Given that all participants discussed all four cases, the case texts were kept short to avoid rushing through the fnal cases for tiredness. The cases are reported below, translated to English from Italian.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.1">Narrative 1 (profit).</head><p>"In 2016, an engineering student could not access the fles saved on his laptop. The fles included the only copy of the thesis he was completing. A hacker encrypted the fles through software that the student downloaded unintentionally on his computer (malware). After the student found that his fles were blocked, a message appeared on the screen asking for 700 € in bitcoin in exchange for the decryption key; however, the student was allowed to cut the ransom price to one half by sending an e-mail -that very likely was infected with malware -to another person".</p><p>Narrative 1 is inspired by the type of ransomware in which the victim can infect new victims to relieve her/his ransom, as happened with the malware called Popcorn 1 2 . In this narrative, the lay user involved in the attack is a student who is ofered to infect other friends by forwarding the malware. The attackers' purpose is to gain (or save) money; the narrative then illustrates an attack motivated by proft.</p><p>3.1.2 Narrative 2 (recreation). In narrative 2, the lay users involved in the attack are co-workers participating in the prank. The narrative is inspired by the numerous cases of pranks at work targeting the computer of a colleague 3 . Therefore, it is categorized as 'recreation.' A cyberattack like this can consist of freezing the desktop, replacing the desktop with a screenshot, or replacing the normal computer sounds with ridiculous ones. Although a prank is supposed to be received with good humor, the damage caused by the prank can decrease team productivity, foster or encourage an unsafe or even discriminatory work environment, and alter the property. Indeed, a prank like this can be a cause of legal suit 4 5 .</p><p>"Diferent employees wanted to pull a prank on a colleague. They used a web application created by a more expert colleague to create fake copies of existing work-related fles, hiding the latter and leaving in view only the former. The web application did not cause real damages, but only a seeming system crash. Nevertheless, fnding a solution cost the employee a couple of working days and some headaches".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.3">Narrative 3 (revenge).</head><p>In narrative 3, the lay users involved in the attack are people sending queries to the website. This narrative is inspired by the so-called "Operation Avenge Assange, " an instance of the larger 'Operation Payback' against antipiracy opponents by the Anonymous group of activists. The operation consisted of targeting the website of companies such as PayPal, PostFinance, Mastercard, and Visa in retaliation for denying their service to Wikileaks 6 . We changed some details; for example, the reason for blocking the website was a privacy violation in the original event but was a copyright violation in our narrative. The method used to carry out the attack is DDos, in which users insert in their machine a tool that makes their computer available to support the attack that then becomes massive. Europol is tracking down users of DDoSfor-hire websites with the intent of holding them responsible for the damage they have created. 7  "In 2011, several e-commerce and payment service companies ceased to support the fundraising for a website. The American Federal authorities blocked that website for copyright violation. As revenge, a group of hackers organized a cyber-attack against those companies, which was organized as follows: the group instructed thousands of people to query jointly and simultaneously the websites of those companies, to overload them and stop them for one/two days. The attack led to severe economic losses".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1.4">Narrative 4 (ideology).</head><p>In narrative 4, the lay users involved in the attack are again invited to send queries to a website targeted by the attack. However, unlike the previous narrative, the attack does not avenge the attackers themselves but supports a societal issue, i.e., defending the environment; it is then categorized as ideology. This narrative was inspired by the OpGreenRights protest enacted by the hacker group known as Anonymous in Italy. They targeted several institutional websites (Ministry of the Infrastructure and Transport, of Economic Development, and others) with a DDoS attack and at the same time released confdential documents related to the oil and energy company Eni-Saipem. The purpose was to expose the alleged exploitation and pollution for oil in the Italian region of Basilicata. 8 Being a DDos, the attack is a cybercrime, as explained above.</p><p>"In 2012, a group of hackers attacked the main website of a nuclear-power distribution company and other secondary websites traceable to the same society. The attack was meant to be a demonstration against some nuclear projects carried out by that company with severe ecological and global repercussions. The attack masterminds proposed to thousands of people to crash the website servers; the instructions they were given caused them to jointly and simultaneously query the target websites that, overloaded, would stop working for a while (1-2 days)".</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Participants</head><p>Sixteen participants were interviewed. According to Guest et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19]</ref>, a sample size like ours sufces to achieve saturation in case of research on a clear domain of inquiry, narrow objectives, on a topic with which all participants are familiarity being part of current culture, and for which participants are interviewed independently from one another and according to a common protocol. The participants were found in the social network (i.e., personal network of acquaintances, not via social media) of one of the authors or by asking students in the university campus. The recruitment criteria were to include participants who were (a) Italian, (b) either university students at the time of the study or had just graduated from university, and (c) of diferent specialties, closer and farther to the themes of cybersecurity. The recruiter provided only the information that was available on the informed consent (see section 3.4 and supplementary material), in order not to raise diferent expectations in the diferent participants. In particular, the interview was advertised as regarding cyberattacks and the participants' opinion on them.</p><p>The interviews were carried out in 2019. The participants' age ranged from 21 to 29 years (M = 25.38; SD = 2.00). All participants reported using the Internet daily, as expected: 13% of them at least 1-2 hours a day; 25% of them 3-4 hours a day and 62% of them for more than 5 hours a day. Their education was Computer Engineering (N = 4), Economics (N = 1), Law (N = 1), Pharmacy (N = 1), Political Science (N = 4), Primary Education (N = 1), and Psychology (N = 4). </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Procedure</head><p>The interviews were semi-structured. They were conducted faceto-face and, when not possible, via Internet phone calls. At the beginning of each interview, some demographic data were asked (i.e., age, degree course taken, and frequency of Internet usage). Then, after a brief introduction about the types of cyber-attacks reported in the narratives, the participant was asked to read aloud a narrative, to make sure that they read it all, and were allowed to do so as many times as needed to understand it well. When the interview was conducted face-to-face, the narrative was printed on paper; when the interviewee was contacted via Internet phone calls, the narratives were sent as separate attachments via e-mail and opened one by one at the interviewer's request. After reading the frst narrative, the interview started. The questions were meant to articulate the interviewees' position on the attack described in the narrative they just read: 1. What is your opinion about it? Why? 2. What do you think about the person who started the attack? Why? 3. What is your opinion about the users who chose to participate in the attack? Why? 4. Do you think you could join this type of attack yourself? Why? This procedure was repeated for all four narratives. The presentation order of the narratives was randomized across the sample, to balance the efect of order and fatigue. Each interview lasted 40 minutes on average, and its audio was recorded.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Ethics</head><p>This study followed the international standard code of conduct when doing research with humans (American Psychological Association Ethics' Code <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>), and the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR, EU 2016/679 <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43]</ref>), since the data collection took place within the European Union. All participants signed the informed consent. When Internet phone calls were employed, the signed consent was sent via mail. The informed consent described the aim of the study (to collect the opinions about some types of cyber-attacks perpetrated in the last years), the data collected (answers to the questions and some personal data), the presence of an audio-recording and the right to leave the study at any moment were underlined. No compensation was given for the participation. All participants had the opportunity of asking for clarifcations before starting. All demographic data and the interview transcripts were anonymized; an alphanumeric code was assigned to each participant, and no data connecting the code to their identity was retained. Reference to names and institutions in the interview was also deleted.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.5">Analysis</head><p>The objective of the analysis was to identify the arguments used by the interviewees to support their positions on the four cyberattacks presented to them. We were not interested in identifying which position prevailed in the sample but in discovering the grounds on which such positions rested and were articulated. In other words, we were interested in the arguments <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3]</ref> supporting or opposing the cyberattacks described in our narratives. The analysis was carried out manually to identify arguments that were not fully formulated (enthymemes, <ref type="bibr" target="#b61">[60]</ref>) and would then fail to emerge by automatically looking for argumentative markers such as 'because' or 'then. ' Consistently with the constructionist framework of discursive psychology <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15]</ref>, the analysis aimed at generating meaning by interpreting the data (refexive thematic analysis), rather than identifying a preexistent meaning in the data (neopositivist thematic analysis) <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref>. To avoid arbitrariness and occasionality in the fndings we could not seek reliability, which pertains to neopositivist methods, but intersubjectivity and accountability. Intersubjectivity consists of building a shared description of the data <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref> and is pursued by seeking transparency when reporting the analysis and by using the scrutiny of peers in the analytic process <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>. Accountability consists of tying the fndings with the data from which they derive <ref type="bibr" target="#b29">[30]</ref>. Accountability is pursued here by using a data-driven inductive process to create the categories in the initial phase of the analysis and by ensuring that all data can be described by those categories <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>.</p><p>All interviews were transcribed, and then a two-stage thematic analysis <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>, was carried out, employing a combination of inductive and deductive analytic processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13]</ref>. The analytic process is illustrated schematically in Fig. <ref type="figure" target="#fig_1">1</ref>. The inductive part of the analysis aimed at identifying the premises upon which interviewers articulated their position on the narratives; it consisted of singling out the portions (argumentation token) of the answer in which the interviewee argued against or in favor of the cyberattack described. An argumentation token was, for example, the following excerpt: "they want to express their thought, so that's ok. " We then identifed the premise on which the expressed position rested; in the example above, the premise would be the right to express one's opinion. Long and articulated tokens could contain several premises and one interview could contain positions both in favor and against the attack. Once all tokens were annotated in this way, we grouped the premises by similarity, obtaining 18 categories. In the example above, the category would be "ideals. "</p><p>Subsequently, a deductive analysis with two independent coders was meant to check whether the categories we created to summarize the premises catered for all tokens in the interviews without redundancy (saturation <ref type="bibr" target="#b7">[8]</ref>) and unambiguously conveyed a shared meaning (intersubjectivity <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>). Two authors, independently from each other, assigned each token in the interviews to one or more of the 18 categories and were instructed to advise about the need for adding new categories. No category was added, showing that saturation was achieved by the existing categories. The meaning conveyed by the categories was at times inconsistently interpreted by the two coders, who ended up with diferent codes in 39% of the tokens. With multiple categories and a small dataset such as ours, such a level of disagreement can be expected <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref>; indeed, in refexive thematic analysis identifying disagreement is a step in the intersubjectivity-building process. Thus, we started an agreementseeking process by: (a) improving the discriminatory power of the categories; if two categories were too similar to be successfully discriminated, for example, "lack of damage" and "damage", they were merged. If two categories partially overlapped, such as 'arm' and 'wingman', we reallocated all common premises to one category and revised their labels accordingly (e.g., awareness and premeditation). (b) revising the categories' descriptions to convey their meaning more straightforwardly. For instance, the category "harmful intentions" was re-defned as "ideals," which more openly included the premises referring to the ideology behind the attack. (c) having the two coders solve together the disagreed-upon site is closed for copyright infringement and therefore for a crime ... tokens.</p><p>the [e-commerce companies] can no longer act as an intermediary for</p><p>At the end of this process, the original categories were revised such a site. So, in my opinion, e-commerce companies seem justifed, into 15 categories (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> in supplementary material) that described and I honestly don't understand the hackers' attack in regard".</p><p>The same premise was also found with reference all the premises mobilized by our interviewees to articulate to the means used their to carry out the attack positions on the four narratives proposed.</p><p>"I think the legal route is the only way to go. (...) Suppose I believe the activities of some services are immoral</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">RESULTS</head><p>In this section we describe the premises identifed by the thematic analysis; we start by providing defnitions and interview excerpts to illustrate each of them and then observe the way in which they are distributed across the four diferent narratives.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Premises</head><p>The 15 premises resulting from the thematic analysis of the interview transcripts are listed in Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref>. Each premise is formulated in the table as a condition whose fulfllment or unfulfllment would fip the position in the controversy. For instance, the premise named 'damage' focuses on whether any severe damage derived from the attack; the presence or absence of severe damages would support, respectively, an unfavorable or favorable position on the attack.</p><p>In the rest of this section, we describe in alphabetic order each premise with the help of a few examples from the interviews and report the frequency with which they were evoked with reference to each of the four narratives. The examples are translated from Italian.</p><p>4.1.1 Authority. This premise expresses the notion that actions opposing the legal authority are wrong. For instance: "The government might have some reasons to block the website. So ...I would go and check for those reasons Likewise, another participant said: "If the website was obscured by. . . the government, well, there must have been a reason! I do not suppose that a service agency ...I mean...acts on a whim (P03)". In the same vein, P04 said: "If the or detrimental to society or the community. In that case, I would not use any means or tools other than the legal ones (P09)". Likewise, P15 declared: "Basically, however, it is an illegal action, and I do not agree it."</p><p>4.1.2 Awareness. This premise states that people having a role in carrying out an attack are guilty if they are abreast of the purpose of the attack. This premise is used to sort out whether a user participating in the attack is guilty: "I think they [the users] are equally involved together with the hackers because they did it consciously and shared act and methods (P06). " Similarly, P05 said: "There were aware of what they were doing, they knew that attacking this website, collectively, they would create some discomfort to that company (P05)". This premise is also used with reference to a developer provided the means for the attack but was not involved in its execution: "It would be necessary to know how much he knew of the fact to say precisely he was 100% complicit or did not know what his work would be used for (...). In case he knew, he would be just as guilty as [the executors] (P01). " 4.1.5 Fun. Like the previous premise, one seems to mention a motive that excuses a cyberattack, namely when the attack is made for fun: "It's a joke. Not the most pleasant or intelligent one, in my opinion, but we are faced with a joke between colleagues (P02), " and "relieving the stress (. . .) can be ok (P05). " To apply this premise, the attack must be seen as a joke; some participants wonder whether this is the case: "Ok, one can call it a joke. But on certain things, one must think twice before acting (P01), " and "We went beyond joke because, in my opinion, there is no fun in this joke (P13)." Indeed, some version of the saying that the game is good as long as it is short was present in several interviews (P02, P05, P07, P09).</p><formula xml:id="formula_0">4</formula></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.6">Ideals.</head><p>According to this premise, the attack serving an ideal can be justifed. For instance: "The action [the attack] based on bioethical principles is right. (. . .) In the sense that it is for a good purpose. personally, I think I agree with these hackers (P06)" and "It depends on what content was protected copyright because, in my opinion, cultural goods should be freely accessible to everyone (P16)." Moreover: "If the cause is very important to me and I do not believe that other solutions are or possible but with minimal repercussions I could consider it [being involved an attack] (P10)." In one participant's words: "The end justifes the means (e.g., P02). " 4.1.7 Imprudence. According to this premise, victims who neglected some basic provision to protect themselves from attacks are to be blamed, and then partly responsible; this diminishes -if not the guilt of the attacker -at least the sympathy for the damage sufered by the victim: "If he [the user] downloaded any malware, he must have visited some pretty bad website... (P01), " or "They should take away half of his graduation exams because ... man, you studied electrical engineering so technically you shouldn't be that easy at these things (P07)". Likewise, P15 states: "I would have other copies of my thesis! I can't see myself in his shoes. . ." 4.1.8 Inappropriateness. According to this premise, an attack must be appropriate to the environment in which it is carried out, otherwise, it is wrong. For instance: "I disagree with perpetrating such a prank in a work environment (P02). " Appropriateness of the attack is evaluated by considering the possible outcomes, in a sort of simulation exercise: "Two days of work can be like gold: they can decide whether or not one manages to deliver a project (P08), " and "This can also afect the psychophysical health of the worker" (P04)". Likewise:</p><p>"the fact that one of them has to waste time, days and resources to redo a job for a company they all work for ... is still a loss for the company itself (P03). " 4.1.9 Innocents. According to this premise, if the attack is meant to punish a target, then the mode of the attack must be such that no innocent people is hurt. For example: "It is not just the company to be hit, so to speak...but also the employee, the one who is in a lower position. So, they [the attackers] created some damage also to the poor Christ (P07)." About students forwarding malware to their contacts to have their ransom reduced, one respondent says: "I wouldn't have a good opinion of him, how to say it politely. . . let's just say I would think he's a real asshole (P10)".</p><p>4.1.10 Instigation. According to this premise, if the attack involves specifc to increase the users' motivation to commit an illicit act, it is wrong. For instance: "There is an element of manipulation that makes me not fully agree with what the hackers do (...). Even if I agree with their intentions (P15), " and "[The users] were used as pawns... it is not sure that they were really informed (P04)." While the premise called 'awareness' referred to a person being aware of participating in an attack and of its outcomes, this new premise refers to the information being distorted on purpose to have other people perpetrate crime; it then emphasizes the stronger responsibility of the instigator than that of the instigated person: "in my opinion, what we have here is precisely an instigation. I mean, they [the attackers] want to take advantage of the users' anger. .</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>.(P05)."</head><p>The assumption is that without such information the instigated person would not have attacked at all.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1.11">Premeditation.</head><p>According to this premise, the responsibility for the attack is higher for a person who planned it well in advance of being executed; opposite case is that of an act performed on a whim, instinctively, driven by the situation. For instance: "We know that the crowd gets carried away (P02), " "out of a spirit of aggregation (P04), " "like a fock of sheep (P13). " The online environment in which the attack is proposed can facilitate rapid and irreversible decisions: "I mean, just a few clicks are enough. . . efort (P02), " and "When you navigate the Internet you have a sort of irresponsibility. you do not really realize what you're doing, you click (...) In my opinion, it's not difcult to say 'ok, I'm interested, I'll do it' on the web (P03)." 4.1.12 Profit. According to this premise, if a personal proft is the purpose of the attack, then the attack is wrong. For instance: "It makes me angry. You are blackmailing a person into getting back things that the student already had while [the hacker] had no right to take them (P10), " or "This thing seems completely negative... (...) Here it is even worse, because... is just another way to commit a crime (P09). " 4.1.13 Recoil. This premise states that paying a ransom to solve an immediate problem sets the basis for the persistence of the problem; this decision would recoil because it feeds the phenomenon that tries to extinguish. For instance, P01 said: "It is not a good thing [giving in to blackmail] because he [the user] is encouraging the attacker. " The problem can concern the same victim or new victims. P05 expresses an opinion that exemplifes the former case: "In the end, one doesn't even know if he [the attacker] will return the documents. On the contrary, one risks getting into even more trouble and doing something illegal. Then it would be a stupid act". P08 and P15 refer to new future victims: "In any case, he [the user] directly would have done nothing wrong. However, he indirectly would have provided funds to the hacker who could reinvest in other attacks," and "Paying more and more instigates this vicious circle because then the person gains and continues to do so with impunity."</p><p>4.1.14 State of need. According to this premise, if a person participated in a cyberattack because they were in a state of need, their responsibility is reduced. For instance: "I would not feel like giving neither a negative nor a positive opinion of a person who, perhaps taken aback or being in a delicate situation, actually goes to pay the ransom or forwards the message (P11)." Thus, "if he [the user] is a student and has no money. . . I would justify him. . . would not fnd his action that shameful. . .(P03)." P13 depicts a scenario in which the target is a person "who is in difculty, who does not work, who is demoralized, who does not know how to do it, does not know whom to contact (P13). "</p><p>4.1.15 Usefulness. According to this premise, an attack is wrong if it is ultimately unable to achieve its goals. For instance: "I think that. . . retaliating for its own sake is a bit inefective and (...) this kind of things [attacks] that just last a couple of days would not solve any problem (P09)." Likewise, P03 said: "It ends in itself ... you show your power do not block the root problem. . . is just sticking one dot out of a hundred. . . won't be the only company and you haven't solved the underlying problem. " Conversely, if the aim is achieved, position is more favorable: "I understand the position of hackers who realize that the only to make their voices heard is to attack the economy of the system .... (...) It is evident that the hackers intended to create economic damage and that this is the only way to attract attention from the entities they attacked (P16). "</p><p>4.1.16 Synthesis. These premises suggest that we can expect our interviewees to legitimate a cyber-attack that appears to fulfll some of the following conditions: the cyberattack does not support a cause already condemned by some governmental agency ("authority"), does not create any severe loss to the target ("damage"), has a high probability of achieving its ultimate goals and of fxing the problem ("usefulness") without aggravating it ("recoil"), targets malefactors ("innocents"), does not result in any personal gain for the attacker ("proft"), fts the context in which it takes place ("inappropriateness"). A cyberattack would also be more likely to be legitimated by our interviewees if it appears to be meant as a prank ("fun"), to prove one's skills ("demonstration"), to be inspired by noble intentions ("ideals") or to exploit some basic negligence in the target ("imprudence"). Similarly, common users involved in a cyberattack could be excused more easily if they appeared be manipulated into participating ("instigation"), to play a minor role without full knowledge of the details ("awareness"), to act on a whim ("premeditation"), or to experience some unjust difculties to be relieved only by joining the attack ("state of need").</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Premises across the four narratives</head><p>We also considered the occurrence of the premises in each narrative to see which premises were transversal across multiple types of cyberattacks (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">2</ref>). The breakdown by narrative shows that a few premises are transversal and can be found in more than one narrative with a high frequency. is the case for awareness, premeditation, damage, usefulness, and ideals, which are present in two cases with high frequency, i.e., Narratives 3 and 4. The similarity between the two cases can explain this overlap: the attacks in both narratives relied on DDoS, and on motives that are not personal (activists who seek revenge ecologists who punish a polluter). Instead, authority only refers to narrative 3 in which there was a specifc mention to contrasting the decision of the legal authority.</p><p>The other premises are more specifc to one narrative. Demonstration, inappropriateness, and fun are found almost exclusively with reference to Narrative 2 in which the attack was presented as a prank carried out in a work environment; demonstration and fun are favorable to the attack, while inappropriateness is unfavorable. Imprudence, innocents, recoil, and state of need were found with reference to Narrative 1, in which the attack targets a person via malware. While imprudence, recoil and the involvement of innocents are unfavorable to the student's participation in the attack, identifying a state of need works favorably. Proft is also found only in Narrative 1 although it does not apply to the student but to the attacker who originally asked the student a ransom.</p><p>For all narratives, therefore, there were both extenuating and aggravating premises, testifying of the presence in the respondents' culture of enough ambivalence to provide and withdraw support to the same deed depending on which premise was found applicable.</p><p>although most premises are specifc to one narrative, they are not exclusive to the domain of cyberattacks. For instance, the notion that ransoms must not be paid is culturally available with reference to kidnapping. Similarly, an appeal to their state of need is applied, for instance, when indigents are caught stealing food.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">DISCUSSION</head><p>In this section, we discuss the premises emerged from the analysis, connecting them with the literature on neutralization; we will also refect more broadly on how the argumentative approach described here can be used in designing a cybersecurity intervention. Finally, we will outline the limits of the study.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">Premises and general neutralization techniques</head><p>In the sociological literature, the legitimization (or neutralization) for an action that breaches some social norms rests on a few techniques such as denial of responsibility, of injuries, denial of the victim, appeal to higher loyalties, and condemnation of the condemners (for a full description, see <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[53]</ref>). Several premises we identifed in our analysis can be referred those general techniques.</p><p>Denying the responsibility occurs when the responsibility the attacker is at stake; our interviewees might argue that instigation or state of need applies to the attacker or that awareness of the purpose, authority or lack of premeditation does not apply. In all these cases, some information is found to argue that the person participating in the attack does not have (full) responsibility for it. In particular, the argument of lack of premeditation has the peculiar characteristics of being associated here with the mediated nature of the attack, which is carried out remotely without seeing the victim and made disproportionately efortless by digital tools. The premise we have called "state of need" also resembles a premise that has been found by other scholars and called the defense of necessity <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[37]</ref>. It consists of legitimizing an act for which there seems to be no alternative, even if it is morally wrong.</p><p>Denying the injuries is achieved when the interviewee argues that no serious damage is done by the attack or that the motive was not to create damage but to have fun or to demonstrate the attackers' computer skills. The applicability of these premises is limited in our interviewees by the inappropriateness to the environment in which the attack is carried out.</p><p>Denial of the victims occurs when the interviewer applies premises such as the imprudence of the target, which makes the targets somehow deserve the attack. Conversely, the interviewer fnds it difcult to legitimize the attack when the target is considered innocent.</p><p>Appeal to higher loyalties can amount in our interview to using the 'ideals' argument, according to which there are ideals that justify the perpetration of an attack even though it creates damages. Conversely, this technique is prevented from being applied when the interviewer fnds that the attack fulflls personal advantages (proft) or that the attack can hardly achieve its intended goal (lack of usefulness) or can recoil.</p><p>We did not fnd any premises connected to the neutralization technique called "condemnation of the condemners" (e.g., accusing people who disapprove the illicit behavior to be a hypocrite), probably because our narratives did not mention people condemning the attack.</p><p>Interestingly, so many legitimizing premises have emerged, even though participants did not have to defend their behavior but to discuss other people's behavior. Diferent from other studies, we did not inquire about the participants' own participation in cyberattacks or any other sort of law-breaching behavior. This rationale is less prone to force the respondent to look for neutralization techniques, a problem that according to Maruna and Copes undermines interview-based research on cybercrime <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>; the evaluation of other people's behavior is also less likely to be mitigated by transferring the responsibility to the situation in which it was produced, an attributional bias that is more likely to be at work when a person evaluates their own behavior <ref type="bibr" target="#b21">[22]</ref>. Hence, if legitimization arguments did emerge, this is genuinely indicative of the fact that legitimating premises are culturally available and can be mobilized in the process of taking a position on cyberattacks.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Argumentation and cybersecurity</head><p>Addressing the human vulnerabilities of a system, allowing users to recognize and prevent potential threats, including deception and manipulation <ref type="bibr">[12] [31]</ref> is increasingly recognized as more efective than only addressing the technical factors <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14]</ref>  <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[61]</ref>. Alongside structural interventions that are long-term and need the mobilization of various stakeholders and policymakers, cybersecurity can use brief interventions in the form of seminars.</p><p>The argumentative approach sketched here exposes some vulnerabilities by highlighting the premises that can legitimize an attack. In general, all premises represent a weakness insofar as they can be used to construe the attack as legitimate. In addition, some of the premises highlighted have some risks. One relates to the recurrent attempt at basing the evaluation on the nature of the intention attributed to the attacker; it follows that the lack of such intentions frees the attacker from guilt. This line of argument can be dangerous as cybercrime's economies have begun to progress to an 'industrialized' Collier et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11]</ref> report that such economies rely on an infrastructure of tools and services that are purchased, advertised, designed, and maintained for a cyberattack. This illicit infrastructure includes boring, low-skilled maintenance. If mainstream culture caters for arguments that legitimize being employed in the industry servicing cybercrime not much because of its exciting nature but because of the intention (it is just work), then it is more difcult to prevent it from growing and recruiting more workers, especially in times of economic crisis.</p><p>Finally, the premises we found betray some possible confusion between the legal and the moral domain and then a possible lack of appreciation of their diferent import. Some premises have both ethical and legal relevance: attacking innocent people, for example, is wrong both morally and from the perspective of criminal law.</p><p>having or not the intention of producing some damage (mens rea), or having premeditated not the attack is relevant both morally and legally. Other premises, instead, might justify a cyberattack morally but would have no legal relevance. instance, the non-seriousness of the attacker's intention, who might have acted for fun or bragged about his/her software skills, would not change the legal meaning of a deed engendering some material or psychological harm. Moreover, the Machiavellian principle that the end justifes the means also has no legal bearing. Law and ethics both provide the normative framework against which to sort out good and bad, and legal reasoning can be considered a type of moral reasoning based on a very specifc knowledge base <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref>; <ref type="bibr" target="#b55">[54]</ref>. However, only the latter has a direct connection with what represents an ofense. If a lay citizen is deliberating whether to join a cyberattack, s/he must be aware that moral justifcations would not lessen the legal implications of the deed. The mistake between legal and moral domains seems quite frequent, given that judges themselves seem to be infuenced by extra-legal factors related to ideology <ref type="bibr" target="#b25">[26]</ref>.</p><p>At the same time, the identifcation of these premises ofers a resource to these vulnerabilities by directing interventions to increase users 'awareness. We can identify at least two types of intervention in this sense. One type is meant to provide users with a combination of strategies to reject persuasion attempts <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34]</ref>. First, informing the potential target that a persuasive attempt might be in its way; this in itself puts the potential target on guard. Second, training the potential target to recognize the arguments that could be used to legitimize participation in attack; this introduces in their scenario the possibility that the truth of the information used to legitimize a cyberattack can be questioned. Third, helping the potential target to evoke counterarguments to actively test and oppose the interpretation of the attack provided by its supporters. This kind of intervention relies on the premises we identifed and can use a quick-and-dirty version of our method to trigger the emersion of such premises and arguments.</p><p>The second type of intervention rests on the point made in the discussion that users can incur misconceptions when deciding their positions about an attack in which they might have the chance to participate. Users might rely on a pastiche of premises borrowed from diferent domains. In particular, users mix moral norms and legal norms, which might have been acquired by watching crime shows, or word of mouth; they might lead to misjudging what is really at stake when participating in an attack and misalign arguments with the case at stake <ref type="bibr" target="#b17">[18]</ref>. Appreciating the real technical, societal, and legal consequences and status of an attack can help make better-informed decisions.</p><p>Anna Spagnolli et al.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Limits</head><p>Regarding possible biases introduced the sampling process, we do not have elements to assume that it introduced pertinent to the research topic, i.e., any partiality about cyberattacks. The researcher in charge of the recruiting not belong to any interest group whose ideology and homogeneity would make her network and acquaintances partial to the topic. We sought variety by considering diferent types of cyberattacks so that a premise legitimating one would not necessarily legitimate all of them, and by including participants of various majors whose diferent expertise gave them diferent cultural resources to evaluate the narratives.</p><p>Nonetheless, the results might be diferent if the study is repeated now, older users and in a diferent country. To account for other sources of cultural variation that could bring in new premises, and then obtain a more generalizable result, one should identify sources of cultural variation that can impact the type of premises used. This means that just including some basic variables such as age, jobs, or nationality would not be enough unless they are redefned a way relevant to the phenomena under study. Nationality, for example, might not fulfll this requisite alone, but some national categorization of nations relevant to jurisprudence or crime might. We did not include those further sources of variation, since this exceeded the purpose of the study, which was to showcase the use of an argumentative approach to unveil common user's premises legitimizing the attacks.</p><p>The selection of cases of cyberattacks is also limited in that it was inspired by cases reported in the newspapers at the time of the study or earlier and refers to attack techniques that are bound to be surpassed soon; for instance, DDoS do no longer need a deluge of users voluntarily participating in the attack, since third parties can be made to participate involuntarily via some malware. New techniques and circumstances of cyberattacks might change the premises within which they are culturally framed.</p><p>This study adopts a discursive, argumentative methodology; consistently, it does not investigate the triggers that motivate the engagement with cybercrime and the results are not ofered because they are predictive participating in illegal online activity. This kind of research contributes by highlighting what are the norms and the culture that can afect that behavior, and by supporting the notion that the positions on a controversial behavior depend on the premises with which that behavior is associated, and this gives margin to malicious persuasion as well as preventative interventions.</p><p>Once the limits are acknowledged, study provides generalizable insights regarding the presence of premises legitimizing cybercrimes in the 'general' population and the usefulness of an argumentative approach to understand the users' position on the subject, which is fuid, depends on the presence of several conditions and can be ambivalent. While the study does not make any claims regarding the generalizability of the specifc premises identifed, it proposes a connection with general neutralization techniques in the literature and the general relevance of some abstract characteristics of the premises found, i.e., a blurred distinction between ethical and legal premises.</p><p>We have identifed several premises that can legitimize a cyberattack in the eyes of the law-abiding citizen. This shows that the legitimization of crime is not limited to deviant subcultures of fulltime cybercriminals. The position on a controversial behavior articulate into diferent facets, as the characteristics of each specifc make applicable diferent premises. Those premises can converge consistently into a favorable or unfavorable position but most likely they will be mixed, going in opposite directions. How they are into a fnal behavioral decision is a diferent research question than the we pursued here and needs a psychological model of decision. Instead, the focus here was methodological: we wanted to show the potential of an argumentative approach, which is at ease with the complexity and ambivalence of the premises catalyzed by a certain controversy. An argumentative approach returns a repertoire of premises that can be in the process taking a position, instead of a steady picture of favorable or unfavorable positions. The fndings of our study show therefore another area of human vulnerability, i.e., the premises legitimizing a cyberattack. Unveiling the premises of this legitimization process provides a weapon to avoid this recruitment to go unnoticed. Future studies that can take advantage of the method we have outlined to disclose legitimizing premises with respect to diferent classes of cybercrime and from diferent kinds of participants.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>8 http://operationgreenrights.blogspot.com/2013/10/eneleniansaldo-you-have-beenhacked.html Anna Spagnolli et al.</figDesc></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_1"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Schematic illustration of the steps in the analytic process used in the study&lt;strike&gt;.&lt;/strike&gt;</figDesc><graphic url="image-1.png" coords="5,133.65,83.69,344.71,243.51" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>The 15 premises identifed with the thematic analysis in alphabetic order.</figDesc><table><row><cell>Short name</cell><cell>Description</cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head></head><label></label><figDesc>The appreciation of the severity of the damage works often in combination with other premises so that the higher the damages' severity, less applicable are other legitimizing premises such as fun or skills.</figDesc><table><row><cell>4.1.4 Demonstration. This premise states that attackers who only</cell></row><row><cell>mean to demonstrate or test their skills should be looked at with</cell></row><row><cell>indulgence. For example, P08 states: "Sometimes, one creates some</cell></row><row><cell>silly applications just for the satisfaction of being able to make them"</cell></row><row><cell>and P07 states "Using one's knowledge for a student spirit is not a sin. "</cell></row><row><cell>This might also include an implicit or explicit appreciation the</cell></row><row><cell>technical skills of the attacker, although misused: "If one has skills</cell></row><row><cell>in the technological feld or skills in general, s/he might as well spend</cell></row><row><cell>them more constructively (P15)," or "He [the attacker] might have</cell></row><row><cell>used it [his expertise] in some other ways, but [I judge him] positively</cell></row><row><cell>because I don't think it's that easy to create a web application (P12). "</cell></row><row><cell>.1.3 Damage. This premise states that an attack is wrong if it</cell></row><row><cell>causes damages, less so if it does not create any serious damage.</cell></row><row><cell>For instance: "It [attacking a website] is a far more peaceful protest</cell></row><row><cell>than other types of protest. Nobody gets hurt (P07)." Similarly, P08</cell></row></table><note>recounts: "As I was reading, my initial catastrophic interpretation decreased. It says that they crashed the website; maybe this just means that a website will not appear if you search it on the web, but the (power plant) infrastructure is working."</note></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>Percentage of tokens associated with each type of premise (by narrative)</figDesc><table><row><cell>Premises</cell><cell>Narrative 1</cell><cell>Narrative 2</cell><cell>Narrative 3</cell><cell>Narrative 4</cell></row><row><cell>Authority</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>19.84</cell><cell>4.12</cell></row><row><cell>Awareness</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>20.19</cell><cell>13.22</cell><cell>16.49</cell></row><row><cell>Damage</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>1.92</cell><cell>14.50</cell><cell>14.44</cell></row><row><cell>Demonstration</cell><cell>1.80</cell><cell>8.65</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>0</cell><cell>33.65</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Ideals</cell><cell>0.90</cell><cell>5.77</cell><cell>17.36</cell><cell>20.62</cell></row><row><cell>Imprudence</cell><cell>9.91</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>2.06</cell></row><row><cell>Inappropriateness</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>26.92</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Innocents</cell><cell>20.72</cell><cell>2.88</cell><cell>7.44</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>3.60</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>5.79</cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>Premeditation</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>13.22</cell><cell>9.28</cell></row><row><cell>Proft</cell><cell>18.92</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>4.96</cell><cell>3.09</cell></row><row><cell>Recoil</cell><cell>34.23</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>State of need</cell><cell>9.91</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell></row><row><cell>Usefulness</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>0</cell><cell>4.13</cell><cell>19.59</cell></row><row><cell>Total</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell><cell>100</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">https://www.pandasecurity.com/mediacenter/malware/popcorn-ransomwaremorality/ 2 https://www.computerworld.com/article/3149489/ransomware-may-turn-victimsinto-attackers-infect-2-others-and-decryption-is-free.html 3 https://www.techradar.com/news/computing/pc/22-pc-pranks-to-make-the-ofceless-boring-611029 4 https://www.cbsnews.com/news/fred-for-sending-e-mail/ 5 https://www.xperthr.co.uk/law-reports/sabotage-of-heterosexual-employeesfacebook-page-to-suggest-he-is-gay-was-sexual-orientation-harassment/151074/ ?cmpid=ILC%7CPROF%7CHRPIO-2013-110-XHR_free_content_links%7Cptod_ article&amp;sfd=701w0000000uNMa 6 http://edition.cnn.com/2010/WORLD/europe/12/09/world.wikileaks/ 7 https://www.europol.europa.eu/newsroom/news/authorities-across-world-goingafter-users-of-biggest-ddos-for-hire-website</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>The authors would like to thank Enrico Guarino for his help in organizing the interview fles and the anonymous reviewers for their constructive comments and suggestions.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ethical principles of psychologists and code of conduct</title>
		<ptr target="http://www.apa.org/ethics/code/index.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2002-06-01">2017. 2002. June 1, 2010, and January 1, 2017</date>
			<publisher>American Psychological Association</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Soyoung</forename><surname>Bae</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">Intersubjectivity.10.1002/9781118901731.iecrm0123</idno>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Mechanisms of moral disengagement in the exercise of moral agency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bandura</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Barbaranelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">V</forename><surname>Caprara</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Pastorelli</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of personality and social psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">71</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">364</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Arguing and thinking: A rhetorical approach to social psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Billig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Introduction: new directions in cybercrime research</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Bossler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Berenblum</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Crime and Justice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">42</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="495" to="499" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Using thematic analysis in psychology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Qualitative research in psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="77" to="101" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Collecting qualitative data: A practical guide to textual, media and virtual techniques</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Gray</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">To saturate or not to saturate? Questioning data saturation as a useful concept for thematic analysis and sample-size rationales. Qualitative research in sport, exercise</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Braun</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">health</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="201" to="216" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A cross-national examination of the techniques of neutralization to account for hacking behaviors</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Chua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Holt</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Victims &amp; Ofenders</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">11</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="534" to="555" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Pro-social and antisocial behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Clarke</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2003">2003</date>
			<publisher>Psychology Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cybercrime is (often) boring: infrastructure and alienation in a deviant subculture</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Collier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Clayton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hutchings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">British Journal of Criminology. he British Journal of Criminology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">61</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1407" to="1423" />
			<date type="published" when="2021-09">2021. September 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Cybersecurity: risks, vulnerabilities, and countermeasures to prevent social engineering attacks</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><forename type="middle">Y</forename><surname>Conteh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Schmick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Advanced Computer Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">23</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">31</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Basics of qualitative research: Techniques and procedures for developing grounded theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Corbin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Strauss</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<publisher>Sage publications</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The human factor Social Science Computer Review</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Dupont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">T</forename><surname>Holt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/08944393211011584</idno>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
	<note>in press</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Edwards</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Potter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<title level="m">Discursive psychology</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New Orleans, LA, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1992-04-29">1992. April 29-May 05, 2022</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Sage. CHI &apos;22</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Psychological Profling of Hacking Potential</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Gaia</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Ramamurthy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sanders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sanders</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Upadhyaya</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Yoo</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 53rd Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</title>
				<meeting>the 53rd Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-01">2020. January</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Profling Human Roles in Cybercrime</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">V</forename><surname>Georgiev</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information &amp; Security</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">43</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="145" to="160" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Argumentative misalignments in the controversy surrounding fashion sustainability</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Greco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>De Cock</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Pragmatics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">174</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="55" to="67" />
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">How many interviews are enough? An experiment with data saturation and variability. Field methods</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Guest</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Bunce</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Johnson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="59" to="82" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">An updated taxonomy for characterizing hackers according to their threat properties</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">L</forename><surname>Hald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Pedersen</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">14th International Conference on Advanced Communication Technology (ICACT)</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IEEE</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="81" to="86" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Moral dilemmas and ethical reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Harding</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social perception and phenomenal causality</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Heider</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">358</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1944">1944</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Rethinking victimization: An interactional approach to victimology</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Holstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Miller</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Symbolic Interaction</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="103" to="122" />
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring the provision of online booter services</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Hutchings</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Clayton</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Deviant Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">37</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1163" to="1178" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Putting it in context: the use of vignettes in qualitative interviewing</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Jenkins</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Bloor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Berney</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Neale</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Qualitative research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">10</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="175" to="198" />
			<date type="published" when="2010">2010</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Legal Techniques for Rationalizing Biased Judicial Decisions: Evidence from Experiments with Real Judges</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">Z</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Li</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Empirical Legal Studies</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">16</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="630" to="670" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">On the autonomy of legal reasoning</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Raz</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Ratio Juris</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="15" />
			<date type="published" when="1993">1993</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Exploring Antecedents of Attitude and Intention Toward Internet Piracy among College Students in South Korea</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Khang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Ki</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">I</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Park</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Baek</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Asian Journal of Business Ethics</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="177" to="194" />
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Online and physical appropriation: evidence from a vignette experiment on copyright infringement</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Krawczyk</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Tyrowicz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><surname>Hardy</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behaviour &amp; Information Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">39</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="481" to="496" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Naturalistic inquiry</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Lincoln</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Guba</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Improving Human Performance Quarterly</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="268" to="276" />
			<date type="published" when="1979">1979</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social engineering: The neglected human factor for information security management</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">X</forename><surname>Luo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Brody</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Seazzu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Burd</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Information Resources Management Journal (IRMJ)</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">24</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The research interview. Refective practice and refexivity in research processes</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Mann</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
			<publisher>Palgrave</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">What have we learned from fve decades of neutralization research? Crime and Justice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Maruna</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Copes</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">An Annual Review of Research</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">32</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="221" to="320" />
			<date type="published" when="2005">2005</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Resistance to persuasion conferred by active and passive prior refutation of the same and alternative counterarguments</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Mcguire</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">The Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">63</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">326</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1961">1961</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Essentials of discursive psychology. American Psychological Association</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Mcmullen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1037/0000220-000</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1037/0000220-000" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Why do humans reason? Arguments for an argumentative theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Mercier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Sperber</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behavioral and brain sciences</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">34</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="57" to="74" />
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Techniques of neutralization: A reconceptualization and empirical examination</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">W</forename><forename type="middle">W</forename><surname>Minor</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Research in Crime and Delinquency</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">18</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="295" to="318" />
			<date type="published" when="1981">1981</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computer hacking and the techniques of neutralization: An empirical assessment</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Morris</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Corporate hacking and technology-driven crime: Social dynamics and implications</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>IGI Global</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Intercoder reliability in qualitative research: debates and practical guidelines</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>O'connor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Jofe</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Qualitative Methods</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">1609406919899220</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Does opportunity make the thief? Abilities and moral disengagement in illegal downloading</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Olivero</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Greco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Annoni</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><surname>Steca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">P</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Lowry</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Behaviour &amp; Information Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="17" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trust-oriented argumentation in rhetorical subarenas: from corporate communication to online stakeholder discussions. The &quot;The Facts About case</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Palmieri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Musi</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 19th Workshop on Computational Models of Natural Argument co-located with the 14th International Conference on Persuasive Technology</title>
				<meeting>the 19th Workshop on Computational Models of Natural Argument co-located with the 14th International Conference on Persuasive Technology</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>PERSUASIVE 2019</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A dangerous trend of cybercrime: ransomware growing challenge</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Nanded</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">International Journal of Advanced Research in Computer Engineering &amp; Technology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="373" />
			<date type="published" when="2016">2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Regulation (EU) 2016/679 the Parliament and of the Council of 27</title>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (General Data Protection Regulation</title>
		<ptr target="http://data.europa.eu/eli/reg/2016/679/2016-05-04" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2016-04">April 2016</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Self-reported computer deviant behavior: A bit-5, moral choice, and manipulative exploitive behavior analysis</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">N</forename><surname>Smoak</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Liu</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Deviant Behavior</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">27</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="245" to="268" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A two-dimensional circumplex approach to the development of a hacker taxonomy</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">K</forename><surname>Rogers</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Digital investigation</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="97" to="102" />
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Marvin</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stanford</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Accounts. American Sociological Review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">33</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="44" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="1968">1968</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Efect of Reminders of Personal Sacrifce and Suggested Rationalizations on Residents&apos; Self-Reported Willingness to Accept Gifts</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Sah</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Loewenstein</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Medical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">304</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1204" to="1211" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Defeasibility in law</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Handbook of Legal Reasoning and argumentation</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Bongiovanni •g. Postema</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Rotolo</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><surname>Sartor</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Valentini</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Walton</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<meeting><address><addrLine>Dordrecht</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="315" to="364" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">B</forename><surname>Scott</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Lyman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Accounts. American sociological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="46" to="62" />
			<date type="published" when="1968">1968</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A typology of hackers: Classifying cyber malfeasance using a weighted arc circumplex model. Digital investigation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Seebruck</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2015">2015</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">14</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="36" to="45" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computer criminal behavior is related to psychopathy and other antisocial behavior</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Seigfried-Spellar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Villacís-Vukadinović</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><forename type="middle">R</forename><surname>Lynam</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of Criminal Justice</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">51</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="67" to="73" />
			<date type="published" when="2017">2017</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">I was told to buy a software or lose my computer. I ignored it&quot;: A study of ransomware</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Simoiu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Bonneau</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Gates</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Goel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<editor>Fifteenth Symposium Anna Spagnolli et al.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">on Usable Privacy and Security</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Techniques of neutralization: A theory of delinquency</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">G</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Sykes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Matza</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">American sociological review</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">22</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="664" to="670" />
			<date type="published" when="1957">1957</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Legal reasoning. Virginia Public Law and Legal Theory Research Paper</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Spellman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Schauer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2012" to="2019" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Interactional troubles in face-to-face survey interviews</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">L</forename><surname>Suchman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal of the American Statistical Association</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">85</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">409</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="232" to="241" />
			<date type="published" when="1990">1990</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Building joint understanding of victimisation in calls for help</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><surname>Tennent</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
			<publisher>Discourse &amp; Society</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="volume">30</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="636" to="652" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Do you think it&apos;sa crime?</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">A systematic theory of argumentation: The pragma-dialectical approach</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><surname>Van Eemeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">F</forename><forename type="middle">H</forename><surname>Van Eemeren</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Grootendorst</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Distributed Denial of Service Attack and Defence</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">S</forename><surname>Yu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2013</date>
			<publisher>Springer</publisher>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="15" to="29" />
			<pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Cybercrime in the information age</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Thomas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Loader</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2000">2000</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Fundamentals of Critical Argumentation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">D</forename><surname>Walton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2006">2006</date>
			<publisher>Cambridge University Press</publisher>
			<pubPlace>Cambridge, UK</pubPlace>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hackers: Militants or merry pranksters? A content analysis of defaced web pages</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Woo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Y</forename><surname>Kim</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Dominick</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Media Psychology</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="63" to="82" />
			<date type="published" when="2004">2004</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
