<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main">Bridging Contextual and Methodological Gaps on the &quot;Misinformation Beat&quot;: Insights from Journalist-Researcher Collaborations at Speed</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Melinda</forename><forename type="middle">Mcclure</forename><surname>Haughey</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Martina</forename><surname>Povolo</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><forename type="first">Kate</forename><forename type="middle">2022</forename><surname>Starbird</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<persName><surname>Bridg</surname></persName>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff0">
								<orgName type="department" key="dep1">Center for an Informed Communication</orgName>
								<orgName type="department" key="dep2">Center for an Informed Public</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">Human Centered Design &amp; Journalism &amp; Public Interest Human Centered Design &amp; Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">University of Engineering</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit3">University of Washington Washington Public</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit4">University of Washington</orgName>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff1">
								<orgName type="laboratory">C111 U.S. Local Newspaper M10 J10B R2 Article C112 U.S. Local Newspaper M11 J11A R4, R1 Article C113 U.S. Local Newspaper M11 J11B R1 Article C114 U.S. Local Radio M12 J12 R3 None C115 U.S. Local Radio M13 J13 R6 Radio Segment C116 U.S. National Newspaper</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>M14 J14A R3, R4</postCode>
									<country>S1</country>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff2">
								<orgName type="laboratory">Article C117 U.S. National Newspaper M14 J14A R6 Article C118 U.S. National Newspaper M14 J14A R3 Article C119 U.S. National Newspaper M14 J14A R4 Article C120 U.S. National Newspaper M14 J14B R3 Article C121 U.S. National Newspaper M15 J15A R4, R1 Article C122 U.S. National Newspaper M15 J15B R2 Article C123 U.S. National Newspaper M15 J15C R1 Article C124 U.S. National Newspaper M16 J16 R7 Article C125 U.S. National Newspaper M17 J17A R4 None C126 U.S. National Newspaper</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution">U.S. National Radio</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>R6 None C127</addrLine>
									<postCode>M17 J17B R2, M18 J18</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff3">
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit1">R5 Radio Segment C128 U.S. National Radio</orgName>
								<orgName type="institution" key="instit2">R4 Radio Segment C129 U.S. National TV</orgName>
								<address>
									<addrLine>R7 Article C130</addrLine>
									<postCode>M19 J19 R3, M20 J20A R4</postCode>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<author>
							<affiliation key="aff4">
								<orgName type="institution">U.S. National TV</orgName>
								<address>
									<postCode>M20 J20B R2, R4</postCode>
									<settlement>None</settlement>
								</address>
							</affiliation>
						</author>
						<title level="a" type="main">Bridging Contextual and Methodological Gaps on the &quot;Misinformation Beat&quot;: Insights from Journalist-Researcher Collaborations at Speed</title>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3491102.3517503</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.7.1" ident="GROBID" when="2022-07-22T04:57+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<textClass>
				<keywords>
					<term>social media</term>
					<term>journalism</term>
					<term>misinformation</term>
					<term>disinformation</term>
				</keywords>
			</textClass>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p>As misinformation, disinformation, and conspiracy theories increase online, so does journalism coverage of these topics. This reporting is challenging, and journalists fll gaps in their expertise by utilizing external resources, including academic researchers. This paper discusses how journalists work with researchers to report on online misinformation. Through an ethnographic study of thirty collaborations, including participant-observation and interviews with journalists and researchers, we identify fve types of collaborations and describe what motivates journalists to reach out to researchers -from a lack of access to data to support for understanding misinformation context. We highlight challenges within these collaborations, including misalignment in professional work practices, ethical guidelines, and reward structures. We end with a call to action for CHI researchers to attend to this intersection, develop ethical guidelines around supporting journalists with data at speed, and ofer practical approaches for researchers flling a "data mediator" role between social media and journalists.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>CCS CONCEPTS</head><p>• Human-centered computing → Collaborative and social computing; Empirical studies in collaborative and social computing.</p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="1">INTRODUCTION</head><p>In the United States, the year 2020 saw increased levels of misinformation, disinformation, and conspiracy theories -especially online <ref type="bibr" target="#b30">[31,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b41">42,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b63">65]</ref>. The Covid-19 pandemic sparked what some referred to as an "infodemic" <ref type="bibr" target="#b3">[4,</ref><ref type="bibr">66]</ref>; a time of widespread medical misinformation leading to adverse health impacts. With more people at home due to the pandemic, Americans spent more time on social media <ref type="bibr">[69]</ref>, allowing for more encounters with misinformation and disinformation. For example, following the murder of George Floyd, Black Lives Matter protests broke out across the country, spurring disinformation aimed at labeling the organization as deceptive and trying to align it with other movements that provide vectors for right-wing criticism, including Antifa <ref type="bibr" target="#b54">[54]</ref>. Later, the U.S. election process was also plagued with disinformation surrounding mailin-ballots and later wider voter fraud narratives, including false assertions that the voting machine company, Dominion, was changing votes -which played a role in motivating some of those who participated in the January 6th Capitol insurrection attempt <ref type="bibr" target="#b47">[47,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b55">55]</ref>. Other debunked conspiracy theories gained traction throughout the year as well, like the QAnon canon <ref type="bibr">[67]</ref> and Wayfair conspiracy theory <ref type="bibr" target="#b58">[58,</ref><ref type="bibr">68]</ref>.</p><p>As public interest in the topic grew, so did the news coverage from those on the so-called "misinformation beat" [60, 70] -an area of journalistic coverage (a 'beat') <ref type="bibr" target="#b36">[37]</ref> focusing on 'fake news', misinformation, disinformation, conspiracy theories and harassment <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">[70]</ref>. Journalists who work on the 'misinformation beat' aim to inform readers about online activity, investigate and debunk false claims, and hold social media companies accountable for problematic information on their platforms <ref type="bibr" target="#b65">[70]</ref>. Those who were already covering the topic grew in popularity (e.g. Donie at CNN -who has been on this beat for years -went viral while reporting on misinformation at the post-election Trump rally that spiraled into the U.S. Capitol Insurrection <ref type="bibr" target="#b39">[40,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b61">63]</ref>), and many more, including local journalists (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b42">[43,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b44">45]</ref>), ventured onto the beat for the frst time.</p><p>The rapid increase of this beat came with more journalists facing known challenges of doing this work. Previous work has established that the misinformation beat -which relies heavily on digital trace data due to the outsized role of online platforms -is uniquely challenging due to constantly changing tools, lack of data access, and risks of providing public access to harmful content <ref type="bibr" target="#b10">[11,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b66">71]</ref>. Researchers noticed an opportunity to help these journalists get up to speed by bridging gaps in their contextual understanding (of misand disinformation) and methodological expertise (for using digital trace data as a "source"). Organizations like First Draft news, the Harvard Shorenstein Center, Poynter, and others ofered training and tip sheets for journalists throughout this period, especially focusing on COVID-19 coverage, combatting vaccine misinformation, and election coverage [61, <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[72]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[73]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[74]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">[75]</ref>.</p><p>Even before this period, the co-production of journalism by journalists and researchers had been increasing, according to a scoping review by MacGregor et al. <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>. This trend continued in 2020. For reasons that are discussed in this paper, journalists new and old to the misinformation beat leaned heavily on researchers for support (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b4">[5,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b7">8,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b45">46,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b71">76]</ref>. Researchers took up roles beyond those of a traditional interview source (for background information or an expert quote), increasingly taking on the labor of education, ad-hoc analysis, and helping journalists ethically approach stories. Journalists who regularly turned to misinformation researchers for a quote now turned to these researchers to collaborate.</p><p>University researchers, too, were eager to get their early misinformation analyses to journalists. They learned during the 2016 presidential election and other elections around the world how viral misinformation can emerge before, during, and after an election; and responding on a typical peer-review timeline can miss the mark on having a timely, positive, and broad impact on the public. A conglomerate of misinformation research teams even set up a rapid-response framework for academic researchers to quickly share analyses of misinformation with journalists leading up to and during the 2020 presidential election <ref type="bibr" target="#b72">[77]</ref>. Starting in 2021, these informal collaborations have begun to formalize, as the Harvard Shorenstein center has hired some of the most knowledgeable journalists on this beat <ref type="bibr" target="#b74">[78,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b75">79]</ref> and U.S. national newsrooms have started hiring researchers and data scientists to help with misinformation related investigations 1 . All provide evidence of the current journalist-researcher codependence in tackling the challenges of misinformation journalism.</p><p>Stepping back -in 2019, we began planning journalistresearcher collaborations to learn how to better serve and support journalists covering this challenging beat. As the unprecedented activities of 2020 and early 2021 unfolded, our research team received more data requests than they could have ever imagined. Our crossdisciplinary team spanned multiple departments at the University of Washington. We both participated in and studied these collaborations simultaneously, taking an ethnographic approach. This piece outlines the fndings from thirty researcher-journalist collaborations on misinformation topics and semi-structured debrief interviews with both journalists and researchers.</p><p>The fndings begin with a typology of fve motivations for collaboration on this beat. The frequency of these needs and fndings from interviews suggest that researchers fll a necessary gap for journalists on this beat. From education to data access to 'gutchecking', researchers have become an essential part of the ability to do misinformation journalism well, especially for those new to the beat. Yet both journalists and researchers highlight ethical and professional challenges in this newfound closeness, which will be discussed in both the fndings and the discussion. Finally, the process of translating journalism questions (like "what impact does misinformation have on the voters?") to ones that can begin to be answered using data inquiry was laborious, and researchers said that the education work required to get newer journalists 'up to speed' was unsustainable.</p><p>These fndings help us see these collaborations with more sensitivity and examine some of the socio-technical challenges involved in this work. Our discussion: 1) highlights the value of this situated perspective on the role of academic researchers as data mediators; 2) calls for digital social data researchers to develop ethical guidelines on data sharing and privacy with journalists; and 3) provides practical guidance for researchers managing these relationships.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2">BACKGROUND AND RELATED WORK</head><p>In this literature review, we frst discuss the process of specialization journalism which -with ubiquitous technology in the profession -requires both technical and contextual expertise. We will discuss this process of specialization, and touch on ways that the Human-Computer Interaction (CHI) community has tended to the technical learning and needs of journalists. Next, we introduce the need -necessitated by the events of 2020 -for journalists to rapidly specialize on misinformation, and the tools, stop-gaps, and collaborations put in place to meet this need. Finally, we introduce collaboration on this beat as a site of learning about the sociotechnical challenges that exist between journalists and researchers working to meet evolving public interest needs at speed.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.1">Beat Specialization in the Online Environment</head><p>Online journalism has changed the role of all modern journalists, especially specialists-or beat journalists <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>. A "beat" refers to a thematic specialization in journalism <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>. Reporters cover one or a few beats, allowing them to use their expertise to reliably report on relevant news to the beat. As more information has become available to the masses (the 'new media environment' <ref type="bibr" target="#b43">[44]</ref>), expectations from the audience of beat journalists have moved beyond those of a disseminator or storyteller to roles that involve even deeper expertise like analyst, detective, and educator <ref type="bibr" target="#b16">[17,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b21">22]</ref>. These beat reporters are expected to not only have access to the information but to be able to curate and contextualize it for the public in a responsible and meaningful way. The journalism workforce, according to Marchetti, is structured around the poles of generalists and specialists <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39]</ref>. The process of specialization -or developing this subject matter knowledge -for technology-heavy beats involves both methodological and contextual learning. To the former, researchers have studied the ways that computational tools and algorithms have impacted and shaped the production and dissemination of the news <ref type="bibr" target="#b13">[14,</ref><ref type="bibr">29,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b76">80]</ref>. For example, one well-established development is through the emergence of Computer-Assisted Reporting (CAR) <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr">26]</ref>, which requires helpful, reliable tools.</p><p>Specifcally, within the CHI community, scholars have been eager to prototype and learn from tools that help journalists more quickly understand computational activity and the use of computationenabled resources like crowdsourcing and big data <ref type="bibr" target="#b56">[56,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b77">81]</ref>. CHI researchers have also explored how practitioners support (or impede) journalists through conference workshops <ref type="bibr" target="#b78">[82]</ref>, exploring innovative news processes <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b79">83]</ref> and centering needs of journalists in the digital age <ref type="bibr" target="#b18">[19,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b53">53]</ref>.</p><p>Yet tools and data are hardly enough to do this kind of work. CAR and data journalism practices are still in service to professional journalistic norms and expertise <ref type="bibr" target="#b12">[13,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b34">35]</ref>. The second element of the specialization process -contextual, cultural learning -comes through time-consuming news gathering, analysis, and verifcation related to the area of specialization <ref type="bibr" target="#b33">[34,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b37">38]</ref>. Especially for specialization in the online space, journalists must learn over time what kind of information to trust (often posted anonymously or by people who are difcult to interact with) and what meaning should be ascribed to it. One way to do this is by cultivating a network of expertise across disciples that helps them assess -and sometimes outsource <ref type="bibr" target="#b31">[32]</ref>-credibility <ref type="bibr" target="#b38">[39,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b59">59]</ref>. Doing this specialization at speed, necessitated by the temporal challenges of news-making <ref type="bibr" target="#b8">[9,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b80">84]</ref>, is challenging and risky. In a recent op-ed, Ivan Oransky discussed the challenges of moving onto the health beat as COVID-19 grew globally <ref type="bibr" target="#b81">[85]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.2">Rise and Challenges of the Misinformation Beat</head><p>The norms and practices of beat reporting vary wildly between media organizations and specializations <ref type="bibr" target="#b50">[50]</ref>, necessitating analysis of various beats and associated needs individually. Reporters working on the "misinformation beat" must navigate the complexity of the technical infrastructure underpinning misinformation, in addition to the cultural and ethical challenges, this kind of problematic content creates. Research conducted before 2020 highlights a dearth of resources to meet these needs, in particular a struggle to access appropriate, well-maintained technical tools to track and understand their subject matter <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[71]</ref>. Reporting on big data involves technical, methodological, and ethical challenges <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. There's also deep contextual knowledge needed to understand how and why misinformation spread online and the role of social media platformsand their algorithmic recommendation systems -in shaping those fows.</p><p>To grow this knowledge, journalists have embedded themselves in online spaces and reached out to experts, like industry and university researchers, for assistance <ref type="bibr" target="#b66">[71]</ref>. When health, policy, and election misinformation fourished throughout 2020, researchers and tools, like Crowdtangle, became an essential piece of doing this work <ref type="bibr" target="#b82">[86,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b83">87]</ref>. Those who were new to the beat -or transferred from peripheral beats -had to get up to speed quickly to serve as trusted knowledge brokers <ref type="bibr" target="#b20">[21]</ref> on a beat with such high stakes. Getting it wrong could mean falling victim to 'source hacking' <ref type="bibr" target="#b15">[16]</ref>, accidentally amplifying harmful information <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[49]</ref>, and other forms of media manipulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[74,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b84">88]</ref>.</p><p>Starting in 2016 and increasing in 2020, online tip-sheets and training emerged during this period in an attempt to meet these needs [61, <ref type="bibr" target="#b67">[72]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b68">[73]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b69">[74]</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b70">[75]</ref>. These resources were made publicly available as journalists did work to self-educate both themselves and their newsrooms on how to cover topics like medical misinformation, anti-mask rallies, and claims of voter fraud. However, these stopgap resources alone may not provide the individualized or in-depth contextual knowledge, or the technical expertise needed to report on misinformation as breaking news. Accordingly, reporters look to build relationships with academic and industry experts to build sustainable reporting habits. The relationships themselves contain complexities because of difering publication timelines and working pace, difering incentives, and public orientations <ref type="bibr" target="#b35">[36]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="2.3">How Collaborations and Ethnography Set the Stage for Design</head><p>This highlights the need to examine the driving forces behind the motivations to initiate and maintain journalist-researcher relationships on this challenging beat. The growing prevalence of these kinds of technical, contextual collaborations around misinformation suggests the existence of socio-technical challenges that hinder journalists from meeting the analysis needs of this beat individually or internally within their newsroom. Ethnographic approaches help center members' perspectives and needs in collaborations <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[89]</ref> and developing of empathy <ref type="bibr" target="#b86">[90]</ref>. Studies using participant observation -an approach to ethnography derived from cultural anthropology <ref type="bibr" target="#b1">[2]</ref>-have been used by CHI researchers to understand the socio-technical challenges (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b9">[10,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b27">28,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b29">30]</ref>). Ethnographic approaches, like participant observation, are essential frst steps in deepening understanding <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[89]</ref>. This kind of work can serve as a foundation for future design provocations and implications.</p><p>Collaborations, too, serve a unique role in the Computer Supported Cooperative Work (CSCW) space informing the design of useful systems and solutions <ref type="bibr" target="#b51">[51]</ref>. CSCW scholars have recently studied collaborations between fact-checkers and journalists in Bangladesh, highlighting communication challenges between the professions that lead to misaligned understanding toward professional roles in the media ecosystem and urging the further study of these dynamics in developing contexts <ref type="bibr" target="#b22">[23]</ref>. Our ethnographic approach to collaborations and subsequent analysis surfaces a better understanding of journalists' and researchers' both computersupported and collaborative work together to fulfll growing public interest and concerns about misinformation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3">METHOD</head><p>Adopting an interpretive and inductive approach informed by Charmaz <ref type="bibr" target="#b11">[12]</ref> and Strauss <ref type="bibr" target="#b19">[20]</ref>, the authors analyzed 30 collaborations between (the largely U.S. centric) journalists and members of the authors' research team (described in the appendix) on misinformationrelated investigations, including 14 interviews with researchers and journalists who participated in these collaborations. There were three parts to the method: 1) the collaboration activities, where the frst author took an ethnographic approach to data collection as a participant-observer, 2) semi-structured qualitative interviews of both researchers and journalists who participated in these collaborations, and 3) integrated data analysis of the collaborations and interviews.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.1">Step 1: Collaboration Initiation and Advertising</head><p>The collaborations were positioned as a way of meeting the needs of the journalists working on misinformation and disinformationrelated stories. Recruitment started with members of the research team who advertised their availability for collaborations through tweets and blogs. Adjacent team eforts included rapid response research -e.g., publishing blogs and social media posts highlighting election and vaccine misinformation -that also helped make public our willingness to engage with journalists for their investigations.</p><p>To be considered a collaboration, the request needed to have a data element -quantitative or qualitative -or hint to the need for data or analysis to further develop their story. The collaborations began when journalists reached out to the team (usually via email) with misinformation beat questions that fell into one or more of the following categories:</p><p>-Investigative story about a case, narrative, or spreader of misinformation, disinformation, or conspiracy theories.</p><p>-Story covering breaking news events with a misinformation, disinformation, or conspiracy theory element.</p><p>-Voting or election-related investigation.</p><p>-COVID-19 related investigation. These requests were sparse at the beginning of 2020 but picked up heavily starting in August 2020 (leading up to the U.S. presidential election), extended through November 2020, and surged again in January 2021 (following the U.S. Capitol Siege). These requests typically went to the inbox of a PI or the team communications director. The request would then be forwarded to an appropriate researcher on the team and the frst author would coordinate the start of the ethnographic research component (studying the collaboration).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.2">Step 2: Participant-Observation and Ethnography of Collaborations</head><p>Once a researcher had volunteered to help with the journalist's request, the journalists and researcher(s) would then go back and forth for anywhere from two days to a month exchanging questions and data. These communications and data exchanges happened virtually due to the ongoing COVID-19 pandemic. The frst author performed as both a researcher and ethnographer for most of these collaborations. They took ethnographic notes throughout the collaborations; paying close attention to <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">(1)</ref> the communications between the journalists and the researchers, (2) data, and artifacts (like Google Docs) that were exchanged, (3) challenges to data access and sharing, and (4) outcomes of these collaborations. Within the role as a participant-observer -as has been described by Konstan, Chi, and Höök <ref type="bibr" target="#b86">[90]</ref> -the frst author was able to grow close to the participants' (journalists') experiences to better understand and empathize with their needs. This resulted in rich data about the context from which the journalists were </p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>R1</head><p>Researcher is a PhD candidate R2</p><p>Researcher is a PhD student R3</p><p>Researcher is an associate professor R4</p><p>Researcher is a PhD candidate R5</p><p>Researcher is a postdoctoral fellow R6</p><p>Researcher is a postdoctoral fellow R7</p><p>Researcher is a postdoctoral researcher R8</p><p>Research team member is a data engineer b R9</p><p>Research team member is a communications director b J10A</p><p>Journalist covers misinformation for an international news agency J14A Journalist covers business and misinformation for a digital frst outlet J15A</p><p>Journalist covers technology for an international TV outlet J18 Journalist produces general content with a focus on disinformation for a radio show J20A</p><p>Journalist covers misinformation for a U.S. national TV outlet b Two staf members who were involved with the research team were interviewed for this piece coming and the tensions that they experienced both within their newsrooms and working with collaborators and data along the way. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_0">1</ref> summarizes the 30 collaborations analyzed for these fndings. They involved 20 diferent media organizations, 28 diferent journalists, and 9 participating research team members.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.3">Step 3: Semi-Structured Qualitative Interviews</head><p>After the collaborations ended, the frst author reached out to both the journalist and the researcher team members to set up individual, semi-structured interviews to debrief. The interviews were conducted over video conference. Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_1">2</ref> lists the journalists and researchers who participated in the interviews.</p><p>During the semi-structured interviews, the frst author frst asked the participants about their experiences working with the researchers or journalists (whichever was appropriate) before 2020. They then asked the participant to walk through -start to fnish -the experiences of the collaborations that they participated in. The interviewer asked probing questions about the participants' expectations of the collaborations and their opinions on the outcomes, among other things. The interview protocol and consent practices were reviewed and approved by the authors' University Institutional Review Board.</p><p>The participant interviews added color to the ethnographic fndings and flled important information gaps about collaborations where the frst author was not about to closely observe. These interviews were unique in that they allowed the researchers to learn about a few, in-depth collaborations from both the journalist and source perspective -empirical studies that consider both of these perspectives are rare, according to Magin and Maurer 2020 <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="3.4">Step 4: Qualitative Analysis</head><p>The frst, and most signifcant step of the qualitative analysis was reviewing the ethnographic notes, memos, and artifacts from step Once the fnal collaboration was complete, the authors gathered and placed the most salient ethnographic notes and memos onto a collaborative Miro board. They talked through the observational notes for each collaboration and the authors were able to identify fve key collaboration types and associated motivations.</p><p>Next, the interviews were transcribed, atomized, and placed on the same collaborative Miro board (see Figure <ref type="figure" target="#fig_0">1</ref>). The frst author led an exercise of sorting the 500 atomized quotes and notes from the 14 interviews into themes. As mentioned, the themes from ethnographic notes and memos were also displayed on the board, providing an initial, yet fexible structure for card categories. Many of the interview cards did align to existing ethnographic themes, but other, new fndings emerged from the card sort as well. After discussing and refning the groupings, the authors identifed the most salient fndings to discuss in this paper. In these cases, journalists typically had a story in progress and wanted primarily quantitative data (though occasionally they are already working on. C112 C114 qualitative artifacts were enough) to advance their piece. C120 C121</p><p>Answering these questions was possible due to the team's data C128 C129 collection capabilities, access to tools, and robust data storage. Some of the collaborations that began as 2s, also evolved into 3s. 3</p><p>Research Journalists have a story they C104 C107 Many of these calls included "gut checking" -a need described "Take" are working on, and they C110 C111 in the fndings. Journalists would either share data, a story, or want to talk about the C115 fndings from an interview and get the researchers' take on it. research team's analysis or Put simply, asking "am I approaching this right?". Often these "take" on the topic.</p><p>ended with quotes from the researcher to help put this fnding in perspective for the readers. 4</p><p>Education Journalists have a story they C102 C117 These were important for journalists new to the beat or are working on, and they C127 covering topics that were new to them. Researchers would want contextual provide background knowledge about a topic and guide the (background) information, journalist in how to approach the topic. Sometimes they would data, and misinformation provide direction of where to look for specifc pieces of education to help tell the information online or help with the framing and approach to story.</p><p>the story. These were especially prevalent with stories about vaccine misinformation, especially as many journalists were writing about online anti-vaccination groups online for the frst time. 5</p><p>Open Ended Collabora-</p><p>Journalists have an open-ended question or a C109 C116 C118 C123</p><p>These collaborations started, often, with an open-ended question. The researcher and journalist worked together to tions general topic for an C125 C126 refne the questions and went back and forth with the data investigative story and want C130 many times. These collaborations were the most challenging to work with researchers to and time-consuming, yet some of the most rewarding for shape and gather data for researchers. the piece.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4">FINDINGS</head><p>The fndings ofer four primary insights: First (1), we ofer a typology of motivations for journalist-researcher data and information sharing. Next, we expand on the ethnographic fndings with interview insights to (2) discuss why journalists are relying more on researchers (compared to other beats) for help getting up to speed, accessing data, and 'gut checking' stories on misinformation; and (3) discuss challenges and professional tensions that emerged from these collaborations. Finally (4), we lean back into the ethnographic fndings to describe the challenge of "getting on the same page"the translational work of turning journalistic questions into data inquiry questions, and the shared understandings needed to get to a productive starting point for the collaborations.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.1">Typology of Journalist-Researcher Collaborations</head><p>Drawing on ethnographic notes and memos from thirty diferent collaborations throughout one year, the authors identifed fve categories of motivations for journalists relying on researchers as they developed misinformation journalism. These collaborations involved journalists from a range of organizations: including many well-known, national U.S. outlets, a few international journalists, as well as local print and radio reporters. Because the journalist collaborators were in various cities, all communications were done virtually through e-mail, Slack, phone calls, and video calls.</p><p>Some of these collaborations were short -e.g., just one or two emails exchanged to answer a quick question or a few days to investigate the origins of a viral misinformation meme. Some went much longer, spanning dozens of interactions including email exchanges, phone conversations, and the use of collaborative artifacts like Google Docs or data visualizations. These extended collaborations tended to involve the co-creation of journalism between the journalist and the researcher, where the data questions and conversations guided the reporting. Some collaboration structures were innovative and experimental for both the researcher and the journalists. For example, some were done "live", where researchers and journalists co-worked (virtually, in a chat and video environment) during high visibility events like election debates and on election day -giving tips, journalists asking questions, researchers sharing quick analyses.</p><p>Many, though not all, of these collaborative eforts, contributed to published pieces. In some cases, the collaboration informed and guided the fnal piece. In others, the fndings -even though they took ample research and journalistic efort -simply did not turn out to be newsworthy enough for publication. In these cases, either a piece wasn't published at all, or the journalists included a piece of the analyses as supporting data for an adjacent story.</p><p>Through an ethnographic analysis of these interactions, we identifed fve distinct types of collaborations -each revealing a different aspect of journalists' needs (generally) or goals for working with researchers on the "misinformation beat". Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref> enumerates these diferent collaboration types, providing some details on how they were initiated and unfolded, and serving as a reference point throughout the remaining fndings and discussion section.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.2">Researchers fll an essential -but possibly temporary -expertise gap for journalists working on the misinformation stories</head><p>Our interviews revealed that these collaborations were part of a larger trend: journalists are leaning on external researchers for their contextual and methodological expertise in helping develop reporting on the misinformation beat. Journalists, themselves, discussed this dynamic:</p><p>"Academics are such a large part of what I do. without that, I could not do this job" -J20A</p><p>"On this misinformation beat you're heavily dependent on relationships with researchers, I think probably more than most beats" -J14A</p><p>This section provides color on why journalists are more reliant on the researchers for this beat and why researchers struggle to keep up with those needs.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4.2.1</head><p>Journalists lean into researchers to fill three main newsroom gaps. J18 said explicitly, "since misinfo is a new topic for newsrooms, there is a lot less internal expertise and infrastructure" on this beat. This statement was confrmed through the ethnographic fndings and interviews. The lack of contextual and methodological expertise with social trace data pushes journalists to look externally for needs that are typically met with internal experts -like gut checking and data access and/or analysis. Each of these is explored in this section. Meeting these needs requires that journalists CHI '22, April 29-May 05, 2022, New Orleans, LA, USA build closer, and more collaborative, relationships with researchers. These close relationships also exist in a grey area where researchers sit somewhere between a source and a collaborator -leading to relationship and independence challenges that will be discussed in future sections.</p><p>Gut Checking. Each journalist and researcher interviewed for this piece mentioned the concept of reaching out to researchers to "gut check" their stories, data, or framing; something that -according to J18 -is more accessible internally for other beats. The concept of 'gut checking' isn't new to journalists. Schultz writes that the journalistic gut feeling associated with determining newsworthiness is something that accrues with experience <ref type="bibr" target="#b52">[52]</ref>. Though journalists were doing newsworthiness gut-checking throughout the collaborations (in some cases they walked us through this process), they were primarily turning to researchers for a diferent kind of gut checking; one more aligned with the process of beat specialization and ensuring that they were properly discussing the complexities of the online environment. For example, J18 went on to give an example: when covering a story about armed confict, they can go to a coworker with experience on that beat and talk through their story, approach, framing, and information with them. But on the topic of misinformation, this doesn't yet exist. Researchers, too, noticed this need adding that journalists would reach out "want[ing] validation that they weren't crazy in the way that they were thinking about this" (R1) and to "confrm their suspicion or the hypothesis that they're putting forward or because there's so much uncertainty around like the aspects of the beat" (R9).</p><p>The ethnographic fndings revealed that throughout these collaborations, researchers helped check journalists' fndings and guide them on approaching challenging stories. After discussing the process of asking a researcher on our team for help with story framing, J18 was quick to add, "I would be careful to asterisk that we don't ever really run scripts by researchers". This practice of looking externally for "gut checks" can contribute to an environment where researchers are contributing to the presentation of the story, moving beyond the traditional role of a source -and creating tension for journalists for whom this may violate professional standards.</p><p>Data Access and Analysis. As was shown in the typology, many of the collaborations also involved a specifc data or data analysis request from the journalists. Journalists discussed two reasons why existing internal newsroom approaches to data don't currently meet the needs of misinformation journalists: the data is private and the existing data journalists lack experience analyzing social media trace data.</p><p>To the former challenge, J14A mentioned the fact that accessing social media data -held exclusively by private companies -is unlike the data access process for other beats they had worked on.</p><p>"In other beats, you rely a lot on public information, like things you can [FOIA request]. In this beat, everything comes from those private companies" -J14A Data access, then, is mediated by the social platforms themselves who are hesitant -and in many cases entirely unwilling -to share data with journalists looking into misinformation concerns on their platform. These social media organizations cite privacy concerns in this kind of data sharing, while journalists tended to suggest that these were more about these organizations' self-preservation interests.</p><p>Researchers, though, have unique infrastructure that enables data collection and analysis of social media data. In some cases, this includes privileged access to data from social platforms through partnerships. In other cases, researchers don't have "special" access, per se, but they do have the funding and infrastructure to enable data collection at a meaningful scale. This valuable data was available for the journalists who participated in these collaborations. Specifc Data Requests (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3</ref>, Type 2) collaborations, the research team's data collection capabilities flled the newsroom data needs gap.</p><p>When it comes to the second need, data analysis, many newsrooms lack resources for internal expertise and tools. Though data journalism is an increasingly important part of newsroom activity, formal data journalism training is largely introductory, often focusing on older, traditional data types <ref type="bibr" target="#b24">[25]</ref>. The social media trace data collected in these collaborations is known for having unique challenges requiring both methodological and contextual expertise to properly analyze <ref type="bibr" target="#b26">[27]</ref>. The ethnographic notes from these collaborations -and the authors' previous relationships with journalists -suggest that many newsrooms' data journalists do not have the training or experience to collect, maintain, and analyze this kind of data.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4.2.2</head><p>Researchers are eager to help journalists on this time-sensitive and impactful beat, but these collaborations feel unwieldy and unsustainable. Universities and funders (including the National Science Foundation) have been encouraging researchers to attend to the broader impacts of their work -including through public scholarship. By working with journalists, university researchers, too, feel like their work can have more of an impact on the public discourse; possibly slowing the spread of misinformation, impacting national and platform policy, and bringing the danger of misinformation more into the public conscience at the right time. Collaborations with journalists on this beat fulfll this public scholarship goal. "'So, I kind of see journalists as a potential conduit for our research to the broader public" -R3 "And I feel incredible whenever I get a [journalist] request. [...] I can help not only inform their story but hopefully better inform the public generally" -R6 Yet these collaborations take a lot of researcher time -not just to answer the questions or do the data queries -but to play a role in educating journalists who are new to the beat about this work. In some cases, the education calls lasted over two hours.</p><p>J10A spoke fondly of these education calls: "every time I talked to [a researcher], I would learn more about this topic. And then I would form a much more nuanced, like vision of it" R6 spoke about this process as being a part of the broader impacts of being a researcher: "I want everyone to be really good -at covering this beat. And to do that, it does require a little bit of education. And then that's like one of the responsibilities I guess, being an academic. "</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Melinda Haughey et al.</head><p>Though these eforts feel worthwhile to researchers amid mass online misinformation -educating journalists about the feld improves coverage and mitigates amplifcation risk overall -it also takes away from time that the researcher could have been spending on tasks that are more traditionally rewarded by academia, like writing peer-reviewed papers. This setup felt unsustainable to many of the researchers interviewed. There are also ethical questions surrounding this practice for the long term -e.g., about collaborating too closely with a small number of journalists, feeling pressure to publicize fndings before they are peer-reviewed, and taking opportunities from other researchers to receive visibility. Researchers are currently pondering how to maintain the rigor traditionally required of the feld while also moving at a pace that can have an impact on this fast-moving phenomenon. Collaborating with journalists brings these tensions to the surface.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3">Navigating ethical and professional</head><p>diferences in these collaborations: perspectives on data sharing, newsworthiness, and innovation.</p><p>Researchers and journalists both conceptualize themselves as knowledge brokers and in service to the public. Yet the way that these roles are enacted difer -like the speed of publication, sourcing practices, and epistemologies. This section discusses a few of the salient tensions: (1) researchers' concerns about the speed and nature of data sharing and (2) journalists' professional commitment to newsworthiness and meeting the public with stories of interest.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>4.3.</head><p>1 Sharing data at speed: researchers' hesitations. Researchers are keenly aware of how incomplete and unofcial the social media data they collect, and share, are; the data are often grabbed from public APIs, based on certain keywords, or provided directly by platforms and subject to scrutiny. Researchers are still grappling with ethical quandaries around reporting on these public social data. Sharing the data with reporters is even trickier. Researchers cited two primary hesitations to data sharing: (1) not knowing where the journalists' piece was heading and (2) feeling like the speed did not allow for enough "double-checking".</p><p>Story Direction. Researchers expressed hesitation in sharing data especially when the researcher didn't know the aim of the piece or what argument the data would be used to support. R2 put this explicitly, stating "I felt weird about sharing data so openly with [this journalist], on this topic. Especially without knowing what "the person's angle is". In one case, this concern developed through experience: a researcher refected on sharing since-deleted tweet data from an inauthentic a journalist without much thought to how it would be used: "When I was giving him information on these people, I didn't know what the story was about, which is, in hindsight, probably not the best thing. I probably should have been like, why do you need this data?' But I was just like, 'you're [a big national news organization], you're fne. '" -R4</p><p>In the interview, this researcher refected that they felt uneasy about how they handled the data sharing. Though the published story accurately covered the data, the researcher wasn't aware that the data would be used to confront the account owner -whom the journalist had identifed through an external tip -in person. Moving forward, the researcher was set on understanding the aims of the story and the use case for the data before sharing.</p><p>Yet some journalists are still developing the direction of the piece before contacting researchers for help (Table <ref type="table" target="#tab_2">3, Type 5</ref>). In a few cases, this created a stalemate, where the researcher wanted to know more about the story before sharing data, but the journalist wanted to see data analysis to help determine the direction of their story.</p><p>Data Sharing at Speed. The speed of publication in the newsroom is much faster than that of academia. Though the researchers we interviewed suggested that peer review, too, is a fawed process, they said it does require them to validate their methods in a much more rigorous manner before publication. Researchers spoke about occasionally feeling uncomfortable moving at the journalists' pace during these collaborations.</p><p>"Moving at a rapid scale (esp. &lt;24 hrs.) is challenging and vulnerable for us because we want to make sure things are exactly right. And a lot of things can go wrong, there might be an error in your data you didn't see, or you miscoded something in the script. " -R3 Another researcher said if the same work was for academia: "I would need to do a lot more work than I did to validate my measures" -R1 Multiple researchers spoke to the fact that sharing data outside of peer-review -where methods are scrutinized -felt uncomfortable and risky, especially on a topic of great public interest. The risk of putting out an incomplete data set or having a journalist misrepresent information to the public is a fear that brought to some collaborations. One researcher, R2, didn't even think of the fact they had shared an analysis outside of peer review until people started asking for their paper on it when the article came out. R2 felt uncomfortable saying that no paper had yet been written on the topic.</p><p>The comfort levels can also vary by the kinds of data or methods required to answer the data query. R2 said they felt comfortable sharing some kinds of data publicly and with journalists because they were confdent in it and, in other cases where there was more uncertainty (or were using a new method), they would want it to be reviewed. This was sometimes hard for the team to convey to journalists: why, in one collaboration, the journalists received a straightforward data response and in another, they received a long email explaining the challenges of collecting and sharing a kind of data or analysis.</p><p>As researchers have adapted to collaborating, so have journalists. The frst author noted in their memos that journalists recognized researchers' discomfort around data sharing at speed. Because it is often in journalists' best interest to establish trust and make researchers feel comfortable sharing data, seasoned journalists on this beat tried to add appropriate context to build up this trust, either by running the text back by the researcher or taking the time to fully understand and contextualize the data themselves.</p><p>"I think we reporters have all been in a sort of situation where [a researcher] has rightly been mad [at us] getting something wrong. We want it to be right. But sometimes there's something lost in translation. I always try, especially with academics, to say, 'this is what I think I hear you saying'. Sometimes they reply with 'not quite', then we'll like to massage it to a place that's true" -J20A</p><p>The that help researchers feel comfortable sharing data -by working together to frame fndings and provide ample context -are the ones that benefted more frequently from the knowledge of the research team in these collaborations. These trust-building practices brought certain, privileged journalists and researchers even closer together.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.2">Newsworthiness and what is interesting.</head><p>When collaborating with researchers, the journalist participants also had their professional intentions and priorities to consider. Among other things, journalists are eager to write engaging content that will attract readers, educate them, and that subscribers would fnd valuable. The journalists interviewed talked about how they would break down the dense misinformation research and make it more digestible and relatable for the public.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>"I have to balance the vegetables [info about misinformation]</head><p>with what they're interested in. If I can't get them to like, read it, then it feels a little bit less impactful. " -J10A J20A, too, talked about doing this by putting more data substance in the middle of the article and making the piece interesting by having the beginning and ends be more engaging. This skill, of course, is what makes sharing research with journalists benefcial to the public -there's little value if nobody reads the piece. some of the collaborations, however, journalists and researchers had a hard time fnding harmony between meeting the needs of the business of journalism and using the data output from the collaboration. Sometimes, the analysis fndings just simply weren't that interesting or newsworthy to the journalists (though the researcher sometimes disagreed). Choosing not to run a story or include a quote or fnding from the researcher who worked on gathering the data was common (e.g., C103, C109, C114, C118).</p><p>"The stuf that we ended up fnding ended up being not that newsworthy. And at the end of the day, I have to use my news judgment. " -J14A Sometimes this led researchers to feel like they had wasted time.</p><p>"So, I did all this work. And I did data, I even roped in another researcher to do all of this. And then I gave [the journalist] feedback. Like, why I think this is happening. Here's a deeper analysis of my expertise in the space. and nothing happened" -R6 This highlights an interesting tension for the journalist -balancing the need to meet the public with interesting, informative content with the need to maintain a positive relationship with researchers -especially as the misinformation beat continues to change and comes with ample journalistic capital <ref type="bibr" target="#b37">[38]</ref>.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.3.3">Despite challenges, these collaborations can lead to innovative</head><p>research and journalism practices. For the reasons described above, not all collaboration eforts resulted in publications -despite many of them consuming researchers' and journalists' time. However, in the post-collaboration interviews, researchers and journalists refected on ways that even unpublished eforts ended up contributing to their work, though many of them didn't realize the contributions until later. In their interviews, researchers noted that these collaborations led to innovative methods development (R1, R2, R8) and powerful case studies for presentations and forthcoming papers (R2, R4). Journalists who participated in Open-Ended Collaborations (3, Type 5), noted how working closely with researchers on co-production activities furthered their understanding of how data analysis works and the difculty of gathering, cleaning, and making sense of social media information. Even when these collaborations were seemingly unsuccessful (i.e., no story was published) they had the potential to inspire thoughtful conversations and new ways of thinking about misinformation online.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4">Getting on the same page: translational work from journalism questions to data questions</head><p>So far, we've discussed the necessity of these kinds of work on rapid timelines and the ethical and normative roles of both reporting and academia's role in this beat. This section centers the practical; the how. How do these challenges manifest and what design provocations might this open for researchers and designers in the CHI community? One major procedural challenge to the 'how' of academicjournalist collaborations on this beat was persistent: getting on the same page. Specifcally, aligning journalism questions with data questions that were actionable with the infrastructure and expertise that the research organization had. Two elements of this "getting on the same page" process are discussed: 1) scoping the journalism question to one that could be answered using the data and capabilities at hand (i.e., addressing the challenge of broad questions) and 2) having the right contextual expertise to accurately guide and understand the implications of those fndings (the challenge of making of the data).</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="4.4.1">Qestion translation: from journalism question to data inquiry.</head><p>of the most salient and challenging issues the researchers discussed was the process of tackling big, bold questions from journalists. An example might be: "how much misinformation is on Twitter now compared to before the 2020 election?". From the perspective of the researchers, properly answering this question would require a minimum: a defnition of what constitutes misinformation, access to all tweets in a period before and after the election, and the ability to process and fnd tweets that meet the misinformation criteria.</p><p>Receiving questions like this, over time, became burdensome for researchers for a few reasons: These kinds of questions elicited conversations about data access, data analysis, and data assumptionsas well as education on why these kinds of questions can't easily be answered. R9 refected that, "[Some journalists have] a misconception that we have this big thing of data, <ref type="bibr">[and]</ref> we can just press a couple of buttons and have all your answers like, 'here's your disinformation campaigns'. It was hard to explain to those journalists that's not necessarily how it works" These kinds of questions also prompted educational conversations about the defnition of misinformation, the role that public accounts play in the ecosystem of mis/disinformation, and more. In short, these broad questions often necessitated a great deal of methodological and contextual "onboarding".</p><p>As we've discussed in previous fndings, researchers were eager to help with this, but over time the education work started feeling unsustainable.</p><p>"It felt a little bit like helping to educate [them] on a bunch of diferent fronts, which you know, has value, I guess, if [they're] gonna go on and write about these, about these things, but it did feel a little bit scattered" -R3</p><p>The researcher and journalist would then enter a scoping phase, where those broad questions were refned into ones that could be answered using our data infrastructure and expertise. For example, the "how much misinformation is on Twitter now compared to before the 2020 election?" question might become "how much voting misinformation did these specifc accounts share in the months leading up to the 2016 election vs the 2020 election?" In this case, scoping to a topic, accounts of interest and a time frame helped shape a data question that was answerable to our researchers. They could then use qualitative and/or quantitative methods to begin an analysis.</p><p>Over time, some journalists improved the way they asked questions, making them more actionable for the research team. Researchers, then, were more eager to tend to these well-scoped questions and prioritize these requests -hinting at challenges of equity in doing this work. Through this back and forth, both researchers and journalists learned how to translate these bold journalistic questions into actionable data queries. 4.4.2 Contextual, cultural expertise is necessary. The activities of 2020 reveal that the "misinformation beat", in addition to a beat of its own, spans across numerous other beats. And expertise on those intersecting beats -like health, armed confict, vaccine science, politics, and elections -was essential for success in analyzing and covering the misinformation emerging from those topics. In many cases, researchers -unfamiliar with the context in question -probed the journalists for example artifacts, hashtags, or other evidence of misinformation that could serve as a starting point for a data-led investigation (as suggested in investigative digital ethnography <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[62]</ref>). It became clear, in a two difcult cases, that journalists knew very little about the communities they were investigating, which made data analysis harder, less valuable, and put them at risk of manipulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b84">[88]</ref>.</p><p>"We were hoping that we could work together to get better questions. And if they don't understand the context well enough, then that that doesn't really work. "-R3 Even when questions were scoped to actionable data requests, we found that without contextual, cultural expertise -either from the journalist or the researcher -it was challenging to make sense of the data. For example, when a journalist who formerly covered education began asking questions about voter fraud narratives, the researcher team encountered two challenges: 1) There were hours of contextual and methodological onboarding work to get them up to speed on misinformation and data collection capabilities; and 2) the researcher working with this journalist felt like the journalist couldn't assess the value of the data to a potential story. After going through a long scoping phase and then doing an in-depth data analysis, the researcher -who did have contextual expertise in the topic -felt like their insights had produced meaningful content for the journalist. The researcher later refected that other journalists with contextual expertise would have considered these fndings be interesting and newsworthy. Yet, P4 said, "They kept wanting more and more. And from our perspective, we were like 'the story is right here!'" -R4</p><p>Working with researchers without deep specialization also made some researchers feel 'cagey' -or reluctant to share informationespecially when a historically marginalized group was involved. In refecting on one collaboration, researchers spoke about hesitations working on a data collaboration with a journalist investigating possible inauthentic activity on discourse about a minoritized community in the US. Both the researchers and the journalists had very little knowledge about the community and didn't consider themselves to be part of it.</p><p>"The stakes are high, you're dealing with the marginalized community, I didn't have background in it. All those things, I think made me cagey early on and just make me cagey re-reading [the conversation with the journalist]" -R2 When dealing with marginalized there are added stakes to the conversation -getting it wrong can mean further marginalization or discounting authentic community organizing.</p><p>In contrast, the researchers felt that successful collaborations were ones where journalists did understand the context and did come with specifc data questions. For example, a reporter on war and government asked about a piece of misinformation spreading about President Biden related to international confict. The journalist provided a few online artifacts as a starting point. The researcher was able to use internal and external data tools to trace the provenance of that data and then share the fndings with the journalist. Because the journalist was well versed in reporting on armed confict, they were able to fnd value in the shared data and incorporate it into their story.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5">DISCUSSION</head><p>In our role as participant-observer researchers in these collaborations, we assist the broader research community in seeing these types of collaborations on the 'misinformation beat' with more sensitivity, taking a "this is what happens" (Dourish 2006, 547) <ref type="bibr" target="#b85">[89]</ref> approach. We share insights and a situated perspective on a unique type of collaboration happening at the intersection of social media data and journalism. This all serves to highlight issues at this boundary and give a rich sense of this site of phenomenological interaction <ref type="bibr" target="#b23">[24]</ref>.</p><p>In this discussion, we (1) highlight the most salient tensions in these collaborations and provide practical guidance for social data researchers engaging with journalists; (2) discuss the growing role of researchers as data mediators; and fnally, (3) call for digital social data researchers to develop ethical guidelines on data sharing and privacy with journalists.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.1">A Situated Perspective on the Role of Academic Researchers as Data Mediators</head><p>As discussed in the background, the HCI community has explored tactical ways to equip journalists with tools, data skills, and online crowds to support their work <ref type="bibr" target="#b14">[15,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b56">56,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b57">57,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b78">82]</ref>. In this paper, we build upon those insights to ofer a situated, ethnographic perspective on the collaboration needs of journalists who are reporting on the "misinformation beat" -a role uniquely challenging due to the accessibility of data, analysis, and the possibility of amplifying the very information that they are trying to mitigate. Drawing attention to this intersection is important as role of academic researchers as data mediators increases. This role is becoming more prominent, both as it is enacted through these collaborations, but also as it becomes institutionalized through data transparency initiatives. For example, in November 2021, the Aspen on Information Disorder <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[64]</ref> called for (1) legal protections for both journalists and researchers who violate platforms terms of service in eforts to write about matters of public concern; and (2) platforms to disclose public interest data to qualifed researchers, creating a "safe harbor" to analyze how information spreads on social media. Similarly, Senators Coons, Portman, and Klobuchar recently announced legislation that would grant qualifed researchers access to social media data if/when their proposals were approved by the U.S. National Science Foundation <ref type="bibr" target="#b48">[48,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b87">91]</ref>. Each of these recommendations positions academic researchers in positions of specialized access to social media data for the public interest -reifying their role as data mediators. However, as we demonstrate here, for researchers of online mis-and disinformation, that role is unstable and often fraught, due to pressure to move at the pace of these unfolding phenomena.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2">Call to Action: Developing Ethical Guidelines for Data Sharing with Journalists</head><p>As requests for collaborations around these data will persist, researchers (and the research community at large) will continually be put in the position of making rapid ethical judgments on what data and insights to share with journalists. We know from boyd and Crawford's work that researchers have a role in the culture of big data -what it means, who gets access, how it is shared, and to what ends <ref type="bibr" target="#b6">[7]</ref>. The researchers participating in these collaborations were faced with these culture decisions largely alone and at speed: e.g. churning out analysis; determining which journalists to partner with; making quick user data privacy decisions; and worrying if their work would be properly contextualized in the fnal piece. The interviews revealed that the weight of this work and the need for quick decision-making was heavy -especially since many of these researchers were keenly aware of the harm that can come from revealing personal data or from getting a misinformation analysis wrong in the public eye. Our work fnds that the researcher's role as data mediator on misinformation work comes without guidance, like tactical and ethical frameworks for data sharing, which can lead to uncertainty, vulnerability, and potentially high-profle mistakes at speed. The most common gray areas that our researchers faced centered on the speed of publishing, the robustness of analysis, and user anonymization. We call for social computing researchers, within the CHI community and beyond, to develop ethical frameworks that consider these grey areas of misinformation work, including the need to work at speed and nuances around user privacy.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.1">Ensuring methodological soundness.</head><p>We know that moving too fast and making methodological or analysis mistakes can hurt the public too. Disinformation purveyors actively look for these cases to undermine trust in trusted knowledge brokers <ref type="bibr" target="#b49">[49]</ref>. Thus, working on a framework to help researchers decide what kinds of questions can be done at speed and what kind of analysis they should feel comfortable publishing without traditional peer review is important.</p><p>These determinations will likely involve several interacting dimensions, including complexity, researcher expertise, and the potential damage of being wrong. For example, simply sharing recent tweets from a public fgure or a list of the most-engaged-with Facebook pages may be straightforward and uncomplicated, assuming the methods for calculating or fnding the data is clear. More complicated analyses -for example, network graphs that can both reveal and mislead -may need to be treated with more care. A central question could be: Has this research team previously published a peer-reviewed paper featuring a similar type of analysis? And even in those cases, we likely want to develop other practices to ensure validity.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>5.2.2</head><p>Alternatives to peer review at speed. When it comes to reporting on misinformation, researchers and journalists feel pressure to move quickly -moving too slow to analyze and report on a viral misinformation campaign can allow it to thrive and harm the public. The peer-review process plays an important role in gatekeeping and validating researchers before it goes public, yet the pace is too slow to keep up with evolving threats.</p><p>One potential route is to build up a network of trusted researchers and to encourage parallel analysis of specifc data or online phenomena that warrant a fast-paced response. In the aftermath of the 2020 U.S. Election, the Center for an Informed Public (CIP) researchers were able to point to similar fndings from the Social Technologies Lab at Cornell Tech, who were also publishing not-yet-peer reviewed data and fndings on election misinformation <ref type="bibr" target="#b0">[1]</ref>. The CIP researchers used the work of the Social Technologies Lab to support a decision to publish a list of "repeat spreaders" of misleading claims. Though redundancy can feel like a waste of resources and may reduce the rewards (of seeing one's research featured in an article), the benefts of independent research teams converging on similar conclusions are likely worth the trade-of. Some journalists from the cohort discussed in this paper pursued this kind of triangulation in their data collaborations -reaching out to multiple research teams to confrm fndings. Aligning our recommendations with practice, we encourage journalists, researchers, and even funders to support this kind of triangulation.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.2.3">Developing nuanced guidelines around anonymization.</head><p>Existing research provides some ethical guidance on using social media user data in research and protecting user privacy. Fiesler and Proferes <ref type="bibr" target="#b88">[92]</ref>, for example, present considerations in using social data in published research, focusing on considering users' preferences in the absence of traditional academic processes of consent. They make recommendations such as anonymizing tweets and avoiding using deleted content, among others. Yet in the context of online misinformation, the operators of accounts that play a large -and even intentional role -in the spread of harmful misinformation may not want their activities analyzed and made public, even though it may serve the public interest to do so. Determining if/when it is ethical or not to anonymize their data can be challenging.</p><p>Academic researchers make careful commitments to mitigate potential harms to participants (and social media users become participants in our work, often without consenting). Journalists have a diferent set of commitments, often working -ostensibly in the public interest -to expose 'bad actors'. The tensions between these two sets of competing commitments are especially salient in the domain of online misinformation, where there are recognized harms to public health, democracy, and vulnerable groups <ref type="bibr" target="#b62">[64]</ref>, but also where, even for intentional disinformation campaigns, the majority of participating accounts are "unwitting agents" <ref type="bibr" target="#b5">[6]</ref>. Unfortunately, it is often difcult to distinguish between a "bad actor" and a "sincere believer".</p><p>Our research community will need to come together to surface and navigate through these tensions, building of existing privacy research (e.g. <ref type="bibr" target="#b2">[3,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b17">18,</ref><ref type="bibr" target="#b40">41]</ref>) to develop nuanced guidelines for how/when to protect the identities of accounts and account owners -and how/when to specifcally call out bad actors. Relatedly, as we build tools for exporting data (including network visualizations), we may want to develop (and enact as default display options) criteria for anonymizing accounts -for example, that are private, unverifed, or under a certain threshold of friends or followers.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="5.3">Practical Guidance for Researchers</head><p>Working with Journalists on Social Data</p><p>Finally, this work reveals some of the reasons why journalists are increasingly seeking support from academic researchers, describing how researchers are creating a (perhaps temporary) bridge for those journalists, helping to fll institutional gaps in contextual and methodological know-how for investigations into an online phenomenon. Our collaborations and subsequent analysis also surface some of the professional challenges that journalists and researchers face in working together to fulfll public interest goals at speed. Collaborations with the most tension usually exhibited one or more of the following: (1) ample back-and-forth time spent molding journalism questions into actionable entries for data investigations;</p><p>(2) lack of contextual expertise; and (3) lack of clarity around how the work would be credited. These were discussed in fndings 4.2.2, 4.3.1, and 4.4.</p><p>Drawing inspiration from the process of Investigative Digital Ethnography <ref type="bibr" target="#b60">[62]</ref>, we suggest a light framework for researchers to keep in mind during the initiation of these kinds of collaborations. These can help to save time, set expectations, and mitigate professional tensions.</p><p>Establish a Focus: Upon receiving a data request, the researcher would beneft from asking the journalists to clarify the focus of the inquiry, which can be done by asking for 1-2 explicit research questions. This task can help researchers ideate the possible methods available to answer the questions at hand and establish a focus for the investigation. The questions will likely be tweaked through the life of the collaboration, yet clarity upfront can help with getting on the same page quicker.</p><p>Probe for Prior Knowledge: Finding 4.4.2 highlighted tensions where journalists or researchers lacked contextual expertise about the being researched, making data analysis time-consuming and challenging. Asking questions of both the requesting journalist and the research team can help researchers assess if this investigation has the potential to be fruitful and ethical -e.g. doing data research without knowing about the community can lead to marginalization and put both parties at risk of manipulation <ref type="bibr" target="#b32">[33]</ref>. Questions may include: What do you already know about the impacted parties? Where are you in your current story/research?</p><p>Roles and Credit: Finally asking explicitly: 'How do you envision us helping with this investigation?' can force articulation of expectations and help researchers identify the collaboration type. Researchers may also probe for what kind of credit the journalist usually gives for this kind of contribution and provide journalists with a sense of how much time this work takes.</p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head n="6">CONCLUSION AND LIMITATIONS</head><p>In this paper, we have framed the intersection of social data researchers and journalism as a site of interest. We have discussed tensions, mismatches in expectations, and ethical challenges that can occur during collaborations between these professionals. Better understanding this work will help construct frameworks for more productive collaborations as researchers increasingly serve as data mediators between social platforms and journalists. There is a pressing need for the development of an ethical framework to guide this work. This research is limited by the fact that most of the journalist collaborations were U.S.-centric and took place during a time of civil and political unrest. We acknowledge that journalism is contextual and cultural. More research is needed to understand how collaborations may difer in non-U.S.-centric contexts.</p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>Figure 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>Figure 1: Screenshot of Collaborative Miro Board</figDesc><graphic url="image-2.png" coords="5,331.98,323.29,212.21,130.26" type="bitmap" /></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_0"><head>Table 1 :</head><label>1</label><figDesc>List of Collaborations</figDesc><table><row><cell>Collaboration</cell><cell>News Organization Type</cell><cell>Media Or-</cell><cell>Journalist</cell><cell cols="2">Research Team Collaboration</cell></row><row><cell>Number</cell><cell></cell><cell>ganization</cell><cell>Number</cell><cell>Member</cell><cell>Outcome</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Number</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell></row><row><cell>C101</cell><cell>Academic News Organization</cell><cell>M1</cell><cell>J1</cell><cell>R2, R3</cell><cell>Article</cell></row><row><cell>C102</cell><cell>Digital First Outlet</cell><cell>M2</cell><cell>J2</cell><cell>R5</cell><cell>None</cell></row><row><cell>C103</cell><cell>International Newspaper</cell><cell>M3</cell><cell>J3</cell><cell>R1</cell><cell>Article</cell></row><row><cell>C104</cell><cell>International TV</cell><cell>M4</cell><cell>J4</cell><cell>R1</cell><cell>TV Segment</cell></row><row><cell>C105</cell><cell>International News Agency</cell><cell>M5</cell><cell>J5A,J5B</cell><cell>R4</cell><cell>In Progress</cell></row><row><cell>C106</cell><cell>Niche Newspaper</cell><cell>M6</cell><cell>J6</cell><cell>R4</cell><cell>Article</cell></row><row><cell>C107</cell><cell>Niche Newspaper</cell><cell>M7</cell><cell>J7</cell><cell>R6</cell><cell>Article</cell></row><row><cell>C108</cell><cell>Niche, Non-Proft Newsroom</cell><cell>M8</cell><cell>J8</cell><cell>R4, R2</cell><cell>Podcast</cell></row><row><cell>C109</cell><cell>Niche, Non-Proft Newsroom</cell><cell>M9</cell><cell>J9</cell><cell>R4</cell><cell>None</cell></row><row><cell>C110</cell><cell>U.S. Local Newspaper</cell><cell>M10</cell><cell>J10A</cell><cell>S2, R4</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_1"><head>Table 2 :</head><label>2</label><figDesc>List of researchers and journalists interviewed post-collaboration</figDesc><table><row><cell>Interview Participant</cell><cell>Short Participant Description</cell></row><row><cell>Number</cell><cell></cell></row></table></figure>
<figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" type="table" xml:id="tab_2"><head>Table 3 :</head><label>3</label><figDesc>Typology of Collaboration Types</figDesc><table><row><cell>Type</cell><cell>Name</cell><cell>Short Description</cell><cell cols="2">Associated Details</cell></row><row><cell>Num-</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>Collabora-</cell></row><row><cell>ber</cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>tions</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Follow Up</cell><cell>Journalists follow up on a</cell><cell>C102 C113</cell><cell>In these cases, public scholarship (e.g., a blog or tweet about a</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Piece</cell><cell>piece of public scholarship</cell><cell>C122 C124</cell><cell>fnding from the rapid analysis work) drove interest in the</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>(like a tweet or blog post)</cell><cell></cell><cell>team's research and the establishment of collaborations. These</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>and want to write a story</cell><cell></cell><cell>collaborations were typically initiated on Twitter or via email</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>featuring the research</cell><cell></cell><cell>and involved follow-up conversations describing the underlying</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>team's analysis.</cell><cell></cell><cell>data of what the researchers had reported and providing</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell></cell><cell>additional context (and sometimes data) for the story.</cell></row><row><cell>2</cell><cell>Specifc Data</cell><cell>Journalists have a specifc</cell><cell>C103 C105</cell></row><row><cell></cell><cell>Question</cell><cell>data question for a story</cell><cell>C106 C108</cell></row></table></figure>
			<note xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" place="foot" n="1">This information came from the interviews conducted for this paper. Two journalists said their teams were actively hiring for these roles.</note>
		</body>
		<back>

			<div type="acknowledgement">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>ACKNOWLEDGMENTS</head><p>This research was conducted at the UW Center for an Informed Public (CIP) with support from NSF Grant 1749815 and CIP funders. We want to acknowledge the CIP funders that supported aspects of this work, the John S. and James L. Knight Foundation, William and Flora Hewlett Foundation, Craig Newmark Philanthropies, Gates Ventures, and the Omidyar Network. We also want to express appreciation to the journalists and the CIP researchers and staf who participated in this research: Andrew Beers, Joe Bak-Coleman, Ian Kennedy, Kolina Koltai, Rachel Moran, Joseph Schafer, Paul Lockaby and Michael Grass. Finally, we would like to acknowledge and thank the students in the Fall 2020 UW directed research group and Ahmer Arif -who helped evolve this work by supporting the authors.</p></div>
			</div>

			<div type="annex">
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>A APPENDICES A A NOTE ON COLLABORATIVE INFRASTRUCTURE OF THE PARTICIPATING RESEARCH TEAM</head><p>This research took place within an interdisciplinary team primarily based within the University of Washington. The team has robust, reliable, and fexible infrastructure -including social media data collection infrastructure, team members with methodological and contextual expertise, communications staf, and funding resources -that enabled these kinds of collaborations with journalists. While this study was taking place, the team had (1) nearly a dozen parttime student researchers (including R1-R7), (2) a dedicated PI and three faculty researchers volunteering efort, and (3) three staf members -including a full-time data engineer who maintained servers, social media data collections, and the technical infrastructure for distributed analysis.</p><p>During the study period, the team also had key partnerships and chat channels with other organizations doing misinformation research on social media, which helped them stay up to date on emerging misinformation narratives and provided analysis support. In Autumn 2020, during the most active period of this research, the team was partnering with other research teams to do rapid analysis of misinformation related to the 2020 Election. These partnerships continued from December 2021 -June 2022 with a focus on vaccine misinformation. This rapid response work involved rapidly identifying, analyzing, and communicating about emergent misand disinformation online, and led to the publication of dozens of blogs and social media posts which became a route for journalists to become aware of our team and its research (and the potential for collaboration). Through this work, the team was also able to obtain fnancial assistance in hiring several student researchers dedicated to "rapid analysis" for the fall and winter of 2020, which enhanced their ability to engage in these collaborations. The frst and third authors of this paper are members of this team and were participants in these collaborations.</p></div>			</div>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Anton</forename><surname>Abilov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yiqing</forename><surname>Hua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Hana</forename><surname>Mataov</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mor</forename><surname>Naaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://github.com/sTechLab/VoterFraud2020" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020">VoterFraud2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Ltd, 1 Oliver&apos;s Yard, 55 City Road, London England EC1Y 1SP United Kingdom</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Atkinson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><surname>Cofey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sara</forename><surname>Delamont</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Lofand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Lyn</forename><surname>Lofand</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4135/9781848608337</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.4135/9781848608337" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2001">2001</date>
			<publisher>SAGE Publications</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Handbook of Ethnography</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b2">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy in Context&quot; Workshop</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karla</forename><surname>Badillo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://medium.com/acm-cscw/a-review-of-the-cscw-2018-privacy-in-context-workshop-ae380040f1ec" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">ACM CSCW</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-01-08">2019. 2018. January 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>A Review of the CSCW</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b3">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The epic battle against coronavirus misinformation and conspiracy theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Philip</forename><surname>Ball</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Maxmen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1038/d41586-020-01452-z</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1038/d41586-020-01452-z" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Nature</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">581</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="371" to="374" />
			<date type="published" when="2020-05">2020. May 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b4">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Russian Disinformation Targets Vaccines and the Biden Administration. The New York Times</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julian</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Barnes</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/08/05/us/politics/covid-vaccines-russian-disinformation.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-09-05">2021. September 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b5">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The KGB and Soviet disinformation: an insider&apos;s view. Washington: Pergamon-Brassey&apos;s</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ladislav</forename><surname>Bittman</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1985">1985</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b6">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Six provocations for big data</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Danah</forename><surname>Boyd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Crawford</forename></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">A decade in internet time: Symposium on the dynamics of the internet and society</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2011">2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b7">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">y Zadrozny is a senior reporter for NBC News She covers misinformation, extremism, and The Internet</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zadrozny</forename><surname>Br</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Br</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.nbcnews.com/tech/tech-news/youtubes-recommendations-still-push-harmful-videos-crowdsourced-study-rcna1355" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">NBC News</title>
		<imprint>
			<date>September 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>YouTube&apos;s recommendations still push harmful videos, crowdsourced study fnds</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b8">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Temporal refexivity in journalism studies: Making sense of change in a more timely fashion</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matt</forename><surname>Carlson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Seth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1464884918760675</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1464884918760675" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journalism</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">20</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="642" to="650" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-05">2019. May 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b9">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Design, adoption, and assessment of a socio-technical environment supporting independence for persons with cognitive disabilities</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stefan</forename><surname>Parry Carmien</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gerhard</forename><surname>Fischer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1357054.1357151</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/1357054.1357151" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;08)</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;08)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008">2008</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="597" to="606" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b10">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Watching Them, Watching Us: How the Misinformation Beat Redefnes Journalism&apos;s Relationship with Conspiracy Theories</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Regina</forename><surname>Kayla Catipon</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.6082/uchicago.2922</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.6082/uchicago.2922" />
		<imprint/>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>University of Chicago</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b11">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Grounded theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kathy</forename><surname>Charmaz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Linda</forename><forename type="middle">Liska</forename><surname>Belgrave</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007. 2007</date>
			<publisher>Blackwell Encycl. Sociol</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b12">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Clarifying Journalism&apos;s Quantitative Turn</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Coddington</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/21670811.2014.976400</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/21670811.2014.976400" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Digit. Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="331" to="348" />
			<date type="published" when="2015-05">2015. May 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b13">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Automating the News</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Diakopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.4159/9780674239302/html</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.degruyter.com/document/doi/10.4159/9780674239302/html" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019-09-02">2019. September 2</date>
			<publisher>Harvard University Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b14">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding and assessing social media information sources in the context of journalism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Diakopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mor</forename><surname>Munmun De Choudhury</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Naaman</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI conference on factors in computing systems</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI conference on factors in computing systems</meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2012">2012</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2451" to="2460" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b15">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Source hacking: Media manipulation in practice</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joan</forename><surname>Donovan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brian</forename><surname>Friedberg</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s">Retrieved DataSociety Website Httpsdatasociety Netoutputsource-Hacking-Media-Manip.-Pract.</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b16">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The science journalist online: Shifting roles and emerging practices</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Declan</forename><surname>Fahy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Matthew</forename><forename type="middle">C</forename><surname>Nisbet</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1464884911412697</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1464884911412697" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journalism</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">12</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="778" to="793" />
			<date type="published" when="2011-10">2011. October 2011</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b17">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">We Are the Product&quot;: Public Reactions to Online Data Sharing and Privacy Controversies in the Media</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Casey</forename><surname>Fiesler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Blake</forename><surname>Hallinan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3173627</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173627" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-01-08">2018. January 8</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b18">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Finding &quot;real people&quot;: trust and diversity in the interface between professional and citizen journalists</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Thomas Garbett</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rob</forename><surname>Comber</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Paul</forename><surname>Egglestone</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Maxine</forename><surname>Glancy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Patrick</forename><surname>Olivier</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2556288.2557114</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2556288.2557114" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;14)</title>
				<meeting>the SIGCHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI &apos;14)<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="3015" to="3024" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b19">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">The discovery of grounded theory</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Barney</forename><surname>Glaser</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Alsine Gruyter N. Y</title>
		<editor>Strauss, A.</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="1967">1967. 1967. 1967</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b20">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Crowding at the frontier: boundary spanners, gatekeepers and knowledge brokers</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Aurore</forename><surname>Haas</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1108/JKM-01-2015-0036</idno>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">J. Knowl. Manag</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1029" to="1047" />
			<date type="published" when="2015-01">2015. January 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b21">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Journalism beyond democracy: A new look into journalistic roles in political and everyday life</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Thomas</forename><surname>Hanitzsch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Tim</forename><forename type="middle">P</forename><surname>Vos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1464884916673386</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1464884916673386" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journalism</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">19</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="146" to="164" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b22">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Combating Misinformation in Bangladesh: Roles and Responsibilities as Perceived by Journalists, Fact-checkers, and Users</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3415201</idno>
		<idno>130:1- 130:32</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3415201" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact</title>
		<editor>Md Mahfuzul Haque, Mohammad Yousuf, Ahmed Shatil Alam, Pratyasha Saha, Syed Ishtiaque Ahmed, and Naeemul Hassan</editor>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">W2</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-10">2020. October 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b23">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The three paradigms of HCI</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Steve</forename><surname>Harrison</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Deborah</forename><surname>Tatar</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Phoebe</forename><surname>Sengers</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007">2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b24">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">2019. 3Ws of Data Journalism Education</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">R</forename><surname>Bahareh</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Heravi</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17512786.2018.1463167</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17512786.2018.1463167" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal. Pract</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">13</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="349" to="366" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-03">March 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b25">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Computer-Assisted Reporting: A Practical Guide</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brant</forename><surname>Houston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2014">2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Routledge</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b26">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Towards a big data framework for analyzing social media content</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jose Luis Jimenez-</forename><surname>Marquez</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Israel</forename><surname>Gonzalez-Carrasco</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jose</forename><forename type="middle">Luis</forename><surname>Lopez-Cuadrado</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Belen</forename><surname>Ruiz-Mezcua</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2018.09.003</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ijinfomgt.2018.09.003" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Inf. Manag</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">44</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="12" />
			<date type="published" when="2019-02">2019. February 2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b27">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Chapter 3 Ethnographic workplace studies and CSCW</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Brigitte</forename><surname>Jordan</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/S0923-8433(96)80005-0</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/S0923-8433(96" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Human Factors in Information Technology</title>
				<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dan</forename><surname>Shapiro</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Michael</forename><surname>Tauber</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<editor>
			<persName><forename type="first">Roland</forename><surname>Traunmüller</surname></persName>
		</editor>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>North-Holland</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="1996">1996</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="80005" to="80005" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b28">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Computational Journalism in Norwegian Newsrooms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Joakim</forename><surname>Karlsen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Eirik</forename><surname>Stavelin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17512786.2013.813190</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17512786.2013.813190" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal. Pract</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">8</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="34" to="48" />
			<date type="published" when="2014-01">2014. January 2014</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b29">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">When the designer becomes the user: designing a system for therapists by becoming a therapist</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julie</forename><forename type="middle">A</forename><surname>Kientz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gregory</forename><forename type="middle">D</forename><surname>Abowd</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1358628.1358639</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/1358628.1358639" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">CHI &apos;08 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2008-09">2008. September 9</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="2071" to="2078" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b30">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Social Media in 2020: A Year of Misinformation and Disinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kathryn</forename><surname>Kranhold</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.wsj.com/articles/social-media-in-2020-a-year-of-misinformation-and-disinformation-11607712530" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Wall Street Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-08-31">2020. August 31</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b31">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Hiding Behind Databases, Institutions and Actors: How Journalists Use Statistics in Reporting Humanitarian Crises</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><forename type="middle">T</forename><surname>Lawson</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17512786.2021.1930106</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17512786.2021.1930106" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal. Pract</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">0</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="21" />
			<date type="published" when="2021-05">2021. May 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b32">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Media Manipulation and Disinformation Online</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Becca</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Alice</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Marwick</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://datasociety.net/library/media-manipulation-and-disinfo-online/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Data &amp; Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2017-03-18">2017. March 18</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b33">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Seth</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Oscar</forename><surname>Lewis</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Westlund</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/21670811.2014.976418</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/21670811.2014.976418" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Big Data and Journalism. Digit. Journal</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="447" to="466" />
			<date type="published" when="2015-05">2015. May 2015</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b34">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Data-driven reporting: An on-going (r)evolution? An analysis of projects nominated for the Data Journalism Awards</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Wiebke</forename><surname>Loosen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Julius</forename><surname>Reimer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Fenja De</forename><surname>Silva-Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1464884917735691</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1464884917735691" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2013">2020. 2013-2016. 21. September 2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1246" to="1263" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b35">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A scoping review of co-production between researchers and journalists in research communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Stephen</forename><surname>Macgregor</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amanda</forename><surname>Cooper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Andrew</forename><surname>Coombs</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Christopher</forename><surname>Deluca</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1016/j.heliyon.2020.e04836</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.heliyon.2020.e04836" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Heliyon</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">6</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">9</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page">e04836</biblScope>
			<date type="published" when="2020-09">2020. September 2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b36">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Beat Journalism and Reporting</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melanie</forename><surname>Maginmelanie Magin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter Maurerpeter</forename><surname>Maurer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/acref/9780190694166.001.0001/acref-9780190694166-e-905</idno>
		<ptr target="http://www.oxfordreference.com/view/10.1093/acref/9780190694166.001.0001/acref-9780190694166-e-905" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Oxford Encyclopedia of Journalism Studies</title>
				<imprint>
			<publisher>Oxford University Press</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020-09-07">2020. September 7</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b37">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Oxford Research Encyclopedia of Communication</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melanie</forename><surname>Magin</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Peter</forename><surname>Maurer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1093/acrefore/9780190228613.013.905</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1093/acrefore/9780190228613.013.905" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Beat Journalism and Reporting</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b38">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Sub-felds of specialized journalism</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dominique</forename><surname>Marchetti</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">15</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b39">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Trump supporter warns CNN reporter of &quot;civil war&quot; if former president not reinstated &quot;soon</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Dominick</forename><surname>Mastrangelo</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://thehill.com/homenews/media/560681-trump-supporter-warns-cnn-reporter-of-civil-war-if-former-president-not" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">TheHill</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-09-05">2021. September 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b40">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Privacy and Power: Acknowledging the Importance of Privacy Research and Design for Vulnerable Populations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nora</forename><surname>Mcdonald</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Karla</forename><surname>Badillo-Urquiola</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Morgan</forename><forename type="middle">G</forename><surname>Ames</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicola</forename><surname>Dell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elizabeth</forename><surname>Keneski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Manya</forename><surname>Sleeper</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Pamela</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wisniewski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3334480.3375174</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3334480.3375174" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Extended Abstracts of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI EA &apos;20)</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="8" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b41">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Political Divides, Conspiracy Theories and Divergent News Sources Heading Into 2020 Election. Pew Research Center&apos;s Journalism Project</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Amy</forename><surname>Mitchell</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Mark</forename><surname>Jurkowitz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">J</forename><surname>Baxter</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Elisa</forename><surname>Oliphant</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Shearer</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.pewresearch.org/journalism/2020/09/16/political-divides-conspiracy-theories-and-divergent-news-sources-heading-into-2020-election/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-08-31">2020. August 31</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b42">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">As states count votes, some of Texas&apos; most prominent Republican politicians are spreading misinformation about the election. The Texas Tribune</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Abby</forename><surname>Livingston</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Shawn</forename><surname>Mulcahy</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.texastribune.org/2020/11/06/texas-republicans-trump-results/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-09-05">2020. September 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b43">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Blogging and the emerging media ecosystem</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Naughton</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b44">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Michigan&apos;s immigrant communities hit with misinformation on closed platforms</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ashley</forename><surname>Nerbovig</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.freep.com/story/news/politics/elections/2020/11/27/michigan-election-misinformation-immigrant-whatsapp/6393693002/" />
		<imprint>
			<date>September 5</date>
			<publisher>Detroit Free Press</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b45">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Most Popular J&amp;J Vaccine Story On Facebook? A Conspiracy Theorist Posted It</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Miles</forename><surname>Parks</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-09-05">2021. September 5, 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b46">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Melinda</forename><surname>Haughey</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b47">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Public Sphere and Misinformation in the U.S. Election: Trump&apos;s Audience and Populism Indicators in the COVID-19 Context</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Concha</forename><surname>Pérez-Curiel</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ricardo</forename><surname>Domínguez-García</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Gloria</forename><surname>Jiménez-Marín</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.3390/journalmedia2030020</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.3390/journalmedia2030020" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal. Media</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">2</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="335" to="350" />
			<date type="published" when="2021-09">2021. September 2021</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b48">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">OPENING A WINDOW INTO TECH: THE CHALLENGE AND OPPORTUNITY FOR DATA TRANSPARENCY</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nathaniel</forename><surname>Persily</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b49">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The oxygen of amplifcation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Whitney</forename><surname>Phillips</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018. 2018</date>
			<publisher>Data Soc</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b50">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Diferent Practices, Similar Logic: Comparing News Reporting across Political, Financial, and Territorial Beats</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Zvi</forename><surname>Reich</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1940161211420868</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/1940161211420868" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Int. J. Press</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">17</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="76" to="99" />
			<date type="published" when="2012-01">2012. January 2012</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b51">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Taking CSCW seriously: Supporting Articulation Work</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kjeld</forename><surname>Schmidt</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Liam</forename><surname>Bannon</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Comput. Support. Coop. Work</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">1</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="7" to="40" />
			<date type="published" when="1992-03">1992. March 1992</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b52">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">THE JOURNALISTIC GUT FEELING</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Ida</forename><surname>Schultz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17512780701275507</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1080/17512780701275507" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Journal. Pract</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2007-04">2007. April 2007</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b53">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Un]breaking News: Design Opportunities for Enhancing Collaboration in Scientifc Media Production</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">Estelle</forename><surname>Smith</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Xinyi</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Haiyi</forename><surname>Raghav Pavan Karumur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Zhu</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3173955</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3173574.3173955" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2018-09-07">2018. September 7</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="13" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b54">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Black Lives Matter &amp; Disinformation</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jessica</forename><forename type="middle">De</forename><surname>Sylvanna Falcón</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">La</forename><surname>Cruz</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sydney</forename><forename type="middle">Lark</forename><surname>Eliot</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://humanrights.ucsc.edu/publications/black-lives-matter-disinformation.html" />
		<imprint>
			<date>August 31</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b55">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">The Long Fuse: Misinformation and the 2020 Election</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>©stanford University</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">California</forename><surname>Stanford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>94305</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://purl.stanford.edu/tr171zs0069" />
		<imprint>
			<date>May 28</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b56">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">GroundTruth: Augmenting Expert Image Geolocation with Crowdsourcing and Shared Representations</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Sukrit</forename><surname>Venkatagiri</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Jacob</forename><surname>Thebault-Spieker</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rachel</forename><surname>Kohler</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">John</forename><surname>Purviance</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Rifat</forename><surname>Sabbir Mansur</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Kurt</forename><surname>Luther</surname></persName>
		</author>
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Proc. ACM Hum.-Comput. Interact</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">3</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="30" />
			<date type="published" when="2019">2019. 2019</date>
			<publisher>CSCW</publisher>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b57">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Journalistic Source Discovery: Supporting The Identifcation of News Sources in User Generated Content</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Yixue</forename><surname>Wang</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nicholas</forename><surname>Diakopoulos</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3411764.3445266</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/3411764.3445266" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">Proceedings of the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems</title>
				<meeting>the 2021 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems<address><addrLine>New York, NY, USA</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<publisher>Association for Computing Machinery</publisher>
			<date type="published" when="2021-09-08">2021. September 8</date>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1" to="18" />
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b58">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">District of Columbia 1100 Connecticut Ave NW Suite 1300B Washington and Dc</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.politifact.com/article/2020/oct/31/scariest-misinformation-2020/" />
		<imprint>
			<date>20036. August 31</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>PolitiFact -The scariest misinformation of 2020. @politifact</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b59">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">misinformation-for-more-than-a-year-hereswhat-ive-learned/ [61] 2020. How journalists can avoid spreading coronavirus misinformation. The Journalist&apos;s Resource</title>
		<ptr target="https://journalistsresource.org/politics-and-government/coronavirus-misinformation-crowdsourcing-truth-mit-david-rand/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="1980-09-08">1980. September 8. 2018. September 5. September 5</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">60</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>I&apos;ve reported on misinformation for more than a year. Here&apos;s what I&apos;ve learned</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b60">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Investigative Digital Ethnography: Methods for Environmental Modeling. Media Manipulation Casebook</title>
		<ptr target="https://mediamanipulation.org/research/investigative-digital-ethnography-methods-environmental-modeling" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-05-05">2020. May 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b61">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">CNN&apos;s Irish reporter Donie O&apos;Sullivan goes viral during Washington unrest</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.irishcentral.com/news/cnn-irish-reporter-donie-o-sullivan" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">IrishCentral.com</title>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-09-05">2021. September 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b62">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Commission on Information Disorder Final Report. The Aspen Institute</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.aspeninstitute.org/publications/commission-on-information-disorder-fnal-report/" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021-01-08">2021. January 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b63">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Disinformation Broke The US</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.buzzfeednews.com/article/janelytvynenko/disinformation-broke-us" />
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2020-08-31">2020. August 31</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b64">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Dividing Communities, Undermining Democracy</title>
		<ptr target="https://networkcontagion.us/reports/the-qanon-conspiracy-destroying-families-dividing-communities-undermining-democracy/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">/15/20 -THE QANON CONSPIRACY: Destroying Families</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b65">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3415204</idno>
		<ptr target="https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3415204" />
		<title level="m">On the Misinformation Beat: Understanding the Work of Investigative Journalists Reporting on Problematic Information Online: Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction</title>
				<imprint>
			<date>January 6</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b66">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3415204</idno>
		<ptr target="https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3415204" />
		<title level="m">On the Misinformation Beat: Understanding the Work of Investigative Journalists Reporting on Problematic Information Online: Proceedings of the ACM on Human-Computer Interaction</title>
				<imprint>
			<date>January 6</date>
			<biblScope unit="volume">4</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b67">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Countering Tips for Journalists. Columbia Journalism Review</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.cjr.org/united_states_project/_countering_misinformation_tip.php" />
		<imprint>
			<date>August 31</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b68">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Prepare for US election misinformation. First Draft</title>
		<ptr target="https://frstdraftnews.org:443/long-form-article/prepare-for-us-election-misinformation/" />
		<imprint>
			<date>September 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b69">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Media Manipulation Casebook. Media Manipulation Casebook</title>
		<ptr target="https://mediamanipulation.org/homepage" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Retrieved September</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">5</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b70">
	<monogr>
		<ptr target="https://www.poynter.org/shop/fact-checking/mediawise-fact-checking-certifcate-winter-2020/" />
		<title level="m">MediaWise Fact-Checking Certifcate (Winter 2020/21). Poynter. Retrieved September 5</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b71">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Misinformation on Facebook got six times more clicks than factual news during the 2020 election, study says</title>
		<ptr target="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2021/09/03/facebook-misinformation-nyu-study/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Washington Post</title>
		<imprint>
			<date>September 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b72">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m">The Long Fuse: Misinformation and the 2020</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2021">2021</date>
		</imprint>
		<respStmt>
			<orgName>Center for an Informed Public, Digital Forensic Research Lab</orgName>
		</respStmt>
	</monogr>
	<note>Graphika, &amp; Stanford Internet Observatory</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b73">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Election</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Stanford</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://purl.stanford.edu/tr171zs0069" />
		<title level="m">Digital Repository: Election Integrity Partnership. v1.3.0 Available at</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b74">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="https://twitter.com/BrandyZadrozny/status/1432413838025142280" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Brandy Zadrozny on Twitter. Twitter</title>
		<imprint>
			<date>September 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b75">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="https://twitter.com/ShorensteinCtr/status/1433796196565348357" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Shorenstein Center on Twitter. Twitter</title>
		<imprint>
			<date>September 5</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b76">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1080/17512786.2011.616655?casa_token=yMQd4goD7sgAAAAA%3AfrfI6bM1e0GPLVtJ1ISHFpPOIT65GUFc2u3rY9bObK5eCyMINNlbzFxd-0ut9-IRTxQ07qAeMBn7LQ</idno>
		<ptr target="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/17512786.2011.616655?casa_token=yMQd4goD7sgAAAAA%3AfrfI6bM1e0GPLVtJ1ISHFpPOIT65GUFc2u3rY9bObK5eCyMINNlbzFxd-0ut9-IRTxQ07qAeMBn7LQ" />
		<title level="m">THE PROMISE OF COMPUTATIONAL JOURNALISM. Retrieved</title>
				<imprint>
			<date>September 7</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b77">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3025453.3025892</idno>
		<ptr target="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3025453.3025892" />
		<title level="m">Supporting the Use of User Generated Content in Journalistic Practice | Proceedings of the 2017 CHI Conference on Human Factors Computing Systems. Retrieved</title>
				<imprint>
			<date>September 7</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b78">
	<monogr>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Hci Accurate</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3290607.3299007</idno>
		<ptr target="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3290607.3299007" />
		<title level="m">Impartial and Transparent Journalism | Extended Abstracts of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. Retrieved</title>
				<imprint>
			<date>September 7</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b79">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/3173574.3174049</idno>
		<ptr target="https://dl.acm.org/doi/10.1145/3173574.3174049" />
		<title level="m">Making the News | Proceedings of the 2018 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Systems. Retrieved September</title>
				<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">7</biblScope>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b80">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/1464884916688964?casa_token=hwE0MmBdXt4AAAAA%3AO7AJHn_jMA6GysK5PzWPM1IS4blBdLfYmVghjT-uMxquXonoFlNcNHJ6fYQovq8jLvtBDuO1MIY</idno>
		<ptr target="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1464884916688964?casa_token=hwE0MmBdXt4AAAAA%3AO7AJHn_jMA6GysK5PzWPM1IS4blBdLfYmVghjT-uMxquXonoFlNcNHJ6fYQovq8jLvtBDuO1MIY" />
		<title level="m">Epilogue: Timing the study of news temporality -Barbie Zelizer</title>
				<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-09-08">2018. Retrieved September 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b81">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Covering science at dangerous speeds</title>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Op</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.cjr.org/opinion/pandemic-science-publishing-journals-how-to.php" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Columbia Journalism Review. Retrieved</title>
		<imprint>
			<date>September 7</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b82">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>Coronavirus</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://frstdraftnews.org:443/long-form-article/coronavirus-tools-" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="s">Tools guides for journalists. First Draft.</title>
		<imprint>
			<date>September 7</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b83">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Uses CrowdTangle To Source and Tell Local Stories on a National Level</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">Nbc</forename><surname>How</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><surname>News</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="http://help.crowdtangle.com/en/articles/4554891-how-nbc-news-uses-crowdtangle-to-source-and-tell-local-stories-on-a-national-level" />
		<imprint>
			<date>September 7</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b84">
	<analytic>
		<title/>
		<ptr target="https://datasociety.net/research/media-manipulation/" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Media Manipulation &amp; Disinformation. Data &amp; Society</title>
		<imprint>
			<date>May 25</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b85">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/1124772.1124855</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/1124772.1124855" />
		<title level="m">Implications for design</title>
				<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b86">
	<monogr>
		<title level="m" type="main">Being in the thick of in-the-wild studies</title>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1145/2207676.2208561</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1145/2207676.2208561" />
		<imprint/>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b87">
	<monogr>
		<title/>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">U</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Senator Christopher Coons Of Delaware</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<ptr target="https://www.coons.senate.gov/news/press-releases/coons-portman-klobuchar-announce-legislation-to-ensure-transparency-at-social-media-platforms" />
		<imprint>
			<date>January 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
	<note>Retrieved</note>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b88">
	<monogr>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/2056305118763366</idno>
		<ptr target="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/2056305118763366" />
		<title level="m">Perceptions of Twitter Research Ethics -Casey Fiesler</title>
				<meeting><address><addrLine>Nicholas Proferes</addrLine></address></meeting>
		<imprint>
			<date type="published" when="2018-01-08">2018. January 8</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
